<bug id='1484' author='doccosmos' open_date='2020-05-25T07:24:53Z' closed_time='2020-10-05T12:03:47Z'>
	<summary>Coregionalization with heteroscedastic errors</summary>
	<description>
Under GPflow 1.5.1, I was able to construct a coregionalized kernel with HeteroskedasticGaussian likelihoods by following the two tutorials on this. However, now upgrading to GPflow 2.0.4, the code no longer works. I have followed the upgrade guidelines but it appears that I can no longer use SwitchedLikelihood with HeteroskedasticGaussian that just extends Likelihood but rather needs to extend ScalarLikelihood.
If I then set num_latent_gps = 1 in VGP (as per the HG tutorial):
m = gpflow.models.VGP((X_augmented, Y_augmented), kernel=kern, likelihood=lik, num_latent_gps = 1)
I get:
super().init(latent_dim = 1, observation_dim = 2, **kwargs)
File "/opt/anaconda3/lib/python3.7/site-packages/gpflow/likelihoods/base.py", line 310, in init
super().init(latent_dim=None, observation_dim=None, **kwargs)
TypeError: init() got multiple values for keyword argument 'latent_dim'
Correcting for this gives other issues so I'm wondering what the best advice now is for combining HeteroskedasticGaussian with Coregion?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='doccosmos' date='2020-05-27T08:54:56Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/doccosmos&gt;@doccosmos&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for your interest in GPflow and reporting your issues! To help us investigate what's going on, could you please complete your minimal example so that it is self-contained and we can run it (and reproduce your bug) by copy&amp;pasting (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/help/minimal-reproducible-example&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/help/minimal-reproducible-example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details)? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='doccosmos' date='2020-10-05T12:03:47Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/doccosmos&gt;@doccosmos&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if this is indeed a bug in GPflow we'd be happy to look into fixing this - however, without a reproducible example of your issue this isn't feasible for us. Please do re-open this if you're able to provide more details! Thanks:)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>