<bug id='1521' author='irum' open_date='2020-07-03T16:11:36Z' closed_time='2020-08-03T13:16:32Z'>
	<summary>deployment issue with transfer learning</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I am using transfer learning technique and added my custom layers in it . When I use the prediction from last layer of my transfer learning as input to GPflow model , It trains well but when I use saved checkpoints from the model for deployment then it does not work. I have checked the hyper-parameters after training and during deployment , values are same. So it rules out the possibility that model is not saved properly as checkpoints.
If I remove my custom layers from base-model of ResNet50v2 then I can successfully deploy the model on test images. Then it gives the same accuracy as I get after training on test images.
Please can you identify the reason behind it by just making a simple example. Otherwise, Please can you send me a confidential link where i can send my code.  I do not understand what technical issue is in the program as i mentioned earlier it works if I just use base-model but does not work on custom layers.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


GPflow version: 2.0.4
GPflow installed from: installed by cloning from GitHub and used command python setup.py install
TensorFlow version: 2.2.0
Python version  : 3.6
Operating system: linux

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='irum' date='2020-07-19T12:15:34Z'>
		Hi,
Can anyone please help me on this. I have been stuck on this for long.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='irum' date='2020-07-20T12:38:26Z'>
		Hi Irum,
It is hard to fully understand your problem without having example code and/or a stack trace. However, it may be due to how you save the model as Tensorflow does not support saving instances of . Maybe &lt;denchmark-link:https://gpflow.readthedocs.io/en/master/notebooks/intro_to_gpflow2.html#TensorFlow-saved_model&gt;check out this notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as it details the problem and a simple workaround. If this is not the issue then I would suggest creating a minimal working example that produces the same error so that it is easy for someone else to understand.
Best,
Aidan
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='irum' date='2020-07-20T12:51:14Z'>
		Hi Aidan,
I am saving the checkpoints and then restoring it as mentioned in  the &lt;denchmark-link:https://gpflow.readthedocs.io/en/master/notebooks/intro_to_gpflow2.html#Checkpointing&gt;notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I understand that when I add custom layers during transfer learning (CNN) then my code does not work . If its only in the following form then it works
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        model = resnet50V2()
       cnn_model = tf.keras.Models.Sequential([ model, global average pooling layer])
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Then it works but if I add more Dense layers then it does not work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='irum' date='2020-07-20T12:54:03Z'>
		It is mistakenly closed. I reopened it
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='irum' date='2020-08-03T13:16:32Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/irum&gt;@irum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, GPflow is an open-source project maintained by volunteers - I'm afraid we don't have the capacity to debug other people's code. We try and respond promptly to bug reports and help out to the best of our abilities, but I don't think what you are describing here is something we can fix through changes to GPflow-core. Without a &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/help/minimal-reproducible-example&gt;minimal reproducible example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that showcases more clearly what the issue is, there's not much others can do to help you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>