<bug id='703' author='sadatnfs' open_date='2018-04-05T00:21:17Z' closed_time='2018-09-19T13:29:55Z'>
	<summary>MCMC example documentation on readthedocs didn't render</summary>
	<description>
In the section where we attempt to use MCMC on theta, that block errored out:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gpflow.readthedocs.io/en/stable/notebooks/regression.html&gt;https://gpflow.readthedocs.io/en/stable/notebooks/regression.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-04-06T19:06:30Z'>
		Thx, we will fix it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-04-06T19:31:28Z'>
		Thanks! I feel like something might have changed with the API eh? (I'm also getting errors when I'm trying to MCMC)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-04-10T10:26:03Z'>
		This is working for me locally. How does the readthedocs version get updated?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-04-10T14:56:44Z'>
		Related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/GPflow/GPflow/issues/582&gt;#582&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - same notebook, just latest vs stable...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-04-19T09:19:30Z'>
		The notebook has actually been fixed in the master branch.
However, there are different versions on readthedocs:

master points to master, has the current documentation and working notebook.
stable points to GPflow-1.0-RC, which is now out of date, and contains the broken notebook. This should probably point to the latest release?
latest seems to be completely broken.
docupdate is completely out of date and should be removed altogether.

README.md points to latest...
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='sadatnfs' date='2018-09-19T13:29:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sadatnfs&gt;@sadatnfs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 "stable" and "latest" versions of readthedocs are deprecated. We now have "master" for the master branch (latest actual release) and "develop" for the develop branch (bleeding-edge latest version on github). Please check you are looking at the correct version of the docs. If you find any links pointing to "stable" or "latest", please let us know so we can fix them! (Feel free to re-open this issue!)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>