<bug id='1576' author='ultmaster' open_date='2019-09-27T04:59:13Z' closed_time='2019-10-25T09:25:47Z'>
	<summary>nnictl package install not working for venv</summary>
	<description>
It seems that nnictl package install makes the package going to user level, which makes it not accessible from a venv.
Warning:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Installing collected packages: ConfigSpaceNNI, docutils, pynisher, pyrfr, sphinxcontrib-htmlhelp, sphinxcontrib-qthelp, sphinxcontrib-devhelp, imagesize, Jinja2, sphinxcontrib-applehelp, alabaster, sphinxcontrib-jsmath, Pygments, snowballstemmer, sphinxcontrib-serializinghtml, packaging, sphinx, sphinx-rtd-theme, smac
  Running setup.py install for ConfigSpaceNNI ... done
  The script pygmentize is installed in '/home/zhangyuge/.local/bin' which is not on PATH.
  Consider adding this directory to PATH or, if you prefer to suppress this warning, use --no-warn-script-location.
  Running setup.py install for snowballstemmer ... done
  The scripts sphinx-apidoc, sphinx-autogen, sphinx-build and sphinx-quickstart are installed in '/home/zhangyuge/.local/bin' which is not on PATH.
  Consider adding this directory to PATH or, if you prefer to suppress this warning, use --no-warn-script-location.
  Running setup.py install for smac ... done
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Corresponding code:



nni/tools/nni_cmd/command_utils.py


         Line 49
      in
      958efab






 cmds = 'cd ' + requirements_path + ' &amp;&amp; {0} -m pip install --user -r requirements.txt' 





We could consider removing this --user.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ultmaster' date='2019-10-02T03:16:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultmaster&gt;@ultmaster&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you try to fix it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ultmaster' date='2019-10-02T03:18:48Z'>
		Sure. By removing this --user. I just don't understand why we have it in the first place.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ultmaster' date='2019-10-02T13:05:20Z'>
		If users installed nni locally (not in virtual env), no --user means users have to use sudo to run pip command.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ultmaster' date='2019-10-02T14:36:23Z'>
		I don't know about this. As far as I remember, last time I run pip outside a virtual env, it automatically goes into some ~/.pip without asking sudo. I think removing --user is better than adding this, because --user might contaminate the outside environment, which is definitely not wanted.
Meanwhile, I will check whether there is a way to tell pip is inside a virtualenv/conda or not.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>