<bug id='11785' author='reedkotler' open_date='2017-07-26T13:49:09Z' closed_time='2018-02-08T00:00:45Z'>
	<summary>proposed new github for tensorflow notebooks</summary>
	<description>
I would like to propose that we make a separate repository in github for jupyter notebooks.
I think it should be separate from the main tensorflow github so that people can check it out without having to check out all of tensorflow.
I've created such a github and will work on it by myself for now but I think eventually there should be something more official or at least maybe what I have can be considered official enough to have pointers to it from the main tensorflow github.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/reedkotler/tensorflow-notebooks&gt;https://github.com/reedkotler/tensorflow-notebooks&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='reedkotler' date='2017-07-27T01:45:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I would be concerned about having divergent copies of the same tutorials. Has there been any progress on what we discussed a few months ago about being able to download a jupyter notebook from any tutorial page (i.e. a dynamically concerted notebook form of any doc page). That would be nice, and it wouldn't have a possibility of out of sync. It would also allow us to unit test our tutorials easily to make sure they didn't get stale.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='reedkotler' date='2017-07-28T06:13:54Z'>
		I agree with same code/git base.
Having notebooks unittested would be great. That probably would solve python version differences on ie &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
* too.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 where is that discussion documented?

download a jupyter notebook from any tutorial page (i.e. a dynamically concerted notebook form of any doc page).

Is a link to raw version not enough?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='reedkotler' date='2017-12-20T19:21:39Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='reedkotler' date='2018-01-04T19:09:53Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='reedkotler' date='2018-01-24T13:12:21Z'>
		Nagging Assignee: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='reedkotler' date='2018-02-08T00:00:45Z'>
		Hi.  We're working on an experiment with notebooks for tensorflow.org pages.  It's still in the planning stage, but we are actively looking into it.  I'm going to close this, as there is some internal tooling we need to write, and tracking it here is not going to be helpful.
Thanks for your suggestion!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>