<bug id='11784' author='jubjamie' open_date='2017-07-26T13:46:11Z' closed_time='2017-08-29T08:31:24Z'>
	<summary>[docs] Windows Instructions need updating.</summary>
	<description>
Any way to contribute to the installation instructions for Windows? I deal with a lot of people having installation instructions on Stack Overflow etc. and there are a couple of things on the Install pages that could do with being corrected, clarified or changed. Happy to do these myself if you'd like. I'll list them below:


"TensorFlow only supports version 3.5.x of Python on Windows." is no longer true since 1.2 as 3.6 is supported.


The r1.3 version of the install page introduces this new line: "TensorFlow will not load if it cannot find cuDNN64_5.dll. To use a different version of cuDNN, you must build from source." however I thought that 1.3 was built with cuDNN 6. Users may find this conflict confusing because, as I found with #11645, 1.3.0 will NOT load with cuDNN64_5.dll. Shouldn't this change to cuDNN64_6.dll?


Anaconda Installation slightly misleading? I use anaconda to run our tensorflow environments without a problem. I download via pip install tensorflow(-gpu) instead of the unsupported conda version and, from a user's point of view, there's no reason for it be unsupported. is there a reason that a pypi installation put in an anaconda environment would act differently enough to virtual env/root install to be unsupported? I also don't see why the installation page can't recommend downloading straight from pypi instead of using the long storage.googleapis... url. Especially as 3.6 is now supported.


Happy to implement these changes if I knew where. Are the markdown files in docs_src linked to the website? If so i'll pop a PR into there.
Cheers
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jubjamie' date='2017-07-26T17:38:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, could you update the documentation?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jubjamie' date='2017-07-26T22:57:53Z'>
		Yes, we generate the website from docs_src.
Assigning to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gunan&gt;@gunan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for install docs update.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jubjamie' date='2017-07-27T18:52:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/av8ramit&gt;@av8ramit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you update documentations on the release branch and master branch?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-21T16:14:51Z'>
		Hate to be that guy but the current installation instructions still say that you should have cuDNN 5.1 installed then linking to 1.3 binaries which I believe are built with cuDNN 6 which means users won't be able to successfully install. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gunan&gt;@gunan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/av8ramit&gt;@av8ramit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Unless something has changed where cuDNN 5.1 WILL work. I've not personally tried it since rc1 but I assume that hasn't changed as the release notes suggest otherwise. I've already helped a user today try to get up and running because of these errors.
Cheers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T12:37:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mrry&gt;@mrry&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Am I correct in saying that you submitted a PR for this and it's just not showing on the website? If so I can close the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T14:02:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jubjamie&gt;@jubjamie&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/12383&gt;#12383&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 made the change, but I don't know what it takes to get the website to rebuild. (Perhaps &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would know, or know the right person to ask?)
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T15:07:09Z'>
		Ok. I'll leave the issue open to track at least. I know it's not a huge problem but it's caught a lot of people out! If you are tracking this internally however feel free to close. Cheers
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T17:57:56Z'>
		We will republish the website later today.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T20:10:44Z'>
		In master, linux says 6 but windows still says 5.1.  In r1.3, Windows
contains 5.1 -&gt; 6 transformation, but Linux is still at 5.1.

Do we need all four of these docs to say 6?
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Thu, Aug 24, 2017 at 10:58 AM, gunan ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 We will republish the website later today.

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#11784 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AA1YDu0Jk7mtTip5TchEU2lDQh29oyjLks5sbbm8gaJpZM4Oj8bu&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-24T20:14:08Z'>
		All four should say 6.
Amit is working on fixing all of these.

On Thu, Aug 24, 2017 at 1:12 PM, Wolff Dobson &lt;notifications@github.com&gt;
wrote:
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


 In master, linux says 6 but windows still says 5.1. In r1.3, Windows
 contains 5.1 -&gt; 6 transformation, but Linux is still at 5.1.

 Do we need all four of these docs to say 6?

 On Thu, Aug 24, 2017 at 10:58 AM, gunan ***@***.***&gt; wrote:

 &gt; We will republish the website later today.
 &gt;
 &gt; —
 &gt; You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 &gt; Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &gt; &lt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/
 11784#issuecomment-324710316&gt;,
 &gt; or mute the thread
 &gt; &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/
 AA1YDu0Jk7mtTip5TchEU2lDQh29oyjLks5sbbm8gaJpZM4Oj8bu&gt;
 &gt; .

 &gt;

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#11784 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AHlCOTbrz49PQgXEeIRK14q85M6nc41uks5sbdkTgaJpZM4Oj8bu&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T02:40:51Z'>
		Ran into this today installing tensorflow-gpu and even worse: the NVIDIA cudnn archive page doesn't have version 6 anymore: &lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-archive&gt;https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-archive&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T03:15:42Z'>
		i am very sorry about hear that,my cudnn is shared from baiducloud,so,Do U have a baidu account.
this is my share url: &lt;denchmark-link:https://pan.baidu.com/s/1o8zCUz4&gt;https://pan.baidu.com/s/1o8zCUz4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 密码: 3k7y

At 2017-08-25 10:43:18, "Kevin Watters" &lt;notifications@github.com&gt; wrote:


Ran into this today installing tensorflow-gpu and even worse: the NVIDIA cudnn archive page doesn't have version 6 anymore: &lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-archive&gt;https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-archive&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


—
You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub, or mute the thread.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T03:57:37Z'>
		@WangChengLongWilliam I get "Oh oh, the page you are visiting does not exist" at that link.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T04:05:01Z'>
		ok ,i try to send the file to you email

At 2017-08-25 11:59:25, "Kevin Watters" &lt;notifications@github.com&gt; wrote:


@WangChengLongWilliam I get "Oh oh, the page you are visiting does not exist" at that link.

—
You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub, or mute the thread.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T04:14:54Z'>
		@kwvinw Not sure what that page is, but AFAIK cudnn is distributed through here, with a few terms and conditions.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn&gt;https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I cannot log in and check, but can anyone see if this site includes cudnn v6 after logging in?
Our installation instructions still should point to this site.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T13:45:30Z'>
		false alarm: looks like they brought back the 6.0 link. I had emailed them about it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-25T14:00:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-download&gt;https://developer.nvidia.com/rdp/cudnn-download&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
      has cuDNN 6 it is not on the archive page. kevinw already said this above but adding the link so people are not on the archive page wondering where it is.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-29T08:31:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gunan&gt;@gunan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 This looks like it has mostly been resolved apart from the inclusion of Python 3.6 but that's not as bad of an issue as people being unable to run the binaries. Thanks for sorting it, i'm sure it will help lots of people in the long run. Closing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-29T16:30:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jubjamie&gt;@jubjamie&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Good catch! &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/av8ramit&gt;@av8ramit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can we also add python 3.6 support in windows docs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-29T17:12:54Z'>
		Done. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/12687&gt;#12687&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='21' author='jubjamie' date='2017-08-30T08:12:49Z'>
		Hi,
From version 1.4,  TF will depend on scipy, then the user should either have a FORTRAN compiler or get it from a third-party python distribution (e.g. Anaconda).  We need document this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>