<bug id='11831' author='yhu9' open_date='2017-07-27T22:39:54Z' closed_time='2018-09-27T16:54:50Z'>
	<summary>No mention of how to use custom RunConfig with Estimator in the Estimator tutorial</summary>
	<description>
On the tutorial of creating estimators using tf.contrib.learn there doesn't seem to be any mention of how to create your own RunConfig object in order to specify the configurations for an Estimator run. The configuration in particular I wanted to find was on how to write summaries after custom sized steps. I eventually found it in the RunConfig description, but I think it would be worthwhile to mention it in the tutorial.
Link to the tutorial:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/extend/estimators&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/extend/estimators&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Link to the RunConfig description:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/contrib/learn/RunConfig&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/contrib/learn/RunConfig&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I was wondering if the tutorial could be updated to show how to create your own RunConfig object and use it with the Estimator.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yhu9' date='2017-07-27T23:17:39Z'>
		The API also does not specify that the  parameter to &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/contrib/learn/Estimator&gt;tf.contrib.learn.Estimator&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 should be a &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/contrib/learn/RunConfig&gt;RunConfig&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Often a tutorial does not contain all the details of a class, but we should at least specify this in the API.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dr4b&gt;@dr4b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sandersk&gt;@sandersk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thoughts?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yhu9' date='2017-07-29T10:41:05Z'>
		Related to this issue, I wonder if we should not try to update the tutorial to use the core Estimator API?
In general, are tutorials considered as contributions to Tensorflow?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yhu9' date='2017-07-31T15:32:19Z'>
		Hi all,
Agree it would be worthwhile to mention RunConfig in the tutorial, and link to appropriate resources.
Also agree that it would be good to update this tutorial to use core Estimator rather than tf.contrib.learn. I'll grab this issue and get to these changes as soon as I can.
Thanks,
Sanders
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yhu9' date='2018-05-10T18:07:48Z'>
		Unassigning myself from this one, as others have taken over this tutorial.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yhu9' date='2018-05-16T23:23:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sandersk&gt;@sandersk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you re-assign to whomever has taken over the tutorial?  (Otherwise the butler will just randomly auto-assign, as it did to me :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='yhu9' date='2018-06-04T13:31:47Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, can you get this issue assigned to the appropriate person?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='yhu9' date='2018-06-29T14:57:00Z'>
		The TF page on check points tells you how to do run config for an estimator:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/checkpoints#checkpointing_frequency&gt;TensorFlow checkpoints&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Just about to try it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='yhu9' date='2018-07-16T10:42:23Z'>
		The TensorFlow checkpoints link leads to a 404- &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/checkpoints#checkpointing_frequency&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/checkpoints#checkpointing_frequency&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

A redirect, rather than removing, would be nice. I still can't find any doc on how to use the RunConfig with an Estimator.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='yhu9' date='2018-08-03T16:44:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/natalieharris&gt;@natalieharris&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I can't see anything wrong with the link I provided, or yours for that matter.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='yhu9' date='2018-08-08T14:38:30Z'>
		Yes, this has now been fixed
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='yhu9' date='2018-09-07T18:51:29Z'>
		Nagging Assignee &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: It has been 29 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='yhu9' date='2018-09-15T00:19:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yhu9&gt;@yhu9&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='yhu9' date='2018-09-27T16:54:50Z'>
		Closing this, feel free to open a new one if any issues come up.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='yhu9' date='2019-01-15T06:24:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wt-huang&gt;@wt-huang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The original issue stated:

The configuration in particular I wanted to find was on how to write summaries after custom sized steps.

And indeed, in the new link &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/checkpoints#checkpointing_frequency&gt;Checkpointing frequency&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, there is mention of the  parameter, but not .
It might be confusing because it is different from the parameter every_n_iter of LoggingTensorHook. So it would be nice to make a link from both these pages to RunConfig:

Guide: Creating Custom Estimators
Tutorial: Build a Convolutional Neural Network using Estimators

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>