<bug id='11977' author='ultimatespirit' open_date='2017-08-02T19:22:24Z' closed_time='2018-01-19T04:56:29Z'>
	<summary>Multiple runs of Configure with MKL enabled leads to cyclic symlinks</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): No
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Linux Centos 7
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): Compilation from source
TensorFlow version (use command below): v1.2.1 and v1.3.0-r1
Python version: Python 3.5.2
Bazel version (if compiling from source): 0.5.2
CUDA/cuDNN version: N/A
GPU model and memory: N/A
Exact command to reproduce: ./configure [enter] [enter] y y [enter till complete], twice

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Currently the way the configure script is written for the MKL decision branch it does not ensure no cyclic symbolic links are created for libdl.so.2
This becomes a problem if MKL has been downloaded already upon a re-run of the configure script and the first line of the locate output happens to be the symlink located in the third_party/mkl directory. If that occurs then the ln -sf command will create a cyclic symlink.
This can be fixed either by checking that "$loc" is not the same string as "$PWD"/third_party/mkl/libdl.so.2 or by checking for the existence of the symlink before the ln command.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

configure, line 276, 277.
loc=$(locate -e libdl.so.2 | sed -n 1p) &lt;- can end up returning the destination file if it already exists
ln -sf $loc third_party/mkl/libdl.so.2 &lt;- if "$loc" == "$PWD"/third_party/mkl/libdl.so.2, creates cyclic link.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ultimatespirit' date='2017-08-02T19:39:05Z'>
		I have seen elsewhere in the issue tracker mention that this section of configure code may change soon, so rather than making a pull request immediately I will just say here how I fixed the script for this specific problem. This would also fix Issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/11029&gt;#11029&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Instead of using locate use whereis, which checks the $PATH alone.
Line 276 becomes
loc="$(whereis libdl.so.2 | awk '{print $2}')"
Unfortunately whereis has no easy to detect failure status, so there should be an empty check for $loc to make the script more robust (though not having libdl is a very bad sign).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ultimatespirit' date='2017-12-20T01:17:20Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ultimatespirit' date='2018-01-03T19:12:38Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ultimatespirit' date='2018-01-18T19:14:55Z'>
		Nagging Assignee: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ultimatespirit' date='2018-01-19T04:56:29Z'>
		This issue is most likely obsolete due to changes in recent months. If it's still an issue, let me know and I'll reopen.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>