<bug id='12156' author='galvk' open_date='2017-08-09T19:57:41Z' closed_time='2018-01-23T18:00:18Z'>
	<summary>tf.pow edge case failure</summary>
	<description>
The tf.pow() function has an edge case which causes it to hang with no error message.
If you try to evaluate tf.pow(x,y), when x is an integer (and thus the output tensor is also an integer), while y is a negative value, tensorflow hangs trying to cast the fraction as an integer.
Examples;
sess.run(tf.pow([5,2],[-2,3]))
sess.run(tf.pow([5],[-2]))
sess.run(tf.pow(5, -2))
sess.run(tf.pow(tf.constant(5), tf.constant(-2)))
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='galvk' date='2017-08-09T20:22:37Z'>
		Was able to reproduce this issue... actually if y is double, we also have a problem... I tried passing in 1.2 and that didn't work.
TypeError: Expected int32 passed to parameter 'y' of op 'Pow', got [1.2] of type 'list' instead.
The documentation (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/core/ops/math_ops.cc#L656&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/core/ops/math_ops.cc#L656&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) seems to suggest that y can be int32 or double etc. So either we should fix the documentation or increase the capability.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='galvk' date='2017-08-12T11:20:09Z'>
		Hi, I found the doc of gen_math_ops._pow is:
    y: A `Tensor`. Must have the same type as `x`.
Hence, if both x and y are double, it works well.
In [4]: sess.run(tf.pow(5.0, 1.2))
Out[4]: 6.8986487
So for double, there are two solution in my option:

cast x or y automatically when dtypes are different.
or fix the document: y must be the same type as x.

I prefer to the first one, and I can work on the double issue.
As for negative value, it indeed hangs out.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='galvk' date='2017-10-23T06:42:35Z'>
		I am interested in working on this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='galvk' date='2017-12-20T01:15:02Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='galvk' date='2017-12-24T01:21:50Z'>
		Added a PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/15607&gt;#15607&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to try to address the issue. It follows a similar approach as safe_mod/safe_div. Please take a look if interested.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='galvk' date='2018-01-07T18:54:40Z'>
		Nagging Assigneee: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>