<bug id='13288' author='EFanZh' open_date='2017-09-25T06:42:53Z' closed_time='2018-03-31T22:57:01Z'>
	<summary>Cannot put a Tensor into a StagingArea</summary>
	<description>
TensorFlow version: 1.3.0
According to the document, I should be able to put a tensor to a StagingArea[1]. But the following code does not work:
import tensorflow as tf
from tensorflow.contrib import staging

staging.StagingArea(dtypes=[tf.int32]).put(tf.constant(1))
The output says:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Traceback (most recent call last):
  File "/███████/dataset.py", line 4, in &lt;module&gt;
    staging.StagingArea(dtypes=[tf.int32]).put(tf.constant(1))
  File "/███████/site-packages/tensorflow/python/ops/data_flow_ops.py", line 1671, in put
    vals, _ = self._check_put_dtypes(values, indices)
  File "/███████/site-packages/tensorflow/python/ops/data_flow_ops.py", line 1480, in _check_put_dtypes
    raise ValueError("Indices must be supplied when inserting a list "
ValueError: Indices must be supplied when inserting a list of tensors
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='EFanZh' date='2017-09-25T09:47:59Z'>
		This question seems suitable for StackOverFlow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='EFanZh' date='2017-10-04T07:39:29Z'>
		This question is better asked on  &lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 since it is not a  bug or feature request. There is also a larger community that reads questions there. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='EFanZh' date='2017-10-04T08:08:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/asimshankar&gt;@asimshankar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Maybe my description is not very clear, but I was not asking a question. I am fairly sure this is a bug, because the code’s behavior is different than the documented behavior. I think either the implementation is wrong, or the documentation is wrong.
Consider the following two pieces of codes:
import tensorflow as tf
from tensorflow.contrib import staging

staging.StagingArea(dtypes=[tf.int32]).put(tf.constant(1))
import tensorflow as tf
from tensorflow.contrib import staging

staging.StagingArea(dtypes=[tf.int32]).put((tf.constant(1),))
The first one won’t work as I described, the second one works. If the documentation is correct, both ones should work, so I think this is a bug that need to be fixed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='EFanZh' date='2017-10-04T16:59:53Z'>
		I see. Indeed it seems the documentation is incorrect.
Possible fixes include:

Updating the documentation in this line to something like A tuple or list of Tensors. The number of elements must match the length of the list provided to the dtypes argument when creating the StagingArea.
Updating the code to allow for a single Tensor by changing this line so that indices ends up as [0] instead of None when the argument is an instance of Tensor

PRs to fix these are welcome!
FYI &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ekelsen&gt;@ekelsen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='EFanZh' date='2017-10-05T06:34:12Z'>
		Thank you for outlining how to address this, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/asimshankar&gt;@asimshankar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and for making it accessible for my first contribution. I've created a PR here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/13502&gt;#13502&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and tested it locally.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>