<bug id='13549' author='Remi-Coulom' open_date='2017-10-07T09:37:48Z' closed_time='2018-08-24T22:01:27Z'>
	<summary>const_op.h missing from C++ API documentation</summary>
	<description>
I could not find the documentation for tensorflow::ops::Const starting from the C++ API documentation. I figured out it is declared in ops/const_op.h, but there is no link from the main C++ docs:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

A search returns this, but it looks orphaned:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/group/const-op&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/group/const-op&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So I guess there is something wrong in the docs.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2017-10-07T18:08:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/skye&gt;@skye&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Is  somehow excluded when generating the API docs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2017-10-09T14:37:56Z'>
		I'm not sure what's going on. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dr4b&gt;@dr4b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do you have any ideas? I wonder if this somehow has to do with Const being in the namespace ops, and all the other op methods being in nested namespaces inside ops?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2017-10-09T17:32:48Z'>
		Another strange problem I noticed is that tensorflow::Input::Initializer appears twice in the menu on the left:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/struct/tensorflow/input/initializer&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/cc/struct/tensorflow/input/initializer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2017-10-12T22:40:12Z'>
		hey, so I looked into the const_op thing and basically it's not showing up because that module/file has no classes in it (you might notice the index pages are all based around listening classes/structs in each part of the API).  We'll have to think of a way to deal with this, I guess.
(Initializer is a separate bug that I was aware of a while ago but didn't realize was still there)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2018-01-26T00:07:59Z'>
		Assigning to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dr4b&gt;@dr4b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, since it seems like this is a bug we should fix.  Feel free to re-assign as appropriate.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2018-01-26T21:26:14Z'>
		I've already looked into this but I'm still not sure what the right solution is given that seriously const_op had no classes/structs in it.  Unless that's changed?
The duplicate inner struct bug that Remi mentioned, however, is out against me in our internal tools and I should look into that at some point, it's true.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2018-04-02T20:52:49Z'>
		I no longer work on Tensorflow and won't be able to address this any time soon (as I said, the issue is that there's nothing inside the file that Doxygen is going to pick up.)  Reassigning if Wolff cares to deal with it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2018-08-24T21:42:02Z'>
		Nagging Assignees &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MarkDaoust&gt;@MarkDaoust&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: It has been 112 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Remi-Coulom' date='2018-08-24T22:01:27Z'>
		There's no simple way to fix this, and the C++ api is relatively low priority.
Sorry.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>