<bug id='1374' author='alquraishi' open_date='2016-03-03T18:44:24Z' closed_time='2018-05-02T21:29:31Z'>
	<summary>Document trick with slash in scope names</summary>
	<description>
The documentation for tf.name_scope is rather ambiguous on what happens if the scope name ends with '/', merely stating what happens if it doesn't end with a '/'. The fact that the behavior is different, specifically that ending with a '/' does not result in automatically uniqueifying the scope name, is very important and useful, because sometimes one wants to reenter a previously created scope. This possibility is only alluded to when describing recapturing scope variables, but the functionality is more general than that.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='alquraishi' date='2017-08-24T08:23:31Z'>
		Does the code with scope name ends with '/' run ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='alquraishi' date='2018-02-08T00:06:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alquraishi&gt;@alquraishi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 does this issue still look relevant?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='alquraishi' date='2018-02-22T13:09:28Z'>
		Nagging Awaiting Response: It has been 14 days with no activityand the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='alquraishi' date='2018-03-09T13:37:44Z'>
		Nagging Awaiting Response: It has been 14 days with no activityand the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='alquraishi' date='2018-03-25T03:46:57Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='alquraishi' date='2018-04-17T12:45:07Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='alquraishi' date='2018-05-02T18:49:35Z'>
		It has been 29 days with no activity and the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='alquraishi' date='2018-05-02T21:29:31Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>