<bug id='14007' author='tongda' open_date='2017-10-26T18:29:28Z' closed_time='2018-09-13T17:17:01Z'>
	<summary>BatchNorm not working in a _FuncGraph</summary>
	<description>
I am working on macOS 10.12.6 with TensorFlow 1.3.0, Python version: 3.6.2. CPU only.
I found that if tf.contrib.layers.batch_norm is called inside a Defun, a TypeError will be thrown. To clarify, the function here is a map_func that will be used in Dataset.map invoke, instead of a normal python function.
To regenerate the scenario, try this piece of code:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Dataset.range(27).batch(27) \
  .map(lambda x: tf.cast(tf.reshape(x, (3, 3, 3)), tf.float32) / 32.0) \
  .map(lambda img: tf.contrib.layers.batch_norm(img)) \
  .make_one_shot_iterator().get_next().eval()
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

You will get an error like this:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;TypeError: In op 'BatchNorm/AssignMovingAvg', input types ([tf.float32, tf.float32]) are not compatible with expected types ([tf.float32_ref, tf.float32])
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I did some investigation. One thing that I found is that inside the batch_norm, we will assign a new value to the mean variable by calling assign_sub, which accept a variable with ref type and a value with a basic type. But the variable has been created some where in the _FuncGraph with a basic type, instead of a ref type, which make the compatibility check failed.
I will keep digging into this issue, but I think this seems a bug.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tongda' date='2017-10-26T22:06:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mrry&gt;@mrry&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if this isn't supported can you document/give a better error message do you think?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tongda' date='2017-12-21T05:20:30Z'>
		Reassigning to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/akshayka&gt;@akshayka&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, since he is currently revamping the function API.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tongda' date='2018-02-08T20:26:21Z'>
		This somehow slipped under my radar; I'll dig into this ...
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tongda' date='2018-09-08T18:37:01Z'>
		Nagging Assignee &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/akshayka&gt;@akshayka&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: It has been 120 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tongda' date='2018-09-13T17:17:01Z'>
		This won't be fixed for Defun(), which is being replaced with tf.contrib.eager.defun. Once Datasets switch to using tf.contrib.eager.defun, the pasted code will work as intended.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>