<bug id='1449' author='lfwin' open_date='2016-03-10T07:42:04Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T18:21:28Z'>
	<summary>Need better doc about the difference between name scope and variable scope in tensorflow and What's the context manager?(Soved))</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
Although stack overflow have a question about this, &lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/34215746/difference-between-variable-scope-and-name-scope-in-tensorflow&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/34215746/difference-between-variable-scope-and-name-scope-in-tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. But right now the answers are not so clear and the doc also not tell the difference too, but I believe understanding the difference between name scope and variable scope and context manager is beneficial to programming for newbie using tensorflow.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lfwin' date='2016-03-12T10:56:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/alexgorban/fa5755c7f7fa49b47961&gt;https://gist.github.com/alexgorban/fa5755c7f7fa49b47961&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, This may be helpful for anyone confused by these functions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lfwin' date='2016-03-17T02:26:59Z'>
		there're few &lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/35919020/whats-the-difference-of-name-scope-and-a-variable-scope-in-tensorflow&gt;more questions&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 regarding this issue - and it's not me asking :)
and even after reading answers and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lfwin&gt;@lfwin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 's gist, I would rather not say that I understand the purpose of this scope diversity
could anyone give any practical recipe/code snippet illustrating those scopes' usage examples? (or just something like: "most of the time if you think you need a scope, use tf.variable_scope()")
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lfwin' date='2017-06-16T18:21:28Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. We hope that you were able to resolve it on your own. However, since this is a support issue rather than a bug or feature request, you will probably get more information by posting it on StackOverflow.
Documentation continues to change and I hope improve.  I do not want to suggest your issue was solved without giving you a link.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lfwin' date='2017-10-16T17:01:43Z'>
		To understand  and why it's useful, I suggest reading the "Name scoping and nodes" section on this page:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/graph_viz#name_scoping_and_nodes&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/graph_viz#name_scoping_and_nodes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

To understand  and why it's useful, I suggest reading the "Sharing Variables" section on this page:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/programmers_guide/variables#sharing_variables&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/programmers_guide/variables#sharing_variables&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I stumbled upon this issue after some Googling because:

I was reading the beginner tutorial, Deep MNIST for Experts, and in the beginning it said "...you can download the fully implemented deep net from mnist_deep.py"
mnist_deep.py had lots of tf.name_scope() calls, but there was no mention of name_scope on the tutorial itself.

I believe some beginners going through the same tutorial will find this a bit confusing.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>