<bug id='14533' author='mikhovr' open_date='2017-11-14T07:19:58Z' closed_time='2017-12-23T02:18:04Z'>
	<summary>Tensorflow Website XSRF Token missing or incorrect</summary>
	<description>
The error occurs when I read current TF API documentation. My default lang is set to Russian (but it does not matter and has influence only on the bottom menu). But when I'm trying to change the language to English or Chinese I get the following error message:

XSRF Token missing or incorrect

Is it ok or this is the TF Website bug?
Windows 10
Firefox 56.0.2 x64
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7415950/32767632-4ab78b0e-c925-11e7-8cff-6843af74ef71.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7415950/32767633-4ada17c8-c925-11e7-8e82-4f2bd322350a.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mikhovr' date='2017-11-15T20:27:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MarkDaoust&gt;@MarkDaoust&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this your territory, and can you please advise or reassign?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mikhovr' date='2017-11-15T20:50:04Z'>
		This one is over my head, maybe &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 knows who to send it to.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mikhovr' date='2017-12-20T01:25:50Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and the awaiting tensorflower label was assigned. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mikhovr' date='2017-12-20T05:40:48Z'>
		I can't repro this on my machine.  You probably shouldn't be given the option for Russian, as we have no Russian pages.  I would expect that to be a bug, possibly transient.  Is it still happening?  Do you still have the option for Russian?  If so, which page is it appearing on?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mikhovr' date='2017-12-23T02:18:04Z'>
		This seems like a bug, as evidenced by curl -H 'Accept-Language: ru' https://www.tensorflow.org.
It's now been brought to the attention of the right people internally in b/70993883. We can hopefully have this fixed sometime soon but I'm going to close this issue out just to get it out of triage queue. Thank you for bringing this to our attention.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>