<bug id='14672' author='RainbowZephyr' open_date='2017-11-17T22:03:01Z' closed_time='2018-01-04T20:02:05Z'>
	<summary>Compilation Flags</summary>
	<description>
Can someone please explain the flags that can be enabled when compiling TensorFlow from source? I don't seem to understand the functionality of most of them and they are not documented.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RainbowZephyr' date='2017-11-18T16:14:41Z'>
		where could you find the detail list of them? i only see those in the window compiling instruction ~
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='RainbowZephyr' date='2017-11-18T20:09:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/colmantse&gt;@colmantse&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I am not sure I understood what you mean exactly, but this is the list I am referring to:
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with Google Cloud Platform support? [Y/n]:
Google Cloud Platform support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with Hadoop File System support? [Y/n]:
Hadoop File System support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with Amazon S3 File System support? [Y/n]:
Amazon S3 File System support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with XLA JIT support? [y/N]:
No XLA JIT support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with GDR support? [y/N]:
No GDR support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with VERBS support? [y/N]:
No VERBS support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with OpenCL support? [y/N]:
No OpenCL support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with CUDA support? [y/N]:
No CUDA support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
Do you wish to build TensorFlow with MPI support? [y/N]:
No MPI support will be enabled for TensorFlow.
I understand Hadoop, XLA, CUDA, OpenCL and MPI however, I do not understand what the rest does
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='RainbowZephyr' date='2017-12-05T18:17:07Z'>
		Sorry, I think right you pretty much have to know what you're doing. Usually you should keep with the default unless you know what you are doing.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MarkDaoust&gt;@MarkDaoust&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 maybe there is something I am missing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='RainbowZephyr' date='2017-12-05T18:51:15Z'>
		A quick search seems to indicate that the other options,  GDR and VERBS are for these two contrib packages:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/contrib/verbs&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/contrib/verbs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/contrib/gdr&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/contrib/gdr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Maybe we should link to these on the install/sources page? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RainbowZephyr&gt;@RainbowZephyr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it could be relatively straight forward, care to send a PR?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='RainbowZephyr' date='2017-12-22T07:33:52Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>