<bug id='15148' author='adwaye' open_date='2017-12-06T08:38:54Z' closed_time='2017-12-23T03:31:03Z'>
	<summary>Using function defun and while loops</summary>
	<description>
Please go to Stack Overflow for help and support:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If you open a GitHub issue, here is our policy:

It must be a bug or a feature request.
The form below must be filled out.
It shouldn't be a TensorBoard issue. Those go here.

Here's why we have that policy: TensorFlow developers respond to issues. We want to focus on work that benefits the whole community, e.g., fixing bugs and adding features. Support only helps individuals. GitHub also notifies thousands of people when issues are filed. We want them to see you communicating an interesting problem, rather than being redirected to Stack Overflow.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Linux Ubuntu 16.04
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.4.0
Python version: 3.5.2
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version: 8/6
GPU model and memory: Tesla x Pascal 12gb
Exact command to reproduce: run defun_while.py

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture script:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can obtain the TensorFlow version with
python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Describe the problem clearly here. Be sure to convey here why it's a bug in TensorFlow or a feature request.
Function.defun when used alongside a while loop is throwing shape errors.
More explicitly: when using a concatenation operation of sliced tensors with the loop variable, the newly defined op throws no errors.  However, when the slices are added to the loop variable, it throws shape errors related to the while loop.
It might be an issue with the fetch argument that fails to work in this case.
The code (along with a more detailed explanation) can be found on:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47646962/tensorflow-function-defun-with-a-a-while-loop-in-the-body-is-throwing-shape-err&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47646962/tensorflow-function-defun-with-a-a-while-loop-in-the-body-is-throwing-shape-err&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached. Try to provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='adwaye' date='2017-12-06T17:21:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/skye&gt;@skye&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alextp&gt;@alextp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any idea?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='adwaye' date='2017-12-07T22:21:51Z'>
		The shape of the tf.add(...) tensor returned from the body seems to be confusing / not invariant. Do instead x = tf.add(...); x.set_shape(...); return index+1, x in your body and it should work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='adwaye' date='2017-12-08T04:44:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/drpngx&gt;@drpngx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alextp&gt;@alextp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  got some updates on &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47646962/tensorflow-function-defun-with-a-a-while-loop-in-the-body-is-throwing-shape-err/47707845#47707845&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47646962/tensorflow-function-defun-with-a-a-while-loop-in-the-body-is-throwing-shape-err/47707845#47707845&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Still have the issue of global N though.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='adwaye' date='2017-12-22T19:00:40Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>