<bug id='15978' author='nbro' open_date='2018-01-09T16:34:52Z' closed_time='2019-09-26T17:03:41Z'>
	<summary>No documentation for ConfigProto</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Not necessary in this case.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

No documentation for the ConfigProto class in the TF website. Specifically, in neither of the following pages

https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/ConfigProto
https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r1.5/api_docs/python/tf/ConfigProto
https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/master/api_docs/python/tf/ConfigProto

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Possible solutions&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The following article &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/using_gpu&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/using_gpu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 contains info about . Either the docs for  can be written based on that info or, at least, a link to that article should be added to the  docs.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nbro' date='2018-01-09T20:54:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/josh11b&gt;@josh11b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it looks like you originally wrote those lines of the tutorial. Can you take a look or assign someone more appropriate, please?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nbro' date='2018-05-04T04:58:16Z'>
		As with all protobufs on tensorflow.org, we (now) link to the definition file itself, so you can click on the provided link see the documentation where the proto is defined. Even if we were to generate a more extensive field listing, it would be generated from the proto file's comments.
If we feel strongly that the protobuf should link to this doc on tensorflow.org, it should be linked to tensorflow.org in the proto definition itself in a comment.
I'll leave this open for now and see if that's a practical thing to do.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nbro' date='2018-09-28T21:43:47Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nbro' date='2018-11-07T10:15:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Harshini-Gadige&gt;@Harshini-Gadige&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 why you close it? Look at  last post:

It has been 142 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.

So, the problem is still present and issue is inactive bacause assignee does nothing. May be you should change an assignee to fix the problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nbro' date='2019-08-07T09:55:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RomanSteinberg&gt;@RomanSteinberg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did you check  &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/using_gpu&gt;page&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that has good number of examples on . I am closing this issue as it is stale issue. Please feel free to open the issue if there are not sufficient examples and tutorials on .  Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nbro' date='2019-08-07T10:19:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jvishnuvardhan&gt;@jvishnuvardhan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Well, the using_gpu page is not the documentation of ConfigProto.  I think this issue should remain open.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='nbro' date='2019-08-15T18:57:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nbro&gt;@nbro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Are you interested in contributing through changing the documentation? You could raise  a Pull-Request. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='nbro' date='2019-09-25T16:53:58Z'>
		The TF2 launch is coming soon, and TF2 does not expose ConfigProto except as tf.compat.v1.ConfigProto. So it might be reasonable to close this as "obsolete".
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jaingaurav&gt;@jaingaurav&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, you wrote the TF2 version of "Using GPU" do you know the status of ConfigProto? is it dead? should we close this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='nbro' date='2019-09-25T23:09:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MarkDaoust&gt;@MarkDaoust&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: ConfigProto has been replaced by many  APIs for 2.0. Under the hood it uses ConfigProto, but that is an implementation detail. Please let me know if there is any known functionality missing from the  APIs, as not all fields may have been exposed in the new APIs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='nbro' date='2019-09-26T17:03:41Z'>
		Okay, so this is mentioned in the migration guide now.  Closing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='nbro' date='2019-09-26T17:03:43Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=15978&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=15978&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>