<bug id='17351' author='spiiph' open_date='2018-03-01T12:04:40Z' closed_time='2018-03-02T01:27:40Z'>
	<summary>Examples and tutorial missing from pip tensorflow package</summary>
	<description>
After searching for and eventually posting a question on StackOverflow (&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/49007742/tensorflow-examples-and-tutorials-missing-from-the-pip-package&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/49007742/tensorflow-examples-and-tutorials-missing-from-the-pip-package&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) I was recommended to report this as a bug:
When installing Tensorflow (e.g. tensorflow-1.5.0-cp36-cp36m-manylinux1_x86_64.whl from &lt;denchmark-link:https://pypi.python.org/pypi/tensorflow/1.5.0&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/tensorflow/1.5.0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) from pip, there is only the tutorials/mnist example in tensorflow/examples. It would be nice to have the examples available without having to get them separately from GitHub. Is there a reason why the rest of the examples are not included? Can they be included in future releases?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='spiiph' date='2018-03-02T01:19:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yifeif&gt;@yifeif&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any comments on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='spiiph' date='2018-03-02T01:27:40Z'>
		We want to keep our distribution as small as possible. As tutorials are not part of the APIs, we don't plan to include them in the standard package.  the repo would be the recommended way to get them. Hope this answer your question &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/spiiph&gt;@spiiph&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='spiiph' date='2018-03-02T10:39:14Z'>
		Thanks for the response.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='spiiph' date='2019-12-14T01:38:57Z'>
		I have had a similar issue with that. To overcome this issue without downloading the whole repository, since I already installed the newest version through pip, I used SVN to download the specific part related to the examples,
For example &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/examples&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/examples&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is the path to the examples folder on the github repository.
To use it with SVN, one simply replace the tree/master with trunk in the repo URL, resulting in the following command:
svn checkout https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/trunk/tensorflow/examples
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>