<bug id='18214' author='sibyjackgrove' open_date='2018-04-03T20:12:11Z' closed_time='2018-05-07T14:06:03Z'>
	<summary>Documentation missing for tensorrt in Python API</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
No
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): N/A
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): N/A
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.7
Python version: 3.6
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: N/A
GPU model and memory: N/A
Exact command to reproduce: N/A

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Native TensorRT support in TensorFlow was announced by both &lt;denchmark-link:https://developers.googleblog.com/2018/03/tensorrt-integration-with-tensorflow.html&gt;Google &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and Nvidia blog posts last week. But  is missing from the Python API list. Currently, the only documentation is on readme file in the  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/contrib/tensorrt&gt;tensorflow/contrib/tensorrt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 repository. But it doesn't given details about using the API.  Please include documentation for this important feature.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-04-19T18:58:22Z'>
		Nagging Assignee &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aselle&gt;@aselle&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-04-25T16:29:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, please take a look.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-05-04T16:29:12Z'>
		There's an example pointed to by the README. I think that's the intended usage pattern. We can certainly export functionality under tf.contrib.tensorrt if that's useful.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/samikama&gt;@samikama&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 WDYT?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-05-04T17:43:19Z'>
		AFAIK at present users need to export graphdef and rewrite it using a python api in trt_convert.py, we are working on APIs to remove the rewrite process. But we probably need to document the current approach in the README.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aaroey&gt;@aaroey&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-05-04T17:52:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sibyjackgrove&gt;@sibyjackgrove&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you mean updating documentation in tensorflow.org or in the README? if it is the first one, as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/protoget&gt;@protoget&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 mentioned, we are working heavily on the API and will probably simplify things thus documentation will be incorrect quite rapidly. If it is the second one I will try to update it in master but the test_tftrt.py should show some examples on how to use the api. Also python help should explain the parameters of the api.
import tensorflow.contrib.tensorrt as trt
help(trt.trt_convert)
Nevertheless you are right and we will try to update it soon.
Thanks,
Sami
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-05-04T17:56:39Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sibyjackgrove&gt;@sibyjackgrove&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Thanks for the interest on TF-TRT integration. Currently the integration is still in progress and we're actively working on it. The API is not stable yet and may change in the future. You may want to take a look at the  script mentioned in the README, which is in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/contrib/tensorrt/test/test_tftrt.py&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/contrib/tensorrt/test/test_tftrt.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I'll leave to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/samikama&gt;@samikama&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 about the documentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='sibyjackgrove' date='2018-05-07T14:06:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aaroey&gt;@aaroey&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/samikama&gt;@samikama&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the response and updates. If the API is not stable yet, it makes sense to wait until it is so before updating documentation on tensorflow.org. Closing the issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>