<bug id='18644' author='dalgu90' open_date='2018-04-18T09:49:34Z' closed_time='2018-05-04T04:51:58Z'>
	<summary>TensorBoard not running correctly with TF 1.8.0-rc0</summary>
	<description>
Hi, I upgraded TF to 1.8.0-rc0 to use the new  feature. But with this version tensorboard won't run well. Here is output when I run tensorboard.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13655756/38924425-e7eb7f16-4337-11e8-81a9-5b07dfcf39a1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

(The command was valid when I entered with TF 1.7.)
Also when I entered to the tensorboard on the browser, tensorboard page opened but no event was displayed.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13655756/38924904-1ec3ab3e-4339-11e8-94e3-233242a0f14b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment info
TF version: ('v1.7.0-1569-g3970b47da5', '1.8.0-rc0')
Operating System: Ubuntu 16.04.3
Installed version of CUDA and cuDNN: CUDA 9.0 and cuDNN 7 but I guess it's not CUDA related.
The latest version of TensorBoard is still 1.7.0, so there might be a reason for the problem.
Thank you for your hard working :^)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dalgu90' date='2018-04-18T11:00:29Z'>
		I also encountered the same problem!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dalgu90' date='2018-04-18T15:04:06Z'>
		This is probably because you are using a Tensorboard of version 1.7.0, which must have been already fixed in its corresponding release. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/pull/1086&gt;tensorflow/tensorboard#1086&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for a dispatching solution that handles both version of , which might already have fixed the issue in TB 1.8.
But why TF core has changed its API? As a result, it seems that there are some kind of requirements that minor versions of TF and TB should match.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dalgu90' date='2018-05-03T18:45:36Z'>
		Nagging Assignee &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rohan100jain&gt;@rohan100jain&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dalgu90' date='2018-05-03T22:03:40Z'>
		Apologies for the backwards incompatible change that was made but following the discussion on the PR pointed out by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wookayin&gt;@wookayin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, this should work now. Can you confirm?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='dalgu90' date='2018-05-04T04:51:42Z'>
		I found new version of tensorboard(tensorboard-1.8.0) is installed when I install tensorflow-gpu-1.8.0, and I works well! I think this issue can be closed!
Thanks for your hard working!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>