<bug id='18767' author='hedenface' open_date='2018-04-22T01:00:34Z' closed_time='2018-04-24T22:48:08Z'>
	<summary>Documentation issues regarding installing on ubuntu</summary>
	<description>
While I was perusing the documentation for install_linux, I got to the section Determine which TensorFlow to install, and then I continued on.
I was at Determine how to install TensorFlow and I settled on Virtualenv. So I went to that section, and I followed the steps. But when I got to the sub-section (2) stating

where targetDirectory specifies the top of the Virtualenv tree. Our instructions assume that targetDirectory is ~/tensorflow, but you may choose any directory.

I was caught off guard a bit. I didn't know if I had missed something, so I spent a bit of time back-tracking the documentation to see if that was the case. I finally decided to mkdir ~/tensorflow and give it a go.
It would be nice if there was a (sub-)section stating this. I don't want to write it, so I'm making it as an issue instead. I did do this amazing thing though: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/18766&gt;#18766&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-22T12:27:19Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
Have I written custom code
OS Platform and Distribution
TensorFlow installed from
TensorFlow version
Bazel version
CUDA/cuDNN version
GPU model and memory
Exact command to reproduce
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-22T14:29:51Z'>
		
Have I written custom code

No

OS Platform and Distribution

Linux Mint

TensorFlow installed from

My issue is regarding the documentation before installation, so I'll say this is N/A.

TensorFlow version

N/A

Bazel version

N/A

CUDA/cuDNN version

N/A

GPU model and memory

N/A

Exact command to reproduce

N/A
My issue is simply regarding some confusion I faced during reading the installation documentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-23T17:43:49Z'>
		thanks for the PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-23T20:27:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lamberta&gt;@lamberta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 maybe see if this can be clarified. But the branching install is going to be some cognitive burden no matter how much we describe the steps.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-23T20:39:13Z'>
		I don't disagree that it will be a cognitive burden. (I like that phrase). I mean more in the sense of "did I miss something?" and then having to re-read to identify that I did not in fact miss anything.
Or even something like "read all the way through before doing anything." If I were better with words I would probably be able to come up with something better than that. No words, only code.
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='hedenface' date='2018-04-24T05:34:20Z'>
		Thanks for reporting.
The entire page could use a scrubbing, but I went through the pip install instructions using virtualenv and system install and clarified some steps (and cut out some cruft).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>