<bug id='196' author='cesarsalgado' open_date='2015-11-13T14:06:27Z' closed_time='2015-11-17T03:01:46Z'>
	<summary>Padding type definition is swapped in the documentation.</summary>
	<description>
In &lt;denchmark-link:http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#pooling&gt;http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#pooling&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#convolution&gt;http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#convolution&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The definition of the padding types should be swapped.
Now it is like this:

padding = 'SAME': Round down (only full size windows are considered).
padding = 'VALID': Round up (partial windows are included).

But it should be like this:

padding = 'SAME': Round up (partial windows are included).
padding = 'VALID': Round down (only full size windows are considered).

I also think it should be made clear that the padding is already included in the shape(value) of the formula "shape(output) = (shape(value) - ksize + 1) / strides".
Or maybe the formula should be changed to the following simpler one (taken from &lt;denchmark-link:http://cs231n.github.io/convolutional-networks/#conv&gt;http://cs231n.github.io/convolutional-networks/#conv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
):

shape(output) = ((shape(value)+2*pad - ksize) / strides) + 1

where pad = 0 if padding='VALID' or pad = floor(ksize/2) if padding='SAME'.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cesarsalgado' date='2015-11-15T20:19:36Z'>
		Thanks - the padding documentation definitely needs modification. The padding scheme is not as simple as you mentioned though - it follows some legacy reason which involved some non-trivial padding computations. I'll update the documentation to add the details.
For the time being, if you are interested in the the exact math, it is described here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yangqing/caffe2/blob/master/caffe2/proto/caffe2_legacy.proto#L8&gt;https://github.com/Yangqing/caffe2/blob/master/caffe2/proto/caffe2_legacy.proto#L8&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='cesarsalgado' date='2015-11-17T03:01:46Z'>
		Thanks again for reporting this. We have fixed this in our internal codebase and will be pushing it soon. Closing this for now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='cesarsalgado' date='2016-01-02T19:26:48Z'>
		Propose to enrich the document of convolution. It is still quite confusing.
&lt;denchmark-link:http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#convolution&gt;http://tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/nn.md#convolution&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I think what cesarsalgado mentioned is correct.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='cesarsalgado' date='2016-05-31T13:48:37Z'>
		Could anyone help me to calculate each step output of cifar10 example of tensorflow?
The input image size is 24*24. But in max pooling step, the kernel size is 3 and stride is 2, so (24-3)/2+1 is not integer. What is wrong here? I am new in deep learning. Thank you for helping
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='cesarsalgado' date='2016-05-31T13:49:51Z'>
		Hi,
Beginner questions are best suited for Stack Overflow, not random semi-related bugs. Please post your question there instead.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>