<bug id='19899' author='armanschwarz' open_date='2018-06-11T06:31:02Z' closed_time='2018-10-11T23:42:05Z'>
	<summary>Documentation feature request: Explain Nesterov Accelerated Gradient implementation</summary>
	<description>
I haven't filled out the provided form because this is a feature request for the documentation.
The documentation for &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/train/MomentumOptimizer&gt;tf.train.MomentumOptimizer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 offers a  parameter on which the documentation says the following:

use_nesterov: If True use Nesterov Momentum. See Sutskever et al.,
2013. This
implementation always computes gradients at the value of the
variable(s) passed to the optimizer. Using Nesterov Momentum makes the
variable(s) track the values called theta_t + mu*v_t in the paper.

The problem is that the linked paper outlines the normal NAG algorithm, which requires computation of a gradient at a different value to those provided (namely at the next step). This is not clarified in the documentation and led me to some confusion. I ended up &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/50774683/how-is-nesterovs-accelerated-gradient-descent-implemented-in-tensorflow&gt;asking this question on StackOverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and cobbled together &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/a/50774886/1613983&gt;an answer myself&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, however I think the answer by  is so complete that without too much wrangling it could greatly enhance the documentation:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/a/50778921/1613983&gt;Answer by user1735003&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Some clarification to the fact that tensorflow actually implements a modified version of the algorithm which is only correct under certain conditions would have been very helpful and would have saved me some time.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='armanschwarz' date='2018-06-11T18:47:40Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
Have I written custom code
OS Platform and Distribution
TensorFlow installed from
TensorFlow version
Bazel version
CUDA/cuDNN version
GPU model and memory
Exact command to reproduce
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='armanschwarz' date='2018-06-11T21:05:20Z'>
		Have I written custom code: N/A
OS Platform and Distribution: N/A
TensorFlow installed from: N/A
TensorFlow version: 1.5
Bazel version: N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: N/A
GPU model and memory: N/A
Exact command to reproduce: N/A
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Tue, Jun 12, 2018, 04:53 Alfred Sorten Wolf ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following
 field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in
 your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
 Have I written custom code
 OS Platform and Distribution
 TensorFlow installed from
 TensorFlow version
 Bazel version
 CUDA/cuDNN version
 GPU model and memory
 Exact command to reproduce

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#19899 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AHpQ2YEF7Kkf5SJsLTCynUt83gGgnPanks5t7ryegaJpZM4UiIX7&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='armanschwarz' date='2018-06-12T01:26:37Z'>
		Great, sounds good. Marking as contributions welcome as we'd welcome a pull request to update the documentation to make it more helpful.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>