<bug id='203' author='cauerego' open_date='2015-11-13T17:35:16Z' closed_time='2015-11-15T01:51:51Z'>
	<summary>Promote usage of docker above all other installation methods</summary>
	<description>
Shouldn't we just focus on docker? At least on the main page, and then link to other methods elsewhere.
Would just need a good docker development workflow (I personally got none yet).
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:18:49Z'>
		Docker has tricky GPU support as well as CPU resource allocation that can lead to poor outcomes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:25:11Z'>
		Ouch. That's really good to know. But are you sure those are issues for TF?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:28:50Z'>
		Well, I should caveat that my experiences has been on windows 10.  Perhaps it's better on linux/mac.  I'm having a hard time get a simple matrix_inverse to peg one of my cores to --cpu-shares=0  or even recognize more than one core.   The GPU issues are tricky though, they don't come by default.   Have you got it working with docker yet?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:45:39Z'>
		Nope. I'm currently at &lt;denchmark-link:https://codenewbie.slack.com/archives/general&gt;https://codenewbie.slack.com/archives/general&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 trying to work out a dev workflow first. Never done any with docker before. Here are a few trails I'm following:

http://stackoverflow.com/questions/30090007/whats-the-right-way-to-setup-a-development-environment-on-os-x-with-docker
http://discourse.codenewbie.org/t/docker-boot2docker-exposing-app-on-localhost/1148/3
https://www.airpair.com/node.js/posts/getting-started-with-docker-for-the-nodejs-dev

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:49:32Z'>
		Ah, ok, well fwiw, for docker I just installed it from &lt;denchmark-link:http://docs.docker.com/v1.8/installation/&gt;http://docs.docker.com/v1.8/installation/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and ran the command they give on the tensorflow website docker run -it b.gcr.io/tensorflow/tensorflow.  It all worked perfectly fine.   Well, I had to open my computer's firewall to accept loopback connections, but I don't that's related to either docker or TF.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-13T18:55:55Z'>
		It's related to boot2docker's vm. I'm at nearly that point as well, but not happy while I can't git everything up properly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-15T01:51:51Z'>
		Thank you for the suggestion.  In general, docker is the best approach for building a hermetic installation of TensorFlow and I encourage most heavy TensorFlow users to follow this approach.  In general, however, pip installs are easier for users who just want to play with TF.  And while I would encourage most such users to install in virtualenv, in practice it's always less friction to just gamble that there won't be any conflicts with system installed packages in a regular pip install.
All that to say is, &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/there-is-more-than-one-way-to-skin-a-cat.html&gt;there's more than one way to skin a cat&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  Closing this for now since &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/149&gt;#149&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is tracking building proper Docker images.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/timshephard&gt;@timshephard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cauerego&gt;@cauerego&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 PTAL at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/41930f0b81b52a34fb56d921c9bad65c36168323/tensorflow/tools/docker/docker_run_gpu.sh&gt;this script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for details on how to forward GPU support into the docker container.  This has worked for us.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='cauerego' date='2015-11-15T18:58:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ebrevdo&gt;@ebrevdo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:http://talk.cregox.com/t/my-social-unfair-undervaluation-and-why-the-financial-system-is-broken/7751?u=cregox&gt;To me&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, you're just saying you will probably look at this back again in the future, but can't predict when! ;P
If you can confirm this, I will try and make docker installation simpler than pip. Would this work for you? If it is possible, I can probably and will eventually do it! :)
(Just not with GPU support, of course, but that's beyond the point)
PS: Never heard of &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.acronymfinder.com/PTAL.html&gt;PTAL&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 before, google didn't help . :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>