<bug id='20629' author='nbro' open_date='2018-07-08T16:04:00Z' closed_time='2019-01-15T21:10:43Z'>
	<summary>Improve the documentation for tf.tables_initializer</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

No relevant for this issue.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The current documentation for &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/tables_initializer&gt;tf.tables_initializer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 states

Returns an Op that initializes all tables of the default graph.

As a beginner, it is not clear to me why we would need tables in TF. So, I think the documentation should add a few examples of use-cases where tables are created (initialized) and used. In other words, the documentation should briefly answer the questions

Why do we need tables in TF?
What does it even mean to initialize a table?

In which cases would tables need (or not) to be initialized?


What kind of tables are these? Hash-tables?
In general, what are examples of use-cases where tables are used?

In the documentation, there's also "See the guide: Variables &gt; Sparse Variable Updates", but &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_guides/python/state_ops#Sparse_Variable_Updates&gt;Variables &gt; Sparse Variable Updates&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, if I understood correctly, doesn't answer the questions above.
Given that I don't think I am very qualified to answer the questions above, I decided to open this issue, instead of submitting a PR.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

No relevant for this issue.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nbro' date='2018-07-09T00:33:48Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
Have I written custom code
OS Platform and Distribution
TensorFlow installed from
TensorFlow version
Bazel version
CUDA/cuDNN version
GPU model and memory
Exact command to reproduce
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nbro' date='2018-08-09T17:25:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ysuematsu&gt;@ysuematsu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you provide some more detailed examples?
If you have any more extensive examples you could put them in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/docs_src/api_guides/python&gt;docs_src/api_guides&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

api_guides are automatically linked to by any api-pages for python objects they mention.
But we would welcome examples from anyone.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nbro' date='2018-11-02T12:37:24Z'>
		I found something useful to understand table in &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/low_level_intro&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/low_level_intro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Feature columns can have internal state, like layers, so they often need to be initialized. Categorical columns use tf.contrib.lookup internally and these require a separate initialization op, tf.tables_initializer.

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nbro' date='2018-11-02T15:53:42Z'>
		Good point &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jayhenry&gt;@jayhenry&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Anyone want to send a PR adding a link from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r1.11/tensorflow/python/ops/lookup_ops.py#L63&gt;the source file&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to  that &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/low_level_intro&gt;low_level_intro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nbro' date='2019-01-03T18:45:52Z'>
		It has been 26 days with no activity and the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>