<bug id='21062' author='dhingratul' open_date='2018-07-23T17:43:44Z' closed_time='2019-01-25T21:57:52Z'>
	<summary>Quantize nodes with Graph Transform tool</summary>
	<description>
Please go to Stack Overflow for help and support:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If you open a GitHub issue, here is our policy:

It must be a bug, a feature request, or a significant problem with documentation (for small docs fixes please send a PR instead).
The form below must be filled out.
It shouldn't be a TensorBoard issue. Those go here.

Here's why we have that policy: TensorFlow developers respond to issues. We want to focus on work that benefits the whole community, e.g., fixing bugs and adding features. Support only helps individuals. GitHub also notifies thousands of people when issues are filed. We want them to see you communicating an interesting problem, rather than being redirected to Stack Overflow.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): no
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 16.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: n/a
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):bazel
TensorFlow version (use command below):latest commit
Python version:2.7
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):0.14.1
CUDA/cuDNN version:9/7.1
GPU model and memory:1080ti
Exact command to reproduce:
bazel build tensorflow/tools/graph_transforms:transform_graph bazel-bin/tensorflow/tools/graph_transforms/transform_graph \ --in_graph=model.pb \ --out_graph=optimized_model.pb \ --inputs='Input/input' \ --outputs='fc2/Relu' \ --transforms=' add_default_attributes remove_nodes(op=Identity, op=CheckNumerics) fold_constants(ignore_errors=true) fold_batch_norms fold_old_batch_norms quantize_weights quantize_nodes strip_unused_nodes sort_by_execution_order'

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture script:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can obtain the TensorFlow version with
python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Describe the problem clearly here. Be sure to convey here why it's a bug in TensorFlow or a feature request.
ValueError: Node 'conv2/act_quant/AssignMinEma/conv2/act_quant/min/AssignAdd/value' expects to be colocated with unknown node 'conv2/act_quant/min'
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached. Try to provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dhingratul' date='2019-01-10T01:23:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dhingratul&gt;@dhingratul&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Could you provide more details on the issue and provide any codes to reproduce the error. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dhingratul' date='2019-01-25T21:57:52Z'>
		Closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>