<bug id='21096' author='nbcsm' open_date='2018-07-24T16:19:45Z' closed_time='2020-01-31T18:43:06Z'>
	<summary>documentation request: Prebuilt binary build configuration</summary>
	<description>
There are many flags/options for tensorflow build, some of them are performance related.
User may want to build a whl from source (with some modifications) , using exactly the same build configuration that prebuilt binary used
With previous Jenkins CI server, we can still figure out the build configuration from log of a release-xxxx build job.
But now with the new internal build system, it is not quite clear what build configuration is used for prebuilt binary anymore.
e.g.
cuda compute capability: default value in configure.py (3.5,7.0) seems not complete.
cpu simd option: one may have to search release note to figure out whether it is still AVX.
It will be great to document the build setting somewhere, or introduce some script to produce prebuilt binary for a release.
Thanks.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nbcsm' date='2018-07-25T01:05:15Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
Have I written custom code
OS Platform and Distribution
TensorFlow installed from
TensorFlow version
Bazel version
CUDA/cuDNN version
GPU model and memory
Exact command to reproduce
Mobile device
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nbcsm' date='2018-08-10T23:47:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gunan&gt;@gunan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you shed any light here, please?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/drpngx&gt;@drpngx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 was also curious.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nbcsm' date='2018-08-10T23:52:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/av8ramit&gt;@av8ramit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do we have these options documented?
I think at the moment, in configure you need to just pick the deafult options.
The only non-defaults we may have are CPU optimization levels, which is fixed to avx, and CUDA, which is selected and unselected depending on CPU/GPU builds.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nbcsm' date='2018-08-11T00:10:42Z'>
		No we don't but that is a good point. I can add this information to the build from sources page if you'd like.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nbcsm' date='2018-09-16T20:31:02Z'>
		I'm working on an update to this page which has a section for &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lamberta/docs/blob/install/site/en/install/source.md#configuration-options&gt;configuration options&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
We can add some more after this lands. If this list becomes unwieldy for the doc page, maybe we can just put it in a file in the tensorflow repo and link to it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nbcsm' date='2018-09-21T02:24:54Z'>
		The updated  page is up, here's a link to the section: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#configure_the_build&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#configure_the_build&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

To update, it's here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/install/source.md&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/install/source.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='nbcsm' date='2018-09-21T17:05:59Z'>
		Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lamberta&gt;@lamberta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ! To be precise, I think we're looking for the exact scripts that are used to generate the images, docker etc.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='nbcsm' date='2018-09-28T12:49:59Z'>
		Thanks for the update, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lamberta&gt;@lamberta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Agree with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/drpngx&gt;@drpngx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it would be great to share the exact script which is used to produce the pre-built binary.
E.g. from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/install/source.md&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/install/source.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I still have no idea what CUDA compute capability is used for pre-built binary.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='nbcsm' date='2018-09-28T17:20:16Z'>
		Except for windows, we bake all supported CUDA Compute Capabilities into our binary.
The reason for windows not having this is a bug in eigen we are waiting a fix on.
Since our strategy is to include all compute capabilities, they have not been documented.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='nbcsm' date='2018-10-03T20:28:45Z'>
		Sharing the script sounds like a fine idea, but then this PR is no longer a documentation request :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='nbcsm' date='2018-10-31T17:39:03Z'>
		Status update: Still working on this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='nbcsm' date='2019-06-28T21:14:17Z'>
		Hey @angersson I'm assigning this over to you. It's possible you may make our build scripts opensource in your work this quarter. Unfortunately, I never got around to this.
We did make the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/tools/ci_build/builds/pip_new.sh&gt;pip_new.sh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the standard for building packages so maybe these are some temporary answers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='nbcsm' date='2020-01-31T18:43:06Z'>
		So all our build scripts are now externally available. Closing this now.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/tools/ci_build/presubmit&gt;Presubmit example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='nbcsm' date='2020-01-31T18:43:08Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/21096&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/21096&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>