<bug id='23148' author='gokul-uf' open_date='2018-10-21T19:02:20Z' closed_time='2019-02-22T16:45:37Z'>
	<summary>Doc Request: Better Documentation for TFRecords</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version: 1.11.0
Doc Link: NA


With the introduction of  and deprecation of , TFRecords seem to play a major role if you want to effeciently use accelerators while training on large datasets. Unfortunately, the current  &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/datasets&gt;documentation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 starts off assuming we already have  on disk without even linking how we could convert images, say  or even arbitrary images to the s format.
To be precise, there is no documentation for TFRecord , TFExample or even the readers and writers. Moreover, the examples do not cover how these things would work in eager execution mode. It would be great if these could be fixed as it would improve adoption of TFRecords and help more people use the tf.data pipelines.
PS, I am aware of code examples in the repo such as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/models/blob/1af55e018eebce03fb61bba9959a04672536107d/research/deeplab/datasets/build_voc2012_data.py&gt;1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/examples/how_tos/reading_data/convert_to_records.py&gt;2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 but would prefer to have better documentation and maybe a guide for this.
Thanks
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue? no
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gokul-uf' date='2018-10-22T19:02:37Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the following field in the issue template. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Thanks.
Have I written custom code
OS Platform and Distribution
TensorFlow installed from
Bazel version
CUDA/cuDNN version
GPU model and memory
Exact command to reproduce
Mobile device
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gokul-uf' date='2018-10-22T19:05:08Z'>
		Related to this issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/1749&gt;Request: Better documentation on TFRecords and their use&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 .
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gokul-uf' date='2018-10-22T19:45:38Z'>
		Since the awaiting response label is still applied
Have I written custom code: N/A
OS Platform and Distribution: N/A
TensorFlow installed from: N/A
Bazel version: N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: N/A
GPU model and memory: N/A
Exact command to reproduce: N/A
Mobile device: N/A
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gokul-uf' date='2018-11-07T17:00:24Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gokul-uf&gt;@gokul-uf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
There is a new tutorial for this in review right now.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.sandbox.google.com/github/raskutti/docs/blob/master/site/en/tutorials/load_data/tf-records.ipynb&gt;https://colab.sandbox.google.com/github/raskutti/docs/blob/master/site/en/tutorials/load_data/tf-records.ipynb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Try it out, and add comments to the pr if anything is unclear:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/pull/130&gt;tensorflow/docs#130&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='gokul-uf' date='2019-02-22T06:16:08Z'>
		We desperately need some simple documentation describing what the TFRecord format actually is. If you cannot use an existing writer / reader, it's very hard to find any notes on how to create or how to read the format yourself. Maybe I'm missing something obvious in the existing documentation, but searches for a description just lead me to a multitude of blog posts.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable_Network_Graphics#File_format&gt;A description like this&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would be incredibly helpful when building tools that interact with TFRecords outside of a TensorFlow environment
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='gokul-uf' date='2019-02-22T16:50:04Z'>
		Added, WDYT?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>