<bug id='23667' author='palisadoes' open_date='2018-11-12T01:04:56Z' closed_time='2019-12-26T17:13:49Z'>
	<summary>Incorrect cuda9.0 package installation required. Should be cuda-9-0</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version: 1.11 +
Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/install/gpu


The documentation states that you will need to install the cuda9.0 package. This does not exist in the repo - &lt;denchmark-link:http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/repos/ubuntu1604/x86_64/&gt;http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/repos/ubuntu1604/x86_64/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. It should be the cuda-9-0 package instead.
If you don't install the package, tensorflow works, but the GPUs are not engaged. This can be verified using the gpustat -cp command provided by the python pip gpustat library.
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='palisadoes' date='2018-11-12T01:21:50Z'>
		The documentation should also include installing the  and  packages found at &lt;denchmark-link:http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/repos/ubuntu1604/x86_64/&gt;http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/repos/ubuntu1604/x86_64/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 versus mentioning the Nvidia website links:

https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-zone
http://docs.nvidia.com/cuda/cupti/

They could still be included as a background reference. But the Ubuntu packages are available on the repo.
There should also be instructions on how to install tensorflow-gpu using RPMs. It's not much of a stretch, but it would really help newcomers to RedHat Linux variants.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='palisadoes' date='2019-12-26T17:13:50Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/23667&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/23667&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='palisadoes' date='2019-12-26T17:16:33Z'>
		Closing out this issue because it hasn't been updated in the last year.  Please reopen if this is still relevant.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>