<bug id='23876' author='MatthiasKohl' open_date='2018-11-20T10:47:38Z' closed_time='2018-11-28T01:24:24Z'>
	<summary>How to use tf.contrib.periodic_resample</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version: 1.6.0
Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/contrib/periodic_resample/periodic_resample

Describe the documentation issue
There is no example on how to use the operation at all. Specifically, most graphs that this operation is useful for (DCGANs) use 4D tensors (batch size, height, width, channels), with the batch size being unknown already (None) and the operation should decrease a single dimension specified as None. Since we usually don't want to decrease the batch size with this operation, I have no idea how to actually use it in this case.
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
If I understand how to actually use this function, yes.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MatthiasKohl' date='2018-11-20T18:05:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/akshaym&gt;@akshaym&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/caisq&gt;@caisq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 seem to be the owners of this code.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MatthiasKohl' date='2018-11-20T19:18:12Z'>
		I don't know anything about tf.contrib.periodic_resample. Removing myself from assignees.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MatthiasKohl' date='2018-11-20T19:32:44Z'>
		I'm sorry, I don't know much about this code either.
CC &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mrry&gt;@mrry&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 who reviewed the original PR (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/14339&gt;#14339&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jhetherly&gt;@jhetherly&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 who authored the original PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MatthiasKohl' date='2018-11-28T01:24:24Z'>
		This is in contrib, which is maintained and supported by the community. If you cannot identify an owner, you can ask on StackOverflow. If you cannot get help there, I fear that we won't be able to help.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>