<bug id='24101' author='yurivict' open_date='2018-12-02T01:39:06Z' closed_time='2019-05-31T22:36:52Z'>
	<summary>Choosing the right Bazel version to build TF is confusing</summary>
	<description>
This bug was closed while the problem still exists: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/21362&gt;#21362&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yurivict' date='2018-12-19T15:42:00Z'>
		i have the problem while following this : &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#docker_linux_builds&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#docker_linux_builds&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to build the docker image
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yurivict' date='2018-12-21T13:46:46Z'>
		I still get the issue with version 1.12 with tensorflow/configure.py
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yurivict' date='2018-12-25T02:46:30Z'>
		I have same issue too. exact error shown in pc is
root@0d56190c7f6e:/tensorflow# ./configure
WARNING: --batch mode is deprecated. Please instead explicitly shut down your Bazel server using the command "bazel shutdown".
You have bazel 0.15.0 installed.
Please upgrade your bazel installation to version 0.19.0 or higher to build TensorFlow!
even if i have latest bazel  version 0.21.0
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yurivict' date='2019-01-17T02:25:33Z'>
		Can be fixed by upgrading bazel (as was stated in ./configure output)
$ wget https://github.com/bazelbuild/bazel/releases/download/0.21.0/bazel-0.21.0-installer-linux-x86_64.sh # bazel installer from https://github.com/bazelbuild/bazel/releases
$ chmod +x bazel-0.21.0-installer-linux-x86_64.sh 
$ ./bazel-0.21.0-installer-linux-x86_64.sh 
...
Uncompressing.......

Bazel is now installed!

$ bazel version
Extracting Bazel installation...
INFO: Invocation ID: f6ac0879-d756-4b94-8818-dcab72c7370c
Build label: 0.21.0
Build target: bazel-out/k8-opt/bin/src/main/java/com/google/devtools/build/lib/bazel/BazelServer_deploy.jar
Build time: Wed Dec 19 12:58:44 2018 (1545224324)
Build timestamp: 1545224324
Build timestamp as int: 1545224324

$ ./configure 
INFO: Invocation ID: a33256ba-1596-40c5-999c-ec304b868c89
You have bazel 0.21.0 installed.
Please specify the location of python. [Default is /usr/bin/python]:
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yurivict' date='2019-01-18T21:16:38Z'>
		I have the same exact error. The official build guide shows 1.15 as the tested version though.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='yurivict' date='2019-01-29T19:54:54Z'>
		The reason I installed 0.15 bazel is because of the above comment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='yurivict' date='2019-03-14T14:26:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dveselov&gt;@dveselov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It does not work with tf 1.12.0 when upgrade bazel to 0.21.0
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='yurivict' date='2019-03-15T15:48:42Z'>
		I get the following error, can anyone help me, I believe that it is related to this issue. When configuring bazel I get the following error.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;root@636420111df0:/tensorflow# ./configure
Extracting Bazel installation...
WARNING: --batch mode is deprecated. Please instead explicitly shut down your Bazel server using the command "bazel shutdown".
You have bazel 0.23.2 installed.
Please downgrade your bazel installation to version 0.21.0 or lower to build TensorFlow!
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Using tf 1.13 with bazel 0.23.2.
Am I better off down grading tf or bazel, I can't seem to find any instructions to install a different version of bazel
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='yurivict' date='2019-03-15T16:22:37Z'>
		cmake does't seem to have such problems. Why not just use cmake instead?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='yurivict' date='2019-03-15T21:14:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lamberta&gt;@lamberta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 "What version of Bazel do I install to build TF" seems to be a common problem, and a static doc may be unreliable because the recommended version is likely to change as changes are made to master. Our best reference for any branch is always the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/configure.py#L1624&gt;configure script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Do you think it would be best to link straight to that from the build docs, or something like that?
Unfortunately, it looks like this issue has migrated from its original intent (to ask about the --batch warning). Since that's just a warning and the issue has changed topic, I'll adjust the title. If anyone still experiences issues with --batch mode, please create another issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='yurivict' date='2019-05-31T13:30:31Z'>
		So, there is not solution to this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='yurivict' date='2019-05-31T14:59:19Z'>
		If the issue is that bazel ... prints
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;WARNING: --batch-mode is deprecated...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

that's something caused by Bazel, not TensorFlow (also, it's just a warning, nothing breaks, can be safely ignored).
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If the issue is that every version of TensorFlow can only build with some specific Bazel versions, then running ./configure before doing any compile will check if you have a Bazel that is supported. Afaik, there is no bug in the logic there, but if there's an issue, please open one and tag me.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Upgrading/downgrading bazel is just a matter of running the following commands
$ BAZEL_VERSION="0.26.0"     # insert your desired version here, for example 0.26.0
$ wget https://github.com/bazelbuild/bazel/releases/download/${BAZEL_VERSION}/bazel-${BAZEL_VERSION}-installer-linux-x86_64.sh   # if not on x86_64, change that too
$ chmod +x bazel-${BAZEL_VERSION}-installer-linux-x86_64.sh   # or the file you just downloaded
$ ./bazel-${BAZEL_VERSION}-installer-linux-x86_64.sh
$ bazel version   # this should now print the same as BAZEL_VERSION
I think this issue diverged too much, so I propose we close it and open new issues for individual components, if needed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='yurivict' date='2019-05-31T15:29:08Z'>
		My issue was that the TF guide was telling me to use bazel 0.23.0 or lower but Bazel was telling me to upgrade to 0.24.1 to use it. In the end, I just upgraded and it worked. i believe this should be closed as well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='yurivict' date='2020-08-18T11:50:19Z'>
		Please downgrade your bazel installation to version x.x.x or lower to build TensorFlow! Even if you follow the version compatibility at &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#cpu-only_2&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source#cpu-only_2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please downgrade your bazel installation to version 0.0.0 and still it doesn't work.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>