<bug id='24203' author='colinmorris' open_date='2018-12-06T17:33:38Z' closed_time='2020-01-28T23:40:25Z'>
	<summary>Markdown formatting issue in tf.keras.layers.Layer docs</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version: r1.12
Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/keras/layers/Layer

Describe the documentation issue
Below the 'Arguments' list, it looks like there are supposed to be lists of read-only properties and mutable properties, but they render as paragraphs rather than lists.
Seems like the issue is that the parser splits the docstring into sections based on a magic list of keywords, detail_keywords = '|'.join(['Args', 'Arguments', 'Fields', 'Returns', 'Yields', 'Raises', 'Attributes']), and that list does not include the strings 'Read-only properties', or 'Mutable properties'. So it treats everything below "Arguments" as part of the list of arguments, and trips over itself.
(There's also some question as to whether these lists should be there at all, or whether this information should be in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/keras/layers/Layer#properties&gt;Properties&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 section)

Not with my current understanding of the docs system. I was able to find a script for generating a markdown index of the docs locally (), but when I ran it, I got &lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/colinmorris/0a180ea671e12ccdb65fe6cc9f0319fa&gt;a markdown file that didn't seem to have the issue I see on the site&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Maybe it's because I used  but the docs on the site are generated by ? Maybe the lists are fine in GitHub-flavoured markdown but not whatever engine is used when converting the docs from md to html for the site? (I'll file a separate issue about this meta-documentation issue)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='colinmorris' date='2018-12-28T23:59:17Z'>
		Apologies for the delay in response. You are right about this. Thanks for reporting.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='colinmorris' date='2020-01-28T23:40:25Z'>
		This should be fixed by tomorrow or day-after tomorrow.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>