<bug id='25306' author='RicCu' open_date='2019-01-30T05:20:49Z' closed_time='2020-01-28T23:32:54Z'>
	<summary>[Docs] Do not link to symbols within code blocks</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version: 1.12, 1.13, 2.0
Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/data/TFRecordDataset#map


The &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/58e99a76ebd4b533fed5591147441ee3f6db3dae/tools/tensorflow_docs/api_generator/parser.py#L119&gt;documentation's symbol resolver&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 will automatically replace all appearances of `tf.symbol` with markdown links to the symbol's definition, which is generally great, however when these symbols appear
within code blocks (e.g. in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/09696450acc1a69dcac4717de87ee4f30544865a/tensorflow/python/data/ops/dataset_ops.py#L912&gt;usage examples&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) the inserted link cannot be rendered correctly, and is interpreted as a plain string like . Thus, it would be best if symbols within code blocks are not replaced by links, or by links that do render correctly (AFAIK links cannot be placed within code blocks).
Note: I have only observed this behavior in comments within code blocks.
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
Yes, I could submit a PR. However I'm unsure as to the best strategy to efficiently determine if the symbol lies within a code block. I imagine that one could split the strings by re matching ``` and then deciding whether or not to re.sub the current section of the docstring, but this much string manipulation might be somewhat costly.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RicCu' date='2020-01-28T23:33:02Z'>
		This has been fixed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>