<bug id='25311' author='sarmadidrees' open_date='2019-01-30T07:35:07Z' closed_time='2019-02-12T07:23:04Z'>
	<summary>tflite_convert makes no difference to converted model after changing detection_postprocess.cc</summary>
	<description>
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Linux Ubuntu 16.04
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): source
TensorFlow version (or github SHA if from source): r1.12


I am converting SSD object detection model trained through object detection api. The only difference in my custom model and other pre-trained model is that the  have 6 output coords instead of 4 box coords, I am also predicting the center coordinates of the bounding box to make the model more robust. It is performing great in frozen_graph.pb but as I convert it into .tflite format by using tflite_convert, it only gives 4 box coords whereas I need 6 box coords. But, eventually I figured out that I need to change the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/lite/kernels/detection_postprocess.cc&gt;detection_postprocess.cc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, but changes made in this file are not effecting the model, it seems like tflite_convert is ignoring this file while converting the model.
Steps to reproduce the issue

tensorflow build from source and installed in a virtualenv
make some changes in the detection_postprocess.cc
uninstall tensorflow from virtualenv
again build tensorflow using bazel and install it using pip in same virtualenv
run following command to convert model:
tflite_convert \ --output_file=detect.tflite \ --graph_def_file=tflite_graph.pb \ --input_shapes=1,300,300,3 \ --input_arrays=normalized_input_image_tensor \ --output_arrays='TFLite_Detection_PostProcess','TFLite_Detection_PostProcess:1','TFLite_Detection_PostProcess:2','TFLite_Detection_PostProcess:3' \ --mean_values=128 \ --std_dev_values=128 \ --change_concat_input_ranges=false \ --allow_custom_ops

More information

tflite_graph.pb is obtained by using export_tflite_ssd_graph.py

How to make sure that changes made in detection_postprocess.cc will effect the converted model using tflite_convert?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sarmadidrees' date='2019-01-30T07:40:11Z'>
		As, suggested by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/achowdhery&gt;@achowdhery&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in this &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/21230#issuecomment-456803457&gt;comment&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I already build the whole tensorflow from source after making changes to detection_postprocess.cc but still no success.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>