<bug id='26012' author='danaugrs' open_date='2019-02-22T13:32:55Z' closed_time='2019-02-22T19:25:58Z'>
	<summary>[TF 2.0] tf.keras.losses duplication?</summary>
	<description>
Windows 10
TF Version: b'v1.11.0-rc2-4-gc19e29306c' 1.11.0
Anaconda Python 3.6.5
GPU: GeForce GTX 1070 Max-Q Design
Tensorflow 2.0 (gpu) preview installed via pip.
I'm building a &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danaugrs/huskarl&gt;reinforcement learning framework&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 on top of TensorFlow 2.0 using the  API and I've come across the following issue.
The 2.0 API docs for &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/keras/losses&gt;tf.keras.losses&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 shows many objects that are not actually available in the preview package. For example the loss classes such as Huber. Hinge, etc... are not accessible.

Why are those classes not included in the preview package?
Why are there both classes and functions for many of the same loss types? That seems like unnecessary duplication.
2a. Why is there a Huber class but no huber function?
I'd love to contribute PRs and help fix these issues. Would that be desired?

Edit: This has also been noticed here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/26007&gt;#26007&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-22T17:05:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danaugrs&gt;@danaugrs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Adding &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/fchollet&gt;@fchollet&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 -- and we'd love to have help resolving the issues you detailed in the API documentation.  exists in TF 2.0, for example; but it's listed as &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/losses/Hinge&gt;tf.losses.Hinge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
; and  is listed under , but doesn't exist in TF 2.0.
PS: thanks for the great work on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danaugrs/huskarl&gt;Huskarl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! 
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-22T19:25:58Z'>
		It looks from the description like this is regarding 1.11 (TF Version: b'v1.11.0-rc2-4-gc19e29306c' 1.11.0)?
This is expected, this was fixed in later versions (it wasn't ready back in late Summer 2018 when 1.11 was cut). I'll close this.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pavithrasv&gt;@pavithrasv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 FYI
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-22T20:36:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks, I must have gotten my virtual envs confused - apologies. I updated in any case and the docs match what I see. However, with the latest version () executing  still shows . This is preventing my library from requiring TF 2.0 explicitly. Is there a reason the PyPI version hasn't been updated?
As a heads up, tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION don't exist in the latest version, so the "Bug/Performance Issue" template instructions don't work in this case.
Also, would someone be able to answer questions 2 and 2a ?


Why are there both classes and functions for many of the same loss types? That seems like unnecessary duplication.
2a. Why is there a Huber class but no huber function?


		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-22T20:47:20Z'>
		That's because the preview is a different package (tf-nightly-2.0-preview).
So technically you haven't upgraded the TensorFlow package as far as pip is
concerned.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-22T20:53:06Z'>
		=&gt; 2. The functions compute per sample loss value. The classes call the functions in them internally and also apply weights and reduce the loss value to a scalar.
=&gt; There is a huber function. It is called huber_loss. May be the the _loss suffix in the name can be removed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-23T12:47:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pavithrasv&gt;@pavithrasv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/python/keras/losses.py#L813&gt;huber_loss&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 exists but as you can see it's not exported and therefore not accessible.  is also not exported but IMHO should be. I made a PR to address these issues: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/26034&gt;#26034&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I also strongly agree that huber_loss should be renamed to huber for consistency. I think the only loss which requires 'loss' in the name is logloss
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='danaugrs' date='2019-02-24T03:01:31Z'>
		Oh yes, we can definitely export those, thank you for the PR!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>