<bug id='26097' author='herbakamil' open_date='2019-02-25T18:32:00Z' closed_time='2019-03-04T22:38:01Z'>
	<summary>sorry, unimplemented: non-trivial designated initializers not supported</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a build/installation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:build_template
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 16.04.5 LTS - docker images tensorflow/tensorflow:latest and tensorflow/devel
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: -
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): source
TensorFlow version: commit a2bb5db
Python version: Python 2.7.12
Installed using virtualenv? pip? conda?: sources
Bazel version (if compiling from source): 0.19.2
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): gcc (Ubuntu 5.4.0-6ubuntu1~16.04.11) 5.4.0 20160609
CUDA/cuDNN version: -
GPU model and memory: -

Describe the problem
Some of the tests don't compile because of the incorrect order of parameters and cause the following error:
sorry, unimplemented: non-trivial designated initializers not supported
Problem is caused by the order in designated initializer which is different from the order in struct.
How should be tensorflow tested so that this test passes? It even doesn't pass on official Google tensorflow images.
Provide the exact sequence of commands / steps that you executed before running into the problem
bazel test --config=opt --test_size_filters=small,medium -- tensorflow/lite/toco/tflite:operator_test
Any other info / logs
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='herbakamil' date='2019-03-04T10:01:09Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jianlijianli&gt;@jianlijianli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 you've recently worked on this code. Is it tested on some internal Google compiler which behaves differently form gcc on official TF docker image?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='herbakamil' date='2019-03-04T22:38:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/herbakamil&gt;@herbakamil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I am closing this as this is a duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/26093&gt;#26093&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. We will resolve in the other issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>