<bug id='26199' author='rockbass2560' open_date='2019-02-28T08:37:50Z' closed_time='2019-03-06T17:06:03Z'>
	<summary>Tensorflow lite model requests a buffer bigger than the neccesary</summary>
	<description>
Hi, I created a custom model using keras in tensorflow. The version that I used was tensorflow nightly 1.13.1. I used the official tool to build the tensorflow lite model (the method tf.lite.TFLiteConverter.from_keras_model_file ).
After I created the model I reviewed the input shape and nothing seems is bad.
The input and output shapes in tensorflow lite model are:
[{'name': 'input_1', 'index': 59, 'shape': array([  1, 240, 240,   3], dtype=int32), 'dtype': , 'quantization': (0.0, 0)}]
[{'name': 'dense/Softmax', 'index': 57, 'shape': array([1, 6], dtype=int32), 'dtype': , 'quantization': (0.0, 0)}]
you can note that input shape is 1 * 240 * 240 * 3 so I expected that the buffer would have a size of 172800 units.
However, when I try to run the model in an android device I received the next error:
E/AndroidRuntime: FATAL EXCEPTION: main
Process: com.megacode, PID: 15067
java.lang.RuntimeException: Unable to create application com.megacode.base.ApplicationBase: java.lang.IllegalArgumentException: Cannot convert between a TensorFlowLite buffer with 691200 bytes and a ByteBuffer with 172800 bytes.
at android.app.ActivityThread.handleBindApplication(ActivityThread.java:5771)
at android.app.ActivityThread.-wrap2(ActivityThread.java)
at android.app.ActivityThread$H.handleMessage(ActivityThread.java:1648)
I don't understand the reason why the model request an input shape of 691200 units.
If someone has a suggestion I would appreciate it
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rockbass2560' date='2019-03-06T17:06:03Z'>
		The input type is int32, which is 4 bytes (4 x 172800 == 691200).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rockbass2560' date='2020-04-28T11:48:29Z'>
		Did you get any solution for above problem? I am facing same issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rockbass2560' date='2020-04-28T12:32:03Z'>
		In my case I needed to put the size in bytes of int type. So the operation was 4x240x240x3
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rockbass2560' date='2020-04-28T14:34:59Z'>
		Thanks rockbass2560, i tried and in my case it was issue of input size. inputsize 224 works for me. I am not getting error anymore and model run successfully but not getting image mask. How to configure remaining value in the below formula?

ByteBuffer.allocateDirect(1 * imageSize * imageSize * NUM_CLASSES * 4)

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>