<bug id='26316' author='lermag' open_date='2019-03-04T10:38:14Z' closed_time='2019-03-19T22:26:36Z'>
	<summary>TF crashes when tensor size is increased</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):Yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Windows 10
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): not sure
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.12.0
Python version: 3.6.8
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version: release 9.0, V9.0.176/ 9.0
GPU model and memory: GeForce RTX 2080 Ti 11GB

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with
python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
Describe the current behavior
I am running a custom code using TF. Part of the code includes a 2d convolution using tf.nn.conv2d. The code is running great, but when I increase the size of one of the tensors by a factor of 2 then everything crashes and I get this error:
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:56.729188: I tensorflow/core/platform/cpu_feature_guard.cc:141] Your CPU supports instructions that this TensorFlow binary was not compiled to use: AVX AVX2
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:56.988944: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:1432] Found device 0 with properties:
name: GeForce RTX 2080 Ti major: 7 minor: 5 memoryClockRate(GHz): 1.65
pciBusID: 0000:65:00.0
totalMemory: 11.00GiB freeMemory: 8.99GiB
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:56.995629: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:1511] Adding visible gpu devices: 0
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:57.467089: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:982] Device interconnect StreamExecutor with strength 1 edge matrix:
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:57.467875: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:988] 0
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:57.468098: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:1001] 0: N
2019󈚧󈚨 12:29:57.468449: I tensorflow/core/common_runtime/gpu/gpu_device.cc:1115] Created TensorFlow device (/job:localhost/replica:0/task:0/device:GPU:0 with 8665 MB memory) ‑&gt; physical GPU (device: 0, name: GeForce RTX 2080 Ti, pci bus id: 0000:65:00.0, compute capability: 7.5)
2019󈚧󈚨 12:30:06.043926: E tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_driver.cc:981] failed to synchronize the stop event: CUDA_ERROR_LAUNCH_FAILED: unspecified launch failure
2019󈚧󈚨 12:30:06.044411: E tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_timer.cc:55] Internal: error destroying CUDA event in context 000001F8E589DCD0: CUDA_ERROR_LAUNCH_FAILED: unspecified launch failure
2019󈚧󈚨 12:30:06.044888: E tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_timer.cc:60] Internal: error destroying CUDA event in context 000001F8E589DCD0: CUDA_ERROR_LAUNCH_FAILED: unspecified launch failure
2019󈚧󈚨 12:30:06.045401: F tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_dnn.cc:231] Check failed: status == CUDNN_STATUS_SUCCESS (7 vs. 0)Failed to set cuDNN stream.
The problem might not be connected to the convolution operation but it fails after I increase the size of this tensor.
Can you help me solving this issue?
Thank you very much,
Gilad
Describe the expected behavior
Code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
Other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lermag' date='2019-03-08T21:59:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lermag&gt;@lermag&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 May be there is an issue with selection of some parameters. Could you provide a code to reproduce the bug? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lermag' date='2019-03-19T22:26:36Z'>
		Closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will open a new issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lermag' date='2019-04-25T11:20:16Z'>
		Hello, do you solve it? I met the same error using RTX2070, thank you
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lermag' date='2019-07-15T01:00:08Z'>
		Same problem and could you post the solution to fix it? Thank you!!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lermag' date='2019-07-15T17:37:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/KimMeen&gt;@KimMeen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wumeng2&gt;@wumeng2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you create a new issue with a standalone code and also fill issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/new?template=10-build-installation-issue.md&gt;template&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>