<bug id='26463' author='edwardCao' open_date='2019-03-08T02:02:38Z' closed_time='2019-03-12T02:53:46Z'>
	<summary>Load data tutorial model fails to converge</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

TensorFlow version:
Doc Link:

site/en/tutorials/load_data/images.ipynb
Describe the documentation issue*
The model fails to converge most of times. I changed the steps per epoch to run through all the data but it fails to converge. A lot of times just stuck in high loss low accuracy.
I noted last layer output logits. It this expected?
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='edwardCao' date='2019-03-08T02:03:38Z'>
		BTW I ran only on colab with GPU. Yes I am aware this is a data loading tutorial but it would be nice to see it converges.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='edwardCao' date='2019-03-08T23:56:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/edwardCao&gt;@edwardCao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you point out which tutorial you are referring to? Please let us know If there is any mismatch in what was mentioned in the website and what you are seeing. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='edwardCao' date='2019-03-09T03:24:03Z'>
		site/en/tutorials/load_data/images.ipynb
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='edwardCao' date='2019-03-10T01:27:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/edwardCao&gt;@edwardCao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the link. I think intention of the tutorials is to teach how to load image dataset using tf.data. In order keep the tutorial simple as well as take minimum time, it was developed like that. There are other tutorials that talk about how to improve performance of a DL model. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='edwardCao' date='2019-03-12T02:53:46Z'>
		I am closing the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>