<bug id='26781' author='canyon289' open_date='2019-03-16T04:29:51Z' closed_time='2021-01-15T20:00:50Z'>
	<summary>Confusing documentation for  to tf.Graph in Tensorflow 2</summary>
	<description>
System information

tensorflow-estimator-2.0-preview==1.14.0.dev2019031500
tensorflow-probability==0.5.0


Doc Link : https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/Graph


I believe for TF2 these docs can be more explicit that tf.Graph should not be used directly, and instead provide guidance similar to what Alex does in his talk
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Up9CvRLIIIw&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Up9CvRLIIIw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The wording that A default Graph is always registered is confusing in TF2 verbiage. and I believe the warning that the graph will not be executed eagerly should also be made more prominent, potentially by moving it up.
The confusion compounds because after using this method the user is left with a tf.Tensor but we're advised not to use tf.Session so it's not entirely clear what should be done next to evaluate the graph.
Some of my confusion is visible in this thread (Big thanks to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/brianwa84&gt;@brianwa84&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for the help)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pymc-devs/pymc4/pull/93#issuecomment-473490764&gt;pymc-devs/pymc4#93 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for reference
Thanks in advance!
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
If I can get some help on how to word things correctly then yes
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='canyon289' date='2021-01-06T16:25:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/canyon289&gt;@canyon289&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
The documentation has been updated for TensorFlow v2.4. Could you please take a look at it and let us know if this is still an issue? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='canyon289' date='2021-01-13T17:03:30Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='canyon289' date='2021-01-15T20:00:49Z'>
		I doubt it is. Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/amahendrakar&gt;@amahendrakar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>