<bug id='27026' author='weixsong' open_date='2019-03-22T08:05:44Z' closed_time='2019-04-07T20:31:09Z'>
	<summary>dilated convolution does not convergence with data format NHWC</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): CentOS Linux release 7.4.1708
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: N/A
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): conda installation
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.9.0
Python version: 3.6.5
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: CUDA Version 9.0.176，
GPU model and memory: V100, 16G

Describe the current behavior
I implemented WaveGlow model, in the model it contains dilated convolution, so in early time I used tf.nn.conv2d to implement the dilated convolution model- -- WaveNet, I used the default data format NHWC, but after many experiments, I found the model does not convergence. Even after 700K steps with a small learning rate, it did not convergence. I have tried many hyper-parameters settings.
So I changed the dilated convolution to a native implementation from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ibab/tensorflow-wavenet&gt;tensorflow-wavenet&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Then the WaveGlow model convergence quickly after 50k-80k steps.
Then, I want to understand what's wrong with my usage of tf.nn.conv2d, but no clue. Then I tried data format NCHW, the model convergences quickly after 70K steps.
So I doubt there may be a bug in Tensorflow's implementation of dilated convolution with data format NHWC.
Describe the expected behavior
tf.nn.conv2d with data format NHWC should convergence as expected, it should behave the same as data format NCHW or naive dilated convolution implementation.
Code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
my code: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow&gt;https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

master branch is the naive implementation of dilated conv1d
model samples are also in the repo.
branch  is the implementation by tf.nn.conv2d with data format NHWC : &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow/tree/tf_dilated_conv&gt;https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow/tree/tf_dilated_conv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

branch  is the implementation by tf.nn.conv2d with data format NCHW  , &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow/tree/tf_dilated_conv_channel_first&gt;https://github.com/weixsong/WaveGlow/tree/tf_dilated_conv_channel_first&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Other info / logs
N/A
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='weixsong' date='2019-03-22T18:57:33Z'>
		Could you provide us a MCVE (See &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/help/mcve&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/help/mcve&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) that involves only a single TensorFlow operation and the results have large difference with data format NHWC and NCHW with a particular input?
Also, could you give it a try after setting 'TF_CUDNN_USE_AUTOTUNE' to '0' with NHWC data format to see if that helps? Winograd convolution that is used in case of NHWC is known to have higher numerical error. See section 4 in &lt;denchmark-link:https://openreview.net/pdf?id=H1ZaRZVKg&gt;https://openreview.net/pdf?id=H1ZaRZVKg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='weixsong' date='2019-04-06T12:54:37Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and the awaiting response label was assigned. Is this still an issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='weixsong' date='2019-04-07T20:31:10Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=27026&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=27026&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>