<bug id='27030' author='laiqb' open_date='2019-03-22T09:57:31Z' closed_time='2019-04-12T09:39:03Z'>
	<summary>'tensorflow/core/framework/numeric_types.h' file not found</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a documentation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:doc_template
System information

OS Platform and Distribution : cenos7
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: no
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): source code
TensorFlow version: 1.93
Python version: 3.6
Installed using virtualenv? pip? conda?: un installed virtualenv
Bazel version (if compiling from source): 0.22.0
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version: no
GPU model and memory: no

Describe the documentation issue
In centos, I downloaded the tensorflow project. I open '/root/tensorflow/tensorflow/core/framework/allocator.h' file,  Tips can not find thoese included files, such as 'tensorflow/core/framework/numeric_types.h' file not found.but those files are already exists. thanks
We welcome contributions by users. Will you be able to update submit a PR (use the doc style guide) to fix the doc Issue?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='laiqb' date='2019-03-22T17:55:47Z'>
		Thank you for your post. We noticed you have not filled out the fields in the issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/new?template=10-build-installation-issue.md&gt;template&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A? Along with the template, please provide as many details as possible to find the root cause of the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='laiqb' date='2019-03-22T23:37:18Z'>
		if I change as  #include  ‘numberic_types.h’ , it works. it maybe the path problem. thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='laiqb' date='2019-03-23T02:09:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/laiqb&gt;@laiqb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 If it is resolved, please close the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='laiqb' date='2019-03-23T06:38:10Z'>
		I think there is a better way, otherwise I must modify many files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='laiqb' date='2019-04-03T21:26:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/laiqb&gt;@laiqb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you check whether the bug persists in tf-nightly? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='laiqb' date='2019-04-05T21:02:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/laiqb&gt;@laiqb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't see path issue here as all the files are in the correct path. I am not sure what we can do from tensorflow side as all the files are in right location. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>