<bug id='27583' author='tarrade' open_date='2019-04-06T19:02:48Z' closed_time='2019-05-09T17:11:03Z'>
	<summary>Doc keras/Model for "predict" function the list of argument is not display properly (fullblock instead of list)</summary>
	<description>
System information

TensorFlow version: 2.0
Doc Link:
https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/keras/Model

Describe the documentation issue
In the documentation keras/Model for "predict" function the list of argument is not display properly (fullblock instead of list) on both Chrome and Firefox
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12021701/55674016-0cdf6980-58af-11e9-995f-fc569131a741.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tarrade' date='2019-04-07T02:34:55Z'>
		I think the issue is that the first line  should be prefixed with 4 spaces (not 5). Created a PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/27596&gt;#27596&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for the fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tarrade' date='2019-04-24T06:29:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dynamicwebpaige&gt;@dynamicwebpaige&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/margaretmz&gt;@margaretmz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Since you are experts, any idea why this PR didn't pass test ? It was just to fix some display issue of the Keras doc. I didn't do the PR but I see it didn't pass the test and it is not clear why. Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tarrade' date='2019-05-04T14:20:28Z'>
		I don't know if it normally take 2 days to deploy the new version of the doc, but I still see the same issue in the doc:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/12021701/57180374-4c867a80-6e88-11e9-97ee-1da60b9932bf.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tarrade' date='2019-05-09T15:56:02Z'>
		The issue was not fixed with the PR, please reopen the ticket. Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tarrade' date='2019-05-09T16:14:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tarrade&gt;@tarrade&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The page is pointing to 2.0.0alpha so it still use the docstring in 2.0.0 python. The PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/27596&gt;#27596&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fixes the issue in the master branch, it will show up in the next release of 2.0.0 (alpha or beta), then the web page will be re-rendered to capture the change.
I will re-open the issue for now, though I think once the next release of 2.0.0 (alpha or beta) is out the page will be updated and corrected automatically.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='tarrade' date='2019-05-09T16:55:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yongtang&gt;@yongtang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ah ok got it. Since this was independend of a Tensorflow version (the format), I was think it will be probagated to the main branch and I could see the update on the main page. I am fine to have the ticket closed since the issue is really fixed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='tarrade' date='2019-05-09T17:11:03Z'>
		I am closing the issue as it was resolved. I have checked that the PR was merged already. It will reflect on the website soon. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>