<bug id='27612' author='ToonTalk' open_date='2019-04-08T03:42:57Z' closed_time='2020-01-29T00:54:16Z'>
	<summary>Incomplete instructions for using images as metadata in https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/embedding</summary>
	<description>
System information

Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/embedding

Describe the documentation issue
The guide says

To use images as metadata, you must produce a single sprite image, consisting of small thumbnails, one for each vector in the embedding.

It then goes on to explain what the sprite image should look like (but it doesn't make clear if it needs to be "square" where each row contains a number of thumbnails close to the square root of the total number of vectors). Is any standard image format OK? What does one do with the image file? It doesn't work to choose it in the dialog that says "Step 2 (optional): Load a TSV file of metadata.". If one creates a config.json file how should one refer to the sprite image URL?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ToonTalk' date='2019-04-08T09:24:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ToonTalk&gt;@ToonTalk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

sprite.png : It consist all the sample images in a very large image.
metadata.tsv : It store index and label of each sample
Not any standard image format is ok, till now .png is what it supports to my knowledge, if we do not use these files, then our visualization is nothing but some points on the Visualizer, introducing these files will help the visulaizer to use the particular image of the point and labels too.
You have to generate the sprite.png and metadata.tsv with the help of a function and yes the tutorial lacks some key points upon the usage of these files and there generation that how a user generate these files.
If you want any help in how to generate these file please let me know i would love to help.
I hope your confusion is clear now if any more doubts feel free to ask.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ToonTalk' date='2019-04-08T09:44:18Z'>
		Thanks. I finally got this working when I noticed that if I click the "Publish" button it shows an example of how to specify the image URL and the dimensions. If someone could update the guide this would have been much easier.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ToonTalk' date='2019-04-08T09:51:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ToonTalk&gt;@ToonTalk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Thanks for raising this issue. I am working on it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ToonTalk' date='2020-01-29T00:54:16Z'>
		A while back a PR addressing this was merged, and now this link is about word embeddings, so I'm going to close it.  Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>