<bug id='27631' author='csukuangfj' open_date='2019-04-08T11:53:53Z' closed_time='2019-05-14T17:22:20Z'>
	<summary>[doc/keras] `predict` of `tf.keras.models.Sequential` is rendered incorrectly</summary>
	<description>

Doc Link: https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/keras/models/Sequential#predict

Describe the documentation issue
The argument list is not rendered correctly.
See it below
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Arguments:
x: Input samples. It could be: - A Numpy array (or array-like), or a list of arrays (in case the model has multiple inputs). - A TensorFlow tensor, or a list of tensors (in case the model has multiple inputs). - A tf.data dataset or a dataset iterator. - A generator or keras.utils.Sequence instance. * batch_size: Integer or None. Number of samples per gradient update. If unspecified, batch_size will default to 32. Do not specify the batch_size is your data is in the form of symbolic tensors, dataset, dataset iterators, generators, or keras.utils.Sequence instances (since they generate batches). * verbose: Verbosity mode, 0 or 1. * steps: Total number of steps (batches of samples) before declaring the prediction round finished. Ignored with the default value of None. * max_queue_size: Integer. Used for generator or keras.utils.Sequence input only. Maximum size for the generator queue. If unspecified, max_queue_size will default to 10. * workers: Integer. Used for generator or keras.utils.Sequence input only. Maximum number of processes to spin up when using process-based threading. If unspecified, workers will default to 1. If 0, will execute the generator on the main thread. * use_multiprocessing: Boolean. Used for generator or keras.utils.Sequence input only. If True, use process-based threading. If unspecified, use_multiprocessing will default to False. Note that because this implementation relies on multiprocessing, you should not pass non-picklable arguments to the generator as they can't be passed easily to children processes.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

It should be rendered in a list/item format.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='csukuangfj' date='2019-04-09T00:00:12Z'>
		PR submitted already &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/27596&gt;#27596&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='csukuangfj' date='2019-05-14T17:22:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/csukuangfj&gt;@csukuangfj&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I am closing this issue as the PR was already merged and I have looked into the source code that show update. TF website will be updated soon and then you can see correct rendering. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>