<bug id='28272' author='Apromixately' open_date='2019-04-29T19:49:31Z' closed_time='2019-05-07T16:08:31Z'>
	<summary>Website claims that there is no internet connection</summary>
	<description>
JavaScript on the website runs some sort of detection to see if there is network connectivity or tries to establish a connection in a surprising way.
This fails and I get a message "There is no Internet connection :(" which is clearly wrong. I am writing this issue with the same internet connection.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-01T03:04:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Apromixately&gt;@Apromixately&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you show a screenshot of the error and link to the JavaScript that is the source of this issue? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-06T19:06:42Z'>
		Sorry, I don't really know a lot about web technologies or how to debug this. Could you tell me exactly what to do?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-06T23:35:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Apromixately&gt;@Apromixately&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 When did you see this  error? You might have visited some page on tensorflow.org where you found this error. Can you take a screenshot (Press  on your keyboard) and paste it in the reply. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-07T09:49:45Z'>
		It happened on several different API documentation pages. Unfortunately, I cannot reproduce it right now, I think it might require me to be connected to the office via VPN.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-07T16:08:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Apromixately&gt;@Apromixately&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Tensorflow Team is upgrading TF website for future launch of stable TF2.0. It might be that when TF team was upgrading some parts of API docs, you might have visited and noticed the issue. I am closing the issue as you you are not experiencing the issue. Please reopen if you notice the issue again. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-23T11:45:09Z'>
		I just encountered this issue again. The JS console says:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Failed to load ‘https://www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.

Failed to load ‘https://www.tensorflow.org/_d/profile/ogb’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.

Failed to load ‘https://www.tensorflow.org/_d/profile/user’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-23T11:45:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jvishnuvardhan&gt;@jvishnuvardhan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Should I create a new issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-23T17:27:26Z'>
		Sure. Please open a new issue. thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Apromixately' date='2020-03-04T14:52:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/18472072/75891470-d206ee00-5dfd-11ea-8ac8-92c070437e1c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I have exactly the same problem. Does anyone know why?
Here is the link that I try: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/customization/custom_training&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/customization/custom_training&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks in advance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Apromixately' date='2020-03-04T16:52:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/15thai&gt;@15thai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you please open a new issue with your issue details, and (i) steps you have taken before this error, (ii) what was the status of internet at that time, (iii) your region (just country is enough) to see whether this problem is happening to more people in that region, (iv) any other details that you think will help us in resolving the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>