<bug id='28798' author='lgeiger' open_date='2019-05-17T11:46:21Z' closed_time='2019-07-25T16:32:22Z'>
	<summary>tf.data.Dataset::cache doesn't cleanup unused lock and tmp files</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 18.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.13.1 / 1.14.dev / 2.0.0-alpha0
Python version: 3.7.3
CUDA/cuDNN version: -
GPU model and memory: -

Describe the current behavior
tf.data.Dataset::cache doesn't cleanup unused lock and tmp files if the iterator doesn't complete a pass over the whole dataset or if the process exits before cache has been completed. This means subsequent runs of the same code with an incomplete cache will fail with:
tensorflow.python.framework.errors_impl.AlreadyExistsError: There appears to be a concurrent caching iterator running - cache lockfile already exists ('cache/mnist_0.lockfile'). If you are sure no other running TF computations are using this cache prefix, delete the lockfile and re-initialize the iterator. Lockfile contents: Created at: 1558092594 [Op:IteratorGetNextSync]
Describe the expected behavior
The iterator should cleanup incomplete cache files if finished or if the process exits. This would be really handy when running multiple runs on the machine and if processes might error or finish before the cache has been complete.
Code to reproduce the issue
import tensorflow as tf 
import tensorflow_datasets as tfds 

tf.enable_eager_execution() # if version 1.x

data = tfds.load("mnist", split=tfds.Split.TRAIN) 
cached = data.cache("cache/mnist").shuffle(100).repeat().batch(128) 
 
for feat in cached: 
    print("iterating")
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lgeiger' date='2019-05-20T09:06:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lgeiger&gt;@lgeiger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 After running the provided code, got the below error.
NotFoundError: cache/mnist_0.lockfile; No such file or directory [Op:IteratorGetNextSync]
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lgeiger' date='2019-07-25T16:32:23Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=28798&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=28798&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>