<bug id='28929' author='hsm207' open_date='2019-05-22T13:50:37Z' closed_time='2019-09-06T20:56:54Z'>
	<summary>TF2.0 Problem making prediction from a checkpoint if model has an embedding column</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): No
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Google Colab
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): NA
TensorFlow version (use command below):  v1.12.0-9492-g2c319fb415 2.0.0-alpha0
Python version: 3.6.7 (default, Oct 22 2018, 11:32:17) \n[GCC 8.2.0]
Bazel version (if compiling from source): NA
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): NA
CUDA/cuDNN version: NA
GPU model and memory: NA

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with: 1. TF 1.0:  2. TF 2.0: 
Describe the current behavior
I have a keras model that has an embedding column as a  feature.
I can train and save the model's weights just fine. Making predictions immediately after training works too.
The problem is when I recreate the model and reload the weights. Making a prediction from that model gives a shape error.
Describe the expected behavior
Same output as making predictions immediately after training.

Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
Please refer to this &lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/hsm207/305d068c982edf9e1df7db77446df50c&gt;gist&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='hsm207' date='2019-05-23T12:18:37Z'>
		I was able to reproduce the mentioned output on Colab with TensorFlow version 2.0.0-alpha0.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='hsm207' date='2019-09-06T20:56:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hsm207&gt;@hsm207&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I could not reproduce the issue as it was resolved in . I can see exactly same results with model_1  (original) and model_2(restored model). Please check the &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.sandbox.google.com/gist/jvishnuvardhan/a6a1ca212893e68b4b2448bca31bfa05/tf2_bug_embedding_column.ipynb&gt;gist here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
I am closing the issue as it was resolved in tf-nightly-2.0-preview. Please feel free to open it if the issue persists again. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='hsm207' date='2019-09-06T20:56:56Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=28929&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=28929&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>