<bug id='29046' author='Apromixately' open_date='2019-05-27T07:32:10Z' closed_time='2019-06-06T21:14:37Z'>
	<summary>Website claims that there is no internet connection</summary>
	<description>
JavaScript on the website runs some sort of detection to see if there is network connectivity or tries to establish a connection in a surprising way.
This fails and I get a message "There is no Internet connection :(" which is clearly wrong. I am writing this issue with the same internet connection.
The JS console says:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Failed to load ‘https://www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.

Failed to load ‘https://www.tensorflow.org/_d/profile/ogb’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.

Failed to load ‘https://www.tensorflow.org/_d/profile/user’. A ServiceWorker passed a promise to FetchEvent.respondWith() that rejected with ‘TypeError: NetworkError when attempting to fetch resource.’.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Apromixately' date='2019-05-28T16:33:31Z'>
		I was facing exactly the same issue. Turns out it was caused by one of my browser's plugin which blocks trackers (Privacy Badger). It was blocking the loading of https://www.tensorflow.org/_d/profile.... Turning it off solved the issue for me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Apromixately' date='2019-06-06T21:14:37Z'>
		Automatically closing this out since I understand it to be resolved by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Breta01&gt;@Breta01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 suggestion, but please let me know if I'm mistaken.Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Apromixately' date='2019-07-10T00:36:47Z'>
		Well, uninstalling privacy badger does make the website functional, but that means that anyone that wants to use the official documentation has to accept google analytics? Sounds like you're paying with your private data to use the documentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Apromixately' date='2019-08-06T16:13:20Z'>
		Dealing with the same problem with Firebase docs, but disabling my adblocker (uBlock Origin) has no effect. Works fine in private browsing with the adblocker though.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>