<bug id='29639' author='sunzhe09' open_date='2019-06-11T11:31:56Z' closed_time='2020-01-13T04:13:21Z'>
	<summary>quantized  tflite model result is different with CPU and NNAPI on my Android P devices</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:Reno710
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):conda  install
TensorFlow version (use command below):tf1.13.1
Python version:3.6
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version:10
GPU model and memory:

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with: 1. TF 1.0:  2. TF 2.0: 

custom quantized model run on android P with CPU get the right result.when I set use NNAPI  it get wrong result. So I had done some research :when I use tensorflow-lite-1.13.1.aar ,the two model get the same result.because my model have to use Op resizebiliear,but NNAPI before dose not include the Op ,I change it to tensorflow-nightly-0.0.0.aar,so I got the wrong result.Besides,I have build a aar with tensorflow master code,the result is still wrong.I have check the first Conv,and print the result.I found the result is still different.I don't know why.

got the same result with quantized model between CPU model  and NNAPI

Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/30410113/59268453-46519e00-8c7f-11e9-9b36-adc9b0173baa.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

here is my test model,just to verify the  output data
Other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sunzhe09' date='2020-01-13T04:13:23Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/29639&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/29639&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>