<bug id='29727' author='kami93' open_date='2019-06-13T04:49:45Z' closed_time='2019-07-22T05:13:52Z'>
	<summary>EagerFunc tensor conversion error - dtype mismatch</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): 18.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: N/A
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.13.1
Python version: 3.7
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.0 / 7.4.2
GPU model and memory: 1080Ti


&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/kami93/27da32514c4c9b085bf4fd20dcf6ef57&gt;GIST Link 1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/kami93/49355db2491ff7b4a03a22fbfbce09f7&gt;GIST Link 2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I am trying to use tfe.pyfunc to combine eager block in the operation graph (See Link 1). There are four input arguments to the eager mode function of dtype tf.float32 and tf.int32. When I try to calculate the gradient of a tensor w.r.t some variables that the calculations involving them are happen in the eager block, the error in the Link 2 is raised (TypeError: Cannot convert provided value to EagerTensor. Provided value: 0.0 Requested dtype: int32).
Describe the expected behavior
The gradient is calculated and returned after calling tf.Session.run,
Code to reproduce the issue
See Link 1.

See Link 2.
I posted a Pull Request for the fix of this issue. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/29728&gt;#29728&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kami93' date='2019-07-16T12:31:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kami93&gt;@kami93&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Let us know is this still an issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kami93' date='2019-07-22T05:13:51Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kami93' date='2019-07-22T05:13:53Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=29727&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=29727&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>