<bug id='29885' author='CrackerHax' open_date='2019-06-17T18:34:08Z' closed_time='2019-06-21T17:29:34Z'>
	<summary>https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/using_tpu 2.0b</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/using_tpu&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/using_tpu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Needs to be completely redone
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Clear description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Everything is wrong and examples do not work
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CrackerHax' date='2019-06-20T22:45:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CrackerHax&gt;@CrackerHax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the noticing issues in that page. Could you be little more clear in describing what do you mean by  and could you point which examples donot work? Are you interested in raising a PR to update the page? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CrackerHax' date='2019-06-20T22:47:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/guide/using_tpu.md&gt;Here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is the page if you are interested to update and raise a PR. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CrackerHax' date='2019-06-20T23:01:23Z'>
		Try the example... literally nothing works. Error for everything. If I knew how to do this I wouldn't mind fixing it but the whole reason I am reading the documentation in the first place is that I don't know how to do this.... Somebody who knows how this works since the code has been butchered needs to write the documentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CrackerHax' date='2019-06-21T17:27:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CrackerHax&gt;@CrackerHax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks! Yesterday I made some corrections and the PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/pull/710&gt;tensorflow/docs#710&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 raised was merged already. I agree this is one of the old content which need to be updated. More changes are in our pipeline. Please stay tuned. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='CrackerHax' date='2019-06-21T17:29:34Z'>
		I am closing this for now as we have listed this in our pipeline and will be updating in the near future. But, if you or any one want to contribute then please raise PR's to correct. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>