<bug id='30577' author='robseward' open_date='2019-07-10T18:38:39Z' closed_time='2019-11-27T02:16:36Z'>
	<summary>TensorflowLiteSwift fails pod validation</summary>
	<description>
System information

OS Platform and Distribution: MacOS 10.14.5
TensorflowLiteSwift Pod version: 0.2.0
Commit: 4774471
Cocoapods version: 1.7.3
Xcode version: 10.2.1

Describe the problem
When running the command pod spec lint, tests fail because i386 architecture cannot be found. This happens not only on my machine, but also on our private pod system. Failing validation means we cannot use the pod for our apps without turning off the tests.
Provide the exact sequence of commands / steps that you executed before running into the problem

cd to TensorflowLiteSwift directory
run pod spec lint --verbose

Any other info / logs
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/files/3378927/log.txt&gt;here's the output&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I was able to resolve this issue by upping the the iOS deployment target in the podspec from 9.0 to 11.0. I believe pod spec lint wants to compile a 32 bit version of TensorFlowLiteC for iOS 9 and 10, but the TensorFlowLiteC binary only contains x86_64 and no i386. A more robust solution might be to compile for i386. Or it may be possible to configure the podspec to only execute tests on arm and x86_64.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='robseward' date='2019-11-25T05:14:51Z'>
		Is this still a problem for you? When I run pod spec lint --verbose --allow-warnings TensorFlowLiteSwift.podspec in the tensorflow/lite/experimental/swift directory, it succeeds on my side.
A few more things to note.

The i386 target is now included in the TensorFlowLiteC nightly binaries (as of 29e6eaf).
The --allow-warnings flag will be needed due to a swift version related warning.
If the missing i386 still causing you a problem, you could also use --skip-import-validation to pass the lint, although it's not ideal.

Please let me know.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='robseward' date='2019-11-26T19:36:35Z'>
		We turned off the tests for this pod as a short-term workaround. Also, since we only support the last 2 versions of iOS, since iOS 13 is out we'll drop support for iOS 10 which should also fix the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='robseward' date='2019-11-27T02:16:36Z'>
		Sounds good. Let me close this bug for now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='robseward' date='2019-11-27T02:16:38Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/30577&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/30577&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>