<bug id='30820' author='patelprateek' open_date='2019-07-17T19:15:11Z' closed_time='2019-08-14T23:02:23Z'>
	<summary>Can xla compile tf.estimator.DNNLinearCombinedEstimator?</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a build/installation issue. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:build_template
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): ubuntu 16.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: n/a
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): source 1.13
TensorFlow version: 1.13
Python version: 2.7
Installed using virtualenv? pip? conda?:
Bazel version (if compiling from source): 0.19
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):4.8
CUDA/cuDNN version: n/a
GPU model and memory:n/a

Describe the problem
trying to AOT compile a model trained using XLA
error :  {{node dnn/input_from_feature_columns/input_layer/xyz/axyz_embedding_weights/SparseReshape}}
.  Registered:  
){{node dnn/input_from_feature_columns/input_layer/ad__ad_id_embedding/ad__ad_id_embedding_weights/SparseReshape}}
Is there any ETA on this being supported ?
How can AOT xla compile : tf.estimator.DNNLinearCombinedEstimator , is this even possible with current support ?
Provide the exact sequence of commands / steps that you executed before running into the problem
bazel-bin/tensorflow/compiler/aot/tfcompile --graph=mygrapht.pb --config=graphv.config.pbtxt --cpp_class="mynamespace::MyComputation"
Any other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-18T10:36:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/patelprateek&gt;@patelprateek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you provide more details about the issue.Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-18T15:53:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gadagashwini&gt;@gadagashwini&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 : can you please elaborate what details you need ?
I took the DNNLinearCombinedEstimator code , trained a model and then tried xla AOT compilation.
Can't get that to compile because of the following error :
error : {{node dnn/input_from_feature_columns/input_layer/xyz/axyz_embedding_weights/SparseReshape}}
. Registered:
){{node dnn/input_from_feature_columns/input_layer/ad__ad_id_embedding/ad__ad_id_embedding_weights/SparseReshape}}
seem slike SparseReshape is not supported yet.
Please let me know what details are you looking for , because i belive the above information is enough to reproduce the problem as well ?
tf 1.12 bazel 0.19 gcc 4.8 python 2.7 ubuntu 16.04
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-19T08:11:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/patelprateek&gt;@patelprateek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Please provide the reproducible code to expedite the trouble-shooting process. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-19T17:01:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gadagashwini&gt;@gadagashwini&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 : Please read my previous update , you can take DNNLinearCombinedEstimator provided by estimators api and try compiling with xla.
There is no need for me to share any code here (plus that is all internal code and would be hard to share , i already gave you enough information), i am talking about the pre built estimators
Also the error clearly shows what kind of feature is problematic.. i.e embedding
I think this is sufficient to reproduce
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-26T20:28:58Z'>
		
Is there any ETA on this being supported ?

No, we're not investigating adding any sparse operations to XLA at this time.
I don't know enough about the TF ops to state whether they're even a good fit for XLA, but if they are a good fit for XLA I'd be fine reviewing a PR adding XLA support for these ops.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-27T04:21:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sanjoy&gt;@sanjoy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 : can you please provide me some pointers or documentation regarding "what is a good fit for xla". I am happy to contribute and add PRs but would need some guidance , can you point me to some example PRs that adds support for few ops , that would be very helpful for me to understand the different pieces that needs to go in for supporting a new op .
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='patelprateek' date='2019-07-29T16:34:20Z'>
		Probably the easiest way to get started is to look at some example TF-&gt;XLA lowerings and try to find one that is close to SparseReshape.  All the TF-&gt;XLA lowerings are in tensorflow/compiler/tf2xla/kernels/.
For instance, this file contains the dense reshape operation: tensorflow/compiler/tf2xla/kernels/reshape_op.cc, although I suspect the implementation of SparseReshape is probably going to be very different from Reshape.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='patelprateek' date='2019-08-14T23:02:22Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='patelprateek' date='2019-08-14T23:02:24Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=30820&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=30820&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>