<bug id='30994' author='steph-en-m' open_date='2019-07-24T15:20:37Z' closed_time='2019-10-24T10:17:11Z'>
	<summary>[TF 2.0 API Docs] tf.math.sqrt</summary>
	<description>
Documentation contributor guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

TensorFlow.v.2.0
Link to doc : &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/math/sqrt&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/math/sqrt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Doc issue description:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

1. The generated file in which this symbol is defined .i.e python/ops/gen_math_ops.py is just plain text rather than a link to the source file. It would be great if it's rightly linked to the source file to enable change proposals.
2. There isn't a clear distinction between the choice of usage of either tf.sqrt or tf.math.sqrt and the implications (may be performance wise) of choosing one over the other.
3. The usage example isn't a complete code sample but largely syntax-like. One of the parameters the function takes is represented by a placeholder symbol rather than a real valued tensor.
4. There should also be a mention of the at-least the common errors that may arise as a result of incorrect usage of this function.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='steph-en-m' date='2019-08-27T12:41:32Z'>
		If needed I could work on this if is ok with you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dynamicwebpaige&gt;@dynamicwebpaige&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . Reading now this &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Can you point me to a guideline on how to update such files? Am I correct that I need to update the source file docstring? Thanks in advance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='steph-en-m' date='2019-10-15T15:15:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/michelucci&gt;@michelucci&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 have you achieved any luck on this? I don't seem to locate the  file. I only see  in the  directory and in the , imports from  are made !!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='steph-en-m' date='2019-10-17T07:44:02Z'>
		Let me check what the status is. I am in London for a conference until Sunday, so I will have limited time. Will update this issue as soon as I can.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='steph-en-m' date='2019-10-24T10:17:03Z'>
		I got the file where its defined..no more queries.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>