<bug id='31092' author='zuoshaobo' open_date='2019-07-27T02:07:51Z' closed_time='2020-11-18T17:36:36Z'>
	<summary>Tensorflow-lite gpu ios memory leak</summary>
	<description>
I use TensorFlowLiteGpuExperimental  for inference ,I have 60 models, if i only use one model to inference ,it works well, but if i switch different models in running , than memory leak occurs, I just use code :
interpreter = nullptr;
DeleteGpuDelegate(delegate);
to free resources
so if i loss other free function ?
if TensorFlowLiteGpuExperimental a bug?
TensorFlowLiteGpuExperimental the newer version number is what?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zuoshaobo' date='2019-07-29T18:17:47Z'>
		I assume you are storing interpreter in a std::unique_ptr so that interpreter=nullptr doesn't leak.
Could you give a complete repro example. Reassigning &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/impjdi&gt;@impjdi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 who has more insight.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zuoshaobo' date='2020-11-18T03:38:12Z'>
		sorry about my english. I use tensorflow and i leak memory on ip. Does anyone have the same problem and how can i fix it
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zuoshaobo' date='2020-11-18T17:36:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zuoshaobo&gt;@zuoshaobo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Sorry, I missed this re-assignment... and this is already over a year old.  My apologies.
We don't have experience with multiple gpu delegates, but usually, deleting the GPU delegate and the interpreter (maybe the other way around... I forgot.  there is a particular order) should be clean without memory leaks.  Given that this bug is quite old without updates, I assume the OP solved the issue by him/herself and will close the bug.  Feel free to reopen.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NALanhnt2&gt;@NALanhnt2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I think it's better to create a new issue for this with additional information.  If you say "it doesn't work on ip", it doesn't tell us much.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='zuoshaobo' date='2020-11-18T17:36:38Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/31092&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/31092&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>