<bug id='31474' author='Shine-ZhangGuomin' open_date='2019-08-09T09:41:07Z' closed_time='2019-08-09T18:53:12Z'>
	<summary>tflite unsupported ops:  Log1p, SparseReorder, SegmentSum</summary>
	<description>
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow version (or github SHA if from source):

Provide the text output from tflite_convert
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Copy and paste here
tflite unsupported ops:  Log1p, SparseReorder, SegmentSum
Some of the operators in the model are not supported by the standard TensorFlow Lite runtime and are not recognized by TensorFlow. If you have a custom implementation for them you can disable this error with --allow_custom_ops, or by setting allow_custom_ops=True when calling tf.lite.TFLiteConverter(). Here is a list of builtin operators you are using: ADD, CAST, CONCATENATION, EXPAND_DIMS, FILL, FULLY_CONNECTED, GATHER, LESS, LOGISTIC, MUL, RESHAPE, SELECT, SHAPE, SOFTMAX, STRIDED_SLICE, SUM, TILE, UNIQUE, ZEROS_LIKE. Here is a list of operators for which you will need custom implementations: Log1p, SparseReorder.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Also, please include a link to a GraphDef or the model if possible.
Any other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Shine-ZhangGuomin' date='2019-08-09T18:53:12Z'>
		Apologies that it doesn't work out for you. We are continuously adding new ops into tflite, in the mean time;
You can use  to convert your model it will help to reduce custom implementations.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/guide/ops_select&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/guide/ops_select&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You will have to custom implement  ops.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/guide/ops_custom&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/guide/ops_custom&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Shine-ZhangGuomin' date='2019-08-09T18:53:13Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=31474&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=31474&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>