<bug id='32098' author='jtressle' open_date='2019-08-30T00:19:12Z' closed_time='2019-09-24T23:26:27Z'>
	<summary>Unable to create TF-TRT model using docker image tensorflow/tensorflow:nightly-gpu-py3</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our GitHub Policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):  Yes, my model is custom.
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 18.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.14
Python version: 3.6.8
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.1 Cuda Drivers
GPU model and memory: T4, 12GB

Describe the current behavior
When I run the following code from the latest python3 gpu build, nothing happens.  When I run it from the nightly build, I'm able to get a model with 1 TRT Engine node.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;	converter = trt.TrtGraphConverter(
		input_saved_model_dir = str(saved_model_dir),
		max_batch_size = batch_size,
		precision_mode = precision )
	converter.convert()
	converter.save(output_saved_model_dir = str(output_saved_model_dir))
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Is there an issue with the latest gpu build?
Thanks,
Describe the expected behavior
Should be able to create a TRT model using the latest docker build.
Code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
Other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jtressle' date='2019-09-17T22:29:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jtressle&gt;@jtressle&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Sorry for the delay. Could you try using TF1.15.0rc1 that was released recently and let us know if the issue persists. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jtressle' date='2019-09-24T23:26:27Z'>
		Closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jtressle' date='2019-09-24T23:26:29Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=32098&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=32098&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>