<bug id='33776' author='EgorLakomkin' open_date='2019-10-28T09:26:19Z' closed_time='2020-02-03T23:55:36Z'>
	<summary>LSTMCell name is ignored in trainable_variables when wrapped in keras.layers.RNN</summary>
	<description>
I created a model with several LSTMCell cells, wrapped in keras.layers.RNN.
When I print trainable_variables, cell names are ignored, which results into duplicate variable names (several same recurrent_kernel/etc), which confuses Tensorboard for example.
Collab notebook to reproduce: &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/11W6ntLFGj4gqh5sS09CeVgb0LMNb_Fiu&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/11W6ntLFGj4gqh5sS09CeVgb0LMNb_Fiu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment: tensorflow 2 release
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-29T04:59:16Z'>
		Issue replicating for the given code - TF-2.0.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-29T21:39:56Z'>
		I would like to work on this one. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qlzh727&gt;@qlzh727&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-29T22:15:52Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this issue. I think this is a historical issue since the we directly invoke cell.call() method rather than cell.call(). This cause the name scope in the call to be ignored, which result into the variable name doesn't have the prefix.
The fix might need some special care since it affects the existing saved model (since the variable name changed, as well as the ops under the cell, they will now have a prefix of the cell's name). For anyone who want to try a fix, I would suggest to make sure the save model and checkpoint is explicitly verified.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-30T13:47:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qlzh727&gt;@qlzh727&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you! Maybe you have an idea of a simple workaround (not sure if calling  explicitly for each cell would help) until the proper fix is done?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-31T17:17:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qlzh727&gt;@qlzh727&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 How do you recommend to manually set the LSTM weights before the first call of  ?
The  method will say that the layer was expecting 0 weights, but was provided with a list of N weights.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-10-31T18:31:28Z'>
		The weights of the layer is initialized in build(), so you have to build the layer first with proper input_shape, so that it can init the weights with proper shape. then set_weights() should work fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2019-11-06T12:14:56Z'>
		I tried to build each cell, but the names are still duplicated
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='EgorLakomkin' date='2020-02-03T23:55:37Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/33776&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/33776&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>