<bug id='34385' author='bigmw' open_date='2019-11-18T18:32:50Z' closed_time='2019-11-22T00:59:41Z'>
	<summary>GPU device not found in Colab</summary>
	<description>
My code worked well with GPU in Colab yesterday. But this morning it became very slow. So I suspect that CPU is used despite hardware accelerator is set to GPU in “change runtime type” explicitly. So I check the availability of GPU following the tutorial:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/notebooks/gpu.ipynb&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/notebooks/gpu.ipynb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

code chunk:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;%tensorflow_version 2.x
import tensorflow as tf
device_name = tf.test.gpu_device_name()
if device_name != '/device:GPU:0':
  raise SystemError('GPU device not found')
print('Found GPU at: {}'.format(device_name))
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Indeed, I got SystemError: GPU device not found. I tried this with different sessions or google user accounts, the same results. You should be able to replicate this in a new Colab session.
Maybe some tensorflow updates are involved? It could be that Colab session provide GPU, but tensorflow can’t see it, e.g. tf.test.gpu_device_name() or tf.test.is_gpu_available().
Please help, thank you!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T18:52:59Z'>
		The best available hardware is prioritized for users who use Colaboratory interactively rather than for long-running computations. Users who use Colaboratory for long-running computations may be temporarily restricted in the type of hardware made available to them, and/or the duration that the hardware can be used for.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://research.google.com/colaboratory/faq.html&gt;Why are hardware resources such as T4 GPUs not available to me?&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You may try shut down current notebook and start a new one.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T19:12:45Z'>
		Thanks for the response. I only use Colaboratory interactively, and never for long-running computations. It is not likely that I am temporarily restricted because I tried the GPU test in different sessions and different user accounts (mentioned above). That’s way I think it is more likely related to tensorflow update.
Can you try the code chunk above in Colab (of course with hardware accelerator is set to GPU in “change runtime type” first) to see whether you can replicate the problem? thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T19:43:04Z'>
		Thanks. I was able to reproduce the behavior.
As a workaround you may try installing tf-nightly-gpu version;
pip install tf-nightly-gpu
You can also comment out %tensorflow_version 2.x lines from the colab.
Can you please point me to the webpage where you found the tutorial? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T20:05:45Z'>
		I have the same issue. Yesterday everything worked fine. I also didn't use it for long-running computations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T21:00:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ymodak&gt;@ymodak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

installing tf-nightly-gpu does not help. Commenting out %tensorflow_version 2.x lines works. Unfortunately, I need to work with tensorflow 2. It's even more likely that this is due to some recent update in tensorflow 2. You can find the tutorial in my original question above. Thanks.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qo4on&gt;@qo4on&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

glad that someone replicates my problem more precisely! Hope the tensorflow team can quicly noticed this and reverse the problematic update.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T21:27:56Z'>
		I'm also having the same problem and in this morning worked fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-18T22:20:19Z'>
		Same here. pip install tf-nightly-gpu and commenting %tensorflow_version 2.x doesn't work for me
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-19T05:03:07Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bigmw&gt;@bigmw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I got the same issue.  tf 2.0 GPU worked yesterday and today it is not working.
Tf 1.15 still can find GPU but same like tf 2.0 can't find GPU (include K80, T4 and P100 in google colab).
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-19T11:22:38Z'>
		Downgrading cuda from 10.1 to 10.0 may solve the problem. &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/58926378/unable-to-run-even-basic-example-with-tf-2-0-and-gpu-support-in-colab&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-19T12:38:44Z'>
		Thank &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ymodak&gt;@ymodak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, tensorflow 2.1.0-dev20191119 worked for me.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;!pip install tf-nightly-gpu
try:
  import tensorflow.compat.v2 as tf
except Exception:
  pass
tf.enable_v2_behavior()
print(tf.__version__)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

2.1.0-dev20191119
Comment: %tensorflow_version 2.x still get tf 2.0 so that wont work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-19T15:22:41Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/QuangHa97&gt;@QuangHa97&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

installing tf-nightly-gpu following your code above does solve the GPU error. However, GPU under tf-nightly-gpu (TF 2.1.0-dev20191119) seems to be much slower than the original TF 2.0 (before this bug occurred). My code used to take 5.6 seconds per epoch, now it’s 8.6 seconds, about ~54% slower than before. There should still be some issue there with tf-nightly-gpu. Hope the TF team would notice and work on this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-22T00:54:29Z'>
		UPDATE:
GPU is working with TF 2.0 now in Colab. Thanks for all your comments/suggestions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-22T00:59:41Z'>
		Awesome. Closing this issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='bigmw' date='2019-11-22T00:59:43Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/34385&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/34385&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='bigmw' date='2020-10-05T04:13:41Z'>
		
UPDATE:
GPU is working with TF 2.0 now in Colab. Thanks for all your comments/suggestions.

I still got the same error; why is that?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>