<bug id='35117' author='suphoff' open_date='2019-12-14T18:01:52Z' closed_time='2020-02-04T09:48:54Z'>
	<summary>lite/micro: micro_speech example:  input tensor lifetime assumption invalid</summary>
	<description>
@tensorflow/micro
System information

Host OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 18.04
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): source
Tensorflow version (commit SHA if source): e12ba3d
Target platform (e.g. Arm Mbed OS, Arduino Nano 33 etc.): All

Describe the problem
The feature provider accumulates feature slices using the input tensor in the arena as a buffer.
However the lifetime of the input buffer is only the first operation of the model.
As such the feature buffer may be overwritten when the memory is reused for tensors with different lifetimes.
This is the case with the current model and the current greedy memory planner.
As only the front of the feature buffer is currently overwritten - and the front feature slice  is  never reused this does not currently impact the example.
However using the example as a base of more complex models would trigger this problem.
I will submit a PR to add a buffer to the feature provider.
Alternatively the model could be changed to pass the input through to the output. (To keep the tensor alive)
Please provide the exact sequence of commands/steps when you ran into the problem
Code review
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='suphoff' date='2020-02-04T09:48:55Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/35117&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/35117&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>