<bug id='35745' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' open_date='2020-01-10T16:22:16Z' closed_time='2020-08-14T22:08:16Z'>
	<summary>Add a warning that tfds.load can not be used for own Datasets</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/api_docs/python/tfds/load&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/api_docs/python/tfds/load&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Add a warning that tfds.load() can not be used for the users own Datasets, i.e. that he creates himself. To a new user trying to to load a Dataset from a set of files it is not obvious that this method is only for pre-made, immutable Datasets.
Although it does say

Loads the named dataset into a tf.data.Dataset.

i initially interpreted it such that my own Dataset can be assigned a name.
I was looking for a way to split a Dataset into train and validation subsets and stumbled upon this documentation. I was redirected from &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/splits&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/splits&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which comes up as one of the most prominent search results when searching for "tensorflow Dataset splits" .
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Result&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A user who visits &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/api_docs/python/tfds/load&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/api_docs/python/tfds/load&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 will not spend 1 h of trying to understand all the documentation but will immediately realize that this is only for immutable pre-made Datasets.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-04-08T16:13:56Z'>
		Hey, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PanCakeConnaisseur&gt;@PanCakeConnaisseur&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Tensorflow Datasets (tfds) is used to load the datasets which are present on the library. For knowing which datasets are included in this library you can
Use  . For loading your custom dataset you can use .
See tf.data documention : &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/data&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/data&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If your query has solved then kindly close this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-07-18T11:59:30Z'>
		Hi everyone, i have a query, I have made a customized dataset by using different images available online. Can i add that dataset in the tfds directory ?
Looking forward to your replies
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-08-07T05:21:19Z'>
		Thanks for the issue we can only load datasets (pre-made) mentioned in the catalog &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/catalog/overview&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Perhaps we can add this to the function documentation. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-08-07T17:54:07Z'>
		Sorry for the late answer.
This is not true. tfds.load can be used to load any datasets (including user defined) as long as they have been imported. Otherwise TFDS has no way to know where the datasets is declared.
import tensorflow_datasets as tfds

import my_custom_dataset  # Register `MyCustomDataset`

tfds.load('my_custom_dataset')
To create a TFDS dataset, you can use the following guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/add_dataset&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/datasets/add_dataset&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-08-07T17:57:17Z'>
		I only see this issue now. In the future, please post the  issues in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/datasets&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/datasets&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as TFDS library is developed independently from TensorFlow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='PanCakeConnaisseur' date='2020-08-14T18:27:25Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>