<bug id='36347' author='pavanky' open_date='2020-01-30T19:37:45Z' closed_time='2020-02-02T21:46:33Z'>
	<summary>Official release of tensorflow==1.15.2 does not include GPU support</summary>
	<description>
System information

OS Platform and Distribution: Linux
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version: 1.15.2
Python version: python2, python3.6
Installed using virtualenv? pip? conda?: pip

Describe the problem
As &lt;denchmark-link:https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!topic/developers/iRCt5m4qUz0&gt;announced&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Tensorflow 1.15 contained GPU support by default. Tensorflow 1.15.2 no longer has GPU support.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-30T21:34:09Z'>
		Related:

There is no 1.15.2 version of tensorflow_cpu: https://pypi.org/project/tensorflow-cpu/#history
The Java version of 1.15.2 hasnt been released either: https://mvnrepository.com/artifact/org.tensorflow/libtensorflow_jni

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-30T21:54:18Z'>
		There has been an unfortunate change in our build scripts and 1.15.2 uses tensorflow_gpu for GPU and tensorflow for CPU.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-30T22:45:31Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mihaimaruseac&gt;@mihaimaruseac&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 This isnt a blocker, but it would nice if you can make an announcement about this at least.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-31T08:05:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pavanky&gt;@pavanky&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Is this still an issue? Please please free to close it if if answers your query.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-31T18:13:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/amahendrakar&gt;@amahendrakar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I can build the combined wheel if I build from source, but this is about the official release.
I dont see the download page updated yet.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-31T18:25:49Z'>
		For 1.15 what our scripts did was:

produce tensorflow_gpu and tensorflow pip package
upload tensorflow_gpu pip package as it is
rename tensorflow pip package to tensorflow_cpu and upload it under tensorflow_cpu
rename tensorflow_gpu as tensorflow and upload it under tensorflow

Both of these renames are more than just a cp source.whl target.whl, they also required changing the metadata in the wheel. But this process caused issues with integrity checks as filenames changed.
After 1.15.0 was released (actually, just before 2.1.0 was released) we fixed all of those issues but the fix was not backported into r1.15.
Currently, one could think we could attempt to manually do the steps above. Except we cannot. Pypi doesn't allow us to reuse package names (for good reasons) so once we have uploaded tensorflow_gpu==1.15.2 and tensorflow==1.15.2 we cannot change them around.
Actually, it is better to not do this since the move above caused tensorflow_estimator to depend on tensorflow_cpu_estimator for example (due to a bug). So if we wanted to manually do the steps above then we would need to create 3 more patch releases with no actual changes (2 for tensorflow, 1 for estimator).
We will update documentation on download page though
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='pavanky' date='2020-01-31T23:16:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mihaimaruseac&gt;@mihaimaruseac&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 updating the documentation sounds good. this can be closed at that point.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='pavanky' date='2020-02-02T21:46:33Z'>
		Documentation updated. Please let me know if there's something else to change.
Apologies again for not having a single pip anymore on 1.15
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='pavanky' date='2020-02-04T12:00:46Z'>
		With all due respect I think we should release a hotfix ASAP (say 1.15.3, 1.15.2.1 or something) to provide GPU support. Also, we could remove the 1.15.2 binary from pypi (as we did with 1.15.1). I believe it is obviously an unintended behavior and therefore a bug. I don't think it makes a sense to have a very unconsistent package scheme in the same version series.  UPDATED: Please see the comments below.
Due to the promise of v1.15, some people (definitely in certain cases) might have a dependency specification like tensorflow&gt;=1.15 rather than tensorflow-gpu&gt;=1.15 in the hope that GPU is enabled. But, in such cases we might end up installing a package without GPU (which I did).
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='pavanky' date='2020-02-04T12:16:08Z'>
		I carefully went through the documentation and the history again, and now I think it also makes a sense to revert the package consolidation behavior for 1.15.x series (which also makes a sense as this is kinda breaking change around v2.0). Given that &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/pip&gt;the documentation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 has been already updated, we should keep this one.
Only remaining issues would be legacy package specification in some cases, or outdated &lt;denchmark-link:https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/g/developers/c/iRCt5m4qUz0&gt;announcements&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
UPDATE 1: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/gpu&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/gpu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 still says 1.15 has a consolidated package (which needs to be updated).
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='pavanky' date='2020-02-06T13:15:58Z'>
		Hi, I also got confused and used the wrong package (tensorflow==1.15.2 without GPU support), because I read this section in the install documentation:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/gpu#older_versions_of_tensorflow&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/gpu#older_versions_of_tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


For the 1.15 release, CPU and GPU support are included in a single package:
pip install --pre "tensorflow==1.15.*"

Please add a remark to this section, that it does not apply to the version 1.15.2 (and upwards). It's quite confusing if you explicitly state that the 1.15.x versions do NOT use a separate "-gpu" package, when in fact some of them do.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='pavanky' date='2020-02-06T16:40:47Z'>
		Should be handled soon (with a 24hours delay due to the upgrade process). Apologies for missing that page
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='pavanky' date='2020-06-20T04:11:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mihaimaruseac&gt;@mihaimaruseac&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Which cuda version is compatible with tensorflow-gpu==1.15.2 in windows?
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='pavanky' date='2020-06-22T20:42:20Z'>
		It should be the same CUDA version as 2.0.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='pavanky' date='2020-06-22T20:52:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mihaimaruseac&gt;@mihaimaruseac&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have tested that it works with cuda 10.0
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>