<bug id='36803' author='dMokaMoka' open_date='2020-02-17T01:15:55Z' closed_time='2020-03-13T09:38:38Z'>
	<summary>Start the thread in Hook, resulting in failure to exit when train_step fails</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our
GitHub Policy,
we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and
build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information - Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock
example script provided in TensorFlow): - OS Platform and Distribution (e.g.,
Linux Ubuntu 16.04): - Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if
the issue happens on mobile device: - TensorFlow installed from (source or
binary): - TensorFlow version (use command below): - Python version: - Bazel
version (if compiling from source): - GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from
source): - CUDA/cuDNN version: - GPU model and memory:
Ubuntu16.04 x86_64 GNU/Linux
You can collect some of this information using our environment capture
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with: 1. TF 1.0:  2. TF 2.0: 
Tensorflow@v1.12.0
Describe the current behavior
I use the Estimator for training, and implements a hook (I'm sorry, but for some reason I can't show the source code), in the hook's’ after_create_session method, I started a python thread (a bit like TPUInfeedOutfeedSessionHook) which sess.run a block type op(eg. dequeue). Also, I implemented the end method,which will run an op(eg. enqueue) to prevent the thread from getting stuck.But Estimator explicitly describes the behavior of the hooks: if sess.run on in train step return failure, it will not call the end (and after_run) method. In the code, MonitorSession call the _close_internal method (it will invoke the Session.close()) which will wait for all the work thread ends, but obviously, the thread executing sess.run in my hook's after_create_session will not be able to exit )
Describe the expected behavior
I feel my usage is not strange, also the realization of the reference part TPUEstimator (TPUInfeedOutfeedSessionHook is similar to my hook). Does tensorflow not allowed to start a thread in the hook?As once it's started, when something goes wrong in the training step, the next call is session.close()，Eventually the Tensorflow process got stuck.
Code to reproduce the issue Provide a reproducible test case that is the
bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
def my_thread_task:
 while True:
        try:
          session.run(self._dequeue_ops)
        except tf.errors.OutOfRangeError: # this signal will send by end() method
          break
        except Exception as e:
          # raise runtime error
def after_create_session:
  threading.Thread(target=my_thread_task)
Other info / logs Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to
diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full
traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dMokaMoka' date='2020-03-13T09:38:39Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/36803&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/36803&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dMokaMoka' date='2020-03-13T09:39:26Z'>
		forget this issue...TF provides the mechanism for coord
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>