<bug id='36881' author='Hui-Zhi' open_date='2020-02-19T08:16:40Z' closed_time='2020-02-20T18:06:27Z'>
	<summary>How could I can add a new OS on the support on the "tested and supported" list?</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Could someone instruct me how to add a new OS on the support on the "tested and supported" list, I would like to make some efforts for Opensuse and SLE.
There might have some steps to make sure an OS is "tested and supported", right?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Hui-Zhi' date='2020-02-19T09:24:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hui-Zhi&gt;@Hui-Zhi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Opensuse and SLE are Linux flavours. Can you please follow the instructios in &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/source&gt;TensorFlow website&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and see how it progresses. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Hui-Zhi' date='2020-02-19T10:10:07Z'>
		Yes, you're right, I should not use new OS, thanks for figuring it out. And Ubuntu is also Linux flavors. On this website, it only have instructions for Ubuntu and Mac OS, what I am trying to do is adding Opensuse and SLE to the "tested and supported" list to give users more options, sure I believe the instructions for Opensuse and SLE is needed, and it's different from Ubuntu and Mac.
But what I am not sure is should I just add Opensuse and SLE to the website source code (instructions will also be updated), the make a pull request? Or there has some previous steps should be done?
I don't even know if the community would like to accept this change.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Hui-Zhi' date='2020-02-20T18:06:27Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hui-Zhi&gt;@Hui-Zhi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
The tensorflow.org/install pages are for officially-supported install and build configs by the TensorFlow team. So we should not add new OSes here.
But organizing an "extended" support list sounds like it could fall under &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/forums&gt;SIG Build&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Maybe send a message to the &lt;denchmark-link:https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!forum/build&gt;build@tensorflow.org list&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Hui-Zhi' date='2020-02-20T18:06:29Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/36881&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/36881&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Hui-Zhi' date='2020-02-20T19:37:04Z'>
		Our python packages are built according to the "manylkinux2010" standard.
So if you use the prebuilt packages from pypi, they should work on 90% of the linux distributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>