<bug id='37228' author='ngc92' open_date='2020-03-02T11:10:11Z' closed_time='2020-03-23T20:03:27Z'>
	<summary>tf.debugging.assert_shapes</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/debugging/assert_shapes&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/debugging/assert_shapes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The documentation for the shapes argument states that is expects a dict, but in fact in many circumstances it is not possible to assemble such a dict because eager tensors are unhashable.
So while it is possible to submit a dict here in GraphMode, Eager expects a list of (key, value) pairs.
It should also state whether tf.Variables can be used as keys.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Usage example&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The usage example seems to confuse the two concepts, and provides a mixup of both in invalid python syntax:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;tf.assert_shapes([
  (x: ('N', 'Q')),
  (y: ('N', 'D')),
  (param: ('Q',)),
  (scalar: ()),
])
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This seems to be fixed already in master
Further, tf.assert_shapes should probably be changed to tf.debugging.assert_shapes
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Submit a pull request?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Yes
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ngc92' date='2020-03-02T15:15:35Z'>
		Looking at the code in master, this seems to have been partially fixed (the usage example). However, now there are assert_shapes and assert_shapes_v2 functions which slightly different documentation, even though the latter does nothing but call the former.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ngc92' date='2020-03-03T09:47:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ngc92&gt;@ngc92&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Could you please check the nightly version of the docs from this &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/debugging/assert_shapes?version=nightly&gt;link&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
I was able to reproduce the error with the example given on the stable version. However, the example given in nightly docs works without any issues. Please find the gist of it &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.sandbox.google.com/gist/amahendrakar/b63bf1fd7194fa28fa1a198f17c5baab/37228.ipynb&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ngc92' date='2020-03-03T15:55:03Z'>
		yes, the example from the nightly docs works. The point about the shapes argument documented as being a dict still stands, though.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ngc92' date='2020-03-23T20:03:27Z'>
		Closing this issue since the associated PR has been merged. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>