<bug id='3750' author='tomrunia' open_date='2016-08-11T12:51:51Z' closed_time='2016-08-17T17:40:03Z'>
	<summary>TensorBoard doesn't show Events on TensorFlow v0.10 RC</summary>
	<description>
After a clean install of TensorFlow v0.10 (from master) my TensorBoard is suddenly broken. The scalar event plots do not show upon clicking (see screenshow below). While the logs in the terminal do not show any errors, the Chrome Developer console shows the following error upon opening a figure:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;tf-tensorboard.html:1517 Uncaught Error: tf-chart-scaffold's content doesn't implement the required interfaceinsertBefore @ VM2478 polymer-mini.html:560
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I am running Chrome Version 52.0.2743.116 (64-bit) on Linux Mint 17.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://camo.githubusercontent.com/bedbaf7fd1ce31a10c862fe38488e3863d919e0c0446d7b8f3825d41bd5245bd/687474703a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f476e5234364e4c2e706e67&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-11T18:11:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danmane&gt;@danmane&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you take a look?  Looks like a dependency version problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-12T04:42:00Z'>
		Got the same error. The server is on a ubuntu, and the client is a mac.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-12T07:52:49Z'>
		I found a temporary fix. Replace the file  with the older version from TensorFlow v0.9. This version can be found here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/r0.9/tensorflow/tensorboard/dist/tf-tensorboard.html&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/r0.9/tensorflow/tensorboard/dist/tf-tensorboard.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. This way the plots will work again. Hopefully there will be a proper fix soon :-)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-15T18:41:26Z'>
		How are you running TensorBoard? I can't reproduce it here.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-15T19:07:34Z'>
		I can reproduce on the master branch, on r0.10 it is working properly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-15T22:11:51Z'>
		We've fixed this internally, and I've verified that a new opensource repo built from the fixed version has a working TensorBoard.
Once we sync the changes to GitHub, I'll merge the fix into the r0.10 branch.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-16T11:30:42Z'>
		I can confirm that this bug is now fixed (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/ccd431b20a82ba2ecb96a82fb6e2712f2b522a11&gt;ccd431b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). Just did a  of the master and rebuild, TensorBoard events are now shown properly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-17T17:40:03Z'>
		Great. As r0.10 was not broken, only master, I'll close this as it's been fixed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='tomrunia' date='2016-08-18T18:05:47Z'>
		(Also, I merged TB25 into r0.10 anyway :) )
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>