<bug id='37516' author='amitDaMan' open_date='2020-03-11T20:49:10Z' closed_time='2020-03-19T13:42:43Z'>
	<summary>Posenet Android Example. TestActivity crashes. Incorrect sample image size. comp:lite type: support</summary>
	<description>
Describe the current behavior
TestActivity Crashes. input image is wrong size.
Describe the expected behavior
Line 209: Posenet.kt
getInterpreter().runForMultipleInputsOutputs(inputArray, outputMap)
inputArray has a direct byte buffer of size 1088659,
Interpreter/model expects a TensorFlowLite buffer of 792588 bytes
The bitmap being used for this TestActivity is 560X353, while the size of the bitmap during the execution of CameraActivity is 257 x 257, which does correspond to the correct buffer size.
Exception message:
Cannot convert between a TensorFlowLite buffer with 792588 bytes and a ByteBuffer with 1088652 bytes.
Solution:
choose a different sample image matching the constraint of producing a buffer of 792588 bytes, and change TestActivity:drawableToBitmap accordingly
For example, I know an image of 257 x 257 works (via CameraActivity), and then I change
Line 33 in TestActivity:drawableToBitmap to
val bitmap = Bitmap.createBitmap(257, 257, Bitmap.Config.ARGB_8888)
Even better would be maintaining the ratio of the input image (rather than hardcoding 257 x 257) and fulfilling the constraint of proper number of bytes for the model. Then any image could be tested, while avoiding unappealing stretching and skewing.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='amitDaMan' date='2020-03-12T17:46:37Z'>
		Would it be easier if I created pull requests instead of opening issues, if I have a solution to a bug.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='amitDaMan' date='2020-03-13T23:42:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/amitDaMan&gt;@amitDaMan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Please go ahead and raise a PR. Also reference this issue thread in the request. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='amitDaMan' date='2020-03-19T05:17:16Z'>
		In general, this &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/examples/blob/master/lite/examples/posenet/android/app/src/main/java/org/tensorflow/lite/examples/posenet/TestActivity.kt&gt;TestActivity&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is not used in the app or not even used for testing in real code. It is only kept for reference.
Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/amitDaMan&gt;@amitDaMan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Please go ahead and raise a PR to fix this. Thank you! :-)
Let me close this bug to reduce tracking cost. Thx!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='amitDaMan' date='2020-03-19T13:42:45Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/37516&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/37516&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='amitDaMan' date='2020-03-23T18:25:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lintian06&gt;@lintian06&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I have raised a PR for this minor change, it uses Tensorflow lite support library to resize the resource image to fit the requisite input size for the posenet model, thank you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>