<bug id='38335' author='ishaghodgaonkar' open_date='2020-04-07T23:04:06Z' closed_time='2020-06-19T08:52:56Z'>
	<summary>tflite Interpreter causes iOS app to crash</summary>
	<description>
System information


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock
example script provided in TensorFlow):  Following this tutorial for tflite with C++: https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/guide/inference


OS Platform and Distribution: MacOS


Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if
the issue happens on mobile device: iPhone XS Max


TensorFlow installed from (binary): - TensorFlow version (use command below): 2.1.0


Python version: - Bazel
version (if compiling from source): bazel 1.1.0


GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from
source): 4.2.1


Describe the current behavior
When using tflite with Mediapipe for hand tracking, building the interpreter causes the app to crash after being built and opened.
Steps to reproduce behavior

Need to clone our project github repo: https://github.com/sne21star/mediapipe
Try building the iOS app from command line using this command: bazel build --config=ios_arm64 mediapipe/examples/ios/handtrackinggpu:HandTrackingGpuApp
Download to iOS and try out app, will crash due to these lines in hand_gesture_recognition_calculator.cc

//  Build the interpreter
tflite::ops::builtin::BuiltinOpResolver resolver;
std::unique_ptrtflite::Interpreter interpreter;
tflite::InterpreterBuilder(*model, resolver)(&amp;interpreter);
Without these lines, app runs fine (same as their out of box hand-tracking example).
Describe the expected behavior
Building the desktop app runs fine and classifies the ASL letters, so expect it to work the same on iOS.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ishaghodgaonkar' date='2020-06-05T07:25:55Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ishaghodgaonkar&gt;@ishaghodgaonkar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Is this still on issue for you? I tried to follow your repro steps, but the  command was failing on my side due to syntax errors in the  file in your repo. Looks like some merge conflicts were not correctly resolved in that file. Could you please take a look?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ishaghodgaonkar' date='2020-06-12T08:09:09Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ishaghodgaonkar' date='2020-06-19T08:52:54Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ishaghodgaonkar' date='2020-06-19T08:52:58Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/38335&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/38335&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>