<bug id='38936' author='AnirudhNarsipur' open_date='2020-04-27T08:08:01Z' closed_time='2020-04-27T19:51:00Z'>
	<summary>Shuffling and batching operations results in keras model not running</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): Yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Linux (Ubuntu)
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: N/A
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): Source (Google Colab)
TensorFlow version (use command below): 2.2.0-rc3
Python version: 3.6.9
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.1

I have a dataset of about 70,000 image files.  I'm following the tutorial - (&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/load_data/images#load_using_tfdata&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/load_data/images#load_using_tfdata&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) to load them and preprocess them. However this function was causing problems:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;def prepare_for_training(ds, cache=True, shuffle_buffer_size=1000):
  # This is a small dataset, only load it once, and keep it in memory.
  # use `.cache(filename)` to cache preprocessing work for datasets that don't
  # fit in memory.
  if cache:
    if isinstance(cache, str):
      ds = ds.cache(cache)
    else:
      ds = ds.cache()

  ds = ds.shuffle(buffer_size=shuffle_buffer_size)

  # Repeat forever
  ds = ds.repeat()

  ds = ds.batch(BATCH_SIZE)

  # `prefetch` lets the dataset fetch batches in the background while the model
  # is training.
  ds = ds.prefetch(buffer_size=AUTOTUNE)

  return ds

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

After applying this function as the final processing step, my model would run but not even start on the first epoch.  The same applied to even a model consisting of a single Dense unit.  Examining the function step by step  I tried to do just the shuffle step or batching step -
ds = ds.shuffle(buffer_size=shuffle_buffer_size) 
 ds = ds.batch(BATCH_SIZE)
This alone resulted in the issue described above.
The preprocessing I have done before this is the same as in the tutorial.
Note: The Image data has no labels (by design) .  This might possibly causing the issue?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AnirudhNarsipur' date='2020-04-27T10:01:19Z'>
		i ran the code shared by you on nightly,  and do not face &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.sandbox.google.com/gist/Saduf2019/10b3b863cac05ace2b0dee87b3ccab20/38936.ipynb&gt;any error&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
could you please share simple standalone code for us to replicate the error, or if possible please share a google colab gist for us to analyse the issue faced by you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AnirudhNarsipur' date='2020-04-27T19:50:59Z'>
		This was an issue on my part. The batch size was too large for memory.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AnirudhNarsipur' date='2020-04-27T19:51:01Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/38936&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/38936&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>