<bug id='40008' author='307509256' open_date='2020-05-30T03:46:12Z' closed_time='2020-06-14T10:09:16Z'>
	<summary>convert error</summary>
	<description>
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow version (or github SHA if from source):

Provide the text output from tflite_convert
&lt;denchmark-code&gt; and pasting the following:

Some of the operators in the model are not supported by the standard TensorFlow Lite runtime. If those are native TensorFlow operators, you might be able to use the extended runtime by passing --enable_select_tf_ops, or by setting target_ops=TFLITE_BUILTINS,SELECT_TF_OPS when calling tf.lite.TFLiteConverter(). Otherwise, if you have a custom implementation for them you can disable this error with --allow_custom_ops, or by setting allow_custom_ops=True when calling tf.lite.TFLiteConverter(). Here is a list of builtin operators you are using: ADD, CONV_2D, DEPTHWISE_CONV_2D, DIV, FLOOR, FULLY_CONNECTED, MAX_POOL_2D, MUL, RESHAPE, SUB. Here is a list of operators for which you will need custom implementations: RandomUniform.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Standalone code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate
the problem. If possible, please share a link to Colab/Jupyter/any notebook.
Also, please include a link to a GraphDef or the model if possible.
Any other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem.
If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files
should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='307509256' date='2020-05-31T09:08:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/307509256&gt;@307509256&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please provide details about what platform you are using (operating system, architecture). Also include your TensorFlow version. Also, did you compile from source or install a binary?
Make sure you also include the exact command if possible to produce the output included in your test case. If you are unclear what to include see the issue template displayed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/new&gt;the Github new issue template&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
We ask for this in the issue submission template, because it is really difficult to help without that information. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='307509256' date='2020-06-07T09:34:31Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='307509256' date='2020-06-14T10:09:14Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>