<bug id='40155' author='aselva-eb' open_date='2020-06-04T15:53:48Z' closed_time='2020-06-04T16:10:37Z'>
	<summary>TFLite: Cannot run inference on TF Lite Model: "Regular TensorFlow ops are not supported by this interpreter. Make sure you apply/link the Flex delegate before inference.Node number 3</summary>
	<description>
System information

OSX Mojave
TF 2.3.0-dev20200602
Python 3.7.7
TF installed using Conda

Command used to run the converter or code if you’re using the Python API
If possible, please share a link to Colab/Jupyter/any notebook.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    converter = tf.lite.TFLiteConverter.from_saved_model(curr_dir + "saved_model")
    tflite_model = converter.convert()

    # Save the TF Lite model.
    with tf.io.gfile.GFile(curr_dir + '/model.tflite', 'wb') as f:
        f.write(tflite_model)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The output from the converter invocation
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Copy and paste the output here.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Also, please include a link to the saved model or GraphDef
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Put link here or attach to the issue.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Failure details
If the conversion is successful, but the generated model is wrong,
state what is wrong:

Producing wrong results and/or decrease in accuracy
Producing correct results, but the model is slower than expected (model generated from old converter)

RNN conversion support
If converting TF RNN to TFLite fused RNN ops, please prefix [RNN] in the title.
Any other info / logs
Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='aselva-eb' date='2020-06-04T16:04:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aselva-eb&gt;@aselva-eb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please provide details about what platform you are using (operating system, architecture). Also include your TensorFlow version
We ask for this in the issue submission template, because it is really difficult to help without that information. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='aselva-eb' date='2020-06-04T16:07:49Z'>
		
@aselva-eb
Please provide details about what platform you are using (operating system, architecture). Also include your TensorFlow version
We ask for this in the issue submission template, because it is really difficult to help without that information. Thanks!

I have my OS and TF version listed at the top. Is there something else in particular that I should add?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='aselva-eb' date='2020-06-04T16:10:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aselva-eb&gt;@aselva-eb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please share a simple stand alone code to replicate the error faced or share the colab gist with error faced for us to analyse
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='aselva-eb' date='2020-06-04T16:10:36Z'>
		Sorry! - just realized how empty this ticket is - not sure how I ended up posting this.
The real ticket with the info is:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/40155&gt;#40155&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>