<bug id='40161' author='benedives47' open_date='2020-06-04T16:55:33Z' closed_time='2020-06-19T07:52:54Z'>
	<summary>&amp;lt;tf.Variable 'Variable:0' shape=(1, 56, 56, 256) dtype=float32, numpy= array([[[[0.        , 3.6259902 , 3.3980963 , ...,        nan,                  nan,        nan],</summary>
	<description>
Does anyone ever experience like this? Please give enlightenment, thank you
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/58981061/83787982-cce86200-a6be-11ea-86be-93c587a5e45a.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='benedives47' date='2020-06-05T06:03:50Z'>
		Please provide details about what platform you are using (operating system, architecture). Also include your TensorFlow version.
Can you please elaborate about the issue &amp; the context.Will it be possible to share colab link or simple standalone code to reproduce the issue in our environment.It helps us in localizing the issue faster.Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='benedives47' date='2020-06-05T06:34:09Z'>
		ฉันอ้อนวอน ด้วยความเมตา ฉันไม่มีความรุ้มากในระบบโซเชียล ฉันต้องการเงินทุนสำรองเลี้ยงบุตรและเริ่มกิจการเล้กๆของตัวเอง ในภูมิภาคิที่ฉันอยู่เต็บไปด้วยกลลวงจนฉันและครอบครัวลำบากหมดทางแก้ไข ฉันเป็นหม้าย แต่ฉันมีงานที่ดี สุจริตและต้องการศึกษาเพิ่มเกี่ยวกับโลกโซเชียล ฉันคงเข้าระบบผิด ถูกบ้าง เพื่อเข้าถึงกระเป๋าเงินและสินเชื่อ ขอบคุณ และกล่าวขอโทษ    ด้วยความนับถือ  Wiphawee
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='benedives47' date='2020-06-12T07:09:08Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='benedives47' date='2020-06-19T07:52:53Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='benedives47' date='2020-06-19T07:52:55Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/40161&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/40161&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>