<bug id='4050' author='zplizzi' open_date='2016-08-26T07:06:53Z' closed_time='2016-09-19T21:14:57Z'>
	<summary>Possible improvement in documentation</summary>
	<description>
I'm following the documentation &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r0.10/how_tos/adding_an_op/index.html#compiling_the_kernel_for_the_gpu_device&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Specifically, I find that running the second command in the code block of the section "Compiling the kernel for the GPU device" returns a linker error complaining about the lack of the  library. I have solved this issue by adding the option  to the command, since the  library is located in that folder on my machine. I'm not sure how else this library would be located (LD_LIBRARY_PATH is only searched on execution, not compile-time), so I'm thinking this problem might not be specific to my configuration. If so, adding mention of this option on the documentation might be valuable.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zplizzi' date='2016-08-26T15:38:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zplizzi&gt;@zplizzi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Could you please let me know what the value was of  as per the following step in the instructions:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;TF_INC=$(python -c 'import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.sysconfig.get_include())')
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keveman&gt;@keveman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Should there also be an equivalent  path?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zplizzi' date='2016-08-26T16:40:23Z'>
		We do have  that gives you the path to use for the  option. However that's for the TensorFlow libraries. These instructions assume that cuda libraries are available in  which is typical if you install cuda with the default options. In that case, you wouldn't need to pass the extra  to point to the location of cuda libraries. But &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zplizzi&gt;@zplizzi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 does have a point, it might be valuable to add that to the documentation. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zplizzi&gt;@zplizzi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do you mind sending out a PR?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zplizzi' date='2016-09-07T05:46:47Z'>
		Okay, I've submitted a PR adding a note in the docs about this.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/prb12&gt;@prb12&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 My  is , since I've installed TensorFlow into a virtual environment. The result of  is , as expected from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keveman&gt;@keveman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's comments.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>