<bug id='41077' author='mhansen' open_date='2020-07-04T09:22:41Z' closed_time='2020-07-11T19:30:02Z'>
	<summary>docs: code style: says to install clang-tidy then examples use clang-format</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/code_style&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/code_style&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Docs say to install clang-tidy but the example given says to run clang-format. Is this intended? I would have expected to run clang-tidy.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-06T19:11:03Z'>
		Thanks for the issue.
The example looks correct since we are using diff to compare the newly formatted file generated by clang-format vs the original file.
Perhaps we can add clang-tidy piece to the documentation to output the warnings from the original file if any as in initial check.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-06T21:17:41Z'>
		I think the clang-format part of the example is correct. I suppose I’d
expect to see an extra example for running clang-tidy, and perhaps an
apt-get install clang-format too.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Tue, 7 Jul 2020 at 05:11, Yasir Modak ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Thanks for the issue.
 The example looks correct since we are using diff to compare the newly
 formatted file generated by clang-format vs the original file.
 Perhaps we can add clang-tidy piece to the documentation to output the
 warnings from the original file if any as in initial check.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#41077 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AAAZYONC6YEO5F6JKYFX23DR2IOVTANCNFSM4OQKE4MQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-07T21:02:44Z'>
		Would you be interested in raising a PR to add it?
This the file we can try editing &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/community/contribute/code_style.md&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/community/contribute/code_style.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-08T01:59:12Z'>
		I could, if I knew what flags you run clang-tidy with?
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Wed, 8 Jul 2020 at 07:03, Yasir Modak ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Would you be interested in raising a PR to add it?
 This the file we can try editing
 https://github.com/tensorflow/docs/blob/master/site/en/community/contribute/code_style.md

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#41077 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AAAZYOOQUINWTJY6P3MKN5LR2OEQRANCNFSM4OQKE4MQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-09T10:21:19Z'>
		Perhaps I should just remove the reference to clang-tidy, it's not easy to invoke (you have to pass all the includes, for example), so it's probably not actionable to just include in the docs without detailed instructions.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://clang.llvm.org/extra/clang-tidy/&gt;https://clang.llvm.org/extra/clang-tidy/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-09T10:21:38Z'>
		CONTRIBUTING.md also needs to be updated in the main tensorflow repo
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='mhansen' date='2020-07-11T19:30:02Z'>
		Thank you for your contribution. Closing this issue since the associated PR is merged.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>