<bug id='41352' author='faustomorales' open_date='2020-07-13T21:51:06Z' closed_time='2020-07-21T12:53:21Z'>
	<summary>TensorFlow Lite runtime check doesn't account for bytecode</summary>
	<description>
This line in TensorFlow Lite doesn't consider the possibility that the name of the file could end with pyc instead of py if the module is compiled to bytecode (e.g., when used by PyInstaller). I can file a PR but wanted to check first if there's a reason why this is the way that it is. Right now, this causes the TensorFlow Lite runtime to try to import full TensorFlow when it's compiled to bytecode, which of course fails.



tensorflow/tensorflow/lite/python/interpreter.py


         Line 28
      in
      df56513






 if not __file__.endswith('tflite_runtime/interpreter.py'): 





I would plan to change this to:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import os

if not os.path.splitext(__file__)[0].endswith('tflite_runtime/interpreter')
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Feedback welcome!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-17T18:14:41Z'>
		Great catch, thanks! &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MeghnaNatraj&gt;@MeghnaNatraj&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you take this one?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-17T18:37:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faustomorales&gt;@faustomorales&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you for catching this bug. Let us know if you've filed a PR, otherwise I'll go ahead and make the update.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-17T19:46:15Z'>
		I'm happy to file the PR for this in the next couple of days. Just wanted to file an issue before I assume that this behavior was unintentional. Thanks for the feedback!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-17T20:28:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faustomorales&gt;@faustomorales&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Whenever you file the PR, feel free to add me as a reviewer for a quicker turnaround time. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-19T06:49:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faustomorales&gt;@faustomorales&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Would a more robust option be to use a try statement to attempt to import the runtime from tensorflow and fall back to tflite_runtime if it fails to load the module?
What is the rationale behind having the check be done with the file name?
Best,
Sebastian
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-19T23:51:46Z'>
		
@faustomorales
Would a more robust option be to use a try statement to attempt to import the runtime from tensorflow and fall back to tflite_runtime if it fails to load the module?
What is the rationale behind having the check be done with the file name?
Best,
Sebastian

Switching to a try/catch seems more idiomatc (ask forgiveness, not permission) but would result in TensorFlow getting used if a user has installed TensorFlow and the TFLite runtime in the same environment. In the best case, this causes surprising behavior (the TFLite runtime would rely on TensorFlow when it was intended to operate independently). In the worst case, there could be an API mismatch between TFLite and TensorFlow. For those reasons, I think it would be wise to stick with the path check. Let me know if I've missed something!
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-20T21:40:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faustomorales&gt;@faustomorales&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the explanation, really look forward to this patch being released in a stable version (right now I am patching "manually" the file to bundle it in pyinstaller).
Best!
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='faustomorales' date='2020-07-21T12:53:23Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41352&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41352&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>