<bug id='41470' author='vdaita' open_date='2020-07-16T21:25:16Z' closed_time='2020-07-19T12:43:21Z'>
	<summary>Model Maker Outputing Single File, no labels.txt</summary>
	<description>
Thank you for submitting a TensorFlow documentation issue. Per our GitHub
policy, we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests, and
build/installation issues on GitHub.
The TensorFlow docs are open source! To get involved, read the documentation
contributor guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/tutorials/model_maker_image_classification&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/tutorials/model_maker_image_classification&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please provide a link to the documentation entry, for example:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/MyMethod&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/MyMethod&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The tutorial for Tensorflow Model Maker says that on export, there will be a model.tflite file and then a labels.txt file. However, when I export the model using the instructions, it only outputs a single model.tflite. The console output says that it is stored in a temp directory (which appears to be subsequently deleted), and that the labels are merged into the model.tflite file. Would I still be able to use this on mobile or is there any way I can extract labels.txt?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Clear description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

For example, why should someone use this method? How is it useful?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Correct links&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Is the link to the source code correct?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Parameters defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are all parameters defined and formatted correctly?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Returns defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are return values defined?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Raises listed and defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are the errors defined? For example,
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/feature_column/categorical_column_with_vocabulary_file#raises&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r2.0/api_docs/python/tf/feature_column/categorical_column_with_vocabulary_file#raises&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Usage example&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Is there a usage example?
See the API guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_ref&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_ref&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

on how to write testable usage examples.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Request visuals, if applicable&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are there currently visuals? If not, will it clarify the content?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Submit a pull request?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are you planning to also submit a pull request to fix the issue? See the docs
contributor guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
docs API guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_ref&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_ref&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and the
docs style guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_style&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/community/contribute/docs_style&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vdaita' date='2020-07-19T05:31:51Z'>
		Hello!
I managed to extract the labels.txt file by the following method.

Let's say that you have a dataset folder where you train your images. Inside the dataset folder, there's bound to be subfolders consisting of images (e.g. inside the dataset folder, there is also dandellions, tulips, lilies, roses, et cetera).
The thing is that TensorFlow trains your data in a descending order. If we take above assumption, then TensorFlow will train your data starting from dandellions, lilies, roses, and then finally the tulips.
What I infer from this is that you can recreate your own labels.txt file by simply listing the names of each folder. How do we do that?

We simply use this following Python snippet (I run this on Google Colab's Jupyter Notebook):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;def recreate_labels():
  # 1) We use this in order to ignore any hidden files that might be here.
  # 'Datasets' is the name of the folder where we store our training data. The 'listdir' is used to fetch all the folder names.
  labels = [folder for folder in os.listdir('datasets') if not folder.startswith('.')]
  
  # 2) Then, we output the contents of each folder name to a file.
  with open('labels.txt', 'w') as file:
    for label in labels:
      file.write(label)
      file.write('\n')

recreate_labels()   
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This should be the workaround for now. After this is done, you could test it using various methods, one of them is &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tensorflow/lite/examples/python&gt;Python's TensorFlow Lite Image Classification Tester&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. If you are using this, then make sure to change the filename where it takes the  file (line 94).
Alternatively, you could use the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/hub/tree/master/tensorflow_hub/tools/make_image_classifier&gt;TensorFlow's Make Image Classifier&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. This tool also outputs the image classifier model that you are creating to a  model, complete with .
Thank you and please don't hesitate to comment if you have anymore questions!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>