<bug id='41643' author='neuralmagic(ghost)' open_date='2020-07-23T00:37:03Z' closed_time='2020-08-04T20:54:47Z'>
	<summary>tf-slim ResNet v1 pre-trained models preprocessing</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Affected Doc URL&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/models/blob/master/research/slim/README.md#pre-trained-models&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/models/blob/master/research/slim/README.md#pre-trained-models&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Both tf-slim VGG and Inception preprocessing cause the ResNet v1 models in the above link to have incorrect outputs.  The other ImageNet models run correctly with either the VGG or Inception preprocessing, however under the same code path, ResNet v1 models produce incorrect outputs.  This issue is also documented in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/17426&gt;this unresolved issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Are we aware of the correct steps to take to correctly run slim's ResNet v1 models and could this be updated in the documentation?
Thank you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='neuralmagic(ghost)' date='2020-07-28T19:11:00Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ymodak&gt;@ymodak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we have found that the model expects inputs not to be scaled by 255, however this does not get the expected top1 accuracy (67% vs 75% on resnet v1 50).  Could you point us to any information or documentation on the proper preprocessing?  Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='neuralmagic(ghost)' date='2020-07-28T19:34:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/neuralmagic&gt;@neuralmagic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the issue and sharing your investigation. I think this issue is better raised on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/google-research/tf-slim/issues&gt;tf-slim repo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 since the  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/models/tree/master/research/slim/preprocessing&gt;tf-slim VGG and Inception preprocessing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 code is hosted on .
The folks of  can provide a better guidance in this regard.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='neuralmagic(ghost)' date='2020-08-04T20:22:58Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='neuralmagic(ghost)' date='2020-08-04T20:54:47Z'>
		Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ymodak&gt;@ymodak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  We will follow up there.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>