<bug id='41833' author='marang7' open_date='2020-07-28T19:57:16Z' closed_time='2020-08-12T06:21:09Z'>
	<summary>Keras ImageDataGenerator Preprocessing-Function</summary>
	<description>
I am quite new to Tensorflow and Keras and not sure if am getting something wrong or if there really is a difference between the documentation and the code. If any futher informations are necessarry I will add them quickly.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://keras.io/api/preprocessing/image/#imagedatagenerator-class&gt;https://keras.io/api/preprocessing/image/#imagedatagenerator-class&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Clear description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

According to the documentation the class ImageDataGenerator takes a function preprocessing_function when initializing it. In the discription it says that the function is executed AFTER the input has been rescaled:
"...The function will run after the image is resized and augmented..."
When going through the code I realized that in the class ImageDataGenerator within the function standardize the preprocessing_function is applied BEFORE rescaling the image.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Correct links&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Is the link to the source code correct? Yes
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Parameters defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are all parameters defined and formatted correctly? yes
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Returns defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are return values defined? Yes
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Raises listed and defined&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Are the errors defined? Yes
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Submit a pull request? No&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='marang7' date='2020-07-29T04:31:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marang7&gt;@marang7&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Could you please fill in the issue template with the issue faced and details as requested for along with tf version [simple stand alone code and error logs or colab gist with the error or steps that you ran before you ran into the issue]
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='marang7' date='2020-08-05T05:22:58Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='marang7' date='2020-08-12T06:21:08Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>