<bug id='41847' author='summa-code' open_date='2020-07-29T07:08:16Z' closed_time='2020-12-03T16:44:02Z'>
	<summary>Timeseries example is a Misnomer. It is NOT a "timeseries" it is rather a simple series.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/structured_data/time_series#part_2_forecast_a_multivariate_time_series&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/structured_data/time_series#part_2_forecast_a_multivariate_time_series&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I do not understand how this can be time series ? The data is "equidistant" with each other. And the time itself is not considered in predicting the values, but rather just as a series. When you include TIME AS A VECTOR, i would accept that it is a Timeseries.
The title is MISLEADING and also we need an example for vectorizing Time... for an actual Timeseries.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='summa-code' date='2020-07-29T17:55:10Z'>
		I do believe the docs go with following &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/time%20series&gt;definition &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 of the term, or close variation on it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='summa-code' date='2020-07-29T23:54:18Z'>
		Wow... are you saying that You go with Merriam Webster but not mathematical definition ? They are wrong. IT is a sequential data. If the data is time ordered or indexed only then it can be Time series. And Webster is not a definitive source for mathematical definitions. I will write to Webster about this discrepancy.
More over when "Time" itself is not considered how could this example be "Timeseries" ? IT is that simple actually.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_series&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_series&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Are we stuck up on the definition or looking to have a future added ? I am confused here.  If you say Timeseries, how do i take a particular time and predict ? I can do this for a sequential data, for example a next step in the sequence.
I want Tensor team to clearly state if they mean any sequential data is a "Timed" series data... And if they come around and say yes.. i have no words for it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='summa-code' date='2020-07-30T05:10:37Z'>
		I'm not sure if either of us misinterpreted the definition.
But I don't see how is what docs describe differs from either Webster or wiki.
The dictionary definition says:

a set of data collected sequentially usually at fixed intervals of time
It's hard not to see the implied sequence of the data points.

The wiki definition on the other hand:

A time series is a series of data points indexed (or listed or graphed) in time order. Most commonly, a time series is a sequence taken at successive equally spaced points in time. Thus it is a sequence of discrete-time data. Examples of time series are heights of ocean tides, counts of sunspots, and the daily closing value of the Dow Jones Industrial Average.

Again sequence, arguably more clearly stated compared to Webster.
Docs example is rather straightforward too, in that it describes:

This tutorial uses a weather time series dataset recorded by the Max Planck Institute for Biogeochemistry.
This dataset contains 14 different features such as air temperature, atmospheric pressure, and humidity. These were collected every 10 minutes, beginning in 2003. For efficiency, you will use only the data collected between 2009 and 2016. This section of the dataset was prepared by François Chollet for his book Deep Learning with Python.

If it's good enough for Chollet, the guy behind Keras, it's good enough for me.
Finally the Statistics Engineering handbook &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.itl.nist.gov/div898/handbook/pmc/section4/pmc41.htm&gt;defines&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 time series as:

Definition of Time Series: An ordered sequence of values of a variable at equally spaced time intervals.

Which again conforms with what I seen in provided example.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='summa-code' date='2020-07-30T16:16:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/summa-code&gt;@summa-code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 As mentioned in the above comment, the dataset that has been used here is a timeseries dataset. I don't really see a problem in here.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='summa-code' date='2020-08-01T03:11:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jpodivin&gt;@jpodivin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ... I say WOW for the examples of the definition. Here is my point. I am not questioning about the DATA that is timeseries. But fortunately or unfortunately, they all fall under equi-distant timeseries... which in other words, simply a sequential data. But for the sack of the problem for "Time" series, the  presented seems to me simply for a sequential data, not taking TIME into consideration.
Anyhow, i am glad that Tensorflow team seems to have updated their Timeseries example. I have not gone through them fully. But i will in the coming days and see if it meets the criteria. Timeseries problems are not perfect, but i like to see some broader approach involving actual time.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='summa-code' date='2020-08-01T06:27:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/summa-code&gt;@summa-code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 As gowthamkpr said the data set is fine as it is. And I fail to see any point to prolonging this conversation.
I am glad that you found my examples, which were numerous and sourced, to be sufficient and well sourced.
If you have further issues with the documentation I can only recommend providing your own sources in the first place, it will help your argument since, all things taken into account, the burden of proof does rest on you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='summa-code' date='2020-08-02T18:23:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jpodivin&gt;@jpodivin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 My statements are very clear, there is no confusion. The DATA does have times, but they are periodic equidistant time. The solution presented was simply for a sequential data, does not include time. Think of IoT data that comes out based on random timed event, and they are not equidistant time. They can not be simply be considered as series, because they happen at random times, so they are Timed series than a simple series. But the new example that is published seems to consider time as a cyclical feature. I will go over them and see if it makes sense. I still think that Time should be considered as a linear increasing value than cyclical event.
I could not run the latest notebook. Not sure if they have tested these before publishing,
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41987&gt;#41987&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Filed a bug again, let me see if they fix this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='summa-code' date='2020-09-02T03:37:17Z'>
		And then i could not run on an IoT data that does not fit in memory. These need to be converted to tensor graphs. :-(
So i can only test with simple sample code with this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='summa-code' date='2020-11-19T15:24:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/summa-code&gt;@summa-code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
If the Data is huge, you can &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/tutorials/structured_data/time_series#4_create_tfdatadatasets&gt;Create_TF_Dataset&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Please let us know if you have any other concerns. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='summa-code' date='2020-11-26T14:02:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/summa-code&gt;@summa-code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Can you please respond to the above comment. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='summa-code' date='2020-12-03T14:51:04Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='summa-code' date='2020-12-03T16:44:02Z'>
		Definitions are context dependent. This usage is consistent with most common usage.
If you have variable timestep data you can just include the time deltas as a feature.
If your data doesn't fit in memory then you'll want to use &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/data&gt;tf.data&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
But anymore implementation questions should probably go on Stack Overflow. Github issues are for tracking problems in TensorFlow.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>