<bug id='41874' author='yixingfu' open_date='2020-07-29T20:52:18Z' closed_time='2020-08-12T18:19:03Z'>
	<summary>Keras ModelCheckpoint callback not raising exception when h5 save fails</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): Yes
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 2.3
Python version:3.6

Describe the current behavior
The callback conceals the exception thrown by save_model. The checkpoints are not saved but no error is reported.
Describe the expected behavior
The callback should re-throw the error after catching it.

Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate
the problem. If possible, please share a link to Colab/Jupyter/any notebook.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1Nq5ARA3BHTxUyguiFFBBH74tXC54MABB?usp=sharing&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1Nq5ARA3BHTxUyguiFFBBH74tXC54MABB?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Other info / logs Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to
diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full
traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yixingfu' date='2020-07-30T02:01:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yixingfu&gt;@yixingfu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The colab gist you shared cannot be opened due to permissions. Can you please save it as GitHub gist and share again? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yixingfu' date='2020-07-30T02:34:38Z'>
		Here is the gist
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/yixingfu/79e0693627c8e0aeaccaead6d4068cbf&gt;https://gist.github.com/yixingfu/79e0693627c8e0aeaccaead6d4068cbf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yixingfu' date='2020-08-03T17:17:41Z'>
		As per new tf-nightly version 2.4.0-dev20200803 the error is not raised while loading weights.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/gist/ymodak/a6e26acf6a1bfb3d2d042cac55a8b655/callback-exception.ipynb&gt;gist&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yixingfu' date='2020-08-04T15:38:56Z'>
		No it still raises error when loading weight. And this error comes from the checkpoint failing to save, which should actually raise an error.
I think I know where the error come from. I will open a PR to fix it soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yixingfu' date='2020-08-04T21:51:57Z'>
		You are right this works for tf format but not h5.
I forgot to reset the colab runtime while testing for different formats so didn't get any error.
Feel free to raise a PR and tag this issue thread. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='yixingfu' date='2020-08-12T18:19:04Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41874&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41874&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>