<bug id='41932' author='Sixaxis9' open_date='2020-07-31T10:09:10Z' closed_time='2020-08-05T23:07:45Z'>
	<summary>Only 1 subgraph is currently supported - CMSIS-NN</summary>
	<description>
@tensorflow/micro
System information
Host OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): make with Linux Ubuntu 20.04, complied on Atmel Studio on Windows 10, Python 3.7.7
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): downloaded from master
Tensorflow version (commit SHA if source): 2.3.0, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/e544dce3a3a43631811e0760db5c33fe0a7519ba&gt;e544dce&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Target platform (e.g. Arm Mbed OS, Arduino Nano 33 etc.): Atmel SAMD51 - Atmel Studio
Describe the problem
After some issue to link correctly the TFLite with cmsis-nn kernels files into my Atmel Studio project I have built a static library with Atmel Studio and linked the .a file. To do that I make the project with TAGS=cmsis-nn, copy the the files from a Keil project (I used the image recognition example) from the make directory and compile with Atmel Studio to get the .a file.
When I run inference compiling the C files (obtained without the cmsis-tag in the Tensorflow-Lite subdirectory of the image recognition example in the make folder) within the project everything works fine. When I run inference with the static library obtained from making with the cmsis-nn tag I get the following error: "Only 1 subgraph is currently supported. Exiting with status 1". The flatbuffer file is the same.

Please refere to this Colab to see the python code: &lt;denchmark-link:https://drive.google.com/file/d/1k-9Id6ljpf4EjlcYIy6D4-fAHwOg1hI-/view?usp=sharing&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1k-9Id6ljpf4EjlcYIy6D4-fAHwOg1hI-/view?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please refere there to see the trained models: &lt;denchmark-link:https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1hQgInGGy3A7EEOB0xZHw5CgheXp8nl_9?usp=sharing&gt;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1hQgInGGy3A7EEOB0xZHw5CgheXp8nl_9?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please refere there for the project (in the cmsis-nn brench): &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Sixaxis9/TFLite-SAMD51&gt;https://github.com/Sixaxis9/TFLite-SAMD51&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Replicating the issue: copying and pasting the flatbuffer inside a working project with the cmsis-nn version of TFLite, loading the model and running inference.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-08-03T11:49:52Z'>
		I get the same error, "Only 1 subgraph is currently supported. Exiting with status 1" when trying to implement RNNs.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/36688&gt;Issue: 36688&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-08-03T12:02:59Z'>
		Are you trying to implement it with CMSIS-NN or with the TF kernels? Are different subgraph visible via tools like Netron?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-08-05T23:07:37Z'>
		Update on the issue. I manage to solve the problem and to compile the C files within the uC project. I run the make with the TAGS=cmsis-nn and TARGET=sparkfun_edge (since my board has a Cortex M4-F, same as Sparkfun edge) and imported the folders "tensorflow" and "third_party" in the my project directory from the Kiel folder created by the makefile. After some dependancy fixing I successfully built the project.
I now have another problem, my output are constant zeros, but I'll open another issue for that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-08-05T23:07:47Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41932&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/41932&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-11-14T16:15:06Z'>
		
I get the same error, "Only 1 subgraph is currently supported. Exiting with status 1" when trying to implement RNNs.
Issue: 36688

bro did u find sloution
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Sixaxis9' date='2020-11-15T15:39:01Z'>
		Hi ossa77, are you having troubles with RNNs?
I might help on CNNs
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>