<bug id='42126' author='perone' open_date='2020-08-07T13:48:09Z' closed_time='2020-08-28T04:37:14Z'>
	<summary>Tensorflow getting stuck when running forward pass for a tf hub module</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): MacOS Catalina 10.15.6
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: N/A
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): pip install tensorflow
TensorFlow version (use command below): v2.3.0-rc2-23-gb36436b087 2.3.0
Python version: 3.6.4
Bazel version (if compiling from source): N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source): N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version: using on CPU
GPU model and memory: using on CPU

Describe the current behavior
Tensorflow get stuck, it hangs suddenly and intermittently
Describe the expected behavior
Tensorflow not getting stuck
Standalone code to reproduce the issue
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import tensorflow as tf
import tensorflow_hub as hub
import tensorflow_text

module = hub.load("https://tfhub.dev/google/universal-sentence-encoder-multilingual-qa/3")
for i in range(50):
    response_embeddings = module.signatures['response_encoder'](
        input=tf.constant(["I am happy", "I am not happy"]),
        context=tf.constant(["I am happy", "I am not happy"]))
    t = response_embeddings["outputs"].numpy()
    print(t.shape)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

If you repeat that last loop of 50 iterations like 3 times or something it will just get stuck and hang.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='perone' date='2020-08-10T03:52:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/perone&gt;@perone&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I have tried in colab with TF version 2.3 and i am not seeing any issue.Please, find the gist &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/gist/ravikyram/e563938fdcc37b888f45e4eb16b7273b/untitled.ipynb&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='perone' date='2020-08-12T15:06:07Z'>
		If it is working on Colab, it looks that it might be something related to environment or resources, since it is a big model, it might be memory management, are there any debugging flags I can enable to get more verbose info on what is going on ? I understand it doesn't reproduce on Colab, but that is like "works on my computer".
This is the log I get on the first run of the loop:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;2020-08-12 16:03:37.207634: I tensorflow/core/platform/cpu_feature_guard.cc:142] This TensorFlow binary is optimized with oneAPI Deep Neural Network Library (oneDNN)to use the following CPU instructions in performance-critical operations:  AVX2 FMA
To enable them in other operations, rebuild TensorFlow with the appropriate compiler flags.
2020-08-12 16:03:37.262803: I tensorflow/compiler/xla/service/service.cc:168] XLA service 0x7f854448af90 initialized for platform Host (this does not guarantee that XLA will be used). Devices:
2020-08-12 16:03:37.262836: I tensorflow/compiler/xla/service/service.cc:176]   StreamExecutor device (0): Host, Default Version
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

it allocates 922MB of memory, and then the process just get stuck (no CPU usage).
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='perone' date='2020-08-14T03:46:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/perone&gt;@perone&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Issues related to TensorFlow Hub are handled in the Hub repo. Please submit a new issue using &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/hub/issues/new&gt;this link&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and fill in the template, so that we can track it there. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='perone' date='2020-08-21T04:25:29Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='perone' date='2020-08-28T04:37:13Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='perone' date='2020-08-28T04:37:15Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/42126&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/42126&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>