<bug id='42287' author='yongwww' open_date='2020-08-12T21:58:05Z' closed_time='2020-08-27T12:25:45Z'>
	<summary>graph_util.remove_training_nodes removes library from graphdef</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our
GitHub Policy,
we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and
build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): no
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 16.04
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.15
Python version: 3.6
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version: only cpu
GPU model and memory: only on cpu

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with:

TF 1.0: python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
TF 2.0: python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.version.GIT_VERSION, tf.version.VERSION)"

Describe the current behavior
graph_util.remove_training_nodes will remove library from graphdef, which is needed for operator like StatefulPartitionedCall.
Describe the expected behavior
The library should not be removed when freezing graph.
Standalone code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate
the problem. If possible, please share a link to Colab/Jupyter/any notebook.
Other info / logs Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to
diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full
traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yongwww' date='2020-08-13T10:59:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yongwww&gt;@yongwww&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
In order to expedite the trouble-shooting process, could you please provide the complete code to reproduce the issue reported here.
Also, TensorFlow 1.x is not actively supported. Could you please update TensorFlow to v2.3 and check if you are facing the same issue? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yongwww' date='2020-08-20T11:27:37Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yongwww' date='2020-08-27T12:25:43Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yongwww' date='2020-08-27T12:25:46Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/42287&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/42287&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>