<bug id='43120' author='PEYMAN333' open_date='2020-09-10T18:42:02Z' closed_time='2020-09-12T11:31:07Z'>
	<summary>After several iterations the error:  "input and filter must have the same depth" is arose</summary>
	<description>
I am trying to fit my model by using a generator working on my dataset (audio files). I use a gold cluster (SLURM) to run my program including generator for creating my input features and corresponding targets (by using yeilding method, and safe threading), and fit_generator for training my model.
Unfortunetly, after 388 iterations including batches with 128 size, the error:
tensorflow.python.framework.errors_impl.InvalidArgumentError:  input and filter must have the same depth: 6 vs 18
[[node model_4/conv2d_80/BiasAdd (defined at /Project1/Training/Prog/preANDtrain_generator_model2.py:187) ]] [Op:__inference_train_function_9095]
Function call stack:
train_function
2020-09-10 17:09:40.560724: W tensorflow/core/kernels/data/generator_dataset_op.cc:103] Error occurred when finalizing GeneratorDataset iterator: Failed precondition: Python interpreter state is not initialized. The process may be terminated.
[[{{node PyFunc}}]]
was shown and my program was failed.
The depth (#channels) of the input features is 6 and the first layer is a covolutional layer with 18 channels (filters). I became confused why the error was shown after 388 iterations, and why the depth of input features and the first layer must be same.
I will be so grateful if someone can help me to solve the problem
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/files/5204020/New.Text.Document.txt&gt;New Text Document.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='PEYMAN333' date='2020-09-10T19:10:31Z'>
		Have you seen &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/59380430/how-to-use-model-fit-which-supports-generators-after-fit-generator-deprecation&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/59380430/how-to-use-model-fit-which-supports-generators-after-fit-generator-deprecation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
?
Please also fill the template issue and share a very, very minimal but runnable example or colab to reproduce this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='PEYMAN333' date='2020-09-10T22:23:31Z'>
		Thank you so much bhack for your answer.
I have just tried fit instead of fit_generator in my program, and the same error was shown at the same iteration (388).
It is really confusing that the error arises after several iterations.
I created a template for this issue and attached a very very minimal program and dataset: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PEYMAN333/relatedtoissue_43120&gt;relatedtoissue_43120&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PEYMAN333/relatedtoissue_43120&gt;https://github.com/PEYMAN333/relatedtoissue_43120&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thank you again for your help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='PEYMAN333' date='2020-09-12T11:30:45Z'>
		I performed line to line double checks, and found out that one line has unwanted TAB, in one of the functions of the generator. This could lead to a reduced dimension feature in audio files with small size. I edited and run again the program. Fortunately, the training phase passed the 388 iteration. However, I am still surprised for the strange shown error which may seem irrelevant! The "ValueError: Error when checking input: expected input_ to have * dimensions, but got array with shape (, ,)**" may be more relevant for this dimension mismatching.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='PEYMAN333' date='2020-09-12T11:31:08Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/43120&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/43120&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>