<bug id='43131' author='SungmanHong' open_date='2020-09-11T03:33:04Z' closed_time='2020-09-13T11:22:37Z'>
	<summary>Just Qustion: In Android JAVA, keras model is ok?</summary>
	<description>
Hi, I'm developing android app
and my NN in python is keras(Tf.keras) with LSTM, conv2d, resnet, attention (very deep)
I want to use this NN in JAVA.android

can I use TF-lite for my keras of python??

I heard TF.lite only support some TF model so I'm worried


and can I convert keras to tensorflow? and just use tensorflow in JAVA?


and can I convert keras to tensorflow? and just use tensorflow lite or tensorflow.mobile in JAVA?


Thx.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SungmanHong' date='2020-09-11T05:27:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SungmanHong&gt;@SungmanHong&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 As I understand you are talking about converting the Keras model to a TF Lite Model and then using that in your Android app. Tp convert your model to a  format I would recommend you to use the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/convert#convert_a_keras_model_&gt;TensorFlow Lite converter&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. To then use this model in your Android app you could very easily make use of &lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.android.com/studio/preview/features#tensor-flow-lite-models&gt;ML Model Binding plugin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with Android Studio (4.1 or above) which makes it easy for you to directly import  files and also generate easy-to-use classes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SungmanHong' date='2020-09-11T05:32:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Rishit-dagli&gt;@Rishit-dagli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Thanks a lot, In fact, so far, I've been trying to port the neural network on the Android app through Pythorch Mobile.
but now, latest pytorch and pytorch mobile are not compatible each other...;; &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pytorch/vision/issues/1943&gt;pytorch/vision#1943&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The App is just CRUSHED WHEN THE MODEL IS LOADED and others have experienced similar things.
I downgraded pytorch and seems its good and is compatible to pytorch.android module yet.
I hope TF and TFmobile is more stable and compatible than pytorch_mobile and pytorch android module.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SungmanHong' date='2020-09-12T12:33:35Z'>
		
@Rishit-dagli Thanks a lot, In fact, so far, I've been trying to port the neural network on the Android app through Pythorch Mobile.
but now, latest pytorch and pytorch mobile are not compatible each other...;; pytorch/vision#1943
The App is just CRUSHED WHEN THE MODEL IS LOADED and others have experienced similar things.
I downgraded pytorch and seems its good and is compatible to pytorch.android module yet.
I hope TF and TFmobile is more stable and compatible than pytorch_mobile and pytorch android module.

I personally have not worked with PyTorch Mobile so I wouldn't be able to compare them, but I have noticed that the TF Lite Android Support Library is pretty stable
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>