<bug id='4358' author='danijar' open_date='2016-09-13T17:59:22Z' closed_time='2016-09-19T23:37:37Z'>
	<summary>Wrong example script in the docs for preprocessing data</summary>
	<description>
I was reading the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r0.10/how_tos/reading_data/index.html#preprocessing&gt;docs for preprocessing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which is a small paragraph linking to the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r0.10/tensorflow/models/image/cifar10/cifar10.py&gt;CIFAR-10 network&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as an example. However, that script does not perform any preprocessing. Do we have a better example illustrating preprocessing steps like data normalization, distorting images, etc?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='danijar' date='2016-09-13T21:23:27Z'>
		This is a question better suited for StackOverflow. Please ask it there and tag it with the tensorflow tag."
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='danijar' date='2016-09-13T21:44:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/andydavis1&gt;@andydavis1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Are you sure? I'm mainly pointing at a "bug" in the docs. I'm not asking for anything, my question was just to suggest a way of improving the docs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='danijar' date='2016-09-13T21:58:14Z'>
		Ah ok. I took that last sentence you wrote " Do we have a better example illustrating preprocessing steps like data normalization, distorting images, etc?". As a general question.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='danijar' date='2016-09-15T17:06:39Z'>
		The folder holding the file referenced in the docs has, e.g. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r0.10/tensorflow/models/image/cifar10/cifar10_input.py&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r0.10/tensorflow/models/image/cifar10/cifar10_input.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which does contain a  routine, is this what you're looking for? If so, then the easiest fix is just to change the link in the docs to point to the cifar10_input.py file instead of the cifar10.py file that imports it (line 47)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='danijar' date='2016-09-15T20:37:31Z'>
		Thanks. Yes, I think that would be suitable. Do you want to create a pull request? Otherwise, I can do that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='danijar' date='2016-09-16T19:29:16Z'>
		You can go ahead.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>