<bug id='43886' author='marcospgp' open_date='2020-10-08T16:06:26Z' closed_time='2020-12-23T03:28:28Z'>
	<summary>Update Keras Conv2D layer docs to specify padding value</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;URL(s) with the issue:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://keras.io/api/layers/convolution_layers/convolution2d/&gt;https://keras.io/api/layers/convolution_layers/convolution2d/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description of issue (what needs changing):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Specify what value is added as padding when padding argument is set to same. Is it zero values?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='marcospgp' date='2020-10-14T08:32:38Z'>
		Yes in padding = "same" we add a n-pixel borders of zero to tell that don't reduce the dimension and have same dimension as input.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='marcospgp' date='2020-10-26T04:27:01Z'>
		Can I work on this issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Saduf2019&gt;@Saduf2019&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='marcospgp' date='2020-11-19T16:35:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcospgp&gt;@marcospgp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
The reason information about  with Zeroes is not mentioned either in &lt;denchmark-link:https://keras.io/api/layers/convolution_layers/convolution2d/&gt;Keras Conv2D&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or in &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/keras/layers/Conv2D&gt;TF Keras Conv2D&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is because it is an  of that  and the  will not be visible to us both in  or .
However, information about  is added via &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/40512&gt;this PR&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='marcospgp' date='2020-11-28T09:45:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcospgp&gt;@marcospgp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Can you please respond to the above comment. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='marcospgp' date='2020-11-28T10:34:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rmothukuru&gt;@rmothukuru&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't see why it being an internal operation means the user doesn't need to know what's going on, especially since it alters the final result.
If that PR adds the information to the docs then great!
Cheers and thanks for your hard work and care!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='marcospgp' date='2020-12-10T07:21:50Z'>
		
@marcospgp,
The reason information about Padding with Zeroes is not mentioned either in Keras Conv2D or in TF Keras Conv2D is because it is an Internal Operation on the Input of that Layer and the Padded Zeroes will not be visible to us both in Input or Output Tensors.
However, information about Padding is added via this PR.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcospgp&gt;@marcospgp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
I take back my comment that it is an internal operation. Yes, it impacts the result. Will update the documentation stating that .
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='marcospgp' date='2020-12-17T08:03:58Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>