<bug id='44044' author='tallamjr' open_date='2020-10-15T10:47:36Z' closed_time='2020-10-15T10:59:18Z'>
	<summary>[tinyML Book] `hello_world` example not running on Ardunio Nano 33 BLE</summary>
	<description>
@tensorflow/micro
System information

Host OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): masOS.Catalina.10.15.5
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
Tensorflow version (commit SHA if source):  2.1.0-ALPHA-precompiled
Target platform (e.g. Arm Mbed OS, Arduino Nano 33 etc.): Arduino Nano 33

Describe the problem
After following the book and the instructions in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://youtu.be/AfAyHheBk6Y?t=1671&gt;video screencast&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I am able to compile the program and apparently load it onto the board, but nothing seems to happen.
Then when I try to inspect the serial port logger, I am always faced with Board at /dev/cu.usbmodem14301 is not available and I am forced to reset the board and start again, but the same problem arises.
Please provide the exact sequence of commands/steps when you ran into the problem
For details, see below.
I face the same situation when I only use the code provided in the examples folder and when I modify it for my own model (following instructions in the book).

Open the Examples&gt;Arduino_TensorFlowLite&gt;hello_world example and upload gives this output:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Library Arduino_TensorFlowLite has been declared precompiled:
Using precompiled library in /Users/tallamjr/Documents/Arduino/libraries/Arduino_TensorFlowLite/src/cortex-m4/fpv4-sp-d16-softfp
Sketch uses 231536 bytes (23%) of program storage space. Maximum is 983040 bytes.
Global variables use 58272 bytes (22%) of dynamic memory, leaving 203872 bytes for local variables. Maximum is 262144 bytes.
Device       : nRF52840-QIAA
Version      : Arduino Bootloader (SAM-BA extended) 2.0 [Arduino:IKXYZ]
Address      : 0x0
Pages        : 256
Page Size    : 4096 bytes
Total Size   : 1024KB
Planes       : 1
Lock Regions : 0
Locked       : none
Security     : false
Erase flash

Done in 0.001 seconds
Write 231544 bytes to flash (57 pages)
[==============================] 100% (57/57 pages)
Done in 9.084 seconds
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This immediately seems fine, but I notice that the orange LED goes from slowly blinking (in a bootloader state) to a solid always on light.
I have tried to change the const int kInferencesPerCycle as I initially thought that I am just not able to see the flicker, but this did not alter the solid light.
I also get this same problem when running a modified model (using the steps in the book and this notebook: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/lite/micro/examples/hello_world/train/train_hello_world_model.ipynb&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/lite/micro/examples/hello_world/train/train_hello_world_model.ipynb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
Each time as well, when I try to inspect using the Serial Plotter, I get the following error in the console:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Board at /dev/cu.usbmodem14301 is not available
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Any help with this would be appreciated. I feel very stuck at the moment on what to try as it seems to compiling fine. Thanks
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tallamjr' date='2020-10-15T10:59:18Z'>
		This seems to be resolved now, I changed the library from 2.1.0-ALPHA-precompiled ---&gt; 2.1.0-ALPHA. I don't know why this specifically helps, but seems to have corrected the issue
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>