<bug id='44057' author='toddwasson' open_date='2020-10-15T18:07:32Z' closed_time='2020-10-19T16:31:14Z'>
	<summary>Embedding metadata is not read or displayed in TensorBoard 2.3.0</summary>
	<description>
Hello, I have trained a model (with TensorFlow 2.3.1) including embeddings via keras.layers.Embedding and prepared label files per embedding dictionary, which I point to via the embeddings_metadata parameter of keras.callbacks.TensorBoard.  TensorBoard executes and displays the various embedding vectors in the Projector without issue, but the embeddings are not labeled per the label files.  The label files are successfully created and stored in the log directory, and I can use them manually just fine via the Load button in the TensorBoard interface.
I debugged the projector_plugin.py code and determined that _get_metadata_file_for_tensor() is never called (verified via prints, debugging with pdb, etc.).  This method looks to be the only place in the code used to retrieve the metadata_path from which the labels would be read, and is apparently only accessed via the /metadata HTTP route.
Incidentally when I add the various Embedding layers in Keras, the first receives the tensor_name layer_with_weights-0/embeddings/.ATTRIBUTES/VARIABLE_VALUE but the subsequent ones are layer_with_weights-1, 2, etc.  I see the keras.callbacks.TensorBoard hard-codes them to layer_with_weights-0 but I think this is a separate issue as I have manually corrected the projector_config.pbtxt file and, as I mentioned above, the _get_metadata_file_for_tensor() method is never called anyway so they aren't even trying to be parsed and used to label tensors.
Any thoughts?  Am I missing something?
Thanks!
Todd
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-16T06:31:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/toddwasson&gt;@toddwasson&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This issue is more suitable for Tensorboard repo.Please post it on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/issues/new/choose&gt;Tensorboard repo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 from here. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-16T16:34:55Z'>
		Oops, that's what I was trying to accomplish -- thanks for pointing me in the right direction!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-16T17:41:26Z'>
		In case anyone comes looking in the future, I did create &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/issues/4246&gt;a TensorBoard repo issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-19T07:17:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/toddwasson&gt;@toddwasson&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Can we close the issue here and track the issue in Tensorboard repo issue you have created. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-19T16:31:14Z'>
		Yes, let's close it.  Thanks again for your help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='toddwasson' date='2020-10-19T16:31:16Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/44057&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/44057&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>