<bug id='44503' author='kaublezw' open_date='2020-11-01T17:22:52Z' closed_time='2020-11-04T16:41:16Z'>
	<summary>IOS: TensorFlow Lite Error: Didn't find op for builtin opcode 'RESIZE_BILINEAR' version '3'</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our
GitHub Policy,
we only address code/doc bugs, performance issues, feature requests and
build/installation issues on GitHub. tag:bug_template
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): No - It's the TensorFlow Lite IOS Object Detection example...I just tried to use my own converted Darknet Tiny Yolo v4 to TFLite
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):  NA
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device: IOS 13.7
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): I ran the POD install command on my mac
TensorFlow version (use command below): unknown...whatever POD install installed
Python version: NA
Bazel version (if compiling from source) NA:
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source) NA:
CUDA/cuDNN version: NA
GPU model and memory: NA

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;script&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also obtain the TensorFlow version with:

TF 1.0: python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
TF 2.0: python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.version.GIT_VERSION, tf.version.VERSION)"

Describe the current behavior
From XCODE -&gt; Play the solution to deploy to my IOS IPhone device.  Fails on the following line:
interpreter = try Interpretor(modelPath: modelPath, options: options)
Describe the expected behavior
I expected it to run the normal TFLite IOS object detection example program on my phone but with my model
Standalone code to reproduce the issue
Provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate
the problem. If possible, please share a link to Colab/Jupyter/any notebook.
Other info / logs Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to
diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full
traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-01T19:44:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kaublezw&gt;@kaublezw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Please share complete stand alone code for us to replicate the issue faced, and the tf version.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-02T13:28:21Z'>
		Here's the source code:  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kaublezw/tflite_ios_example/tree/main/ObjectDetection&gt;https://github.com/kaublezw/tflite_ios_example/tree/main/ObjectDetection&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It is the tensorflow lite object detection ios example program. All I did was change the labels to be my own and added my own model, yolo4-tiny-416.tflite.  It fails on line 110 in ModelDataHandler.swift when it tries to load the Interpreter.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-02T22:47:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kaublezw&gt;@kaublezw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you provide some more details on what error you see? Also, how did you obtain the yolo model? The example app supports models with a specific input/output signature, and possibly requires edits based on the input size &amp; quantization of the model.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-03T17:52:46Z'>
		I don't have any more details other than the error message that's in the title that was shown in xcode...  IOS: TensorFlow Lite Error: Didn't find op for builtin opcode 'RESIZE_BILINEAR' version '3'   The yolo v4 tiny model was trained via darknet installed on a Linux machine.  It was tested thoroughly.  I converted the yolo weights to tflite using this code: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hunglc007/tensorflow-yolov4-tflite/blob/master/save_model.py&gt;https://github.com/hunglc007/tensorflow-yolov4-tflite/blob/master/save_model.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I tested the tflite model and it worked nearly identical to the original yolo tiny model.   I would expect an input/output error to occur at the point when I actually call the model...not when I try to simply instantiate the model using the out-of-box tf lite sample program.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-03T17:57:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yyoon&gt;@yyoon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you take a look at this? Looks like the YOLO model requires ResizeBilinear v3 which was added in a more recent TFLite version. Is there some issue with the pod installed?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-03T20:59:53Z'>
		would it work if I tried training a yolo tiny v3 model and use that instead?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-04T01:41:22Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kaublezw&gt;@kaublezw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Based on the  file in your repository, seems like you are using TFLite version 2.1.0, which is not the most recent version. Can you try running  from your project directory and build the project again? This will update your TFLite dependency to 2.3.0.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/srjoglekar246&gt;@srjoglekar246&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you know which exact stable version is this op available? If this was not available in 2.1.0, I think a simple version update above would probably solve the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-04T13:19:46Z'>
		That did it.  Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-04T16:41:16Z'>
		Thanks for confirming &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kaublezw&gt;@kaublezw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 !
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='kaublezw' date='2020-11-04T16:41:18Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/44503&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/44503&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>