<bug id='45541' author='ando0689' open_date='2020-12-09T14:12:02Z' closed_time='2020-12-17T21:50:12Z'>
	<summary>Official Example For TensorFlow Lite Model Maker keeps crashing</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
No
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
Mac Book Pro 2017(2.3 GHz Dual-Core Intel Core i5, 8 GB 2133 MHz LPDDR3), MacOS Big Sur 11.0.1,
Browser: Version 87.0.4280.88 (Official Build) (x86_64),
but I guess the above info does not matter as I run the example in Google Colab here
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
No
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow is provided by Google Colab environment
TensorFlow version (use command below):
2.4.0-dev20200902
Python version:
Python 3.6.9
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
N/A
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
N/A
CUDA/cuDNN version:
nvcc: NVIDIA (R) Cuda compiler driver
Copyright (c) 2005-2019 NVIDIA Corporation
Built on Sun_Jul_28_19:07:16_PDT_2019
Cuda compilation tools, release 10.1, V10.1.243
GPU model and memory:
I cannot check this as I run the Colab provided in official Tensorflow page on the provided Google Colab Environment, which you can see in the following url: https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/tutorials/model_maker_question_answer

Describe the current behavior
When I try to run the officially provided Colab from TensorFlow Lite Model Maker Library for BERT Q&amp;A
not changing anything, everything goes fine until the training model = question_answer.create(train_data, model_spec=spec)
As soon as training process started, after a while it begins to consume memory with big chunks (e.g. memory consumption increases by 2GB per 2-3 seconds) and shortly it crashes the Colab telling "Your session crashed after using all available RAM". I think this is some sort of a bug, because otherwise this will not be an official example, or it would be documented somewhere in the example that the free Colab environment provided by Google with 16GB RAM is not enough to run this example.
I also tried to run the example with much smaller dataset, but the same problem in the same way is being reproduced. So I am almost sure that this is a bug in the library.
Describe the expected behavior
The example project provided in Official website of TensorFlow should run without any problem on the officially provided Colab Environment.

Please just go node by node through the official example &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/lite/tutorials/model_maker_question_answer&gt;in the following Colab&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with a basic free Colab plan, without changing anything in the example.
when you reach "Customize the TensorFlow Model" point, and run the following code  wait for 2-3 minutes, and you will get and error that Colab environment was crashed telling "Your session crashed after using all available RAM".

There is the logs that I get after running  in Colab just after the crash
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/ando0689/c67406e124ce8180935f36fe5e95e835&gt;https://gist.github.com/ando0689/c67406e124ce8180935f36fe5e95e835&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ando0689' date='2020-12-09T20:07:59Z'>
		The colab crashes on trying with a different model_spec as well.
spec = model_spec.get('bert_qa')
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ando0689' date='2020-12-11T07:52:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ando0689&gt;@ando0689&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you please try with model maker nightly package?
!pip install tflite-model-maker-nightly
The colab does not crash with the nightly package. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ando0689' date='2020-12-16T11:50:49Z'>
		Hi. Thank you very much.
This specific problem is resolved on nightly build, but overall the example is not working, I will post the issues here and if needed I will open a separate issue for this.
here are the issues:

When I do !pip install tflite-model-maker-nightly I see the following error in the log:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ERROR: tensorflow 2.3.0 has requirement h5py&lt;2.11.0,&gt;=2.10.0, but you'll have h5py 3.1.0 which is incompatible.
ERROR: tf-nightly 2.5.0.dev20201215 has requirement numpy~=1.19.2, but you'll have numpy 1.18.5 which is incompatible.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Though this does not stop the execution and I can continue.


When i try to use the created model with TensorFlow Lite Android v 2.3.0 I get the following error when I try to create interpreter with this model:
https://gist.github.com/ando0689/1874b6881dc7af3a31519e1bb2813386


And when I increase the version of TensorFlow Lite on Android to 0.0.0-nightly I get the following error when I try to do inference:
https://gist.github.com/ando0689/b25f00443249da833af08cb8a6235a95


Just a note: The provided dataset with 8000 entities seems to be too much for this example, as running on the free Colab, it takes about 6 hours, and usually fails with some error.. I was only able to train it by reducing the dataset to be 1000 entities, I guess it's enough for example.


Thank you in advance,
Please tell me if I need to create separate issue for this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ando0689' date='2020-12-17T21:50:12Z'>
		Thanks for your issue. Lets continue the discussion on your new thread. I will close this one.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ando0689' date='2020-12-17T21:50:14Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/45541&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/45541&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>