<bug id='45609' author='Arman-IMRSV' open_date='2020-12-11T19:06:12Z' closed_time='2020-12-28T14:34:01Z'>
	<summary>Tensorflow_datsaet api fails to cache my training data.</summary>
	<description>
System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Ubuntu 20
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 2.3.1
Python version: 3.7
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version:
GPU model and memory: V100 (16GB)


Here is the error I get:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/70702200/101952699-727d1080-3bcf-11eb-8aaf-cb55fe37bec4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The calling iterator did not fully read the dataset being cached. In order to avoid unexpected truncation of the dataset, the partially cached contents of the dataset will be discarded. This can happen if you have an input pipeline similar to dataset.cache().take(k).repeat(). You should use dataset.take(k).cache().repeat() instead.
Standalone code to reproduce the issue
I run a custom data loader:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;start_time = time.clock()

data_loader = None

if translation_direction in [Translation_Direction.English_to_Farsi,Translation_Direction.Farsi_to_English]:
    data_loader = Data_loader_persian(translation_direction, fa_vocab_size=12000, en_vocab_size=24000)
    
else:
    raise Exception("Requested Translation Direction is not supported!")
    
train_examples, val_examples, test_examples, dataset_size_dict, tokenizer = data_loader.run()

end_time = time.clock()
print(f"Execution time: {end_time - start_time} seconds.")
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Then I try to cache and prefetch the dataset:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;train_dataset = train_examples.cache()
train_dataset = train_dataset.padded_batch(global_batch_size)
train_dataset = train_dataset.prefetch(tf.data.experimental.AUTOTUNE)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Then when I try to read the dataset:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;for i,x in enumerate(train_examples):
    if i==5:
        break
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Here is when the error comes up! No matter how many times I try to read, every times it reads from file (no caching happens!)
Note: Screenshot of the profiling window is attaches. As could be seen, the program is HIGHLY input-bound.
I would appreciate if you have any idea. Thanks :)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Arman-IMRSV' date='2020-12-12T13:14:41Z'>
		It would be helpful if you could provide a standalone reproducible code example. Without being able to see custom components these things are hard to debug.
Also note that cache works at the second epoch of training. The data is read from disk (or cachefile, if specified), cached in your memory during the first epoch (provided your memory is large enough, otherwise the code will kill itself) and then read from memory from the second epoch onwards. This is at least the case for a "regular" dataset, where each datapoint is fed into the model once per epoch.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Arman-IMRSV' date='2020-12-14T13:29:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Arman-IMRSV&gt;@Arman-IMRSV&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I ran the code shared its incomplete , please share complete code or if possible share a  colab gist with the error reported.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Arman-IMRSV' date='2020-12-21T14:04:00Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Arman-IMRSV' date='2020-12-28T14:34:00Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please reopen if you'd like to work on this further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Arman-IMRSV' date='2020-12-28T14:34:02Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/45609&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/45609&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>