<bug id='4849' author='foxik' open_date='2016-10-09T07:53:01Z' closed_time='2016-10-15T07:55:41Z'>
	<summary>Method docs contain unclosed verbatim, which causes exceeding verbatim block in HTML docs</summary>
	<description>
The HTML docs for  at  &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/master/api_docs/python/state_ops.html#constant_initializer&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/master/api_docs/python/state_ops.html#constant_initializer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 contain unclosed verbatim block, which continues past the method and contains several following methods -- see for example the .
I am not much familiar with the process of documentation generation, but my guess is that the verbatim ending block at 


tensorflow/tensorflow/python/ops/init_ops.py


         Line 142
      in
      2c4af2e






     ``` 




 has wrong indentation (it is indented by two more spaces than the start of the block).
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='foxik' date='2016-10-13T01:59:27Z'>
		Thank you for reporting this. I've contacted just the right person who will be able to help out with this shortly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='foxik' date='2016-10-14T18:32:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it looks like the generated markdown is rendering fine on g3doc, so the website generator is doing something strange here.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='foxik' date='2016-10-14T20:04:37Z'>
		What are we using to generate the website? There are subtle differences between various Markdown implementations. Particularly when it comes to indentation. The solution could be as simple as decreasing the indent of that closing ``` by two spaces, as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/foxik&gt;@foxik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 suggests.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='foxik' date='2016-10-14T20:16:48Z'>
		The website generator uses the same markdown renderer that we use to view the doc internally, so the problem must be some extra pre- or post-processing the website generator is doing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='foxik' date='2016-10-15T07:55:40Z'>
		This was fixed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/8e63535abb29af6f62e65dab624f4a4d3f5581cc&gt;8e63535&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Push to web server is still pending.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>