<bug id='4998' author='3rd3' open_date='2016-10-16T20:27:02Z' closed_time='2017-09-15T21:02:09Z'>
	<summary>Please make the documentation headlines linkable/clickable</summary>
	<description>
That would make it easier to refer to particular parts/anchors in the documentation.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='3rd3' date='2016-10-17T04:05:44Z'>
		This is a terrific idea. Thank you for proposing it. Having anchor links that appear next to headers when you hover over them is a very common practice. Let's see what our documentation czar &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xmbrst&gt;@xmbrst&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thinks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='3rd3' date='2017-06-16T17:47:07Z'>
		This seems like a good idea that we haven't done even in the new docs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='3rd3' date='2017-06-19T19:47:12Z'>
		Sorry, what are we talking about here?  We provide header/subhead links, like this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/get_started#importing_tensorflow&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/get_started#importing_tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

All the links are available on the table of contents on the right.
Can you clarify which headers you want links to?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='3rd3' date='2017-06-19T20:42:31Z'>
		Indeed, the table of contents basically implements this feature. This issue remains a minor feature request that the headers which are already linkable via the table of contents should be wrapped in anchor elements to make them clickable. This is sometimes implemented by displaying a chain/link symbol  on the MouseOver event (e.g. in the &lt;denchmark-link:http://pytorch.org/docs/torch.html#torch.add&gt;PyTorch docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). That saves the step of scanning the table of contents for the particular section that one wants to link to.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='3rd3' date='2017-09-15T21:02:09Z'>
		I will suggest this to the team that manages our CMS, but unless they implement it, we are not going to do it given there's an immediate workaround.  I'm closing the bug against TensorFlow, with the caveat that I will file it against the CMS on another tracker.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>