<bug id='5381' author='TaihuaLi' open_date='2016-11-03T15:40:55Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T21:19:23Z'>
	<summary>Documentation For The New Version of Histogram on TensorBoard</summary>
	<description>
Hello~
I'm trying to interpret the new version of the histogram and it looks like the x-axis represents the value/bin, y-axis represent the step/time, and z-axis represents the density since it is a continuous number. In addition, the color represents the standard deviation??
Is my interpretation correct? If so, I can help putting up the documentation for the new histogram tab.
Thanks!
NOTE: Only file GitHub issues for bugs and feature requests.  All other topics will be closed.
For general support from the community, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
To make bugs and feature requests more easy to find and organize, we close issues that are deemed
out of scope for GitHub Issues and point people to StackOverflow.
For bugs or installation issues, please provide the following information.
The more information you provide, the more easily we will be able to offer
help and advice.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What related GitHub issues or StackOverflow threads have you found by searching the web for your problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Operating System:
Installed version of CUDA and cuDNN:
(please attach the output of ls -l /path/to/cuda/lib/libcud*):
If installed from binary pip package, provide:

A link to the pip package you installed:
The output from python -c "import tensorflow; print(tensorflow.__version__)".

If installed from source, provide

The commit hash (git rev-parse HEAD)
The output of bazel version

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;If possible, provide a minimal reproducible example (We usually don't have time to read hundreds of lines of your code)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What other attempted solutions have you tried?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Logs or other output that would be helpful&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(If logs are large, please upload as attachment or provide link).
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='TaihuaLi' date='2016-11-03T17:19:19Z'>
		Thanks @TalhuaLI. FYI, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danmane&gt;@danmane&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I assume documentation contributions are welcome.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='TaihuaLi' date='2016-11-03T22:57:48Z'>
		Yes, documentation contributions would be welcome. As you hypothesize, the axes are bin value, time in steps, and density. The color is actually just a function of which run it is from, and how far back in time it is.
I label the axes x for value, y for density, and z for time (since the oldest steps seem to recede backwards into the distance)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='TaihuaLi' date='2016-11-10T23:02:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/danmane&gt;@danmane&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Hi Daniel. Thank you for the clarification! I want to confirm one more thing before start writing the description. Is it accurate to state the density the "probability density"? Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='TaihuaLi' date='2016-11-11T03:05:39Z'>
		It's a normalized density. I wouldn't describe it as a probability density,
although I think calling it one would be justifiable.
On Thu, Nov 10, 2016 at 3:03 PM Taihua Li &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

@danmane https://github.com/danmane Hi Daniel. Thank you for the
clarification! I want to confirm one more thing before start writing the
description. Is it accurate to state the density the "probability density"?
Thanks!
—
You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
#5381 (comment),
or mute the thread
https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ABVc19_pwKMXm8rkU7OxJQZy0_m4syRwks5q86LUgaJpZM4KohSg
.

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='TaihuaLi' date='2017-04-28T17:56:42Z'>
		Did this get documented somewhere?  I'm trying to understand the tensorboard outputs in detail; a link at the end of this to where the updated docs are would be great. :D
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='TaihuaLi' date='2017-06-16T21:19:23Z'>
		Take a look here. &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/master/get_started/tensorboard_histograms&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/master/get_started/tensorboard_histograms&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Or in the README for the dashboard, seen here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/blob/master/tensorboard/plugins/histograms/README.md&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/blob/master/tensorboard/plugins/histograms/README.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>