<bug id='5446' author='JosiahKane' open_date='2016-11-07T10:56:04Z' closed_time='2017-06-14T02:38:26Z'>
	<summary>Bus error in quantized network on Android</summary>
	<description>
We have a tensorflow image processing network, which executes fine on osX, iOS and Android. Now that quantization has been pulled into core, we wanted to use it to optimize our install size on phones.
When we run the quantization process there are as expected small differences in the output on the Mac, but nothing that seems unreasonable. Further, when the quantized network is run on iOS it gives a warning that zero is outside the quantization range and it has to revert to a slow version to handle convolution padding. However it runs fine and the numbers are plausible.
On Android, however, and running with precisely the same code that worked perfectly with the unquantized version, it completely breaks. On one phone it gives outputs on the order of 1000 where we expect values on the order of 1. On another, probably the more reasonable, phone it just dies following a bus error. This has been true on the latest commits sampled over the last several days.
If it's relevant, the network was converted from a caffe predecessor using this tool: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ethereon/caffe-tensorflow&gt;https://github.com/ethereon/caffe-tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Regrettably I'm unable to upload the source code or network in question.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='JosiahKane' date='2016-11-07T19:06:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/petewarden&gt;@petewarden&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, do you have any thoughts on this or who can diagnose this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='JosiahKane' date='2016-11-07T19:29:24Z'>
		I just hit a similar "Bus error" problem with another model, so I'll take on debugging this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='JosiahKane' date='2016-11-08T19:17:34Z'>
		Hi there, I'm helping Pete with this bug. As a quick solution you can disable the new codepath, call:
tensorflow::meta::SetEnabled(false);
this will revert to Eigen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='JosiahKane' date='2016-11-08T20:28:02Z'>
		Or even better try building with: TENSORFLOW_DISABLE_META defined
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='JosiahKane' date='2017-06-14T02:07:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/petewarden&gt;@petewarden&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/maciekcc&gt;@maciekcc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, was there any resolution on this bug? Is it still reproducible and relevant?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='JosiahKane' date='2017-06-14T02:33:21Z'>
		IIRC this bug has been fixed in: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/38aec869681e0ac964e33bf44aef57016c5960c5&gt;38aec86&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>