<bug id='5667' author='Antonio95' open_date='2016-11-17T14:59:40Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T17:37:15Z'>
	<summary>Documentation shows None default instead of actual op attr default</summary>
	<description>
This is not a bug but a small mistake in the API:
The &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r0.11/api_docs/python/state_ops.html#assign&gt;documentation &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 says "use_locking" defaults to  in .
That parameter is a boolean, so  would not make a lot of sense. In any case, the source code makes it clear the default value is actually  (file: tensorflow/tensorflow/python/ops/variables.py)
I do not know if this is the case with other boolean default arguments in other functions, but I wanted to point it out.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-17T17:29:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Antonio95&gt;@Antonio95&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yep, this is a problem with our doc generator.  The place that correctly says  is a different thing: it's a convenience method of  that calls down to the underlying op.
This would be great to fix, but we may not get to it soon.  Contributions would be very welcome!
More background: this documentation is for a Python wrapper automatically generated based on the C++ op definition.  The Python wrappers use  as defaults.  Is there a good reason for that, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/josh11b&gt;@josh11b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (I vaguely recall having the discussion but don't remember the result)?  In any case, once the Python wrapper has a  default, the generated docs do too since they pull the defaults out of the Python function definition.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-17T19:45:37Z'>
		I'd be very happy to help (I'm writing my final degree project on TF (python API)), if you tell me how to get started.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-17T19:56:49Z'>
		Thank you!
How to proceed depends on whether &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/josh11b&gt;@josh11b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vrv&gt;@vrv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 think we should fix the Python wrapper generator or the doc generator.  Fixing the Python wrapper generator is more natural, but there may be a subtle reason for the s that I do not recall.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-17T19:59:13Z'>
		I was under the impression that there was an overhaul to our doc generation / website coming and that's why this wasn't being fixed ...  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-21T12:31:24Z'>
		As soon as you make a decision I'll be happy to try and learn how to solve the issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Antonio95' date='2016-11-23T18:52:44Z'>
		To re-iterate what girving@ said:

The documentation you link to does not come from tensorflow/python/ops/variables.py, but from the generated code (gen_state_ops.py, imported by tensorflow/python/ops/state_ops.py).
I'm a bit foggy on the specifics of why we did generated the code the way we did (the documentation just comes from the generated code), but I can hazard a few guesses:


It avoid duplicating the places where we specify the default, reducing friction if we ever want to change the default (especially since sometimes people copy-paste the generated code as a starting point for a wrapper around it).
We'd have to write code to render the default as legal Python in the generated code, which was extra code we didn't really need for anything else.
There is a gotcha if the default value is considered mutable by Python, see e.g.: http://docs.quantifiedcode.com/python-anti-patterns/correctness/mutable_default_value_as_argument.html

Instead we put the defaults in the doc string (search for the string "Defaults to").  We talked about various fixes (for example changing the rendering from "arg=None" to something else that indicates it is optional without specifying what the default is, perhaps "[arg]"), but no one solution made everybody happy so we left it as-is.  Another (tricky) possible solution: get the default out of the doc string, but that seems like it might be a bit fragile (e.g. could be disturbed by word wrapping, or a dot inside the default value).
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Antonio95' date='2017-06-16T17:37:15Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Since this issue is old at this point, please reopen the issue if it still occurs when tried with the latest version of Tensorflow. Thank you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>