<bug id='6108' author='html5cat' open_date='2016-12-06T02:38:42Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T19:32:35Z'>
	<summary>[TensorBoard] Charts in TensorBoard in Safari don't display correctly</summary>
	<description>
macOS Sierra, latest Safari (Version 10.0.1). Works good in Chrome.
Steps to repro:


Run https://github.com/openai/universe-starter-agent


Observe the following graphs:


&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/823890/20910888/30ec783a-bb19-11e6-8514-5c1027ca068a.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Console contains these errors:

&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/823890/20910904/4936486c-bb19-11e6-8032-417677a78d2e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='html5cat' date='2016-12-06T04:10:36Z'>
		Have you tried Firefox or Chrome in Mac? We first need to nail down whether it is the browser's problem or Tensorboard's web-script problem?
MacOS is known to cause problems because Apple developers are typically very ignorant of the conventional standards in HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP/TCPIP and etc.. Last time, I hosted some web service to do online text translation, it turns out that only for MacOS, if your URL query ends with a unicode character, then MacOS or Safari will append a NULL character, then that extraneous NULL character causes my program to function incorrectly. It is a shame that for such a big company, their engineers have actually made such a silly mistake! -:(
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='html5cat' date='2016-12-06T04:12:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xuancong84&gt;@xuancong84&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yeah, as per note above, works good in Chrome.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='html5cat' date='2016-12-06T04:16:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/html5cat&gt;@html5cat&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Then how about Firefox? Firefox is the best explorer in the current state-of-the-art.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='html5cat' date='2016-12-06T06:42:19Z'>
		Don't have it, sorry. Safari has big enough audience - mobile and default on all Macs.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


 On Dec 5, 2016, at 8:17 PM, xuancong84 ***@***.***&gt; wrote:

 @html5cat Then how about Firefox? Firefox is the best explorer in the current state-of-the-art.

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub, or mute the thread.



		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='html5cat' date='2017-03-15T02:01:11Z'>
		We're currently committed to keeping it working on Chrome and Firefox. Open source contributors are welcome to fix it for safari.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='html5cat' date='2017-06-16T19:32:35Z'>
		I'm going to close this for now. If you have a fix, please feel free to submit it to our new repository at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/pulls&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/pulls&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>