<bug id='6313' author='werner-rammer' open_date='2016-12-14T13:04:06Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T19:23:00Z'>
	<summary>Tensorboard has wrong logdir on Windows</summary>
	<description>
I use Tensorflow 0.12rc1 on Windows. "Tensorboard" has problems parsing the logdir. My log-directory is at E:\tmp\tflogs. When I start tensorboard from the windows shell (cmd.exe) with:
tensorboard --logdir=E:\tmp\tflogs
it depends on the current directory / drive if it works or not (i.e., if tensorboard finds the runs and shows the data). If the current directory is, e.g., on the C:\ drive, tensorboard tries to add runs from c:\tmp\tflogs instead of E:\tmp\tflogs.
Example:
C:\Users\wrammer&gt;tensorboard --logdir=E:\tmp\tflearn_logs --debug
The log contains lines such as:
INFO:tensorflow:Starting AddRunsFromDirectory: C:\tmp\tflearn_logs
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='werner-rammer' date='2016-12-14T23:04:18Z'>
		I think this is caused by the TensorBoard &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/dbe5e17e2ed307e86e1a6e79e558ec3e335d46fc/tensorflow/tensorboard/tensorboard.py#L36&gt;syntax for the --logdir flag&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
:

logdir specifies the directory where TensorBoard will look to find TensorFlow event files that it can display. TensorBoard will recursively walk the directory structure rooted at logdir, looking for .*tfevents.* files.
You may also pass a comma separated list of log directories, and TensorBoard will watch each directory. You can also assign names to individual log directories by putting a colon between the name and the path, as in
tensorboard --logdir=name1:/path/to/logs/1,name2:/path/to/logs/2


...which clearly doesn't play well with Windows paths with colons :).
I'll defer to the TensorBoard team about how they'd like to handle this. One workaround could be to use file:/// URIs instead of paths, where we could add support for | in place of : in Windows filenames. (You might also be able to use an "administrative share" \\MachineName\e$\tmp\tflogs if your machine is configured to allow that.)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='werner-rammer' date='2016-12-15T21:09:53Z'>
		Yes this is something we should fix. But it might not be necessary to change the syntax. It might be possible to say, ok, this is a single letter followed by :\, it's probably not a label.
As a workaround, are you able to say --logdir=foo:E:\tmp\tflogs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-01-09T12:44:20Z'>
		I had the same problem and can confirm that --logdir foo:D:\some\path does indeed work on windows with tensorflow 0.12 while --logdir D:\some\path does not.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-02-15T14:55:00Z'>
		I had the same problem with tensorflow 0.12.1. Thanks to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kvothe&gt;@kvothe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it now works for me by adding a name before E:\some\path
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-05-06T20:53:41Z'>
		The solution of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kvothe&gt;@kvothe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 also works for tensorflow 1.0.1 (on Windows 10)
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-06-16T19:23:00Z'>
		I migrated this issue to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/issues/54&gt;tensorflow/tensorboard#54&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 because TensorBoard has moved to a new repository. Lets continue discussion on this bug there.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-09-20T13:36:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiyuan312986471&gt;@jiyuan312986471&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ， what did you add before path？ I came into the same problem, would you like to share your solution?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='werner-rammer' date='2017-09-20T20:04:51Z'>
		See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dandelion&gt;@dandelion&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's comment here for a solution - let me know if that works: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/issues/52&gt;tensorflow/tensorboard#52&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Specifically, the colon in the directory path is problematic, so try relative paths. You could also always specify a run in the logdir argument.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>