<bug id='7741' author='MarvinTeichmann' open_date='2017-02-21T15:20:40Z' closed_time='2017-05-02T02:58:10Z'>
	<summary>The function 'layers/convolutional.py` does not follow `tf.GraphKeys` convention</summary>
	<description>
In &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/python/layers/convolutional.py&gt;convolutional.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 bias and weight variables are created and named  and . However according to the conventions defined in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/g3doc/api_docs/python/functions_and_classes/shard8/tf.GraphKeys.md&gt;tf.GraphKeys.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 those variables should be named   and  and assigned the corresponding collections. There is some (third party) functionality which utilizes this convention, including .
In addition, the names to be used are also stored in the constants tf.GraphKeys.WEIGHTS and tf.GraphKeys.BIASES. So instead of writing the strings hard in the code, I would suggest utilizing those constants. Do you agree with that? I am happy to submit a pull request solving this issue, if desired.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MarvinTeichmann' date='2017-02-22T02:00:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/fchollet&gt;@fchollet&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: Is a PR welcome?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MarvinTeichmann' date='2017-02-22T02:08:26Z'>
		No, the proper convention is kernel and bias, which is used throughout core layers. This has been extensively discussed internally.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MarvinTeichmann' date='2017-02-22T10:36:27Z'>
		ok, you are right. From what I understand by now the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/g3doc/api_docs/python/functions_and_classes/shard8/tf.GraphKeys.md&gt;tf.GraphKeys.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 conventions are not about the names of Variabels but collections those Variabels should be added.
So  the following lines should be in there:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    tf.add_to_collection(tf.GraphKeys.WEIGHTS, self.kernel)
    tf.add_to_collection(tf.GraphKeys.BIASES,  self.bias)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I am happy to put this into a pull request.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MarvinTeichmann' date='2017-04-28T20:37:17Z'>
		These keys are almost never used.
The only layer that uses them is:  "contrib.layers.legacy_fully_connected".
(Then a few things in contrib.layers, book-keeping ops and apply_regularization, read them. They're also mentioned in the contrib/layers/README.md)
There is no way to automatically fill these collections, like is done for GraphKeys.TRAINABLE_VARIABLES.
For it to actually work, and make tf.contrib.layers.apply_regularization work as you would expect, it would need to be set everywhere, not just in convolutional.
So I don't think just fixing convolutional.py is the right choice.
Currently the core tf.layers is not using them so that may be a clue that they are not part of the future.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>