<bug id='7824' author='apiszcz' open_date='2017-02-23T18:41:58Z' closed_time='2017-02-25T01:10:19Z'>
	<summary>Primary install page returning 404 https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/os_setup</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/os_setup&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/os_setup&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


That's an error.

The requested URL was not found on this server.
That's all we know.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='apiszcz' date='2017-02-25T01:10:19Z'>
		Hey, I'm assuming you got to that page through a Google search, or a link from elsewhere, not through navigation on the Tensorflow site itself, right?
We've been redoing a lot of the site structure for tensorflow.org and haven't propagated all of it out to github quite yet, but the entire installing section of getting started -- covered in the os_setup doc -- is now here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install/&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I'll put in a redirect for that particular file though, since we didn't catch it before, so it should go to the proper place instead of a 404 for you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='apiszcz' date='2017-02-25T18:34:19Z'>
		Correct, the page was a google search result. Thank you.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Fri, Feb 24, 2017 at 8:11 PM, Deanna Rubin ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Hey, I'm assuming you got to that page through a Google search, or a link
 from elsewhere, not through navigation on the Tensorflow site itself, right?

 We've been redoing a lot of the site structure for tensorflow.org and
 haven't propagated all of it out to github quite yet, but the entire
 installing section of getting started -- covered in the os_setup doc -- is
 now here:

 https://www.tensorflow.org/install/

 I'll put in a redirect for that particular file though, since we didn't
 catch it before, so it should go to the proper place instead of a 404 for
 you.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#7824 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ABXVTazlt0FIx-xMN1cqfJzsvwvtf0qyks5rf3_JgaJpZM4MKV0F&gt;
 .



		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>