<bug id='8064' author='christopherhesse' open_date='2017-03-03T21:05:49Z' closed_time='2017-05-01T16:22:27Z'>
	<summary>Missing images in docs</summary>
	<description>
The page &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/gather&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/gather&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 has a broken link to an image: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/images/Gather.png&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/images/Gather.png&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/scatter_add&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/scatter_add&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 also has a broken link &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/images/ScatterAdd.png&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/images/ScatterAdd.png&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

In addition, the images seem to be missing from the tensorflow repo.  Could those be put in there? It is hard to build the docs locally for offline use without the images.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='christopherhesse' date='2017-03-04T01:00:20Z'>
		It looks like those images were deleted from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/9c3043ff3bf31a6a81810b4ce9e87ef936f1f529/tensorflow/g3doc/api_docs/images&gt;this folder&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/854f49bd43588c062b046384f239f64a3d819702&gt;this commit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  It looks like those images should be restored to a new tensorflow/docs_src/api_guides/images folder (or, since the URL is being resolved from documentation that is generated from the source code, maybe it should be in a new tensorflow/docs_src/images folder), and the links in the source code documentation need to be changed (e.g., for the ScatterAdd.png image, the image source in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/core/ops/state_ops.cc#L289&gt;this line&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would need to be changed to the correct link.)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='christopherhesse' date='2017-03-04T02:59:48Z'>
		Thanks for filing the issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/christopherhesse&gt;@christopherhesse&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Assigning to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dr4b&gt;@dr4b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='christopherhesse' date='2017-03-05T04:46:50Z'>
		The images will likely never get uploaded to GitHub.  The best solution, which does not have a timeline, would be to replace the image links in the GitHub mark down to point to tensorflow.org.  It might be more work than you want to do, but you could try to script it yourself.  Putting the images in GitHub bloats the repo, or so I am told.   Image links should never break over a line due to internal style guides, so a simple find replace might cover a large percent of the situation.  Our publishing process is a big convoluted due to a desire to accept community contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='christopherhesse' date='2017-04-13T21:13:05Z'>
		We should restore the images in our internal image repo and fix those links to point to /images.  We need to fix this internally, so I will take this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>