<bug id='8507' author='ppwwyyxx' open_date='2017-03-17T19:04:29Z' closed_time='2017-03-24T14:03:16Z'>
	<summary>LocalCLIDebugWrapperSession hides exception messages</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Operating System: osx
Installed version of CUDA and cuDNN: no
If installed from binary pip package, provide:

A link to the pip package you installed: nightly, python3, today
The output from python -c "import tensorflow; print(tensorflow.__version__)":1.0.1

import tensorflow as tf
with tf.device('/gpu:0'):
    x = tf.get_variable('W', shape=[10])

sess = tf.Session()
from tensorflow.python import debug as tf_debug
sess = tf_debug.LocalCLIDebugWrapperSession(sess)
sess.run(tf.global_variables_initializer())
My machine doesn't have GPU, and the above code throws:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;OSError: Dump root directory /var/folders/3t/1kq225bs04j3k_2rbdcn2g34g86_w8/T/tfdbg_fw0uylcr does not exist
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

But it should throw the device error, like when debug session is not used:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Cannot assign a device to node 'W': Could not satisfy explicit device specification '/device:GPU:0' because no devices matching that specification are registered in this process; available devices: /job:localhost/replica:0/task:0/cpu:0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ppwwyyxx' date='2017-03-17T21:18:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ppwwyyxx&gt;@ppwwyyxx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you very much for reporting this issue. I'll take a look at it soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ppwwyyxx' date='2017-03-20T20:17:39Z'>
		Update: the underlying cause of this bug is that LocalCLIDebugWrapper attempts to intercept OpErrors that happen during the underlying tf.Session.run() calls. It works if the OpError happens in the middle of a graph execution, which will generate the debug dump directory. But in this case, the OpError (due to invalid device name) happens before the graph execution even happens, so there is no debug dump directory and LocalCLIDebugWrapper generates an error message that masks the original exception. I will push a fix to this issue soon.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>