<bug id='8556' author='jsimpson2' open_date='2017-03-20T13:48:28Z' closed_time='2017-03-21T22:11:22Z'>
	<summary>Tenor flow distributed support for spectrum lsf</summary>
	<description>
NOTE: Only file GitHub issues for bugs and feature requests.  All other topics will be closed.
For general support from the community, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
To make bugs and feature requests more easy to find and organize, we close issues that are deemed
out of scope for GitHub Issues and point people to StackOverflow.
For bugs or installation issues, please provide the following information.
The more information you provide, the more easily we will be able to offer
help and advice.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What related GitHub issues or StackOverflow threads have you found by searching the web for your problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Operating System:
Installed version of CUDA and cuDNN:
(please attach the output of ls -l /path/to/cuda/lib/libcud*):
If installed from binary pip package, provide:

A link to the pip package you installed:
The output from python -c "import tensorflow; print(tensorflow.__version__)".

If installed from source, provide

The commit hash (git rev-parse HEAD)
The output of bazel version

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;If possible, provide a minimal reproducible example (We usually don't have time to read hundreds of lines of your code)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What other attempted solutions have you tried?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Logs or other output that would be helpful&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(If logs are large, please upload as attachment or provide link).
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jsimpson2' date='2017-03-20T13:51:08Z'>
		We are getting benchmark requests for tens or flow in a distributed environment. Spectrum lsf is our scheduler and tens or flow and all distributed powerai applications need to run in this environment.
Documentation on how to run with spectrum lsf should be included.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jsimpson2' date='2017-03-21T22:12:56Z'>
		LSF is not a workflow that we have knowledge or support of. However, the first google search result for "tensor lsf" links to this stackoverflow which has a link to blog entry that is helpful for setting it up.
&lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/41220475/tensorflow-lsf-distributed-tensorflow-on-lsf-cluster&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/41220475/tensorflow-lsf-distributed-tensorflow-on-lsf-cluster&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>