<bug id='9526' author='tomwanzek' open_date='2017-04-28T23:02:51Z' closed_time='2018-01-02T22:43:50Z'>
	<summary>[Tutorial Update] Logging and Monitoring Basics</summary>
	<description>
Please go to Stack Overflow for help and support:
&lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If you open a GitHub issue, here is our policy:

It must be a bug or a feature request.
The form below must be filled out.

Here's why we have that policy: TensorFlow developers respond to issues. We want to focus on work that benefits the whole community, e.g., fixing bugs and adding features. Support only helps individuals. GitHub also notifies thousands of people when issues are filed. We want them to see you communicating an interesting problem, rather than being redirected to Stack Overflow.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

TensorFlow 1.1
n/a as purely documentation related
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The currently published tutorial for &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/monitors&gt;Logging and Monitoring&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is based on functionality that has been identified as  (see i.p. the discussion in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/7669&gt;#7669&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 .)
I truly appreciate all the hard work 💯  put into moving the functionality of TF itself forward.
It would be most appreciated, if this tutorial could be updated to reflect suggested best practices when using sessionRunHook et al. to ease adoptabilty of TF.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

n/a
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-04-28T23:40:31Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Seems like a reasonable request.  Assigning to you for learn triage.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-05-01T19:17:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ispirmustafa&gt;@ispirmustafa&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I forget the last state of the Hooks tutorial. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sandersk&gt;@sandersk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, were you, or did you, already sign up to do this?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dr4b&gt;@dr4b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 FYI for docs planning.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-06-05T13:20:58Z'>
		Any update on this? Thx in advance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-06-08T15:58:25Z'>
		We're working on a docs update that does include a rewrite of this tutorial. It's not done yet.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-06-14T06:11:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jugglerix&gt;@jugglerix&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 feel free to close once the new Programmer's Guide section is up.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-06-15T16:10:07Z'>
		The current goal is to release the new Programmer's Guide in July.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-07-21T20:08:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jugglerix&gt;@jugglerix&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Is there an updated ETA for the new Programmer's Guide? Thx in advance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-07-21T20:18:09Z'>
		The new Programmer's Guide will go out with V1.3.  However, we may add a
few additional chapters after 1.3 is released.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Fri, Jul 21, 2017 at 4:10 PM, Tom Wanzek ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 @jugglerix &lt;https://github.com/jugglerix&gt; Is there an updated ETA for the
 new Programmer's Guide? Thx in advance.

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#9526 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AVnLsKLeNW9rEZZcOUe9pXjAP-qYWJDtks5sQQXAgaJpZM4NMDdJ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-09-07T15:20:23Z'>
		Is there an update on the timing for this issue's resolution?
And a slightly more general contextual question, Is there a tracking reference to see which parts of the Programmer's Guide/Tutorials are current with Release 1.3 or still awaiting update as per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jugglerix&gt;@jugglerix&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 above comment?
As always, thanks for the hard work!
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='tomwanzek' date='2017-12-22T07:32:24Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='tomwanzek' date='2018-01-02T18:30:30Z'>
		A few notes:

The "Logging and Monitoring Basics with tf.contrib.learn" document was removed from tensorflow.org.
The tutorial entitled "A Guide to TF Layers: Building a Convolutional Neural Network" demonstrates how to use SessionRunHook to set up logging during training.

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>