<bug id='9560' author='korepwx' open_date='2017-05-01T03:54:08Z' closed_time='2018-01-24T16:05:58Z'>
	<summary>tf.pow(x, y) will freeze for negative integer y</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow): yes
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Windows 10, and macOS 10.12.4
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary): binary
TensorFlow version (use command below): 1.1.0 on both operation systems
Bazel version (if compiling from source): not compiled from source
CUDA/cuDNN version: CPU only on Windows, while CUDA 8.0 on macOS
GPU model and memory: Nvidia Titan X, 12GB
Exact command to reproduce: a short piece of Python code
Python version: 3.5.2 (Anaconda) on Windows, 3.6.0 (Anaconda) on macOS

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

tf.pow(x, y) will freeze for negative integer y (and of course, integer x).  It will not freeze for negative floating number y.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

import tensorflow as tf

with tf.Graph().as_default(), tf.Session().as_default():
    print(tf.pow(5, -2).eval())  # this will not stop
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='korepwx' date='2017-05-01T04:48:05Z'>
		I've confirmed and reproduced this, thanks for reporting.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='korepwx' date='2017-09-17T18:09:11Z'>
		I think this issue is related to issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/12156&gt;#12156&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Also related to PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/11852&gt;#11852&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='korepwx' date='2017-09-21T20:53:08Z'>
		I've looked in the source code and the origin of this bug is in Eigen, specifically src/Core/MathFunctions.h. They specialize their template for pow to the case of both parameters integers, and provide an implementation which only works for positive y. The problem is the well-known bug-loop of shifting y to the left: if y &lt; 0, then the bit sign extends and it continues indefinitely.
Here is the code from Eigen:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;template&lt;typename ScalarX,typename ScalarY&gt;
struct pow_impl&lt;ScalarX,ScalarY, true&gt;
{
  typedef ScalarX result_type;
  static EIGEN_DEVICE_FUNC inline ScalarX run(ScalarX x, ScalarY y)
  {
    ScalarX res(1);
    eigen_assert(!NumTraits&lt;ScalarY&gt;::IsSigned || y &gt;= 0);
    if(y &amp; 1) res *= x;
    y &gt;&gt;= 1;
    while(y)
    {
      x *= x;
      if(y&amp;1) res *= x;
      y &gt;&gt;= 1;
    }
    return res;
  }
};
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

However, it would be difficult to fix this: the template specifically requests that the return type is Scalar, and not Real, and changing this in Eigen might break things for other people.
What I could do, would be to change pow in cwise_ops.h in tensorflow/core to fix this bug. But then again, tf.pow would start returning float for integers inputs. Is this acceptable? I don't see any way to fix the bug without accepting that tf.pow should also return float for integer inputs.
If you agree with this change, I can fix the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='korepwx' date='2017-12-22T07:31:36Z'>
		It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee.Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='korepwx' date='2018-01-05T19:06:38Z'>
		Nagging Assigneee: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='korepwx' date='2018-01-05T20:30:46Z'>
		PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/15607&gt;#15607&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is pending review. There are discussions about fixing it in Eigen vs. TensorFlow. Will take a look at Eigen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='korepwx' date='2018-01-24T13:22:55Z'>
		Nagging Assignee: It has been 14 days with no activity and this issue has an assignee. Please update the label and/or status accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='korepwx' date='2018-01-24T16:05:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/korepwx&gt;@korepwx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I think the issue is addressed in PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/pull/15607&gt;#15607&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and this issues could be closed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>