<bug id='9597' author='kemaswill' open_date='2017-05-02T15:31:20Z' closed_time='2017-05-03T01:01:26Z'>
	<summary>Invalid link in https://www.tensorflow.org/deploy/distributed</summary>
	<description>
Seems that the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r1.1/tensorflow_models/tutorials/image/cifar10/cifar10_multi_gpu_train.py&gt;CIFAR-10 multi-GPU trainer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 link in &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/deploy/distributed&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/deploy/distributed&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is broken. Actually this code only exists &lt;= r0.12. There is three ways to fix it:

Use an old version such as  CIFAR-10 multi-GPU trainer
Remove this link in the doc page
Create a new cifar10_multi_gpu_train.py file for r1.1

I can work on this issue, is there any suggestions on which way to go?
Please go to Stack Overflow for help and support:
&lt;denchmark-link:http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If you open a GitHub issue, here is our policy:

It must be a bug or a feature request.
The form below must be filled out.

Here's why we have that policy: TensorFlow developers respond to issues. We want to focus on work that benefits the whole community, e.g., fixing bugs and adding features. Support only helps individuals. GitHub also notifies thousands of people when issues are filed. We want them to see you communicating an interesting problem, rather than being redirected to Stack Overflow.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
TensorFlow version (use command below):
Bazel version (if compiling from source):
CUDA/cuDNN version:
GPU model and memory:
Exact command to reproduce:

You can collect some of this information using our environment capture script:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/tree/master/tools/tf_env_collect.sh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can obtain the TensorFlow version with
python -c "import tensorflow as tf; print(tf.GIT_VERSION, tf.VERSION)"
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Describe the problem clearly here. Be sure to convey here why it's a bug in TensorFlow or a feature request.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Include any logs or source code that would be helpful to diagnose the problem. If including tracebacks, please include the full traceback. Large logs and files should be attached. Try to provide a reproducible test case that is the bare minimum necessary to generate the problem.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kemaswill' date='2017-05-02T20:41:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wolffg&gt;@wolffg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you comment or further triage this issue? Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kemaswill' date='2017-05-03T01:01:10Z'>
		Actually I found that this issue has already been fix by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/commit/0c08c585591152046ca1e6781d1f2fa573427dfc&gt;this commit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, seems that the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is not updated yet, will close this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>