<bug id='9827' author='ddurham2' open_date='2017-05-11T05:16:44Z' closed_time='2017-12-18T21:52:45Z'>
	<summary>tf.abs() isn't documented to handle complex, but it does appear to work as tf.complex_abs() used to.</summary>
	<description>
Issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/7405&gt;#7405&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 was a bug filed that tf.complex_abs() was removed in 1.0.  At the bottom it says that tf.abs() now does that work, but the docs for tf.abs() only mention float.  I confirmed that tf.abs() does in fact do as the comment on the issue describes (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r1.1/tensorflow/python/ops/math_ops.py#L225&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/r1.1/tensorflow/python/ops/math_ops.py#L225&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
Please incorporate the info from &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r0.11/api_docs/python/math_ops/complex_number_functions#complex_abs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/versions/r0.11/api_docs/python/math_ops/complex_number_functions#complex_abs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

into
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/abs&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/api_docs/python/tf/abs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

... specifically the parts about it computing sqrt(a^2 + b^2) for complex numbers.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ddurham2' date='2017-05-11T20:16:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rmlarsen&gt;@rmlarsen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you mind fixing this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ddurham2' date='2017-05-12T03:51:18Z'>
		BTW- I would be happy to regularly make PRs for various documentation fixes.  However, I'm a little confused by the code.  I can grep for some of the descriptions to find current docs in the code, but I find that there is quite a bit of duplicate documentation.   Is this because there is separate documentation for the C++ and python code?
Since I assume you want the same behavior in both, could this be changed to use \copydoc from doxygen to avoid having to put the docs in two places?
Otherwise, If I were to make a change, do I change all the places or is some of it generated and I only need to change one?
So that I can be a contributing citizen, generally, what is the rule for where to change things when fixing documentation?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ddurham2' date='2017-05-12T15:42:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ddurham2&gt;@ddurham2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinwicke&gt;@martinwicke&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
): I don't think we have a good story for avoid code duplication between C++ and Python for ops with wrappers.  In this case (and many others) I don't think there's a good substitute for a human merging the docs, since they're different ops at the C++ level (though they probably shouldn't be).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ddurham2&gt;@ddurham2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Did I interpret correctly that you're volunteering to send a PR?  If so, thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ddurham2' date='2017-05-14T00:44:30Z'>
		Sure.. I'll give it a whirl. Could you give me a pointer on how to build and view the documentation (HTML or otherwise) to make sure my changes would look presentable?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ddurham2' date='2017-05-14T03:24:28Z'>
		The documentation on documentation is here. If you have questions or if something doesn't work as expected, please ask. Note that the doc generator currently only works for Python 2.7.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/docs_src/community/documentation.md&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/blob/master/tensorflow/docs_src/community/documentation.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>