<bug id='9854' author='DarrellThomas' open_date='2017-05-12T07:37:09Z' closed_time='2017-06-16T19:18:20Z'>
	<summary>TensorBoard --logdir=c:\foo support</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;



Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow):
no.  I am working with the full example to get the tensorboard to work.  I changed the file directory for the logs into something on my system:
train_writer = tf.summary.FileWriter('D:/logs_dt' + '/train', sess.graph)
test_writer = tf.summary.FileWriter('D:/logs_dt' + '/test') 


OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):
Window 10


TensorFlow installed from (source or binary):
binary with GPU


TensorFlow version (use command below):
1.1.0


Bazel version (if compiling from source):
n/a


CUDA/cuDNN version:
CUDA 8.0
cuDNN v5 for CUDA 8.0 (27 May 2016)


GPU model and memory:
NVIDIA GTX 1070 4GB


Exact command to reproduce:
from windows cmd:
tensorboard --logdir='D:\logs_dt'


You can collect some of this information using our environment capture script:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/files/995339/tf_env.txt&gt;tf_env.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

python
1.1.0
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm not seeing anything on the tensorboard at all.  I can see where the log director(ies) is/are created by the tutorial script, and the subdirectories /test and /train are there with the event data present.  I point the tensorboard to the populated log directory with the following command,  but it cannot see the event files.  Nothing is present in tensorboard, and I'm redirected back to the tutorials.
tensorboard --logdir='D:\logs_dt'
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/files/995362/tensor_board_hello.zip&gt;tensor_board_hello.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/files/995357/logs_dt.zip&gt;logs_dt.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='DarrellThomas' date='2017-05-12T14:54:01Z'>
		related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/9701&gt;#9701&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='DarrellThomas' date='2017-05-12T15:12:31Z'>
		It looks like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/IgorX2&gt;@IgorX2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 had same issue in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/8845&gt;#8845&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  I reproduced his error too with his data.   His thread references &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow/issues/7856&gt;#7856&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which has the following workaround posted by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mrry&gt;@mrry&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 on 26 Feb

Unfortunately TensorBoard uses a colon as the separator between the optional "run name" and the path in the --logdir flag. That means that --logdir=E:\tmp\tensorflow\mnist\logs is interpreted as a run named E with path \tmp\tensorflow\mnist\logs, which explains why it's sensitive to the current working directory.
As a quick workaround, you could avoid this problem by always specifying an explicit run name as part of the --logdir flag, e.g.:


tensorboard --logdir=training:E:\tmp\tensorflow\mnist\logs


(Reassigning to @dandelionmane, who shows up on the blame for the relevant code.)

This workaround worked for me.  It seems to be a valid bug and the workaround seems valid.   I hope this helps others trying to get this running in windows.  At a minimum, perhaps put a note in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/summaries_and_tensorboard&gt;tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for windows users to specify the explicit run name too?
Very exciting stuff you guys are working on!  Hate to see others get slowed down if a simple fix would work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='DarrellThomas' date='2017-05-15T14:53:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dandelionmane&gt;@dandelionmane&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jart&gt;@jart&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='DarrellThomas' date='2017-05-16T01:40:00Z'>
		I'll write up a change soon to work around this issue. I'm not sure if a perfect solution is possible. It might be best if we just not allow single character run names. Or maybe only impose that behavior on Windows, or when backslashes are used.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='DarrellThomas' date='2017-06-16T19:18:20Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this. I've migrated it to our new repository at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorboard/issues/51&gt;tensorflow/tensorboard#51&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>