<bug id='8475' author='vekterli' open_date='2019-02-12T13:41:46Z' closed_time='2019-03-04T16:50:32Z'>
	<summary>Using global documents in grouped cluster topology triggers bug that may cause reduced replication for subset of data</summary>
	<description>
There is a bug in how we transform the configuration of a grouped cluster topology into a configuration that distributes global documents to all nodes in the topology. The observed impact of this bug is that some data buckets in the global bucket space may not be replicated as expected across all nodes. This can in turn lead to reduced recall for searches that use parent-child and refer to these global documents.
This bug only affects a minor subset of the global bucket space and is presumably the reason why this wasn't detected by our internal integration tests. Non-global document replication is not affected.
The fix for this bug is to correct the configuration transformation so that the data placement algorithm will emit the expected set of replicas.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vekterli' date='2019-02-21T11:59:20Z'>
		The changes introduced as part of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vespa-engine/vespa/pull/8479&gt;#8479&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 had unintended consequences for rolling upgrades. Since the distribution config is generated in-process, it will vary across versions. When distributors and content nodes with different versions try to exchange bucket info upon cluster state changes, they will not agree. This causes info requests to be rejected and stalling the cluster state change.
Will likely need to introduce a workaround.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='vekterli' date='2019-03-04T16:50:32Z'>
		Multiple internal upgrade cycles have passed since the fix was merged with no observed regressions; closing issue.
This issue is likely to have impacted rolling upgrades for content clusters with node groups between (and including) versions 7.12.13 and 7.15.21. Versions before and after are not affected, though it is strongly recommended that anyone using grouped clusters and global documents upgrade to a version  that is &gt;= 7.16.38, as otherwise search results may not always give the expected results across groups.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>