<bug id='165' author='timonehr' open_date='2020-05-25T17:47:28Z' closed_time='2020-05-26T06:48:47Z'>
	<summary>Bug when Pixelformat have a pixel size of 16 bit or 32 bit</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When you try to get images with the pixel size 16 bit or 32 bit you receive too small arrays
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Grab an image with 16 bit or 32 bit pixel size

Expected behavior
I expect for an image with the size 640 x 480 px and 16 bit pixel size an array with the size of 307200 px but i receive 153600 px.
The same for Coord3d_ABC32f: 640 px x 480 px * 3 and 32 bit pixel size would be an array with the size of 921600 px but i receive 230400 px
** Desktop

Harvester: 1.2.2

Additional context
        array = numpy.frombuffer( self._buffer.raw_buffer, count=int(count), dtype='uint8', offset=self.data_offset
Reads the right count of pixel but after:
return pf_proxy.expand(array)
the array have the wrong size.
I think the view() of numpy decreases the size: 16 bit by factor 2 and 32 bit pixel size by factor 4.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T01:42:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/timonehr&gt;@timonehr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Hi. Thank you for the valuable report. I guess you have reproduced the phenomenon when a device is running as a 3D camera as you pointed out , but would that be the same if it's running as a pure 2D camera? /Kazunari
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T02:17:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/timonehr&gt;@timonehr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have just created a development branch . Could you try that out when you can, please? At least that branch should give you an opportunity to check if it fixes the issue for a 3D camera.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T06:22:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kazunarikudo&gt;@kazunarikudo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the fast fix. Yes now everything is fine again.
, und  are working again.
At the beginning only Confidence8 with 8 bit pixel size was the only format which was correct. It was a little bit unclear in the first post.
Thanks again
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T06:33:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/timonehr&gt;@timonehr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Hi, thank you for making a try. I appreciate that. So may I merge the branch in the master branch?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T06:35:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kazunarikudo&gt;@kazunarikudo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 From my point of view: yes please.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='timonehr' date='2020-05-26T06:48:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/timonehr&gt;@timonehr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have just released version 1.2.3. It's been uploaded to PyPI as well.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>