<bug id='2221' author='harsh2ai' open_date='2019-06-02T05:37:33Z' closed_time='2019-06-04T22:00:40Z'>
	<summary>Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement torch&amp;gt;=1.0.1 (from syft) (from versions: 0.1.2, 0.1.2.p</summary>
	<description>
I am using a windows machine, with anaconda navigator I installed as per the instructions given in the readme.md

created an enviornment named pysyft and activated it
initialized pip install syft
The error mentioned above is displayed

I am  Udacity Student for Secure and Private AI
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/39687652/58757245-8e0d5280-8526-11e9-962f-7d231cec825e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='harsh2ai' date='2019-06-02T05:55:20Z'>
		Looks you haven't installed the appropriate version of torch or don't have torch installed in your conda environment. So activate your conda environment and install pytorch. Conda environments are a good way to keep separate dependencies. So if you have had a different version of torch in your system which you usually use. You can still use a specific version of torch separately using virtual environments such as conda.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='harsh2ai' date='2019-06-02T06:19:17Z'>
		Did you execute the following command in your pysyft environment? If not, then please run this command and check.
conda install pytorch torchvision -c pytorch
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='harsh2ai' date='2019-06-03T09:39:19Z'>
		You should update conda and pip. If it doesn't have torch 1.x it's likely very old.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='harsh2ai' date='2019-06-05T04:30:07Z'>
		I have already tried all the mentioned commands I even tried using it within the enviornment in which I had pytorch Installed and I got back the same error my current conda version is 4.5x and the torch version is 1.x &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/iamtrask&gt;@iamtrask&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='harsh2ai' date='2019-08-28T13:13:47Z'>
		I've the exact same issue seems to me that torch 1.2 (latest) isn't compatible with syft ?.
Any suggestions
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>