<bug id='4473' author='superxii' open_date='2020-08-25T06:50:45Z' closed_time='2020-11-19T13:27:26Z'>
	<summary>AssertionError: Searching for #fss_comp_plan_1 on worker1. /!\ 0 found</summary>
	<description>
Description:
AssertionError: Searching for #fss_comp_plan_1 on worker1. /!\ 0 found
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/63416489/91140892-57e76000-e6e2-11ea-83f9-0293be1e5a9c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='superxii' date='2020-08-25T07:57:22Z'>
		Hello, could you provide a method to reproduce this bug? At a first glance it seems the computation command didn't find a worker, but I need a snippet to recreate the bug and help you further.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='superxii' date='2020-08-25T08:29:02Z'>
		Hi,thank you for your help.Actually, I don't know how i made this bug.Maybe I provide the code with you first and to see whether is there a bug on your side.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenMined/PySyft/files/5122356/Federated.learning.with.MNIST.zip&gt;Federated learning with MNIST.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='superxii' date='2020-08-25T10:57:51Z'>
		You need to build from repo with these steps:

git clone https://github.com/OpenMined/PySyft.git
cd PySyft
pip install -r pip-dep/requirements.txt (and possibly other files from pip-dep or other dependencies to ensure the compatibility of your venv with syft)
pip install -e .

There will be another issue to update the version from pip to the latest release.
If there is any other problem let me know!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='superxii' date='2020-08-25T14:43:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/superxii&gt;@superxii&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did what &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/teo-milea&gt;@teo-milea&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 mentioned solved your problem
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='superxii' date='2020-08-26T01:10:52Z'>
		It solved thanks!!! But It appeared another error with the program
Is that something i missed to install?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/63416489/91243206-ff64a100-e77b-11ea-833e-c0484b6e099c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T06:01:49Z'>
		Are you running on Windows?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T06:26:23Z'>
		Yes, I was like running on Windows first before I run on Azure
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T06:27:00Z'>
		Could you try to run on Linux and check if the issue is still there?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T07:59:37Z'>
		I may need some time to fix other errors regarding to tensor flow on Linux.
Meanwhile,in tutorial two, I followed the example code but comes out with
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/63416489/91823544-f25c1c00-ec6b-11ea-9250-85b13c85950e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

ImportError: cannot import name 'ReduceOp' from 'torch.distributed' (C:\Users\user\anaconda3\envs\pysyft\lib\site-packages\torch\distributed_init_.py)
I have do some search and found that the distributed processing seems not to support windows yet,but I can ran the code in serveral weeks ago before I install with other package or libray.How can I fix this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T09:34:37Z'>
		Could you do a pip uninstall crypten? CrypTen is supported only in Linux.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='superxii' date='2020-09-01T09:52:42Z'>
		Thanks, I will comeback later on for the first bug to see whether it appears on linux or not.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='superxii' date='2020-10-09T17:57:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/superxii&gt;@superxii&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any update?
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='superxii' date='2020-11-13T00:17:22Z'>
		This issue has been marked stale because it has been open 30 days with no activity. Leave a comment or remove the stale label to unmark it. Otherwise, this will be closed in 7 days.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='superxii' date='2020-11-19T13:27:26Z'>
		Hello! Just letting you know that we are no longer planning on supporting anything on the 0.2.x product line and that all work should be ported over to 0.3.x, which is considered a complete rebuild of PySyft. Because of that, I'll be closing this issue. If you feel this is a mistake, or if the issue actually applies to 0.3.x as well, please feel free to ping me on Slack and I'll reopen the issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>