<bug id='1393' author='tlkh' open_date='2018-08-21T16:27:48Z' closed_time='2018-08-23T15:06:18Z'>
	<summary>JupyterHub Version Mismatch</summary>
	<description>

Important TLDR
Earlier today I struggled with a version mismatch between JupyterHub and Jupyter Notebook created from the JupyterHub, where I could reproduce the error multiple times on a clean install.
Amazingly in the last hour as I am attempting to replicate the issue, it is now unreproducible despite the version mismatch. I have been unable to isolate the precise cause of why I experience the error.
Despite this, I wish to describe the situation and also make some arguments as to allowing the end-user to fix the version of JupyterHub they would like to deploy.
In addition, I think we can leave this issue up as a reference in case somebody else experiences the same problem, as I managed to resolve it.

Earlier today, I can reproduce the error multiple times by simply installing Kubeflow on a brand new Minikube node in a VM, across about two hours before I managed to resolve it for myself. I used v0.2.2, as installed using ks, and it threw an Redirect Loop error when starting a Jupyter Notebook from the JupyterHub spawner.
I used the image gcr.io/kubeflow-images-public/tensorflow-1.8.0-notebook-cpu:v0.2.1 and other images from Docker Hub, e.g. jupyter/scipy-notebook, and the same error occurred.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Redirect loop detected. Notebook has jupyterhub version 0.9.1, but the Hub expects 0.9.0-dev. Try installing jupyterhub==0.9.0-dev in the user environment if you continue to have problems.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I was only able to address the problem by editing the configuration of the Stateful Set tf-hub, changing the command used as the entry point into the tf-hub-0 container as it is created:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;"name": "tf-hub",
"image": "gcr.io/kubeflow/jupyterhub-k8s:v20180531-3bb991b1",
"command": [
    "/bin/bash",
    "-c",
    "pip3 install jupyterhub==0.9.1 &amp;&amp; jupyterhub -f /etc/config/jupyterhub_config.py"
],
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This forcefully fixes the version of JupyterHub to a compatible one.
Amazingly in the last hour as I am attempting to replicate the issue, it is now unreproducible despite the version mismatch still being present. I have been unable to isolate the precise cause of why I experience the error.
However, I feel that it is still extremely important to give users option to control the exact version of JupyterHub they are using for the following reasons:

it will allow users to use newer images from Docker Hub, which might have some forward compatibility issues like that I experienced.
it will allow users to upgrade JupyterHub without needing for the version packed with Kubeflow to be updated (with the caveat that the user might knowingly introduce some issues)
if users require an older version of JupyterHub for compatibility reasons with certain packages

Thanks for reading!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tlkh' date='2018-08-23T15:06:15Z'>
		I checked as well  with 0.2.4 and  I was able to launch a notebook.
I used:
notebook image: gcr.io/kubeflow-images-public/tensorflow-1.8.0-notebook-cpu:v0.2.1
JupyterHub image: gcr.io/kubeflow/jupyterhub-k8s:v20180531-3bb991b1
Users can customize the JupyterHub image if they want by setting the parameter in their JupyterHub prototype.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/master/kubeflow/core/prototypes/jupyterhub.jsonnet#L9&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/master/kubeflow/core/prototypes/jupyterhub.jsonnet#L9&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The 0.3 scripts will make this a bit easier.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tlkh' date='2018-12-23T21:59:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I used exactly the versions you mentioned ...
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;matthias in ~/projekt/ml/mlaas-ba/gcloud-kubeflow/kubeflow/kubeflow_app/ks_app on gcloud-kubeflow ● ● λ ks param list jupyterhub
COMPONENT  PARAM                   VALUE
=========  =====                   =====
jupyterhub accessLocalFs           'false'
jupyterhub cloud                   'null'
jupyterhub disks                   'null'
jupyterhub gcpSecretName           'user-gcp-sa'
jupyterhub image                   'gcr.io/kubeflow/jupyterhub-k8s:v20180531-3bb991b1'
...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

and in dropdown menu on the hub i used:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/8426566/50387833-33b1cf80-0706-11e9-9f24-da32b41fb1b8.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

and i got still an version mismatch:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/8426566/50387837-4e844400-0706-11e9-899b-f75190e4e280.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>