<bug id='3003' author='gaoning777' open_date='2019-04-11T23:04:56Z' closed_time='2019-07-12T21:02:48Z'>
	<summary>permission error during deployment when GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIAL is set as the environment</summary>
	<description>
If the GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIAL is set as the environment variable, kfctl uses this credential directly instead of the credential from 'gcloud auth application-default login'.
The error looks like:
Error: couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error Set Cleared IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 403: The caller does not have permission, forbidden
Usage:
kfctl apply [all(=default)|k8s|platform] [flags]
Flags:
-h, --help      help for apply
-V, --verbose   verbose output default is false
couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error Set Cleared IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 403: The caller does not have permission, forbidden
After GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIAL is unset, it works.
It is probably a better idea for the kfctl to skip using GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIAL.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-11T23:04:57Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.77. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apps/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-11T23:12:58Z'>
		It's intended behavior of :
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/golang/oauth2/blob/9f3314589c9a9136388751d9adae6b0ed400978a/google/default.go#L61&gt;https://github.com/golang/oauth2/blob/9f3314589c9a9136388751d9adae6b0ed400978a/google/default.go#L61&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-11T23:25:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gabrielwen&gt;@gabrielwen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Should we output a log message indicating that GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS is set and that's the credential being used?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-11T23:49:36Z'>
		Yea, I think so.  We shouldn't change expected behavior (e.g. unset ENV GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS) as poeple might count on it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-16T08:18:11Z'>
		I have set both
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;export CLIENT_ID=
export CLIENT_SECRET=
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

and followed &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/gke/deploy/deploy-cli/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/gke/deploy/deploy-cli/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

But got error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment mana
ger Error Set Cleared IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 403: The caller does not have permission, forbidden
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='gaoning777' date='2019-04-16T16:46:10Z'>
		CLIENT_ID and CLIENT_SECRET is for Oauth.  Your error is most likely because of GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS env.  Could you try to set export GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS= and see if it works?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='gaoning777' date='2019-05-08T04:55:49Z'>
		In my case, my user account only has PROJECT EDITOR role, I think that's why I met IamPolicy error.
Tried getting a service account that has role PROJECT OWNER, then set  GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS to its credential file. Apply kubeflow again, it works.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-13T11:24:54Z'>
		I am getting the same error. I have only PROJECT EDITOR rights on the project due to company policy. Is there anyway we can install kubeflow without PROJECT OWNER rights?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-13T12:28:18Z'>
		
PROJECT EDITOR

Yes, you need to be a project owner or get the IAM Service account.
As &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/travishen&gt;@travishen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 said try &gt; getting a service account that has role 
It will work
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-13T13:50:12Z'>
		It is not feasible to grant PROJECT OWNER role directly for a user or service account due to security policies.
It would help if we could get the granular roles/permissions required, so that they can be granted to the user/service account.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-18T13:53:26Z'>
		Hi,
I'm using a service account with Project Owner role and my account is set Owner as well but i'm still getting this error when deploying kubeflow using the CLI (cloud shell):
couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error could not update storage-kubeflow.yaml: Updating kubeflow-test2-storage error(400): BAD REQUEST.
Any ideas why i'm still getting this error?
Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-25T19:08:51Z'>
		I am also having this exact same problem, and I am a Project Owner.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='gaoning777' date='2019-06-25T19:47:21Z'>
		
and I am a Project Owner.

Oops, How did you try installing using UI?
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='gaoning777' date='2019-07-12T19:47:20Z'>
		I'm not clear on what the solution is here? It seems to be failing because it doesn't have permission to do a deployment manager update when I do have perms. We can't have Project Owner be the expectation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='gaoning777' date='2019-07-12T21:02:46Z'>
		
couldn't apply KfApp: (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp: (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error Set Cleared IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 403: The caller does not have permission, forbidden

The error is indicating there is a problem setting the IAM Policy. This requires owner permissions or IAM policy admin permissions. This is needed if you want kfctl to do things like create and install service accounts.
If you don't have sufficient permission to do that then you will either need to


Get someone with owner permissions to do that for you


Follow the instructions for installing on an existing K8s cluster (https://v0-5.kubeflow.org/docs/started/getting-started-k8s/)

This will skip GCP specific setup that requires elevated permissions
But it means we won't do things like setup service accounts, DNS, or IAP
So that would have to be setup separately



		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='gaoning777' date='2019-09-19T18:57:06Z'>
		Hi,
I am using CLI to deploy kubeflow on gcp. using kftcl to generate files:
sudo kfctl generate all --zone us-central1-c
I got this error:
WARN[0000] Backfilling auth; this is deprecated; Auth should be explicitly set in Gcp plugin  filename="gcp/gcp.go:1733"
ERRO[0000] Could not configure IAP auth; environment variable CLIENT_ID not set  filename="gcp/gcp.go:1762"
Error: couldn't generate KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Generate failed for gcp: Could not configure IAP auth; environment variable CLIENT_ID not set
Usage:
kfctl generate [all(=default)|k8s|platform] [flags]
Flags:
--email string      email if '--platform gcp'
-h, --help              help for generate
--hostname string   hostname if '--platform gcp'
I already set the CLINET_ID environment variable but still, get this error.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>