<bug id='3105' author='jlewi' open_date='2019-04-25T01:24:34Z' closed_time='2019-07-31T02:27:51Z'>
	<summary>[GCP] gcloud build submit error when using VPC</summary>
	<description>
I ran into the following problem when trying to use GCB with VPC Service controls to mirror Kubeflow images.
The job succeeds but gcloud returns an error which is confusing.
Creating this issue to follow up on it. It is likely user error on my part.
I have a project in which I created a perimeter with Google Cloud Storage and BigQuery.
I'm trying to use Google Cloud Build to mirror images into GCR from outside the perimeter.
I created an access level to grant the cloud build service account access to the perimeter:
When I try to submit a GCB job I get a security perimeter violation error
ERROR: (gcloud.builds.submit) HTTPError 403: SecurityPolicyViolatedRequest violates VPC Service Controls.
Request is prohibited by organization's policy

The GCB job succeeds though and images are pushed. So the issue appears to be with gcloud trying to get and report status information. So I added my username to the access levels in order to give gcloud permission.
Any idea what the issue might be here?
Here's my perimeter
name: accessPolicies/216264525333/servicePerimeters/KubeflowZone
status:
accessLevels:

accessPolicies/216264525333/accessLevels/cloudbuild
resources:
projects/235037502967
restrictedServices:
bigquery.googleapis.com
storage.googleapis.com
containerregistry.googleapis.com
unrestrictedServices:
'*'
title: Kubeflow Zone

gcloud beta access-context-manager levels describe --policy=${POLICYID} cloudbuild
basic:
conditions:

members:

user:jlewi@kubeflow.org
user:jlewi@google.com
serviceAccount:235037502967@cloudbuild.gserviceaccount.com
name: accessPolicies/216264525333/accessLevels/cloudbuild
title: Cloud Build



	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jlewi' date='2019-04-25T01:24:36Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.72. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jlewi' date='2019-07-24T01:29:52Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>