<bug id='3214' author='eCeleritas' open_date='2019-05-07T18:46:20Z' closed_time='2019-05-07T19:31:49Z'>
	<summary>Unable to access notebook in kubeflow ui</summary>
	<description>
I have deployed kubeflow v0.5.0 on GCP using IAP. After following these steps (&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/notebooks/setup/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/notebooks/setup/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) to setup a notebook server in kubeflow, I am unable to access the notebook server. I see a pod spin up related to the name of my notebook server (i.e. ) and I am able to port-forward to it using kubectl. However, when accessing via the kubeflow ui (i.e. ), the kubelow ui presents me with the dashboard again.
Looking more closely at the documentation, it says:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;kubectl -n &lt;NAMESPACE&gt; describe pods jupyter-&lt;USERNAME&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I see no pods with this pattern.  I do not see any errors in the ui console nor errors in the backend to help me track down the issue. Is there anything special that is needed for IAP or otherwise missing from the documentation?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='eCeleritas' date='2019-05-07T18:46:22Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.58. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='eCeleritas' date='2019-05-07T19:31:49Z'>
		Restarting underlying pods caused the issue to go away. Closing this for now
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='eCeleritas' date='2019-05-17T19:37:47Z'>
		Which pods did you restart? I'm having the same issue. I've tried restarting the JupyterUI pod and the notebook pod it created multiple times. Thanks.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>