<bug id='3222' author='Tabrizian' open_date='2019-05-08T10:06:20Z' closed_time='2019-05-10T13:35:28Z'>
	<summary>Kubeflow on-prem deployment  Jupyter notebooks not working</summary>
	<description>
Using  a fresh installation of Kubeflow on Kubernetes, it seems like notebook-controller is unable to assign correct serviceaccount to Pods created for notebooks. Here is the logs for the stateful app:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;"my-kubeflow-0" is forbidden: error looking up service account kubeflow/jupyter-notebook: serviceaccount "jupyter-notebook" not foun
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-08T10:06:22Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.90. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-09T02:13:09Z'>
		Having the same issue spinning up a notebook server using version 0.5.0.
Version 0.5.1 does not appear to have a kfctl tar for linux, just darwin.
Environment is a 3 node K8s cluster stood up and controlled by Rancher.
I had previously had Kubeflow 0.10 installed via the Rancher helm chart, but removed that before installing 0.5.0 via kfctl.
create Pod lounau-0 in StatefulSet lounau failed error: pods "lounau-0" is forbidden: error looking up service account kubeflow/jupyter-notebook: serviceaccount "jupyter-notebook" not found
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-09T14:49:26Z'>
		Just tested it on a fresh Rancher 2 k8s deployment, jupyter-notebook service account and all related role bindings are there, but I'm experiencing problems with default-editor role, which is probably unrelated to the topic.
Service account jupyter-notebook is being created by ksonnet during kfctl apply -V deployment. Do you have any error log messages during this process?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-09T15:23:41Z'>
		See attached file for the kfctl generate, and the kfctl apply.  No errors that I see.  And no mention of jupyter-notebook.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/files/3162837/kfctl_output.txt&gt;kfctl_output.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-10T10:11:52Z'>
		Okay, I reproduced that with fresh 0.5.0 deployment.
Jupyter notebook StatefulSet events:
Warning  FailedCreate  25s (x15 over 64s)  statefulset-controller  create Pod test-0 in StatefulSet test failed error: pods "test-0" is forbidden: error looking up service account kubeflow-workspace/jupyter-notebook: serviceaccount "jupyter-notebook" not found
jupyter-notebook service account is not created with kfctl apply k8s.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-10T10:44:29Z'>
		Update: I just read kfctl init --help and found out an interesting fact:
  -v, --version string          desired version of Kubeflow or master if not specified. Version can be master (eg --version master) or a git tag (eg --version=v0.5.0), or a PR (eg --version pull/&lt;id&gt;). (default "master")
So I've tried deploying kubeflow 0.5.0 with  and jupyter-notebook service account was successfully created.  branch seems to be containing an unstable Kubeflow version, so it makes sense using explicit git tags for deployment. That's probably something that should be explicitly mentioned in this page: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/started/getting-started-k8s/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/started/getting-started-k8s/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Tabrizian' date='2019-05-10T13:35:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/3205&gt;#3205&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fixed this n v0.5.1; we now set --version by default to v0.5.1
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>