<bug id='3316' author='karlschriek' open_date='2019-05-20T08:08:18Z' closed_time='2019-08-21T07:16:45Z'>
	<summary>`kfctl.sh apply platform` on EKS fails if automatically selected availability zone has no capacity</summary>
	<description>
When running kfctl.sh apply platform on EKS, kfctl appears to automatically select which availabililty zones it will use. Sometimes one of the selected availability zone does not have capacity, leading to the error below:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Cannot create cluster 'kubeflow-aws' because us-east-1e, the targeted availability zone, does not currently have sufficient capacity to support the cluster. Retry and choose from these availability zoneseast-1a, us-east-1b, us-east-1c, us-east-1d, us-east-1f
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The expected behaviour should surely be that kfctl will only select availability zones that currently do have capacity?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='karlschriek' date='2019-05-20T08:08:20Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.92. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='karlschriek' date='2019-05-22T22:03:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karlschriek&gt;@karlschriek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 This is a problem on eksctl. I would suggest you to control availability zones manually in eksctl cluster config file. Please use AZs a b c for large region.
See this



kubeflow/deployment/aws/infra_configs/cluster_config.yaml


        Lines 11 to 12
      in
      ea43dfa






 # If your region has multiple availability zones, you can specify 3 of them. 



 #availabilityZones: ["us-west-2b", "us-west-2c", "us-west-2d"] 





		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='karlschriek' date='2019-08-20T22:49:41Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='karlschriek' date='2019-08-21T07:16:06Z'>
		As we have documentation there, I will close this issue. Feel free to reopen if you still have questions on it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='karlschriek' date='2019-08-21T07:16:44Z'>
		/close
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='karlschriek' date='2019-08-21T07:16:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: Closing this issue.

In response to this:

/close

Instructions for interacting with me using PR comments are available here.  If you have questions or suggestions related to my behavior, please file an issue against the kubernetes/test-infra repository.

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>