<bug id='3536' author='kimwnasptd' open_date='2019-06-24T16:47:56Z' closed_time='2019-07-04T20:46:37Z'>
	<summary>jupyter-web-app: Error 200 on load</summary>
	<description>
In the new UI if no namespace is selected from the centraldashboard before opening the Jupyter UI, then the value "" is passed as namespace. Because of this the GET will hit an invalid endpoint resulting in an error 200 popup.
The webapp should ignore the empty value from the centraldashboard.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-24T16:47:58Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.97. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-24T16:48:04Z'>
		/assign kimwnasptd
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-24T16:49:56Z'>
		cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/prodonjs&gt;@prodonjs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-24T17:13:17Z'>
		Currently, we send whatever namespace is selected (which could be empty) from the dashboard to a connected iframe child once the child establishes connectivity. One option would be to send only non-empty namespaces but there may be scenarios in the future where that's a valid selection (ie. no selection infers "all namespaces").
Sorry for the confusion as we try to get this interface in place.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-24T19:31:31Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/prodonjs&gt;@prodonjs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 makes sense. Will make the webapp ignore the empty namespace for now and will update the code if necessary when we settle down on the implementation.
Keep me in the loop for this one
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-06-26T20:32:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would you mind having the page display:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Please select a namespace from the toolbar above...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='kimwnasptd' date='2019-07-05T10:00:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sorry for the late reply, would we want this message to be always shown or only when a Namespace will not be selected (value  for now)?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>