<bug id='3625' author='sub-mod' open_date='2019-07-09T16:52:02Z' closed_time='2019-07-23T03:55:02Z'>
	<summary>tensorflow-notebook-image Image build failure due conda updating to python-3.7</summary>
	<description>
Hi All,
I am building tensorflow-notebook-image using below commands
I tested this on v0.5-branch and v0.4-branch
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;git checkout remotes/origin/v0.5-branch
cd components/tensorflow-notebook-image
 ./build_image.sh ./Dockerfile submod/tensorflow-1.13.1-notebook-cpu v0.5.0 ./versions/1.13.1/version-config.json
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

These command worked fine until few weeks ago.
But from past few days I am not able to build them as I get the below error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;...
Successfully installed pip-19.0.1
tensorflow-1.13.1-cp36-cp36m-manylinux1_x86_64.whl is not a supported wheel on this platform.
You are using pip version 19.0.1, however version 19.1.1 is available.
You should consider upgrading via the 'pip install --upgrade pip' command.
The command '/bin/bash -c pip install --upgrade pip==19.0.1 &amp;&amp;     pip --no-cache-dir install     ${TF_PACKAGE}     jupyter     jupyter-console==6.0.0     jupyterhub     jupyterlab     xgboost     git+https://github.com/kubeflow/fairing@bd8313d9a4e4dd3b69a840e7cf0ea0d2326d720e     ${PIPELINE_SDK_PACKAGE}     &amp;&amp; conda clean -tipsy' returned a non-zero code: 1
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I notice that conda update conda would remove python 3.6 and install python 3.7
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;python:                 3.6.4-hc3d631a_1       defaults    --&gt; 3.7.1-h5001a0f_0          conda-forge
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This behavior is seen both on v4.4.10 and v4.5.4 Miniconda version.
Is this is known bug ? if so, is there a workaround other than manually changing the Dockerfile by removing conda update conda ?
v4.5.4 has some notes about this issue
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Install conda as jovyan user and check the md5 sum provided on the download site
# After Miniconda v4.5.4 the default Python version is no longer 3.6, but TensorFlow
# still doesn't support Python 3.7. If we still like to upgrade Miniconda we need
# to add the line "conda install python==3.6" to RUN command below
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

But adding conda install python==3.6 did not help as conda update conda would remove python 3.6 anyways.And since the python version is updated to 3.7 the wheel files mentioned in the version-config.json cannot be installed and the image build fails.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-09T16:52:04Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.85. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-15T15:30:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sub-mod&gt;@sub-mod&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 What are you trying to do? Specifically why are you trying to build the docker images from source rather than using the pre-built docker images?
If you are trying to create a custom Jupyter image; then I would suggest trying to follow the directions here
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/notebooks/custom-notebook/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/notebooks/custom-notebook/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

And simplifying the Dockerfile to install what you need.
It looks like the error you are getting is that you are running into a version mismatch with TF 1.13.
My suggestion would be to start with a TF 1.13 docker image and then follow the instructions above for customizing that docker image to work with Kubeflow and also to install any specific dependencies you have.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-15T17:25:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I am building kubeflow tensorflow-notebook-image container image for my internal kubeflow deployment which will have a custom tensorflow wheel file created by me. I have only created  tensorflow-1.13 wheel and I do not have the wheels for the subprojects like tensorflow-serving-api etc.
creating a dockerfile from scratch is not what I want to do.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-20T01:21:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sub-mod&gt;@sub-mod&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


creating a dockerfile from scratch is not what I want to do.

So it looks like you want to build a custom version in TensorFlow and then build a jupyter image with that version of TF.
The error
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;tensorflow-1.13.1-cp36-cp36m-manylinux1_x86_64.whl is not a supported wheel on this platform.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Indicates the version of TF you have compiled is not compatible with the Docker image you are trying to install it.
I can think of two options


Fix your build of TF to create a compatible version


Find an alternative way to build the docker image that is compatible with your version of

If your using TF's build process then you might investigate whether there's  a way to build a Docker image with your version of TF installed in it.



		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-22T15:59:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I mentioned in my first comment that this is because  would remove python 3.6 and install python 3.7. As a result I am not able to install the py36 tensorflow wheel since the python version is 3.7.
This would fail for kubeflow as well. Because the  file  doesnot have 3.7 tensorflow wheel file URLs. So, option 1. suggestion is not needed.
As soon as I remove  conda update conda  I am able to build the image.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='sub-mod' date='2019-07-23T03:55:01Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sub-mod&gt;@sub-mod&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  Glad you figured it out.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3725&gt;#3725&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 aims to simplify our images and potentially move away from conda.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>