<bug id='3677' author='kunmingg' open_date='2019-07-16T23:14:33Z' closed_time='2019-11-13T09:29:11Z'>
	<summary>Notebook spawn: button turn green even backend not ready.</summary>
	<description>
For now as long as service of notebook instance up, button will turn green.
Even if backend pod not ready (timeout due to first time launch huge image...)
User will end up saw unhealthy upstream after click button.
We should wait till pod is ready.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kunmingg' date='2019-07-16T23:14:35Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.82. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kunmingg' date='2019-07-16T23:15:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karthikv2k&gt;@karthikv2k&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/abhi-g&gt;@abhi-g&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kunmingg' date='2019-07-16T23:40:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Is this a UI issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kunmingg' date='2019-07-17T11:57:35Z'>
		The webapp checks the status.containerState in the Notebook CR. This gets set from the Notebook Controller and it mirrors the state of the undrelying Pod. The UI will show the green check only if the state is running.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kunmingg&gt;@kunmingg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 IIUC your backend Pod is not ready, yet the UI shows a green check? What is the  in that Notebook's CR? How can I reproduce what you saw?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-08T08:21:53Z'>
		I think the issue might be that the status.containerState that we expose in the Notebook CR refers to the containerStatus[0] in the Notebook Pod.
But, if we also have ISTIO then this Container is the one with Envoy. So the UI actually shows the status of the Envoy Container and not the Notebook Image's Container (which might even have an ImagePullBackOff for example).
More info on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3820&gt;#3820&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kunmingg' date='2019-11-06T09:12:04Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>