<bug id='3832' author='SinaChavoshi' open_date='2019-08-06T16:58:20Z' closed_time='2019-12-25T08:00:04Z'>
	<summary>0.6 deployment fails Service account xyz-user@abc.iam.gserviceaccount.com does not exist</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
Executed the a deployment of kfp 6.0 following the CLI deployment instructions. got the following error after
Error: couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error S et New IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 400: Service account kubeflow-demo-2019-user@chavoshi-dev-2.iam.gserviceaccount.com does not exist., badRequest Usage: kfctl apply [all(=default)|k8s|platform] [flags] Flags: -h, --help      help for apply -V, --verbose   verbose output default is false couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 400 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error Set New  IamPolicy error: googleapi: Error 400: Service account kubeflow-demo-2019-user@chavoshi-dev-2.iam.gserviceaccount.com does not exist., badRequest
What did you expect to happen:
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.1
kfctl version: (use kfctl version):  kfctl v0.6.1-rc.2-1-g3a37cbc6
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): GCP
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): google cloud shell

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-06T16:58:22Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.99. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-06T17:40:24Z'>
		one additional details, deployment steps on a separate project work fine, on this particular project I have two instances of KP deployed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-09T17:58:02Z'>
		one of our customers also observed a similar manifestation of this issue with error message
code 400 with message: gcp apply could not create secrets Error cannot create admin secret admin-gcp-sa; Service account key creation error: Post https://iam.googleapis.com/v1/projects/...XYZ...-admin@....XYZ.....iam.gserviceaccount.com/keys?alt=json&amp;prettyPrint=false: read tcp [........]:51273-&gt;[......]:443: read: operation timed out
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-12-18T07:13:52Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>