<bug id='3835' author='SinaChavoshi' open_date='2019-08-06T19:52:31Z' closed_time='2019-09-10T13:43:03Z'>
	<summary>kf 0.6 - User 'xyz@abc.com' is not authorized for namespace 'kubeflow'</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug

[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
In notebook page when i select kubeflow as name space (ie already at .../_/jupyter/?ns=kubeflow) I get an error that my user '&lt;denchmark-link:mailto:xyz@abc.com&gt;xyz@abc.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
' is not authorized for namespace 'kubeflow'. User has admin access to the GCP account
What did you expect to happen:
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:
Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.1
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): kfctl v0.6.1-rc.2-1-g3a37cbc6
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): GCP
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): google cloud shell
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-06T19:52:33Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.97. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-06T19:54:07Z'>
		resolved by changing the name space to kubeflow-user env
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-06T19:56:51Z'>
		The name space is not selected by default  It may makes sense to set the default name space to user account. Also the documentation in kubeflow.org does not reflect the 0.6 UI this may be confusing for users to figure out.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-08-21T22:03:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SinaChavoshi&gt;@SinaChavoshi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'm seeing this error appear on all namespaces. Did you have to create the kubeflow-user namespace? what deployment name did you use?
: never mind, I found&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/other-guides/multi-user-overview/&gt; this page&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and created a new user, and that worked. We should definitely add this to the troubleshooting guide or improve the error message or something
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='SinaChavoshi' date='2019-09-10T13:43:03Z'>
		Closing this issue. Since it looks like it has been resolved.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>