<bug id='3893' author='kunmingg' open_date='2019-08-13T22:35:21Z' closed_time='2019-09-08T23:00:01Z'>
	<summary>Multi-Tenancy Compatibility Reset on v0.6</summary>
	<description>
/kind feature
We need to guarantee kubeflow Multi-Tenancy Compatibility with different environments:

 Always create default profile
 Istio rbac is only ON when coming requests contains identity which is accepted by both Istio and k8s.
 Notebook spawner should not block user creating notebooks when Istio rbac is OFF
 Test for on prem environment; document how to setup Multi-Tenancy on prem.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-13T22:35:23Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.68. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-14T03:21:58Z'>
		See also this comment for list of scenarios we want to test
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3437#issuecomment-520674809&gt;#3437 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-14T12:48:48Z'>
		
Notebook spawner should not block user creating notebooks when Istio rbac is OFF

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kunmingg&gt;@kunmingg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you elaborate a little bit more on this one? What's the use case that the jupyter webapp blocks the user from creating a Notebook?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-14T13:55:19Z'>
		Here's a table I think listing the use cases we want to test



How Installed
ISTIO Identity Aware
Profile Created Automatically




kfctl_k8s_existing yam
No
No


kfctl_k8s_existing_arrikto.yaml
?
No


kfctl_gcp_iap.yam
yes
yes



In all of the above cases we want to verify the following works

If profile isn't created automatically; create one via kfctl
User goes to jupyter web app and sees namespaces for which they have access (e.g. profile created)
User creates notebook
User can connect to notebook

So we want to support two cases;

ISTIO is aware of the user's identity; because requests have a header/JWT identifying the user
ISTIO isn't aware of the identity (e.g. because no identity headers are added as in kfctl_k8s_existing.yaml)

In the case where ISTIO isn't identity aware we need to ensure ISTIO RBAC isn't configured so that users would be blocked from accessing their notebook.
When we are using DEX (kfctl_existing_arrikto.yaml) we should be able to make ISTIO aware of the user's identity. In the short term though; that may not work because we still have to fix some issues in order to use the DEX added identity headers. At the very least though we should be able to fall back to the situation where ISTIO is not identity aware which would achieve parity with current behavior.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-14T14:02:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the existing_arrikto config using Dex is capable of identity awareness.
In order to do that, this issue needs to be resolved first: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3553&gt;#3553&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The packages of some applications in manifests have to be extended to make the userid header customizable.
Right now, it is set to x-goog-authenticated-user-email by default.
I will try to tackle this issue today, as it should be in this release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-16T03:22:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/krishnadurai&gt;@krishnadurai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I created a doc based on the 0.6.0 release demo script.
&lt;denchmark-link:http://bit.ly/2ZgOE1v&gt;http://bit.ly/2ZgOE1v&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Lets get it updated for 0.6.2 and use to make sure we are testing all the scenarios we care about.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-16T07:34:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 looks like you would need to grant access to this document.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-18T22:52:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/krishnadurai&gt;@krishnadurai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Apologies; I thought I'd put it in the kubeflow shared drive but I guess not. Please try again.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='kunmingg' date='2019-08-22T22:03:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Seems &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/v0.6-branch/bootstrap/config/kfctl_existing_arrikto.yaml&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/v0.6-branch/bootstrap/config/kfctl_existing_arrikto.yaml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 still have Istio rbac on.
Will we have user identify setup in proxy under this condition?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='kunmingg' date='2019-09-08T23:00:01Z'>
		0.6.2 has been released so I'm going to go ahead and close this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>