<bug id='3988' author='Snapple49' open_date='2019-08-23T15:42:35Z' closed_time='2019-09-12T02:23:54Z'>
	<summary>Istio deployment fails on kfctl apply</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug

Following the getting &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/started/k8s/kfctl-k8s-istio/&gt;started guide &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 results in an error during the  step:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;INFO[0109] creating VirtualService/tf-job-dashboard      filename="kustomize/kustomize.go:447"
Error: couldn't apply KfApp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: kfApp Apply failed for kustomize:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: couldn't create resources from tf-job-operator Error: Internal error occurred: failed calling webhook "pilot.validation.istio.io": Post https://istio-galley.istio-system.svc:443/admitpilot?timeout=30s: x509: certificate has expired or is not yet valid
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

 I have modified the config yaml slightly, as proposed in PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/3979&gt;#3979&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, since I had some issues with the dashboard, so I set the  field to match those. I still got the same error regarding the certificate even when following the instructions exactly.
What happens is that kfctl does not finish applying the rest of the components so even if I can port forward and access the centraldashboard via the istio-ingressgateway service, the different components of kubeflow are not accessible like the pipelines or katib panels for example. This seems to depend on order of execution as sometimes some of the components are visible, sometimes not and instead I see Sorry, /pipeline/ is not a valid page for example.
What did you expect to happen:
I expected kubeflow and istio to be deployed in my cluster successfully
Anything else you would like to add:
I noticed that if I first apply the config with istio installation commented out and then again with istio installation enabled, kubeflow is deployed and from the dashboard UI seems to be working. But istio still complains with the same error at the same point.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard):
build version v0.6.0-rc.0
kfctl version: (use kfctl version):
kfctl v0.6.2-rc.2
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube):
on-premise bare-metal/VM with rancher 2.2.4 and rke 0.2.8
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Client Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"15", GitVersion:"v1.15.3", GitCommit:"2d3c76f9091b6bec110a5e63777c332469e0cba2", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-08-19T11:13:54Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.9", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
Server Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14", GitVersion:"v1.14.6", GitCommit:"96fac5cd13a5dc064f7d9f4f23030a6aeface6cc", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-08-19T11:05:16Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.9", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):
working environment: "Ubuntu 18.04.3 LTS"
VM nodes: "16.04.6 LTS (Xenial Xerus)"
bare-metal node: "16.04.4 LTS (Xenial Xerus)"

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Snapple49' date='2019-08-23T15:42:38Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.99. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Snapple49' date='2019-08-26T06:14:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Snapple49&gt;@Snapple49&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did you do re-run kfctl apply again on the same cluster? Applying configs for the second time is currently having an issue being discussed here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3810&gt;#3810&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Snapple49' date='2019-08-26T09:25:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/krishnadurai&gt;@krishnadurai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have tried to install multiple times on the same cluster yes, but I delete everything that was installed during the process (I believe, maybe I miss some non-namespaced global resources) between each attempt. I've read that issue and I don't think that's the issue. I got the same error also the first time, so I was thinking that istio probably has some issue setting up certificates with my cluster.
In the end, it does seem to be working running kubeflow in the cluster with the method I mentioned above, I have very limited knowledge of istio so I can't say for sure what's working and not. Should I close this for now and keep you posted if I find any issues again that relate to certificate issues with istio?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Snapple49' date='2019-08-26T20:21:39Z'>
		this is fixed by PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/3957&gt;#3957&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

/priority p0
/area kfctl
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Snapple49' date='2019-09-11T21:23:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kkasravi&gt;@kkasravi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  is this fixed? Can we close the issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Snapple49' date='2019-09-11T22:11:56Z'>
		yes, this has been merged to master. Thanks.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>