<bug id='4003' author='LeonardAukea' open_date='2019-08-26T08:17:36Z' closed_time='2020-02-10T02:02:42Z'>
	<summary>Provided notebook name needs parsing to follow accepted kubernetes naming convention for resources like mounted volumes</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
I installed kubeflow on my local kubernetes cluster following the instructions for kfctl_k8s_istio.
This worked fine and dandy. I happened to notice that there where some restrictions for what may be provided as a name for the notebook, if a server was to launch sucessfully. I guess this is due to the mounted volume name being inherited from the name given to the notebook. It would make sense to make sure all names provided to rescources follow the following rules:

By convention, the names of Kubernetes resources should be up to maximum length of 253 characters and consist of lower case alphanumeric characters, -, and ., but certain resources have more specific restrictions. https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/working-with-objects/names/

I tried to find the location in the codebase to add functionality for parsing the notebook name  in order to force the above conventions when allocated to some kubernetes resource (volume, container, ..) but I'm not yet very familiar with the codebase. I guess that it has something to do with the templated
var notebook-name. One could pipe lower and remove special chars and replace whitespaces and underscores with -. (Assuming jinja2)
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard):
kfctl version: kfctl v0.6.2-rc.2
Kubernetes platform: docker-for-desktop
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): Client Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14", GitVersion:"v1.14.3", GitCommit:"5e53fd6bc17c0dec8434817e69b04a25d8ae0ff0", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-06-07T09:55:27Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.5", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"darwin/amd64"}
Server Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14", GitVersion:"v1.14.3", GitCommit:"5e53fd6bc17c0dec8434817e69b04a25d8ae0ff0", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-06-06T01:36:19Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.5", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): macOS 10.15 (19A536g)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-08-26T08:17:38Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.92. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-09-09T13:42:18Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LeonardAukea&gt;@LeonardAukea&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for the report. Were you using the UI to create notebooks or were you creating notebooks using the kubectl CLI?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Is this something we should fix in the spawner UI?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-09-09T13:50:51Z'>
		Per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3970&gt;#3970&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 looks like we also need to reject invalid names.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-09-11T11:58:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I was using the UI. The name of the server needs to be parsed according to convention.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-09-11T12:34:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


@kimwnasptd Is this something we should fix in the spawner UI?
It doesn't impact correctness, but it will improve the UI if the notebook manager UI rejects invalid names early on. We will pick this up for 0.7.

/assign kimwnasptd
/assign elikatsis
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='LeonardAukea' date='2019-11-05T00:44:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vkoukis&gt;@vkoukis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any update on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='LeonardAukea' date='2020-02-03T01:29:54Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>