<bug id='4011' author='boniek83' open_date='2019-08-27T15:19:28Z' closed_time='2019-12-08T11:28:24Z'>
	<summary>kubeflow installer does not create katib/metadatadb database</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
Install fresh kubeflow 0.6.2 with fresh pv for katib-db and metadata-db. Readiness probe fails in bofh cases.
What did you expect to happen:
Database should be created automatically if it doesn't exist.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.2
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): v0.6.2-0-g47a0e4c7
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube) kubernetes
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): 1.14.5
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): centos 7

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='boniek83' date='2019-08-27T15:19:30Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.97. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='boniek83' date='2019-08-28T13:04:13Z'>
		/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johnugeorge&gt;@johnugeorge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hougangliu&gt;@hougangliu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/andreyvelich&gt;@andreyvelich&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='boniek83' date='2019-08-28T14:14:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/boniek83&gt;@boniek83&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes, for katib-db, the below ENV will create katib database automatically if it doesn't exist (&lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/_/mysql&gt;https://hub.docker.com/_/mysql&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). Can you show me the pod logs of katib-db? how many times had the Pod restarted?
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;          - name: MYSQL_DATABASE
            value: "katib"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='boniek83' date='2019-08-28T14:20:11Z'>
		AFAIK, for some PV,  docker image cannot work well anyhow.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/boniek83&gt;@boniek83&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  so you can also try to change image of katib-db deployment to   and change  value of katib-db deployment as below to try what happens.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        args:
        - --datadir
        - /var/lib/mysql/anotheranyname
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='boniek83' date='2019-08-29T04:18:33Z'>
		Is your PVC bound to PV? Please provide more information
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='boniek83' date='2019-09-02T10:15:53Z'>
		I am using &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/helm/charts/tree/master/stable/nfs-client-provisioner&gt;https://github.com/helm/charts/tree/master/stable/nfs-client-provisioner&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as storage provisioner on on-premises kubernetes cluster. PVC is bound to PV.
mysql:8 restarted only once. It prints a lot of:

[Note] Access denied for user 'root'@'localhost' (using password: YES)

after startup (every 2-3 seconds)
I can manually create database when inside of db container. Only after creating database manually, service shows active endpoint and I can telnet to katib-db at port 3306. I didn't test if connetion works with mysql client command due to errors earlier and recommendation to try mysql 5.
When using mysql:5 image database brings itself up (database is created automatically) but katib-manager is not working:

[mysql] 2019/08/30 10:24:17 packets.go:36: unexpected EOF

is printed to logs and katib-manager restarts. Telnet to katib-db at port 3306 from another container works, but mysql -h katib-db -P 3306 -u root -p doesn't, command exits with error:

ERROR 2013 (HY000): Lost connection to MySQL server at 'reading initial communication packet', system error: 0

Will there be an option to specify our own mysql instance and username? Running mysql on kubernetes with root is not a good practice - no replication, no monitoring, no backups, no security.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='boniek83' date='2019-12-01T10:59:45Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>