<bug id='4021' author='SpontaneousDuck' open_date='2019-08-28T12:43:40Z' closed_time='2019-11-05T00:43:35Z'>
	<summary>Notebooks connection error</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
Creating notebooks looks like it works but any connection returns a 404 error on the jupyter server. tried a bunch of different provided servers  and was only able to get the tensorflow 1.5 w/gpu image working. All other images return a webpage with a 404 error and a jupyter header. Custom images also do the same thing (tensorflow/tensorflow). I just upgraded from kubeflow v0.5 and all images I tried worked on that version.
What did you expect to happen:
Notebook launches correctly from the dashboard
Environment:

Kubeflow version: v0.6.2
kfctl version: v0.6.2-0-g47a0e4c7
Kubernetes platform: Bare-metal
Kubernetes version: 1.14.3
OS: Ubuntu 18.04

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SpontaneousDuck' date='2019-08-28T12:43:42Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.99. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SpontaneousDuck' date='2019-08-28T13:06:16Z'>
		Can you provide the docker image that you are trying, the logs of your jupyter server, and the URL you are trying to hit?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SpontaneousDuck' date='2019-08-28T15:12:17Z'>
		Tested with the provided tensorflow-1.13.1-notebook-gpu:v0.5.0 and tensorflow-2.0.0a-notebook-gpu:v0.5.0 images.
So I have a bare-metal Kubernetes cluster with 1 management node and multiple gpu nodes. It looks like the first problem I had was I deployed with  instead of . After I did that my first notebook worked. Upon creating more notebooks the logs for the first notebook showed that connections for notebook &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/2&gt;#2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/3&gt;#3&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I created all were routed to the first notebook and thus returned a 404 since they were to wrong path. After deleting the original notebook, requests were routed properly to the second and third notebook.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='SpontaneousDuck' date='2019-11-05T00:43:35Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SpontaneousDuck&gt;@SpontaneousDuck&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this was a bug in the notebook controller that was fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4402&gt;#4402&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The fix should be in 0.7.0 which we released this morning.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>