<bug id='4094' author='gar1t' open_date='2019-09-09T17:05:35Z' closed_time='2019-12-26T06:17:01Z'>
	<summary>Namespace select only shows kubeflow-anonymous</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:

Open dashboard
Try to select a namespace

The dropdown contents flash for a moment and then only show a single entry: kubeflow-anonymous.
See this video for a demo:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.loom.com/share/70a896c7fe9948fe82cabb58221107c4&gt;https://www.loom.com/share/70a896c7fe9948fe82cabb58221107c4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

What did you expect to happen:
In my previous use of Kubeflow, there were a number of namespaces.
Anything else you would like to add:
During  the behavior described in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/4087&gt;#4087&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 occurred. The operation exited with code 1 and the env eventually started (verify using  that all pods a running).
After a hard (cache clearning) page reload, I did not see any messages in the browser Console, nor did I see any non 2xx responses in Networks.
The payload of /api/env-info is:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;{
  "user": "anonymous@kubeflow.org",
  "platform": {
    "kubeflowVersion": "v0.6.2",
    "provider": "other://",
    "providerName": "other"
  },
  "namespaces": [
  {
    "namespace": "kubeflow-anonymous",
    "role": "contributor",
    "user": "anonymous@kubeflow.org"
  }
  ],
  "isClusterAdmin": true
}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I see events for the kubeflow by opening the page with the path /activity?ns=kubeflow (i.e. manually editing the namespace in the browser URL).
Environment:

Kubeflow version: v0.6.2
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): v0.6.2-0-g47a0e4c7
Kubernetes platform: microk8s
Kubernetes version: v1.15.3
OS: Linux kubeflow 4.15.0-58-generic #64-Ubuntu SMP

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-09T17:05:37Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.99. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-11T18:10:02Z'>
		I believe v0.6.2 only shows kubeflow-anonymous under namespace on initial deployment. It will then only show namespaces associated with user profiles created. &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/other-guides/multi-user-overview/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/other-guides/multi-user-overview/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I do agree with the UX comment in the video when creating a new notebook server for the first time and trying to edit the namespace from the namespace box when you're suppose to have selected it from the top drop down.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-11T21:14:27Z'>
		There's a lot of (log) activity under the 'kubeflow' namespace in 0.6.2.
The only way to view that, that I can tell, is to hack the URL
(`?ns=kubeflow`).
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Wed, Sep 11, 2019, 13:10 Daniel Nguyen ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 I believe v0.6.2 only shows kubeflow-anonymous under namespace on initial
 deployment. It will then only show namespaces associated with user profiles
 created. https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/other-guides/multi-user-overview/

 I do agree with the UX comment in the video when creating a new notebook
 server for the first time and trying to edit the namespace from the
 namespace box when you're suppose to have selected it from the top drop
 down.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#4094?email_source=notifications&amp;email_token=AABNE5O67E6WUB4DQEQKCL3QJEYA7A5CNFSM4IU5ZARKYY3PNVWWK3TUL52HS4DFVREXG43VMVBW63LNMVXHJKTDN5WW2ZLOORPWSZGOD6PMNNA#issuecomment-530499252&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AABNE5O5WDLKFCRPLQRRWG3QJEYA7ANCNFSM4IU5ZARA&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-18T20:46:17Z'>
		As it stands, this seems to be the behavior that is expected for namespaces (in terms of the list you can see)
/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kunmingg&gt;@kunmingg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/abhi-g&gt;@abhi-g&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

In terms of the UX for notebooks, I agree, we could make this more intuitive (cc: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ajayalfred&gt;@ajayalfred&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 PTAL).
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-18T20:57:38Z'>
		If the kubeflow namespace isn't in the list, how is a user supposed to view the activity associated with that namespace?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-18T20:59:41Z'>
		Starting at v0.6.2, kubeflow namespace will be for infra services like controllers.
User can create notebooks or deploying workloads in their own namespace.
If identity-aware-proxy is not setup, the default user namespace is kubeflow-anonymous
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-18T21:06:34Z'>
		That makes sense. But what if someone wants to to view infra activity - for whatever reason?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-18T21:14:44Z'>
		The infra activity for Kubeflow namespace deployments should be accessible
via the K8s dashboard in general, or on GKE Hub on GKE.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Wed, Sep 18, 2019 at 2:06 PM Garrett Smith ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 That makes sense. But what if someone wants to to view infra activity -
 for whatever reason?

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#4094?email_source=notifications&amp;email_token=ACZ2UZTGWSUZM2KJIHME5RDQKKJ6RA5CNFSM4IU5ZARKYY3PNVWWK3TUL52HS4DFVREXG43VMVBW63LNMVXHJKTDN5WW2ZLOORPWSZGOD7BOOEQ#issuecomment-532866834&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ACZ2UZVE5MSS2HT5WZP2LW3QKKJ6RANCNFSM4IU5ZARA&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-19T02:25:52Z'>
		If you wanted to look at the kubeflow namespace you can also use kubectl
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='gar1t' date='2019-09-20T05:07:22Z'>
		Hi, i am using v0.6.2 and using a notebook server in my namespace to write a pipeline function using the Kubeflow Pipelines DSL with reference &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/pipelines/sdk/sdk-overview/&gt;link&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. i am also specifying the notebook server's pvc name with kfp.onprem.mount_pvc method to store the output to notebook server's directory. when i compile the code i get the link to experiment and run, but the run is in pending state with volume claim not found message.
i know the reason is that the pipelines are being created in kubeflow namespace and not in the notebook's namespace.
am i doing it the wrong way or is it the expected functionality as of now?
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='gar1t' date='2019-12-19T05:46:26Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>