<bug id='4140' author='lluunn' open_date='2019-09-17T21:16:44Z' closed_time='2019-11-05T00:17:42Z'>
	<summary>kfctl with kfctl_gcp_iap.yaml failed</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
kfctl init --config=kfctl_gcp_iap.yaml
kfctl generate all
kfctl apply all
I see error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;WARN[0000] reconcile process has error:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: gcp apply could not update deployment manager Error could not update storage-kubeflow.yaml; Insert deployment error: googleapi: Error 400: Invalid resource field value in the request., badRequest; retrying...  filename="coordinator/coordinator.go:237"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

But the apply continue, and it's creating k8s resources in the cluster my kubeconfig was pointing to before.
I think there are two problems:

in app.yaml, there is no project field, and hostname is kf0917.endpoints..cloud.goog. So it can't infer my gcp project
The reconcile failure should be fatal and stop the process.

Environment:
built kfctl from master
cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gabrielwen&gt;@gabrielwen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lluunn' date='2019-09-17T21:16:46Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.99. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lluunn' date='2019-09-17T21:22:44Z'>
		related:
After I fixed the project field, I got resource error when kfctl apply:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ERRO[0030] Creating kf0917 error: &amp;{Code:RESOURCE_ERROR
...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

But kfctl also continues to apply k8s part..
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lluunn' date='2019-09-18T13:27:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gabrielwen&gt;@gabrielwen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this related to how you implemented reconcile semantics in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4106&gt;#4106&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I think you are using "errors" to indicate that the apply isn't finished and so it just keeps retrying.
I think swallowing the error and just continuing could lead to confusing behavior. We probably want to migrate to using conditions to indicate whether the Apply is done or needs to be reinvoked.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lluunn' date='2019-09-25T23:34:29Z'>
		yea I think this will be fixed after condition based retrying.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lluunn' date='2019-11-05T00:17:42Z'>
		Closing this because IAP is working with 0.7.0
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>