<bug id='4241' author='holdenk' open_date='2019-10-07T07:00:11Z' closed_time='2020-02-06T18:40:19Z'>
	<summary>kfctl on minikube goes into a loop prompting for namespace creation</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
Deployed kubeflow using kfctl apply -f ../kfctl_k8s_istio.yaml. Wait for services to settle by watching the pods. Ran minikube service istio-ingressgateway  --namespace istio-system to connect to the UI. Created namespace in the UI. Pressing finish button did not remove the overlay.
What did you expect to happen:
I expected to see the regular kubeflow UI once I pressed finish.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
The kubeflow UI is loaded underneath (you can see it flash up when you hit refresh).
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard):
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): kfctl 2395c5f
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): minikube
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-07T07:00:19Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-07T22:53:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/holdenk&gt;@holdenk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 by overlay do you mean the UI?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-08T21:36:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this looks like an issue with the centraldashboard. Any suggestion about what debug information to collect to help diagnose this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-08T23:08:15Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/holdenk&gt;@holdenk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
When you run through the registration flow in the UI could you include the output you get from: (using chrome-dev tools)

/api/has-workgroup
/api/env-info
/api/workgroup/create

Note: Fetch this output after you press create / submit
Also, are there any errors in the console?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-09T21:26:29Z'>
		I can take a look &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . When you say "include the output from using chrome dev tools" though can you clarify what you mean? Like what the response was in the request or something else?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='holdenk' date='2019-10-09T21:58:09Z'>
		I mean, what was the response payload, should be JSON. Looks something like:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/5303018/66523594-22735d00-eaa5-11e9-9fcf-2a41e47f805c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='holdenk' date='2019-12-01T17:59:19Z'>
		I am getting this same issue, using microK8s and kfctl v0.7.0 just downloaded and installed today.  I also created the namespaces manually using the instructions on this page:  &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/other-guides/multi-user-overview/&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and verified with , but Kubeflow ignores the manually created ones and still prompts for namespace creation.  I am running Ubuntu 18.04LTS.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='holdenk' date='2019-12-02T01:13:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Christina-Young&gt;@Christina-Young&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you please include your API information as I've outlined above. This will allow us to debug your issue better. Specifically your responses for  and 
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='holdenk' date='2020-01-14T22:45:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/avdaredevil&gt;@avdaredevil&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 what was the PR with the fix that added polling to fix issues with namespace creation?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='holdenk' date='2020-01-22T00:02:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4364&gt;#4364&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4384&gt;#4384&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='holdenk' date='2020-02-06T18:40:19Z'>
		It looks like the PRs have been merged so I'm going to close this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>