<bug id='4358' author='ryandawsonuk' open_date='2019-10-21T11:03:46Z' closed_time='2020-04-23T03:53:41Z'>
	<summary>kfctl build different structure for local or remote kfdef</summary>
	<description>
I am following the flow from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4040&gt;#4040&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If I do a kfctl build -f with https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubeflow/manifests/master/kfdef/kfctl_existing_arrikto.yaml then I get an app.yaml file generated. If I copy the same file to a local path and reference that then I do not get an app.yaml file, meaning that I can't then perform the apply step.
Also the directory structures generated are different. I get a kustomize directory under kfapp. If I use a local path to a kfdef file then I get a kustomize directory parallel to the kfapp dir.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2019-10-21T11:03:55Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2019-10-22T01:09:11Z'>
		I think this is a duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/issues/54&gt;kubeflow/kfctl#54&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. The name of the YAMl file should be whatever the user defines.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2019-10-22T10:05:25Z'>
		Good point, the file generated is indeed kfctl_existing_arrikto.yaml and not app.yaml.
I've re-titled the issue as the other aspect of this I think isn't a duplicate. Namely that when I build from a remote file I get a kustomize folder under kfapp. When I build from a local file then the kustomize directory is placed parallel to the kfapp.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2020-01-10T11:19:55Z'>
		Related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/4301&gt;#4301&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2020-01-16T19:12:20Z'>
		/duplicate
/area kfctl
/kind bug
/priority p2
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ryandawsonuk' date='2020-04-16T03:07:55Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>