<bug id='4400' author='barlock' open_date='2019-10-24T21:45:07Z' closed_time='2020-05-02T14:53:32Z'>
	<summary>Unable to setup OIDC with a domain</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
I'm trying to deploy an authenticated Kubeflow deployment onto an existing k8s cluster on IBM's k8s service.
I'm using the existing_arikto config. After generating and applying (or just applying in the 0.7 branch) I'm able to access the working OIDC with IP addresses.
After an unknown period of time, I can no longer access it with the IP address.
For the 0.7 branch I use IKS's managed Istio and Knative "plugin" to configure both for IBM's ingresses.
Once deployed, I change the host in the kubeflow-gateway from * to my domain, something like (kubeflow.&lt;cluster_name&gt;..containers.appdomain.cloud), for both kubeflow and dex in the 0.6.2 branch, and for just kubeflow in the 0.7 branch. I can't access the kubeflow UI with or without Auth, It gives a 404 for the dashboard and a 504 for dex.
I also tried leaving the gateway as * and changing the virtual services's host, same result.
What did you expect to happen:
I expected to have a kubeflow deployment accessible with auth through dex at the domain specified.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]

I've looked through the code and couldn't find any place to specify a hostname, it seems that the manifests hardcode a *. Is there a supported way to configure a domain? The docs hint at configuring at it and forcing https, both sound great, I'm not sure how to make it work though.
If this is possible, docs should probably be updated, I found a KUBEFLOW_ENDPOINT and OIDC_ENDPOINT those change the values in the services, but not in the router.
I think IBM's ingress terminates TLS before it gets into the cluster, but I'm uncertain, I do have certificates inside the cluster I could configure, but I don't know what to do with them, istio-ingressgatway-certs in the istio-system namespace seems promising, but I don't know.
A base deploy from current master, with istio being installed by an addon, and not via kfctl, returns 504s for both port forwarding and using the loadbalancer's IP

Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.2 and 0.7.0-rc5
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): 0.6.2 and 0.7.0-rc5
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube) IBM IKS
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): 1.15.5
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): Ubuntu
Istio Version (deployed manually with addon): 1.3.3

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='barlock' date='2019-10-24T21:45:10Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.90. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='barlock' date='2019-10-25T04:27:52Z'>
		I'm still uncertain about the 0.6.x branch, but I've been able to get it working for the most part in the 0.7-rc5 branch. Though I am having issues configuring, but I'll open a new issue...
The one thing I had to do was I would get  (similar issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/3975&gt;#3975&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) and if I turn  the  it goes away.
That seems fine, but I'm uncertain what effect it has generally on the rest of the system.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='barlock' date='2019-10-28T12:23:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/animeshsingh&gt;@animeshsingh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 looks like a combination of IBM and the existing arrikto config; could you please take a look?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='barlock' date='2020-01-26T13:10:28Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='barlock' date='2020-01-26T14:10:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/barlock&gt;@barlock&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 does the problem exist in the latest v0.7 existing_arrikto config?
If yes, what is the issue you are seeing there?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='barlock' date='2020-04-25T14:40:22Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>