<bug id='4439' author='sarjeet2013' open_date='2019-10-31T06:15:12Z' closed_time='2019-11-02T20:14:39Z'>
	<summary>GCP config yaml spec.secrets.secretSource` is configured empty for basic-auth</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
Hitting the following error when running kfctl apply with gcp config 0.7* yaml:
kfctl apply -- -V -f kfctl_gcp_basic_auth.0.7.0.yaml
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;INFO[0036] Creating GCP secrets for basic auth...        filename="gcp/gcp.go:1612"
ERRO[0036] There was a problem getting the password for basic auth; error No secret source provided for secret password  filename="gcp/gcp.go:1555"
INFO[0036] Error is not a KfError; No secret source provided for secret password  filename="apis/kferrors.go:59"
Error:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 520 with message: gcp apply could not create secrets Error cannot create basic auth login secret; No secret source provided for secret password
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

What did you expect to happen:
kfctl apply works fine and able to see the pods in running state.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
I tried to debug the issue but not able to root cause the issue. The following env are set before kfctl is run.
KUBEFLOW_USERNAME=testuser
KUBEFLOW_PASSWORD=testpassword
Here is the excerpt from yaml:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;secrets:
  - name: password
    secretSource: {}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Looking at the code, the above secretSource should have populated with the hashed password.
Environment:


Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard):
0.7.0


kfctl version: (use kfctl version):
kfctl v0.7.0-rc.5-20-g618c77be


Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube)
GKE


Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
Client Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"16", GitVersion:"v1.16.2", GitCommit:"c97fe5036ef3df2967d086711e6c0c405941e14b", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-10-15T23:41:55Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.10", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"darwin/amd64"}
Server Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14+", GitVersion:"v1.14.7-gke.14", GitCommit:"d7951e52ecdf56a1de9e031c553569ec13849a80", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-10-11T23:17:57Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.9b4", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}


OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):


	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sarjeet2013' date='2019-10-31T06:15:25Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sarjeet2013' date='2019-10-31T13:30:53Z'>
		I was able to reproduce this behavior using
kubeflow/manifests - v0.7.0-rc.2-16-gd6dad08
kubeflow/kubeflow - v0.4.0-rc.1-802-gd66f8b97

Running `kfctl apply -v -f kfctl_gcp_basic_auth.yaml succeeded

I didn't get the error @sarjeet2013 mentioned above


However, the secret source in my YAML is empty (see below)
Running kfctl apply a second time results in the error listed above

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ERRO[0027] There was a problem getting the password for basic auth; error No secret source provided for secret password  filename="gcp/gcp.go:1555"
INFO[0027] Error is not a KfError; No secret source provided for secret password  filename="apis/kferrors.go:59"
Error:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with message: coordinator Apply failed for gcp:  (kubeflow.error): Code 520 with message: gcp apply could not create secrets Error cannot create basic auth login secret; No secret source provided for secret password
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;



Editing the KFDef YAML file to have a secrets stanza like the following fixes things
secrets:
- name: password
  secretSource:
    envSource:
      Name: KUBEFLOW_PASSWORD



&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/files/3793788/kfctl_gcp_basic_auth.0.7.0.yaml.txt&gt;kfctl_gcp_basic_auth.0.7.0.yaml.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I see three bugs.


When filling in the defaults for basic auth here we store the secret as a hashed literal source

This is a bug; the secret should be stored as an environment source



For EnvSource.Name capitalization is wrong in the json spec it should be name not Name
*



kubeflow/bootstrap/pkg/apis/apps/kfdef/v1beta1/application_types.go


         Line 99
      in
      41dd816






 Name string `json:"Name,omitempty"` 







ConfigConverters doesn't strip out literal sources here

This is a bug; its not related to this issue



&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Explanation&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;



We never want to serialize actual secrets into the KFDef spec file. This is because the KFDef file is intended to be stored in git and we don't want secrets in git


So when we serialize KFDef we only want to allow references to secrets i.e. an ENVSource as opposed to a HashedSource or LiteralSource


So in gcp.go when backfilling the default secret we should be using an EnvSource not a hashedSource


Using a HashedSource and not an EnvSource explain why it works the first time you run kfctl apply because the secret is stored in memory


		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sarjeet2013' date='2019-10-31T17:58:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This works for me. Can use it temporarily until the issue is fixed.

Editing the KFDef YAML file to have a secrets stanza like the following fixes things

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;secrets:
- name: password
  secretSource:
    envSource:
      Name: KUBEFLOW_PASSWORD
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sarjeet2013' date='2019-11-02T20:14:39Z'>
		I just deployed with basic auth using
kubeflow/kubeflow - v0.7.0-rc.7-3-g8dbde9d8
kubeflow/manifests - v0.7.0-rc.2-19-g317c0d8
Everything work so I'm marking this fixed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>