<bug id='4512' author='discordianfish' open_date='2019-11-20T13:49:36Z' closed_time='2020-08-02T11:52:33Z'>
	<summary>istio-policy runs out of memory, no way to adjust limits</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
After running kubeflow for a while with minimal number of users/notebooks (~5) and a bunch of workflows istio-policy started crash-looping because mixer ran out of memory.
What did you expect to happen:
The memory limits should be set sufficiently high to prevent it from crashing.
Anything else you would like to add:
The memory usage might scale with the number of notebooks/istio services in which case a vertical pod autoscaler should be added.
As a stop-gap there should be at least a kustomize option to set the memory limit
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.2
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): 0.6.2

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='discordianfish' date='2019-11-20T13:49:48Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='discordianfish' date='2019-11-20T13:50:38Z'>
		I'd also think it would be completely reasonable to not bundle istio at all but document how to install istio from upstream sources.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='discordianfish' date='2020-01-15T22:11:18Z'>
		/area engprod
/priority p2
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='discordianfish' date='2020-04-14T22:45:24Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='discordianfish' date='2020-04-27T08:24:57Z'>
		/reopen
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='discordianfish' date='2020-04-27T08:25:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/discordianfish&gt;@discordianfish&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: Reopened this issue.

In response to this:

/reopen

Instructions for interacting with me using PR comments are available here.  If you have questions or suggestions related to my behavior, please file an issue against the kubernetes/test-infra repository.

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='discordianfish' date='2020-07-26T08:45:34Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>