<bug id='4515' author='abhijeetchauhan' open_date='2019-11-21T16:20:12Z' closed_time='2020-04-22T19:32:13Z'>
	<summary>Cannot terminate a kubeflow pipeline run.</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
I have created a simple mnist training pipeline with one component. The pipeline fails to pull the gcr image due to insufficient permission and is stuck in an infinite loop. It shows the following error messages:
This step is in Pending state with this message: ImagePullBackOff: Back-off pulling image "gcr.io/ml-team-258801/mnist_tutorial_mlp_regular_minst"
I used the UI button to terminate the run but it has no effect on the actual termination. The experiment is still running.
What did you expect to happen:
To terminate the experiment and stop using resources.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
When i click on terminate button it shows the following message.
Do you want to terminate this run? This action cannot be undone. This will terminate any running pods, but they will not be deleted.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 0.6.2
kfctl version: (use kfctl version):
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube)
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='abhijeetchauhan' date='2019-11-21T16:20:26Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='abhijeetchauhan' date='2020-01-15T22:08:00Z'>
		/area pipelines
/priority p2
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='abhijeetchauhan' date='2020-04-14T22:45:26Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>