<bug id='4576' author='jetbasrawi' open_date='2019-12-16T15:33:27Z' closed_time='2020-04-14T16:45:16Z'>
	<summary>[GCP] CLI Deployment fails after using kfctl delete. Backend unhealthy</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
kfctl delete, soft deletes -vm, -admin, -user service accounts. Does not recreate these accounts or change them to undeleted. They remain prefixes with "deleted:serviceAccount:" Subsequent deployment results in unhealthy backend due to permissions error.
** steps **


Followed the instructions for CLI deployment to GCP.
kfctl apply -V -f  ${CONFIG_FILE}


Used kfctl delete
(kfctl delete -V -f ${CONFIG_FILE}, --delete_storage)


Reinstalled using CLI deployment.
kfctl apply -V -f  ${CONFIG_FILE}


No access to endpoint in browser


One of the backends was showing as unhealthy
kubectl describe ingress -n istio-system


After following Troubleshooting guides and much debugging found the following ERROR on cloud-endpoints-controller-XX


2019/12/16 14:16:04 [ERROR] Could not sync state: [ERROR] Failed to creat Cloud Endpoints service: serviceName: &lt;kfname&gt;.endpoints.&lt;my project&gt;.cloud.goog, err: googleapi: Error 403: Caller does not have permission 'servicemanagement.services.create' on project &lt;my project&gt;., forbidden


Checked the IAM service accounts.
 gcloud iam service-accounts list --format=yaml
The -vm, -admin and -user service accounts created by kubeflow are present and not marked as deleted in any way.


Checked IAM page in GCP Console
The -vm, -admin and -user accounts are prefixed with "deleted:serviceAccount:"


Removed these accounts via GCP Console


Ran kubecl again to apply the config
kfctl apply -V -f  ${CONFIG_FILE}


What did you expect to happen:
If not able to undelete these accounts, I would expect the deployment to at least flag the error.
Anything else you would like to add:
A workaround is that these accounts can be removed via the GCP console or CLI and the kfctl deployment re-creates them and the backends resolve as healthy.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: 0.7.0
kfctl version: v0.7.0
Kubernetes platform: GKE
Kubernetes version: v0.7.0
OS MacOS  Mojave 10.14.6

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jetbasrawi' date='2019-12-16T15:33:48Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jetbasrawi' date='2020-01-08T15:43:11Z'>
		/area kfctl
/priority p0
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jetbasrawi' date='2020-04-07T16:03:02Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>