<bug id='4737' author='Kyrremann' open_date='2020-02-05T11:25:50Z' closed_time='2020-05-06T10:36:26Z'>
	<summary>K8s authrequests filling up</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug

I'm having a problem where Dex is generating a buck load of authrequests, which slowly over time will kill my apiserver. There is already this issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dexidp/dex/issues/1292&gt;dexidp/dex#1292&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, but I was curious if other has had similar problems.
For me it seems like it's API calls to Jupyter that needs to log in all the time, as

/jupyter/api/namespaces//notebooks Cookie not set, redirecting to login

is logged several times each seconds (from authservice). And this again is coming from the jupyter dashboard (aka centraldashboard).
I would also note that I'm using an external load balancer, where I manually added the node ports. Meaning that we have kubeflow.company.no for the dashboard and kubeflow.company.no:5556 for dex.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: v0.6.2
kfctl version: v0.6.2-0-g47a0e4c7
Kubernetes platform: on-prem
Kubernetes version: v1.15.4
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): coreos

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T11:26:02Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




kind/bug
0.95



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T12:11:01Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Kyrremann&gt;@Kyrremann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for the detailed bug report.
I believe there are two orthogonal issues here:

Backend is accumulating too much state. Dex should take measures to prevent that (eg expire time, rate limiting, using a JWT to avoid storing state, etc).
Something in your cluster is constantly accessing Dex while unauthenticated.

IMO, we should take two measures here:

Move the Dex state off of etcd. We don't want Dex crashing the Kubernetes etcd.
Pinpoint the reason why so many unauthenticated requests are generated.

You say that you believe those requests are coming from the Central Dashboard.
What lead you to believe that?
I could think of a scenario where the CentralDashboard is open and constantly pings for the Notebooks, gets logged out in the meantime and ends up accumulating a lot of storage in Dex.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T13:19:57Z'>
		/area front-end
/priority p1
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T13:23:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jtfogarty&gt;@jtfogarty&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I believe this is more of an auth issue, since it's related to Dex:
/assign &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

/remove-area front-end
/area auth
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T13:24:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: Those labels are not set on the issue: 

In response to this:

@jtfogarty I believe this is more of an auth issue, since it's related to Dex:
/assign @yanniszark
/remove-area front-end
/area auth

Instructions for interacting with me using PR comments are available here.  If you have questions or suggestions related to my behavior, please file an issue against the kubernetes/test-infra repository.

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T13:26:03Z'>
		Agree that there is two problem, and moving Dex out would be a safe measurement for future problems.
About &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/2&gt;#2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which is the main problem for me. The reason for that I'm "blaming"  central is that the jupyter dashboard is talking with the API nonstop to get the list of notebooks:

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1830501/73845634-55471b00-4823-11ea-92ed-a1bca773c505.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It may also ask for namespaces as your suggestion.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-05T13:36:38Z'>
		I would expect the Jupyter UI is constantly polling the APIServer in order to get info about notebooks to display.  Its possible that maybe using a watch would be more efficient.
If this is triggering APIServer auth requests, I suspect this might be related to the subject access review checks performed by the notebook UI server.
It looks like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Kyrremann&gt;@Kyrremann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is using 0.6.2 which predates subject access review checks.
/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kimwnasptd&gt;@kimwnasptd&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-02-06T08:17:21Z'>
		Maybe one of the issues in my setup is that I have different address for issuer and redirect?
What is the normal config?
From my Dex configmap:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;issuer: https://kubeflow.company.no:5556/dex
staticClients:
- redirectURIs:
   - https://kubeflow.company.no/login/oidc
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

And from env-vars from Authservice:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;OIDC_PROVIDER:          https://kubeflow.company.no:5556/dex
SELF_URL:               https://kubeflow.company.no
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-05-06T09:02:17Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-05-06T10:36:26Z'>
		just wanted to say that this has been solved in kubeflow v1.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-05-06T12:11:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Kyrremann&gt;@Kyrremann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 how has this been fixed? Do you mean the JWA is not polling as much?
Or that Dex has changed its database?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Kyrremann' date='2020-05-06T12:26:59Z'>
		Not sure what fixed it, but Dex manage to clean up its resources, so they don't build up.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>