<bug id='4749' author='daikeshi' open_date='2020-02-10T18:24:52Z' closed_time='2020-06-17T20:40:44Z'>
	<summary>Profile controller uses project id from user sa for identity namespace</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
We have teams in different gcp projects are using a shared Kubeflow cluster.  When I try to use a gcp service account from a different project for gcpServiceAccount field in a user's profile, profile-controller throws an error:
Identity namespace does not exist (${PROJECT_ID}.svc.id.goog)
It seems the project id used in identity namespace is inferred from user's gcp service account. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/master/components/profile-controller/controllers/plugin_workload_identity.go#L54&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/blob/master/components/profile-controller/controllers/plugin_workload_identity.go#L54&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

What did you expect to happen:
I think it might make more sense to use the id of the project where Kubeflow cluster was created in.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard):
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): 0.7.1
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): GKE
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): v1.14.8-gke.33
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): mac OS Mojave v10.14.6

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='daikeshi' date='2020-02-10T18:25:10Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




kind/bug
0.98



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='daikeshi' date='2020-02-11T06:18:18Z'>
		/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kunmingg&gt;@kunmingg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='daikeshi' date='2020-05-11T11:22:49Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='daikeshi' date='2020-05-18T13:20:59Z'>
		I don't know that we will fix this issue.
Per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/manifests/issues/1136&gt;kubeflow/manifests#1136&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I think we are moving away from profiles and bootstrapping namespaces using GitOps and declarative packages.
We are also moving to using Cloud Config Connector.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/gcp-blueprints&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/gcp-blueprints&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So in this new world if you wanted to configure which GCP service account is bound to a KSA you would just modify the K8s resource and if necessary create an IAMPolicyMember to grant the appropriate workload identity on the GCP SA.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='daikeshi' date='2020-05-19T02:18:16Z'>
		Tha's OK. We currently use a fork of profile controller (with the fix) as the workaround.
We will need some migration after Kubeflow deprecates profile in the future, but it should be fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='daikeshi' date='2020-06-15T17:52:28Z'>
		Removing from 1.1 because I don't think anyone is working on it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='daikeshi' date='2020-06-17T13:40:49Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the fix I made has already been merged in master with this PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/pull/4754&gt;#4754&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I think we just need to publish a new image and update the deployment manifest. Will that be automatically taken care of in Kubeflow 1.1 release so we can remove our fork? Let me know if there's anything I can help with.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='daikeshi' date='2020-06-17T20:40:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/5067&gt;#5067&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is tracking the release of the profile controller for KF 1.1
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>