<bug id='4802' author='karlschriek' open_date='2020-02-27T09:20:52Z' closed_time='2020-08-19T06:43:26Z'>
	<summary>For alb-ingress-controller the cluster-name arg defaults to name of folder where kfdef is stored</summary>
	<description>
When rolling out KF1.0 using kfctl_aws_cognito.1.0.1.yaml (and also kfctl_aws.1.0.1.yaml) , the cluster-name arg in the alb container spec defaults to the name of the folder in which the kfdef file is, regardless of what is input into the kustomize config.
For example, deploying kubeflow with:
/path/to/kfctl apply -V -f /path/to/my_folder/kfctl_aws_cognito.1.0.1.yaml
kubectl -n kubeflow get deployment/alb-ingress-controller -o yaml yields:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;apiVersion: extensions/v1beta1
kind: Deployment
...
spec:
  template:
    spec:
      containers:
      - args:
        - --ingress-class=alb
        - --cluster-name=my_folder
        image: docker.io/amazon/aws-alb-ingress-controller:v1.1.2
        imagePullPolicy: Always
        name: alb-ingress-controller
        resources: {}
        terminationMessagePath: /dev/termination-log
        terminationMessagePolicy: File

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Currently this has to be patched manually afterward deployment.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): dev_local
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): v1.0.1
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): EKS
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): 1.1.4
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='karlschriek' date='2020-02-27T09:21:13Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




kind/bug
0.74



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-16T23:41:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karlschriek&gt;@karlschriek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 have you tried 1.0.1? I think it should not be a problem for 1.0.0 and 1.0.1. I am curious why it happen.. We replace the name from  right?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-20T08:30:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , yep in the yaml file I use my cluster name is correctly set. Haven't tried 1.0.1 yet, will do so next week.
I just realised something though, which might be a strange coincidence, could maybe point to where to look for the issue. I am currently rolling Kubeflow out more or less like this:
/path/to/kf/kfctl apply -V -f /path/to/kf_configs/kfctl_aws_cognito.1.0.0.yaml
I.e., the subfolder within which the YAML file is found is called kf_configs, which is the name that gets pulled into the argument  - --cluster-name=kf_configs. Seems a bit strange to me that this might be the case, but I can test it out a bit next week.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-20T22:44:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karlschriek&gt;@karlschriek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Cool. Let me know your results. This case is weird to me.. before we , we change cluster name. If there's something happen in wrong, it should be 
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-24T17:08:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , just tried it out again with 1.0.1 and also played around with the folder names. It is definitely the case that the name of the subfolder is being taken over as the cluster name
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-24T17:20:53Z'>
		Have pinpointed it a bit more. I generate my yaml file by using sed to replace my cluster name, nodegroup role names etc, but then when I do kfctl apply this yaml get overwritten with a new one where:

some metadata is added
A unique usageId is generated
CognitoUserPoolArn, CognitoUserPoolDomain, CognitoAppClientId and certArn are added to the cognito overlay
a status section is added
and.... my cluster-name is overwritten with the name of the folder

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-24T19:53:20Z'>
		I seem to remember in an older version of kfctl  there was an init step where a folder was created with the name of the cluster. Maybe this is a remnant from there?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-25T13:22:24Z'>
		Very first line when running kfctl apply:
INFO[0000] No name specified in KfDef.Metadata.Name; defaulting to kf_configs based on location of config file: ....
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-25T17:29:09Z'>
		
Very first line when running kfctl apply:
INFO[0000] No name specified in KfDef.Metadata.Name; defaulting to kf_configs based on location of config file: ....

This log is helpful.  by default is empty. I check kfctl logic and it does infer the name if kfDef.Metadata.name is not set.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/blob/088f927bd447aeee68d8f6de7fd0434242e95a85/pkg/kfapp/coordinator/coordinator.go#L195&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/blob/088f927bd447aeee68d8f6de7fd0434242e95a85/pkg/kfapp/coordinator/coordinator.go#L195&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Checking the logic here.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/blob/088f927bd447aeee68d8f6de7fd0434242e95a85/pkg/kfapp/coordinator/coordinator.go#L283-L302&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/blob/088f927bd447aeee68d8f6de7fd0434242e95a85/pkg/kfapp/coordinator/coordinator.go#L283-L302&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It actually find base dir name as name. In my case, spark is my clusterName, it's also the kfDef.metadata.Name. Inference is correct.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;INFO[0000] No name specified in KfDef.Metadata.Name; defaulting to spark based on location of config file: /tmp/workshop/spark/kfctl_aws.yaml.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I think you meet problems is because setting. In aws documentation, we ask to use
KF_DIR is app dir in kfctl and it's base name is ${AWS_CLUSTER_NAME}.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;export KF_NAME=${AWS_CLUSTER_NAME}
export KF_DIR=${BASE_DIR}/${KF_NAME}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-26T12:24:56Z'>
		Yes I also noticed yesterday that if you follow the installation guide exactly then this shouldn't be a problem. Wouldn't it be a better approach instead that the user gets the abilility to set KfDef.Metadata.Name explicitly in the kfdef somewhere? At the moment setting the cluster-name in kfdef is ignored.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='karlschriek' date='2020-03-26T15:06:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karlschriek&gt;@karlschriek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 All kfdef ignore the name. We probably can override the logic in kfctl aws plugin to explicitly set the name. Then it won't do inference. Feel free to file a issue or PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='karlschriek' date='2020-08-12T03:10:12Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>