<bug id='4855' author='Oblynx' open_date='2020-03-12T09:37:04Z' closed_time='2020-09-06T12:59:23Z'>
	<summary>[auth] application_secret exposed in configmap</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
I applied the default kfctl_istio_dex.yaml configuration and realized that the OIDC client secret, used by the authservice-0 pod to retrieve the id_token from my OIDC provider, is stored in a configmap and not in a secret. Specifically in istio-system/oidc-authservice-parameters.
What did you expect to happen:
To store the client secret in a secret. I'm integrating kubeflow on-prem with an external OIDC provider.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): v1.0.0
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): v1.0-0-g94c35cf
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): vanilla (openstack magnum)
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): v1.15.3
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): Fedora 29.20181126.0 (Atomic Host)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Oblynx' date='2020-03-12T09:37:16Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Oblynx' date='2020-03-19T21:36:39Z'>
		/area istio
/priority p1
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Oblynx' date='2020-04-20T14:59:05Z'>
		/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/krishnadurai&gt;@krishnadurai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Oblynx' date='2020-04-20T17:05:17Z'>
		Thanks for opening up an issue.
This is because of a Dex limitation.
It doesn't support getting the app secret from an environment variable or a file, so it is included inside its configmap. (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dexidp/dex/issues/1099&gt;dexidp/dex#1099&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
However, I can see there was a recent improvement on that front: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dexidp/dex/pull/1664&gt;dexidp/dex#1664&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I see two ways for resolving this issue:

Use environment variables if Dex allows it now (dexidp/dex#1664).
Use an init container to render the Dex configuration.

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Oblynx' date='2020-05-28T17:29:26Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Oblynx&gt;@Oblynx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Hi Konstantinos - We have not found a resource to work on this in the Kubeflow 1.1 timeframe.   What is your priority for this enhancement?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Oblynx' date='2020-06-01T09:07:21Z'>
		Hi, thanks for checking in!
Leaking the OIDC secret could help malicious tenants compromise the deployment. For small scale deployments with select users this isn't a big concern, but we are considering a production deployment by late September where mitigation will be necessary.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Oblynx' date='2020-08-30T11:44:03Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>