<bug id='4973' author='leela-uppuluri' open_date='2020-04-22T21:05:29Z' closed_time='2020-08-14T09:28:17Z'>
	<summary>Cannot access kubeflow dashboard as admin</summary>
	<description>
What steps did you take and what happened:
I have deployed the kubeflow installation on open source kubernetes cluster and also by default my profile owns a kubernetes namespace of the same name along with a collection of kubernetes resources. After setting up the Istio load balancer and configuring the node port forwarding for the istio-ingressgateway I could able to access a fresh kubeflow dashboard which asks me to create namespace for my account but I already have namespaces available of my k8s cluster with kubeflow and my name. I still did create one using kubeflow dashboard UI and able to direct into the homepage but I see only one namespace and not as an admin.
What did you expect to happen:
I should be able to access kubeflow dashboard as an admin and should be able to manage all the contributors.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): build version dev_local
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): v1.0.1
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): open source k8s
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): v1.15
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release): Ubuntu 18.04.4 LTS

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43678538/80033888-13895080-84b3-11ea-9751-1f074ace3929.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='leela-uppuluri' date='2020-04-22T21:05:39Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




kind/bug
0.81



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='leela-uppuluri' date='2020-08-06T22:04:35Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>