<bug id='5006' author='paulcarlton-ww' open_date='2020-05-08T08:38:54Z' closed_time='2020-11-14T08:49:37Z'>
	<summary>Authentication for kubeflow dashboard not working</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug

I installed kubeflow on an AWS EKS cluster using instructions at &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I've tried specifying basic auth and cognito without success, I get no login prompt when I point browser at the url.
What did you expect to happen:
A login screen
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
My config for basic auth
auth:
        basicAuth:
          password:
            name: password
          username: admin
for cognito I used
plugins:
  - kind: KfAwsPlugin
    metadata:
      creationTimestamp: null
      name: aws
    spec:
      auth:
        cognito:
          certArn: arn:aws:acm:eu-west-1:xxx:certificate/xxx
          cognitoAppClientId: xxx
          cognitoUserPoolArn: arn:aws:cognito-idp:eu-west-1:xxxx:userpool/eu-west-1_xxxx
          cognitoUserPoolDomain: kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com
      enablePodIamPolicy: true
      region: us-west-1
Environment:

kubeflow version: v0.0.2
kfctl version: fctl v1.0.2-0-ga476281
Kubernetes platform: aws eks
Kubernetes version:
ate:"clean", BuildDate:"2020-03-25T14:58:59Z", GoVersion:"go1.13.8", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
Server Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"15+", GitVersion:"v1.15.11-eks-af3caf", GitCommit:"af3caf6136cd355f467083651cc1010a499f59b1", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2020-03-27T21:51:36Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.17", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
OS:
NAME="Ubuntu"
VERSION="18.04.4 LTS (Bionic Beaver)"
ID=ubuntu
ID_LIKE=debian
PRETTY_NAME="Ubuntu 18.04.4 LTS"
VERSION_ID="18.04"
HOME_URL="https://www.ubuntu.com/"
SUPPORT_URL="https://help.ubuntu.com/"
BUG_REPORT_URL="https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/"
PRIVACY_POLICY_URL="https://www.ubuntu.com/legal/terms-and-policies/privacy-policy"
VERSION_CODENAME=bionic
UBUNTU_CODENAME=bionic

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-08T08:39:02Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




kind/bug
0.97


platform/aws
0.63



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-12T17:32:57Z'>
		cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-12T18:39:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paulcarlton-ww&gt;@paulcarlton-ww&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 basic auth doesn't work for AWS.  for cognito solution, do you see load balancer ready?

I get no login prompt when I point browser at the url.

Could you give more details on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-12T18:39:05Z'>
		/assign
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-13T07:34:08Z'>
		It all works either using istio ingress gateway configured as a load balancer in which case I can access kubeflow UI via my DNS name mapped to the AWS generated external address or using port forward with the ingress gateway configured as a node port. The problem is that I am not prompted to login and the user icon on the top right is grayed out. When I hover my mouse over this it says &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:anonymous@kubeflow.org&gt;anonymous@kubeflow.org&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-13T11:21:52Z'>
		When I configure it for cognito I set the istio ingressgateway to load balancer and can access it via external address or my kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com dns name. I've temporarily secured it by only allowing access from my IP address. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'll add your ip to the security group and send you my configuration details if that helps to diagnose this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-13T18:58:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paulcarlton-ww&gt;@paulcarlton-ww&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

anonymous@kubeflow.org is for kfctl_aws.yaml, cognito doesn't have this.
If you can visit load balancer from cognito setup, it will redirect you to cognito login page? What's the result?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-14T17:43:27Z'>
		I re set up cluster and deployed kubeflow, now it prompted me to create a user/namespace when I visited the ui the first time but still no authentication prompt
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-14T17:44:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'm following the instructions at &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/deploy/install-kubeflow/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/deploy/install-kubeflow/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

what am I doing wrong?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-15T13:56:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan&gt;@Jeffwan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Looking at the code it seems you also support oidc auth too, which is pretty much what I want. I might try that.
Also, now that I have configured a profile and associated it with an AWS iam user which I have registered using eksctl but because kubeflow has be down as an anonymous user in the UI I can't create a notebook in the profile's namespace.
However, on the up side, I have successfully run the Titanic survivors pipeline based on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jeffwan/aws-emr-titanic-ml-example&gt;https://github.com/Jeffwan/aws-emr-titanic-ml-example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/pipelines/blob/master/samples/contrib/aws-samples/titanic-survival-prediction&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/pipelines/blob/master/samples/contrib/aws-samples/titanic-survival-prediction&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-15T15:59:28Z'>
		This is what my istio-ingress looks like
kubectl get ingress istio-ingress  -n istio-system -o yaml
apiVersion: extensions/v1beta1
kind: Ingress
metadata:
  annotations:
    alb.ingress.kubernetes.io/auth-idp-cognito: '{"UserPoolArn":"arn:aws:cognito-idp:eu-west-1:xxxx:userpool/eu-west-1_NNyJaI9VZ","UserPoolClientId":"xxxx",
      "UserPoolDomain":"kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com"}'
    alb.ingress.kubernetes.io/auth-type: cognito
    alb.ingress.kubernetes.io/certificate-arn: arn:aws:acm:eu-west-1:xxxxcertificate/xxx-xxxx
    alb.ingress.kubernetes.io/listen-ports: '[{"HTTPS":443}]'
    alb.ingress.kubernetes.io/scheme: internet-facing
    kubectl.kubernetes.io/last-applied-configuration: |
      {"apiVersion":"extensions/v1beta1","kind":"Ingress","metadata":{"annotations":...}
    kubernetes.io/ingress.class: alb
  creationTimestamp: "2020-05-14T17:05:09Z"
  generation: 1
  labels:
    kustomize.component: istio-ingress
  name: istio-ingress
  namespace: istio-system
  resourceVersion: "6581"
  selfLink: /apis/extensions/v1beta1/namespaces/istio-system/ingresses/istio-ingress
  uid: 91817ef3-dc47-4ad7-bdd7-75b2bb58e5c6
spec:
  rules:
  - http:
      paths:
      - backend:
          serviceName: istio-ingressgateway
          servicePort: 80
        path: /*
status:
  loadBalancer: {}
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-15T20:29:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paulcarlton-ww&gt;@paulcarlton-ww&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Seems you are using custom domain name, have you checked this doc? &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/aws-e2e/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/aws-e2e/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-18T12:54:54Z'>
		Tried this but still not getting any prompt for user authentication.
When I try testing the ui in cognitio it logs me in but then fails when it tries to hit &lt;denchmark-link:https://kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com/oauth2/idpresponse?code=&gt;https://kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com/oauth2/idpresponse?code=&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
....
I can access kubeflow ui using http:// unauthenticated but when I try it with https:// it hangs
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-18T17:11:21Z'>
		It would be better for you to share more details like redirect url or https code you enter https://kubeflow.pc.weaveworks-cx.com etc.  Also, manually type cognito URI to check if you enter login page
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-18T18:19:36Z'>
		Will add more details if that helps but seems like this is not going to work for my workshop. We are using AWS events environment and I'm informed that there is no access to Route 53 so will not be able to create the domain and certificates needed for this solution.
Looks like the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/authentication-oidc/&gt;https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/aws/authentication-oidc/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 approach also requires the use of certificates.
You said that basic auth will not work on AWS, why not? My problem is without authentication the solution is rather insecure unless you use NodePort and port-forward access with is not very real world! Also, without user identity in the kubeflow UI I can't use namespaces due to access errors.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-05-18T19:52:35Z'>
		I added story for multi-user basic auth support here. We are working on that &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/manifests/issues/1164&gt;kubeflow/manifests#1164&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Port-forward is one safe solution in single user cluster, this is for testing purpose.

Also, without user identity in the kubeflow UI I can't use namespaces due to access errors.

This is not true. anonymous user will have a namespace the first time login the central dashboard.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-07-17T20:15:00Z'>
		I am also encountering what I think is the same issue. I setup a new cluster using kfctl_aws_cognito.v1.0.2.yaml and everything appears to be working, but when I visit the AWS LoadBalancer for istio-ingressgateway I get sent directly to the kubeflow homepage without any option to login. The Account icon in the top right is greyed out and says anonymous@kubeflow.org on mouse over. It has been a while since I initially set things up, but looking back at my history I see I also applied a filed called kubeflow-no-auth.yaml, though I can't find it anymore (sorry :( )
Regardless of whether or not I have Cognito setup properly I would expect to be able to get to a login screen and have a failed login. As it stands now, I am not able to even attempt to login through the UI.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-08-04T00:59:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lonnix&gt;@lonnix&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

em. Probably something wrong on auth-adaptor. I am working on open sourcing it and upgrade to higher level istio to make it more reliable.
At the same time, please try 1.1 and it should work well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='paulcarlton-ww' date='2020-11-05T02:11:51Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>