<bug id='5010' author='ConverJens' open_date='2020-05-11T12:37:28Z' closed_time='2020-09-10T20:00:05Z'>
	<summary>Sorry, /notebook is not a valid page</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
Deployed kfctl_istio_dex.v1.0.2.yaml in an on-prem k8s cluster. Created a notebook server through the centraldashboard notebook page successfully. Clicking on 'Connect' leads to
http://CLUSTER_IP:31380/notebook/admin/my-notebook
were error is shown.
Also, centraldashboard 'Recent Notebooks' also shows no notebooks in namespace even though they exist.
What did you expect to happen:
Jupyter server UI to open and 'Recent Notebooks' to be populated.
Anything else you would like to add:
The notebook server is accessible via port-forwarding and notebooks can be spawned and works as expected. All other pages (metadata, experiments etc) works as expected.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: v1beta1
kfctl version: v1.0.1-0-gf3edb9b
Kubernetes platform: vanilla on-prem k8s
Kubernetes version: v1.17.4
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-11T12:37:36Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




area/jupyter
1.00



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-11T12:37:36Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




area/jupyter
1.00



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-botdata/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-16T22:52:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ConverJens&gt;@ConverJens&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 have you searched GitHub for similar issues? This is likely an issue with your networking / ISTIO and similar issues in the past might have helpful information on debugging.
/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johnugeorge&gt;@johnugeorge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-18T09:26:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the response. I've looked at all the similar issues that I can find, closest seems to be: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/pipelines/issues/1442&gt;kubeflow/pipelines#1442&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. However, just like the last three comments on that issue, I'm on KubeFlow 1.0.X but the routing issue remains.
All other components (pipelines, artefacts, setting up notebook servers, etc) are working correctly and can be found through the dashboard. Only the jupyter server page is unavailable through the central dashboard. This leads me to believe that the kubeflow Istio installation is working as it should. Also, since port-forwarding to the notebook server works, the deployed service seems to work.
It might be the case that the notebook server service needs to register somewhere to enable service discovery and that that does't happen. Is it the case that this happens in some other way if KubeFlow is deployed on GCP or AWS?
I can't find any issues in any logs related to these components.
Any help or pointers ahead would be greatly appreciated!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-25T06:21:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johnugeorge&gt;@johnugeorge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yanniszark&gt;@yanniszark&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Any update on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-26T19:20:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ConverJens&gt;@ConverJens&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I think you are going to have to dive into ISTIO and the Dex setup to try to troubleshoot what's going on here.
The first thing to investigate is how the &lt;denchmark-link:https://istio.io/docs/tasks/traffic-management/ingress/ingress-control/&gt;ISTIO ingressgateway&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is deployed.
Per those instructions you should run
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;kubectl get svc istio-ingressgateway -n istio-system
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Is your ISTIO ingressgateway exposed via node port? via service type load balancer? Is it connected to a K8s ingress to wire it up to an external load balancer.
Then I would look at the virtual service for the notebook.

What is the path it is serving on?
Is the ISTIO gateway specified correctly?

If the gateway is in a different namespace then the gateway specification should include the namespace it is specified in



You might want to go through some of the ISTIO tutorials to understand how to expose services externally behind the gateway.
I think the &lt;denchmark-link:https://istio.io/docs/tasks/traffic-management/ingress/ingress-control/&gt;tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 uses httpbin. That might help you verify that your ISTIO is setup correctly and configured.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-26T19:50:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Again, thank you for your respons!
The istio-ingressgateway is exposed via node port:
NAME                   TYPE       CLUSTER-IP     EXTERNAL-IP   PORT(S) AGE   SELECTOR
istio-ingressgateway   NodePort   10.43.125.55   &lt;none&gt;        15020:31741/TCP,80:31380/TCP,443:31390/TCP,31400:31400/TCP,15029:32223/TCP,15030:32129/TCP,15031:32469/TCP,15032:30159/TCP,15443:31846/TCP   20d   app=istio-ingressgateway,istio=ingressgateway
As for the notebook, there is no virtual service deployed, only a service. If that is needed, I would assume that the notebook controller would delpoy this and not that I would need to do this myself. Is the virtual service required?
I will go through the tutorial and see if I can find anything else.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-26T19:53:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ConverJens&gt;@ConverJens&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes a virtual service is required. A virtual service is required to tell ISTIO how to route traffic to your backend. The ISTIO virtual service should be created by the notebook controller.
I would suggest looking at the notebook controller logs to see why the virtual service isn't being created.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-26T20:02:26Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Will do! Thanks for the pointer. I'll let you know what I find.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-27T11:00:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 You were right about the virtualservice. Adding it manually fixed made the notebook server reachable through the dashboard. Still haven't found why it wasn't automatically created.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-27T11:41:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Found the issue, for some reason the USE_ISTIO var is hard-coded to false in notebook-controller/base/deployment.yaml. So even though USE_ISTIO is set to true in notebook-controller/overlays/istio/param.env the Kustomize merge will fail since base/deployment.yaml doesn't use the variable USE_ISTIO. That resolves it for me. Thanks for the help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='ConverJens' date='2020-05-29T14:54:40Z'>
		There should be an overlay in istio that sets the env variable to the kustomize vars
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/manifests/blob/e06c9c0fa41a84580611bbe4e546028c9a560b35/jupyter/notebook-controller/overlays/istio/deployment.yaml#L12&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/manifests/blob/e06c9c0fa41a84580611bbe4e546028c9a560b35/jupyter/notebook-controller/overlays/istio/deployment.yaml#L12&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

In 1.1 we are moving away from vars and to a configmap so not sure how much more this is worth investigating
This works correctly on GCP so its possible its specific to kfctl_istio_dex.v1.0.2.yaml

@johnugeorge and @yanniszark do you want to investigate further or should we close?

		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='ConverJens' date='2020-06-01T06:23:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 There is an overlay with a var that sets USE_ISTIO=true. However, for some reason Kustomize still produces a configmap with USE_ISTIO=FALSE.
I'll chech if this is still an issue when 1.1.0 is released and let you know.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='ConverJens' date='2020-08-30T07:39:15Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='ConverJens' date='2020-09-03T08:29:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jlewi&gt;@jlewi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Just upgraded to KF 1.1.0 using kfctl_istio_dex.v1.1.0.yaml and did no longer have this issue so I think you can consider it solved.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='ConverJens' date='2020-10-05T19:45:21Z'>
		I believe this code causes the problem: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/manifests/blob/master/jupyter/notebook-controller/base/deployment_patch.yaml&gt;deployment_patch.yaml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 AFAIK it is still in master and in  branch. Similar to authors of the patch, I was not able to find any elegant solution, so ended up with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/agilestacks/components/blob/master/kubeflow-v1.0/ext/jupyter/notebook-controller/base/deployment_patch.yaml&gt;this&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Hope it will help to someone
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>