<bug id='5104' author='gettheguru' open_date='2020-07-03T12:22:07Z' closed_time='2020-07-03T13:09:18Z'>
	<summary>Dex SSO Query - when changing the default issuer from dex.auth.svc.cluster.local:5556</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug

[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
When integrated Kubeflow with Azure AD I have had to change away from the default Dex issuer config to be one that is https. This means changing away from the &lt;denchmark-link:http://dex.auth.svc.cluster.local:5556&gt;http://dex.auth.svc.cluster.local:5556&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 configuration
What did you expect to happen:
I can appreciate there is some configuration that will need to change in Kubeflow for expecting this as the new oidc-provider, but I am unsure how to go about changing these values and redeploying the pods.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
I expect this is an obvious issue but I am new to Kubeflow and would appreciate some guidance on how to make any necessary changes to the configuration file that was deployed and to update the deployment
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gettheguru' date='2020-07-03T12:22:15Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




area/kfctl
0.60



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://label-bot-prod.mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gettheguru' date='2020-07-03T12:22:15Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://label-bot-prod.mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gettheguru' date='2020-07-03T13:09:18Z'>
		Found solution through &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/4517&gt;#4517&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and updated the istio-system oidc-authservice-parameters configmap plus a few other configs rather than redeploying.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>