<bug id='5117' author='devashishshankar' open_date='2020-07-08T13:17:02Z' closed_time='2020-09-02T03:10:46Z'>
	<summary>Endpoint not created when reinstalling kubeflow</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
I had installed Kubeflow using the CLI on GKE. First installation generally works out well. However, I had some configuration changes - due to which I did kfctl delete followed by kfctl apply again. I have tried this multiple times with multiple kubeflow clusters (KF_NAME), but this doesn't seem to work.
I have tried troubleshooting, and I have the following observations:

Going to https://${KF_NAME}.endpoints.${PROJECT}.cloud.goog/ gives me a DNS error (DNS_PROBE_FINISHED_NXDOMAIN)
envoy-ingress shows one backend as unhealthy
kubectl describe cloudendpoint -n istio-system shows an active cloudendpoint
No endpoint entry is created in https://console.cloud.google.com/endpoints
Cloud IAP (https://console.cloud.google.com/security/iap) shows an "Error" in one of the backends (saying OAuth client is misconfigured). It auto turns off IAP. I have tried manually turning it on and reinstalling with no avail.

If 5 indeed is a real issue, why does it work when I do a fresh installation (with a new ${KF_NAME})? I export the same CLIENT_ID and CLIENT_SECRET in both cases.
Everything else looks okay (looking at various K8s deployments and services)
What did you expect to happen:
I expected my cluster to be recreated
Anything else you would like to add:
Currently, I workaround by creating a new kubeflow every time. However, that has a major con that all my data (notebooks, Pipelines are gone). We can't keep doing this with a production setup.
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): I installed it using kfctl_gcp_iap.v1.0.2.yaml
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): kfctl v1.0.2-0-ga476281
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): GKE
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version):
Client Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14", GitVersion:"v1.14.10", GitCommit:"575467a0eaf3ca1f20eb86215b3bde40a5ae617a", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2019-12-11T12:41:00Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.12", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"darwin/amd64"}
Server Version: version.Info{Major:"1", Minor:"14+", GitVersion:"v1.14.10-gke.45", GitCommit:"42bef28c2031a74fc68840fce56834ff7ea08518", GitTreeState:"clean", BuildDate:"2020-06-17T19:54:40Z", GoVersion:"go1.12.12b4", Compiler:"gc", Platform:"linux/amd64"}
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):
Mac OS 10.14

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='devashishshankar' date='2020-07-08T13:17:10Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




area/kfctl
0.88



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://label-bot-prod.mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='devashishshankar' date='2020-07-08T13:17:10Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://label-bot-prod.mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='devashishshankar' date='2020-09-02T03:10:46Z'>
		 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kubeflow/issues/5048&gt;#5048&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>