<bug id='5331' author='sameerbhadouria' open_date='2020-10-07T08:51:33Z' closed_time='2020-10-08T21:11:20Z'>
	<summary>default-editor unable to pull image from gcr</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
[A clear and concise description of what the bug is.]
Running the mnist example on the kubeflow installation via a notebook server. The cluster is configured to use workload identity. I am able to create/push the docker image to the gcr registry from the notebook. However, when I try to run the train job, the training pods fail to pull the image.
Error: Back-off pulling image "gcr.io/&lt;project-id&gt;/fairing-job/mnist:929CE29C": ImagePullBackOff
The gcr and the notebook server are in the same project.
What did you expect to happen:
Since push(write) worked, I had expected pull to work and successful completion of the train jobs.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
I am using a custom GSA which is bound to the KSA. Here are the list of roles granted to this gsa:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    "roles/viewer",
    "roles/source.admin",
    "roles/storage.admin",
    "roles/logging.logWriter",
    "roles/monitoring.metricWriter",
    "roles/monitoring.viewer"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I also have "roles/storage.objectViewer" on the backing GCS bucket for gcr.
Environment:


Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): build version dev_local. This is based of the new 1.1 version using the gcp blueprints.


kfctl version: (use kfctl version): N/A


Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube) - GCP


Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): 1.16.13-gke.401


OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):


	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sameerbhadouria' date='2020-10-07T08:51:41Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the labels:



Label
Probability




platform/gcp
0.51



Please mark this comment with  or  to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://label-bot-prod.mlbot.net/data/kubeflow/kubeflow&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sameerbhadouria' date='2020-10-08T21:11:20Z'>
		This is a miss on my part. I had not allowed access to the node pool service account to the gcr bucket.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>