<bug id='5411' author='munagekar' open_date='2020-11-16T07:58:51Z' closed_time='2020-11-30T09:04:09Z'>
	<summary>Central Dashboard is Slow</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
What steps did you take and what happened:
We have eleven profiles in our Kubeflow Cluster. The loading time of central dashboard is too slow.
It is blank for 10.44 seconds and completes loading after 21 seconds. Sometimes this also times out giving us errors as follows:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;An error occurred
{"error":"Failed to authorize with namespace resource reference.: Authorization failure.: InternalServerError: Failed to connect to the KFAM service.: Get http://ip:8081/kfam/v1/bindings?user=user@org.com: net/http: request canceled (Client.Timeout exceeded while awaiting headers)","message":"Failed to authorize with namespace resource reference.: Authorization failure.: InternalServerError: Failed to connect to the KFAM service.: Get ip:8081/kfam/v1/bindings?user=user@org.com: net/http: request canceled (Client.Timeout exceeded while awaiting headers)","code":13,"details":[{"@type":"type.googleapis.com/api.Error","error_message":"Internal Server Error","error_details":"Failed to authorize with namespace resource reference.: Authorization failure.: InternalServerError: Failed to connect to the KFAM service.: Get http://ip:8081/kfam/v1/bindings?user=user@org.com: net/http: request canceled (Client.Timeout exceeded while awaiting headers)"}]}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

What did you expect to happen:
A Faster Loading Time.
Anything else you would like to add:
[Miscellaneous information that will assist in solving the issue.]
I used the browser console to find out that the following are slow:

/api/workgroup/exists : 10.44 seconds. First this request is completed.
/api/workgroup/env-info: 11.25 seconds. Launched only after the first request is complete.

We also have disabled registration flow by setting the following environment.
        - name: REGISTRATION_FLOW
          value: "false"
Environment:

Kubeflow version: (version number can be found at the bottom left corner of the Kubeflow dashboard): 1.1 gcr.io/kubeflow-images-public/centraldashboard:v1.1.0-g35d7484a
kfctl version: (use kfctl version):
Kubernetes platform: (e.g. minikube): gke
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): v1.17.12-gke.150
OS (e.g. from /etc/os-release):

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='munagekar' date='2020-11-30T09:04:09Z'>
		Manually upgraded a few kubeflow deployments image to the latest release, seems to have fixed the problem. If you face this issue, I think an upgrade to kubeflow 1.2 should fix it.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>