<bug id='5431' author='karlschriek' open_date='2020-11-23T10:48:22Z' closed_time='2020-11-24T12:17:38Z'>
	<summary>KF 1.2.0 on EKS: May not add resource with an already registered id: rbac.authorization.k8s.io_v1_ClusterRoleBinding|~X|cluster-local-gateway-istio-system</summary>
	<description>
/kind bug
I am attempting to roll out KF 1.2.0 for the first time, using:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/releases/tag/v1.2.0&gt;https://github.com/kubeflow/kfctl/releases/tag/v1.2.0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubeflow/manifests/v1.2-branch/kfdef/kfctl_aws_cognito.v1.2.0.yaml&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubeflow/manifests/v1.2-branch/kfdef/kfctl_aws_cognito.v1.2.0.yaml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Which eventually results in the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;time="2020-11-23T10:43:23Z" level=error msg="Error evaluating kustomization manifest for cluster-local-gateway: accumulating resources: recursed merging from path 'base': may not add resource with an already registered id: rbac.authorization.k8s.io_v1_ClusterRoleBinding|~X|cluster-local-gateway-istio-system" filename="kustomize/kustomize.go:155"
Error: failed to apply:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with mes****ge: kfApp Apply failed for kustomize:  (kubeflow.error): Code 500 with mes****ge: error evaluating kustomization manifest for cluster-local-gateway: accumulating resources: recursed merging from path 'base': may not add resource with an already registered id: rbac.authorization.k8s.io_v1_ClusterRoleBinding|~X|cluster-local-gateway-istio-system

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This is on a clean installation on EKS 1.18.

Kubeflow version: 1.2.0
kfctl version: (use kfctl version): 1.2.0
Kubernetes version: (use kubectl version): 1.18 (EKS)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='karlschriek' date='2020-11-23T18:13:30Z'>
		I can't reproduce the issue
Suggestions:

Create a fully-new EKS cluster
Install Kubeflow 1.2 on the cluster

/assign
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='karlschriek' date='2020-11-24T06:03:51Z'>
		This is on a fully new EKS cluster already. But I am going to tear everyhing down again and redo from scratch, maybe I messed up somewhere.
Since this is a Kustomize error, it might have something to do with a change in how Kustomize deals with merges. I am using:
{Version:kustomize/v3.8.7 GitCommit:ad092cc7a91c07fdf63a2e4b7f13fa588a39af4f BuildDate:2020-11-11T23:14:14Z GoOs:linux GoArch:amd64}
UPDATE:
Just to be sure, I tore everything down and rebuilt again. Same result.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='karlschriek' date='2020-11-24T12:17:38Z'>
		Ok, so I did yet another clean install, this time also forcibly clearing any caches that might be lying around on the CI/CD workers. Went through this time. I can only assume that there were some hanging YAMLs for a previous 1.0 build.
Thanks for confirming that there is no trouble with the KF 1.2 rollout as such, that help to narrow down the problem.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>