<bug id='235' author='deveth0' open_date='2019-10-09T14:01:34Z' closed_time='2019-10-09T18:08:58Z'>
	<summary>[BUG] waveshare v1 does not display pwnagotchi correctly</summary>
	<description>
Since the installation of the RC1 my pwnagotchi does not display correctly anymore.
I think one reason is, that the display is no longer reset when the gotchi starts (or at least it looks like this).
Describe the bug
See imagd
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Install RC1 on a pi with waveshare v1 display
Enjoy

Expected behavior
I'd expect a clearer picture.
Screenshots
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1718655/66487974-8732b580-eaad-11e9-9a43-efcbd399d517.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment (please complete the following information):

Pwnagotchi version - RC1
OS version
Type of hardware - pi0w, waveshare v1
Any additional hardware used

Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T15:39:05Z'>
		weird, it is cleared &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/pwnagotchi/ui/display.py#L156&gt;https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/pwnagotchi/ui/display.py#L156&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ... might just be that the waveshare v1 have some pixels burnout problems?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T15:40:33Z'>
		Sry missed to say: with an older image it works fine (build a 2-3 days ago)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T15:46:33Z'>
		even weirder, literally nothing in the v1 library code or in how it's used in the display.py changed from the first import: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/commit/cbf7511e1754a41a7f3144d1813603b0bb8b9cef#diff-358ffb3e7079891a9cb715e6738fba48&gt;cbf7511#diff-358ffb3e7079891a9cb715e6738fba48&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T15:48:46Z'>
		Yeah I also checked for changes. I'll get another pi with a waveshare tomorrow hopefully, will try, if I can reproduce it there.
Currently it looks a bit as if the clear is canceled somehow. In older versions the complete screen turned black from outside to inside, now only a few pixel are black and then the first image is displayed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T15:50:57Z'>
		you can try to manually stop the service (sudo service pwnagotchi stop), clearing the display manually (sudo pwnagotchi --clear) and restart (sudo service pwnagotchi start).
It might be an hardware issue and the reason why there's a V2 of that display :D Your help debugging this is precious and appreciated, thanks 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T16:02:35Z'>
		i can confirm that behavior with the ri0w and the ws1^display, except that i still had the default waveshare logo on screen. then changed the setting to waveshare_v1 and rebootet. the image got darker and degraded, for the lack of a better word.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T16:03:34Z'>
		does running a manual clear as described fixes the problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T16:12:59Z'>
		yes and no :)
funny thing is: i have an ethernet dongle which stayed connected during the advised power down, i just removed the wall wart from the wall.
this time i removed it, and it cleared the screen during boot/start.
then i logged in - before the face appeared - and stopped the service
the clear screen command worked.
service restart produced another clear screen then the face came on.
so it works
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T16:28:25Z'>
		i just tried to manually clear the screen using the command mentioned above. it just clears a few pixel on the outside and not the complete screen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T16:29:19Z'>
		it sounds like an hardware bug because that's a full clear
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T17:24:45Z'>
		Damn, seems as if you are right and the display just broke down. I got a complete refresh using the waveshare sdk/examples but now not even this works anymore. Sad, just survived a week or so. I think this can be closed then. Can you recommend another display or was this just bad luck?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='deveth0' date='2019-10-09T18:09:28Z'>
		waveshare v2
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>