<bug id='431' author='w0ntonsoup' open_date='2019-10-27T12:17:53Z' closed_time='2019-10-28T23:51:14Z'>
	<summary>[BUG] Error when running win_connection_share.ps1 script. "An event was unable to invoke any of the subscribers"</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When attempting to run the win_connection_share.ps1 -EnableInternetConnectionSharing command, I get the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;C:\win_connection_share.ps1 : An event was unable to invoke any of the subscribers (Exception
from HRESULT: 0x80040201)
At line:1 char:1
+ .\win_connection_share -EnableInternetConnectionSharing
+ ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
    + CategoryInfo          : OperationStopped: (:) [win_connection_share.ps1], COMException
    + FullyQualifiedErrorId : System.Runtime.InteropServices.COMException,win_connection_share.ps1
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Ensure pwnagotchi is available and alive. SSH into pwnagotchi on 10.0.0.2 to ensure connectivity.
Download win_connection_share.ps1 from script folder within repo
Run win_connection_share.ps1 -EnableInternetConnectionSharing.

Extra step: I've rebooted my computer to see if that would change any outcome.
Expected behavior
To enable internet connection sharing from my Windows host to my Pwnagotchi.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/55900020/67634418-eb5cc400-f878-11e9-9b9a-b8ad74b973d4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment (please complete the following information):

Pwnagotchi version: v1.1.0RC0
OS version: Windows 10
Raspberry Pi Zero W

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='w0ntonsoup' date='2019-10-28T23:51:14Z'>
		I've found that Windows ICS (Internet Connection Sharing) was the culprit here. I restarted the ICS service by following these steps:

Click Windows Start &gt; Control Panel.
Choose Administrative Tools
Choose Services
Scroll down the services window and look for Internet Connection Sharing.
Right-click on the Internet Connection Sharing item, and then select Restart

After these steps, run the script again with the -EnableInternetConnectionSharing flag and you should see that ICS is enabled.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='w0ntonsoup' date='2019-11-04T19:14:42Z'>
		I tried the issues suggested here, did not work. In the end, I found out that if you go to "network connections", rightclick on the connection (in my case the wireless one), Settings, Sharing, and then select the RNDIS network, then it will work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='w0ntonsoup' date='2020-11-20T13:07:24Z'>
		
I found out that if you go to "network connections", rightclick on the connection (in my case the wireless one), Settings, Sharing, and then select the RNDIS network, then it will  work. &lt;

you save my day , thx alot.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>