<bug id='463' author='coderobe' open_date='2019-10-29T18:41:18Z' closed_time='2019-10-30T16:51:52Z'>
	<summary>association and deauthentication frames are sent to open access points too</summary>
	<description>
Is your feature request related to a problem? Please describe.
There are a few networks that are never worth trying to pwn, like open hotspots with login walls, or user-based enterprise networks - right now, pwnagotchi will still spend valuable time associating with these networks and collecting handshakes.
Describe the solution you'd like

Don't associate with open networks
Ignore handshakes from EAP / enterprise networks

Describe alternatives you've considered

Ship a default whitelist of networks i.e.

eduroam - user based auth (EAP)
Telekom_FON - open hotspot with login wall
...



Additional context
I'm not sure if it makes sense to collect handshakes from enterprise networks, as those are usually certificate based, user+pass, or use different means of login a la EAP
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T11:26:53Z'>
		Yep, noticed this as well with the Vodafone Homespot and Telekom ones in Germany. They are "open", but it spends time on them. Maybe a filtering mechanism...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T13:36:32Z'>
		this is a bug bettercap's side, it shouldn't happen ... you guys sure those are open aps?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T15:01:23Z'>
		Yep, I'm seeing mine try associate to "Vodafone Homespot" and "Telekom FON" AP's quite a lot, which are "Open" (but have a captive portal). I'll try spin up an open AP to test with also and see if it tries associate with that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T15:09:06Z'>
		i'm an idiot and i should filter out open networks here &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/pwnagotchi/agent.py#L173&gt;https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/pwnagotchi/agent.py#L173&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T16:51:52Z'>
		fixed with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/commit/1600d8cbd14a0d3343c3d925da86b99d5a6ac296&gt;1600d8c&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T17:40:29Z'>
		what's your opinion on the second half of this issue RE: networks like eduroam which use user:pass auth or certificates, can these be filtered too or is there not enough information available at this stage to be able to filter these automatically?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='coderobe' date='2019-10-30T17:41:24Z'>
		i'd say the latter
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>