<bug id='592' author='neurovish' open_date='2019-11-12T14:19:57Z' closed_time='2019-11-12T23:12:10Z'>
	<summary>Epochs run long when internet is not available</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/files/3836535/pwnagotchi-test.log&gt;pwnagotchi-test.log&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

When there is no connectivity to the internet (specifically the API, &lt;denchmark-link:https://api.pwnagotchi.ai&gt;https://api.pwnagotchi.ai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), pwnagotchi runs very slowly (long epochs) with CPU usage under 50%.
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Power on pwnagotchi with no internet
Wait for AI to load
Wait an hour or so
After about an hour of runtime, the logs should show long-running epochs ( &gt; 20min) once the AI has loaded.

Expectation is the realtime length for an epoch to be far less than 20 minutes. With internet connectivity, epochs usually last less than 5 minutes.
Environment

pwnagotchi v1.2.1
pwngrid v1.10.1
pi0w

Attached file shows output of "egrep -a "[epoch|brain.nn" /var/log/pwnagotchi.log |tail -n 80". The first 33 epochs in this file cover almost 8 hours of runtime off of a battery with no internet connectivity. The next 6 epochs cover 43 minutes of runtime off of a USB connection with connection sharing blocked by the host.
Also of note is the pwngrid-peer.log, which mostly consists of lines that look like:
2019-11-01 15:58:59 err POST &lt;denchmark-link:https://api.pwnagotchi.ai/api/v1/unit/enroll&gt;https://api.pwnagotchi.ai/api/v1/unit/enroll&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (20.012588s) Post &lt;denchmark-link:https://api.pwnagotchi.ai/api/v1/unit/enroll&gt;https://api.pwnagotchi.ai/api/v1/unit/enroll&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: dial tcp: lookup api.pwnagotchi.ai on 9.9.9.9:53: read udp 10.0.0.2:53978-&gt;9.9.9.9:53: i/o timeout
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-12T14:23:50Z'>
		Wait this is the same thing i had happen to me a long time ago when i said i had like 36% cpu usage when i wait 45 min or more and then connect bt tether, yeah this is interesting
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-12T14:57:08Z'>
		Yeah, same thing most likely. I tested on my laptop by not routing the pi to the internet, ran for a couple hours and went through about 4 epochs, then setup iptables to route the pi and instantly saw 10 epochs in about 15 minutes.
I haven't dug into the code/scripts yet to see what it is doing, mostly because I am not familiar at all with go.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-12T23:01:22Z'>
		i think the problem is here &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/bin/pwnagotchi#L123&gt;https://github.com/evilsocket/pwnagotchi/blob/master/bin/pwnagotchi#L123&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ... the grid plugin attempts to talk with the API blocking the loop ... fixing
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-12T23:12:26Z'>
		if you have a way to test from master, let me know if the fix works 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-13T00:07:16Z'>
		Yes! I think it works. Been running for about 30 - 40 minutes with the internet link cut-off, and already on the 18th epoch and 2nd training epoch. Thanks man!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='neurovish' date='2019-11-13T00:07:52Z'>
		great :D
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>