<bug id='870' author='samyhaff' open_date='2020-05-06T10:33:09Z' closed_time='2020-05-06T20:11:22Z'>
	<summary>macOS connection share isn't working</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
The script doesn't share the wifi nor ethernet connection,
instead I get the following errors:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;sharing connecting from upstream interface en0 to usb interface en5 ...
net.inet.ip.forwarding: 1 -&gt; 1
No ALTQ support in kernel
ALTQ related functions disabled
pfctl: pf already enabled
pfctl: Use of -f option, could result in flushing of rules
present in the main ruleset added by the system at startup.
See /etc/pf.conf for further details.

No ALTQ support in kernel
ALTQ related functions disabled
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior: run the script after being able to ssh
Environment:

latest pwnagotchi version
macOS 10.15.4
MacBook pro 2017

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='samyhaff' date='2020-05-06T15:41:41Z'>
		Thats normal.   I always get that and connection share works, ususally.   I think the problem more of a mac tho', thing not pwnagotchi.     Ive found that connection will share only if the pwnagotchi in in manual mode( that might be in the web manual somewhere) and that I need to re-run the script sometimes after rebooting  my macbook.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='samyhaff' date='2020-05-06T18:26:27Z'>
		well that's strange, what's happening for me is that as soon as I launch the script I am even no longer able to ping my pwnagotchi.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='samyhaff' date='2020-05-06T20:09:14Z'>
		hmm. not sure what that could be .  The Pwnagotchi just stops responding or the SSH connection breaks?   Is it still being "seen" in network connections?   Im still running High Sierra, so it could be a new mac permissions thing.     Make sure that you've set up the Pwng to have a static RDNIS, like shown in the "community hacks"  section.   I dont know why that is enabled by default, but if it is changing every time the unit reboots, you will have connection sharing issues.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='samyhaff' date='2020-05-06T20:13:32Z'>
		My bad, it doesn't seem to be a bug with the script: I eventually got it to work thanks to help on slack.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>