<bug id='135' author='asampat3090' open_date='2018-05-18T02:05:15Z' closed_time='2018-06-03T08:00:37Z'>
	<summary>File Collections &amp; Environments &amp; Tasks save files in intermediate locations. Add in `datmo_environment/` and `datmo_files` and remove `datmo_tasks` and `datmo_snapshots` directories</summary>
	<description>
Currently there are 2 issues for each of these functionalities, which boil down to the same issue

 in FileCollection the files are being saved to a temporary directory where the files are being hashed and then they are copied into the correct location. If we can hash the files where they currently are and prevent this, this will prevent having temporary files incase of a fatal error or exit
 in Environments the files for environments are being created in temporary locations where they are then put into a FileCollection (and proceed to the same issue above). If the program exits because of an error or any other reason in between, the temporary locations of the environment files before they are passed to the FileCollection may still be present.
 For tasks, during the run, there should be no folder in datmo_tasks/ (that folder should be removed). Instead the files should be copied into a temporary directory within the .datmo folder during the course of the run, so it will not be visible to the user but will be safe to copy over to a snapshot at the end of the task.

Both of these can be solved without much code change if we use actual TEMP directories of the system to save the files anytime we need them. That way we depend on the system to delete them in case there is a fatal error eventually, rather than have to explicitly do this ourselves.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='asampat3090' date='2018-05-20T23:51:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/datmo/datmo/issues/138&gt;#138&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is a subset of this issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='asampat3090' date='2018-05-28T23:24:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/datmo/datmo/pull/162&gt;#162&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='asampat3090' date='2018-06-03T08:00:37Z'>
		 and  were removed in PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/datmo/datmo/pull/162&gt;#162&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and  and  directories and their respective logic were added in PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/datmo/datmo/pull/163&gt;#163&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 .
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>