<bug id='859' author='atafra' open_date='2020-10-26T19:47:24Z' closed_time='2020-10-29T21:32:45Z'>
	<summary>AVX-512 detected incorrectly on macOS, compile error on older macOS versions</summary>
	<description>
AVX-512 is detected incorrectly on macOS by the included version of Xbyak (typically it detects only AVX2 but it depends on whether any AVX-512 instructions were executed before, outside of oneDNN). Compilation also fails on some older macOS versions. I fixed these bugs upstream:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/herumi/xbyak/commit/a0c49fa2e7b0f6ff2baf7b94363304b382151cbf&gt;herumi/xbyak@a0c49fa&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/herumi/xbyak/commit/70777a69937b1ddd588e0c24091c0fd1781c0897&gt;herumi/xbyak@70777a6&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Upgrading Xbyak to the latest master will fix these issues.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='atafra' date='2020-10-26T19:58:51Z'>
		Thanks for the heads up, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/atafra&gt;@atafra&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! We try keeping Xbyak up-to-date, so will pick the improved version soon.
Is this more a FYI or you have a specific oneDNN version you want to have a fix?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='atafra' date='2020-10-26T20:05:59Z'>
		We already fixed this in our fork for Open Image Denoise but it would be great if this could be fixed in the next v1.x version of oneDNN (ideally v1.7). Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='atafra' date='2020-10-26T20:49:03Z'>
		I see, thank you!
Unfortunately, v1.7 is right around the corner.
So, if there is no explicit need for that we probably will pull that in v1.8 release.
&lt;off-topic&gt;we need to add GitHub milestone for v1.8 release&lt;/off-topic&gt;
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='atafra' date='2020-10-26T21:12:48Z'>
		OK, thanks. It's not critical to have the fix in v1.7 for us because we use our own fork but the official v1.7 will be still broken on macOS systems with AVX-512 (latest MacBook Pro 13 and Mac Pro). Perhaps it would be useful to at least mention this as a known issue in the release notes if you decide to not fix this for now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='atafra' date='2020-10-28T05:45:12Z'>
		Partially addressed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/oneapi-src/oneDNN/commit/d58524e696bb960c051eb78da103252412ea7a80&gt;d58524e&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (future v1.8).
A promotion to v1.7 is WIP.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='atafra' date='2020-10-29T21:32:45Z'>
		Promoted to v1.7 and master branches.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/atafra&gt;@atafra&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>