<bug id='1574' author='wangcan0329' open_date='2018-10-22T10:40:47Z' closed_time='2019-04-04T07:22:24Z'>
	<summary>[Ssh Key File] ~ in filename will be replaced by _ in Chrome.</summary>
	<description>
Now we added namespace as prefix to the jobname and joint with ~,  if we click private key the file will be downloaded but the ~  in file name will be replaced by _ automatically in Chrome. Which will cause the step 3 and 4 failed since the name changed.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-23T02:29:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wangcan0329&gt;@wangcan0329&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can we provide a more efficient way to users by opening a console in webport and connect to the container? So users wouldn't need to download the key file and connect to the container manually.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-23T03:05:26Z'>
		I don't think we should rely on filename auto-generating feature of browser / local file system. Instead of rename the URI of the key file I prefer add a notice like "Make sure your downloaded file named some-key".
In the future, I propose providing a shell script includes current three commands and encourage user to use the commands like
$ bash &lt;(curl http://rest-server/v1/api/user/foo/jobs/bar/containers/baz/connect.sh)
to connect the container, as well as giving the download link of key file as tech details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-23T05:56:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DongZhaoYu&gt;@DongZhaoYu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Actually I had a simple test on web ssh tool but didn't get time to have a further investigation. I will consider to add this feature but I don't think this is high priority thing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-23T06:02:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Gerhut&gt;@Gerhut&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Agree. We can consider to combine these three commands into one script.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-24T03:05:00Z'>
		Chrome replace the tilde ~ with an underscore _ is  to avoid potential filename issue on Windows . please refer to &lt;denchmark-link:https://superuser.com/questions/1360571/character-will-be-automatically-changed-to-in-filename-during-downloadin&gt;Character “~” will be automatically changed to “_” in filename during downloading by Chrome&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='wangcan0329' date='2018-10-26T02:41:25Z'>
		Can we detect whether the page is rendered by Chrome or not? if yes, we can show a warning in the page.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='wangcan0329' date='2019-02-01T03:07:48Z'>
		we publish it as a known issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='wangcan0329' date='2019-04-04T07:22:24Z'>
		PAI does not print the url anymore.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>