<bug id='382' author='Wenbo93' open_date='2018-03-14T09:18:47Z' closed_time='2018-05-25T08:43:51Z'>
	<summary>pai-fs failed to put large number of files to hdfs</summary>
	<description>
I used pai-fs to upload Imagenet data to HDFS.  The data is pre-processed in tfrecord format, consisting of 1024 training files and 128 validation files.
I tried "python pai-fs.py -cp -r SOURCE_PATH DEST_PATH" first.  It crushed after about 10 files in average(I tried several times).
Then I tried to upload one file at a time with "ls | xargs -I {} python pai-fs.py -cp {} DEST_PATH".  It failed after about 280 files.
In both cases, about one in five uploaded files has incorrect size.
Finally, I have to run a container with HDFS and use the native HDFS command to make this.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Wenbo93' date='2018-03-15T10:50:53Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Wenbo93&gt;@Wenbo93&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , for a temporary solution, you can

install native hdfs lib
OR build this docker then mount dataset into docker

and use hdfs cli instead of pai-fs to upload.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hwuu&gt;@hwuu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you help to have a look? Are there any performance tests about pai-fs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Wenbo93' date='2018-03-20T07:07:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Wenbo93&gt;@Wenbo93&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , is it possible to share detailed logs for us to debug?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Wenbo93' date='2018-03-20T08:32:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/abuccts&gt;@abuccts&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for your solutions!  Sorry for replying so late, I didn't get the email reminder.  I started a container with HDFS and uploaded successfully with native hdfs cli.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/fanyangCS&gt;@fanyangCS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The terminal didn't put any error.  The feedback from pai-fs (stating which file it is transmitting and the progress) just seized up and no new files are uploaded to HDFS for a long time.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Wenbo93' date='2018-05-25T08:43:51Z'>
		We decide to stop the support to pai-fs. we recommend to use native hdfs cmds for hdfs file operation.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>