<bug id='517' author='johanlantz' open_date='2019-11-06T13:40:56Z' closed_time='2019-11-16T00:59:46Z'>
	<summary>Setting epochs to any value other than what is in the model definition prevents training</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐞Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I have a trainable model converted from Keras. Starting training works fine but when I try to adjust the epochs value, the training fails to start. It seems I can only use the epochs value in the model default parameters. If I manually change the epochs value when converting the model, I can use the new value from my app but no other values are working.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A bootstrapped example can be found here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PuBzRLS5WjsxJii4KACW9AL4HFXjeiNM/view?usp=sharing&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PuBzRLS5WjsxJii4KACW9AL4HFXjeiNM/view?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

For me, it is sufficient to change the epochs value from the default value 1 to another value here:
configuration.parameters = [MLParameterKey.epochs : 1]
in ViewController.swift and the training will not start.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='johanlantz' date='2019-11-06T17:15:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johanlantz&gt;@johanlantz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I tried downloading that but, google denied access. Could you mark it as public until I download?
One question - what is the error message you see in the catch block?
Thanks for reporting the issue :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='johanlantz' date='2019-11-06T17:40:29Z'>
		Sorry about that, here is the new link:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EKZuJMYrkXzR9ey2h7xO2mAj6hSzLJWY/view?usp=sharing&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EKZuJMYrkXzR9ey2h7xO2mAj6hSzLJWY/view?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The error is this one:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Failed to start update task Error Domain=com.apple.CoreML Code=0 "2 is not a valid value given constraint 
minValue: 1
maxValue: 10
enumeratedNumbers: {(
    1,
    10
)} for key epochs" UserInfo={NSLocalizedDescription=2 is not a valid value given constraint 
minValue: 1
maxValue: 10
enumeratedNumbers: {(
    1,
    10
)} for key epochs}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

So using 1 or 10 is ok but using anything in between like 2 does not work.
Maybe I am misunderstanding but I would expect to be able to input any value less than the epochs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='johanlantz' date='2019-11-07T00:06:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johanlantz&gt;@johanlantz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the following call adds "1" as an allowed epoch value by default since keras model does not capture epochs in the h5 format.
coreml_model = coremltools.converters.keras.convert('empty_model.h5', respect_trainable=True)
Later, when you do builder.set_epochs(10), we extended the allowed epoch values to [1, 10]. The value you provide during runtime should be one of those. That said, you could change the allowed values by specifying allowed_set:
builder.set_epochs(10, allowed_set=[10, 20, 30, 40])
Let me know if that works for you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='johanlantz' date='2019-11-07T08:42:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/anilkatti&gt;@anilkatti&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

As always, thanks for the super fast reply. You are correct, with your solution I can use other values as well as long as they are in the allowed set.
If I may, I would say that the description in xCode is a bit misleading.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7461655/68373027-46789b80-0142-11ea-9f27-f0ea3e55a197.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It says "Maximum number of iterations training takes" and in this case, it shows 10 but I have used:
builder.set_epochs(10, allowed_set=[2, 4, 6, 10, 20])
when converting the model and epochs=20 is working when running training.
The important thing is that I now know how to run other epoch values so feel free to close this and thanks again for the help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='johanlantz' date='2019-11-08T05:42:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johanlantz&gt;@johanlantz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I agree the message is misleading. I have filed a bug to fix this. Thanks for your feedback.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>