<bug id='926' author='teaglin' open_date='2020-09-15T18:41:43Z' closed_time='2020-12-22T22:29:02Z'>
	<summary>Custom layer works in iOS 13 but not 14</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐞Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I have an existing model with a custom layer converted from Keras. It's been working fantastic in iOS 13, but fails to work on iOS 14.
Works: iOS 13 – Xcode Version 11.7 (11E801a)
Fails: iOS 14 – Xcode Version 12.0 beta 6 (12A8189n)
On iOS 14 the model crashes upon loading. Oddly all the income dimension sizes for the custom layer are 0. But the model works great in iOS13.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Trace&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

[espresso] [Espresso::handle_ex_plan] exception=Failed in 2nd reshape after missing custom layer info.
[coreml] Error in adding network -1.
[coreml] MLModelAsset: load failed with error Error Domain=com.apple.CoreML Code=0 "Error in declaring network." UserInfo={NSLocalizedDescription=Error in declaring network.}
[coreml] MLModelAsset: modelWithError: load failed with error Error Domain=com.apple.CoreML Code=0 "Error in declaring network." UserInfo={NSLocalizedDescription=Error in declaring network.}
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;System environment (please complete the following information):&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


coremltools version  3.0:
OS Linux
Xcode version Version 12.0 beta 6 (12A8189n):
How you install python (system):
python version (3.7):
Keras version 2.2

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-15T18:45:45Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/teaglin&gt;@teaglin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, to confirm "Xcode 12 beta 6 + iOS 13" works but "Xcode 12 beta + iOS14" does not (with the same model)?
Can you please share your app to reproduce this issue, either here or via filing a bug report at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/coremltools/issues/926&gt;#926&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-15T19:04:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aseemw&gt;@aseemw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I updated my report. Included:
Works: iOS 13 – Xcode Version 11.7 (11E801a)
Fails: iOS 14 – Xcode Version 12.0 beta 6 (12A8189n)
I haven't tried iOS 13 with Xcode Version 12.0 beta 6 (12A8189n)
Unfortunately, I can't share the app. Is there any other means for you to reproduce?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-15T19:51:05Z'>
		There is a known issue with Xcode 12 and custom layer which is being fixed and will be available in an upcoming Xcode version (12.2). Although that one should not cause the error you are seeing Failed in 2nd reshape after missing custom layer info..
Can you share a toy app, or just the mlmodel that gives this error (or a variant of your actual model that has the same error), via a bug report, then we can verify if its a separate bug.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-15T21:17:00Z'>
		Can you link any details on the issue? I'm curious. I think the issue stems from inputShapes in the function below always containing Zeros.
func outputShapes(forInputShapes inputShapes: [[NSNumber]])
I'll try and prepare something basic and upload tomorrow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-16T16:29:24Z'>
		Also looking for some extra info here such that I can keep an eye out for it.
Is the custom layer in Swift or ObjC?
Is the input shape fixed or flexible shape?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aseemw&gt;@aseemw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Would the bug you refer to affect both Swift and ObjC implementations?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-16T18:03:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/leovinus2001&gt;@leovinus2001&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

-Custom layer is in Swift
-Input shape is fixed
Since the inputShapes are all totally zero there is no way to compute the outputShape. Unless I manually hardcoded them. So there must be some issue interpreting the prior layer's output shape?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-18T14:39:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aseemw&gt;@aseemw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Here is a copy of the model with empty weights.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.dropbox.com/s/02buk75r9e544xe/myModel.mlmodel?dl=0&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/02buk75r9e544xe/myModel.mlmodel?dl=0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-21T21:20:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aseemw&gt;@aseemw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any update on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='teaglin' date='2020-09-23T23:55:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/teaglin&gt;@teaglin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The bug in Xcode coremlcompiler causes the input shape to be incorrect in the compiled model (it incorrectly adds a sequence dimension of value ). If you compile the model "on device", using the API,  , it would work correctly, since then you'll be skipping the Xcode compiler.
I have verified with the model you attached, that it works with the iOS 14.2 seed and the Xcode compiler fix, which will be part of Xcode 12.2.
(It should work with iOS14.0 and Xcode 11).
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='teaglin' date='2020-12-22T22:29:02Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/teaglin&gt;@teaglin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this issue should have been resolved as a result of the fix Aseem provided above. Please feel free to file a new issue, or reopen this issue if you believe this is not the case, or have additional concerns.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>