<bug id='18' author='stuartyeates' open_date='2013-09-27T03:44:30Z' closed_time='2016-05-12T15:17:39Z'>
	<summary>build failed on linux 32 bit</summary>
	<description>
I'm following the instructions in the readme to get the code working, but getting the error:
Caused by: java.lang.RuntimeException: Unable to find a native CRF++ library: Folder /media/D020-1F62/github/grobid/grobid-home/lib/lin-32 does not exist
I'm on  "Linux rb-806-02-c 3.0.0-32-generic-pae &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid/issues/51&gt;#51&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
-Ubuntu SMP Thu Mar 21 16:09:48 UTC 2013 i686 i686 i386 GNU/Linux"
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='stuartyeates' date='2013-09-27T07:00:05Z'>
		Hi,
According to the message the directory /media/D020-1F62/github/grobid/grobid-home/lib/lin-32 does not exist. Apparently, you have pointed GROBID_HOME (commandline -gH) to a non-existing directory (or you did a typo in the name of an existing dir). Change that and it should work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='stuartyeates' date='2013-09-27T10:14:39Z'>
		I don't thin I typed anything wrong. /media/D020-1F62/github/grobid/grobid-home/lib/ exists and looks exactly like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid/tree/master/grobid-home/lib&gt;https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid/tree/master/grobid-home/lib&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . Both have a lin-64 but no lin-32.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='stuartyeates' date='2013-09-27T14:01:00Z'>
		Arg... Sorry my mistake. I'm using an x86_64 so I didn't realize the problem. You are right, on my machine also the directory is missing.
I'm not sure why it's the case. Kermitt2 might give you a better answer than mines.
In the meantime, have you tried creating a lib32/ directory and copying the 32 bit versions of the same files as those in lib64/ from your installed linux? On my x86_64 machine I have 32 bits version of almost all the libs listed in grobid-home/lib/lin-64/ in /usr/lib/i386-linux-gnu/ . I think you'll still lack libcrfpp, but it can probably be found here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://code.google.com/p/crfpp/&gt;https://code.google.com/p/crfpp/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='stuartyeates' date='2013-09-27T18:26:05Z'>
		You are right Stuart the binaries for linux 32 bits are missing. They have disappeared at some stage, but I don't remember when ;). Probably when moving from SourceForge to Github, and as I am also testing on x86_64 I didn't see this problem!
I will try to recompile and add the libraries for lin32 this week-end.
Sorry and many thanks for reporting this problem!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='stuartyeates' date='2013-10-19T14:53:09Z'>
		what happend... can you help us with the libraries for linux-32?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='stuartyeates' date='2016-02-14T14:18:03Z'>
		linux-32 binaries for Wapiti are present since a couple of months and GROBID should work on this architecture, but I've not tested it myself because I don't have linux-32 environment around.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='stuartyeates' date='2016-05-05T04:16:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/stuartyeates&gt;@stuartyeates&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/juanremi&gt;@juanremi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did you have the oportunity to test GROBID with linux 32? May I then close this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='stuartyeates' date='2016-05-12T15:17:39Z'>
		Tested with Ubuntu 32 bit. Works fine.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>