<bug id='379' author='lfoppiano' open_date='2019-01-31T15:08:03Z' closed_time='2019-02-02T10:28:31Z'>
	<summary>Consolidation for citation string parameters sent from the GUI</summary>
	<description>
It seems that the wrong parameters are being sent on the interface
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15426/52063224-8a3be480-25b5-11e9-918f-40d7ae347f96.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

(I was lost in the js file trying to find the place to be changed)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-01-31T16:27:34Z'>
		Thanks! The parameter consolidateCitations works fine, it's just that a useless parameter consolidateHeader is always present, due to weak javascript... it will be ignored by the service and has no impact. I will clean it in the GUI!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-01-31T16:57:17Z'>
		Actually all the queries are ajaxForm sharing the same form to simplify the javascript. Only the relevant consolidation options are visible given the selected service. Then non visible extra-parameters are also sent, but as they are not relevant, they will be ignored by the service. I am not sure it is really useful to "complexify" the javascript with one form per service.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-01-31T22:03:53Z'>
		another thing I forgot to say is that the parameter consolidateCitation is not sent, while it should when the tick box is selected in the interface:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15426/52088510-67c6bd00-25ef-11e9-8cfa-8baf187768df.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

my initial supposition was that the parameter just needed to be updated in the right place, but i could not find it where 😅
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-01-31T23:16:31Z'>
		this one is sent! well my tests are fine for his one
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-01-31T23:19:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2340795/52092159-fbc86280-25b6-11e9-92aa-b4532e9454bb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lfoppiano' date='2019-02-02T10:28:31Z'>
		sorry I might not have the latest version, when I wrote the ticket... sorry
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>