<bug id='1179' author='ramsrivatsa' open_date='2016-02-22T18:13:08Z' closed_time='2016-02-24T15:07:54Z'>
	<summary>Error when using spark over video example from scene classification</summary>
	<description>
When I try to scale up video classification example in spark using dl4j version 0.4-rc3.8, i get an error
Exception in thread "main" java.lang.NullPointerException
at org.deeplearning4j.nn.multilayer.MultiLayerNetwork.getUpdater(MultiLayerNetwork.java:2258)
at org.deeplearning4j.spark.impl.multilayer.SparkDl4jMultiLayer.(SparkDl4jMultiLayer.java:120)
at org.deeplearning4j.spark.impl.multilayer.SparkDl4jMultiLayer.(SparkDl4jMultiLayer.java:129)
at edu.umich.clarity.VideoClassificationExample.main(VideoClassificationExample.java:157)
This error is resolved when using 0.4-rc.7 but i get another error as shown below :-
Caused by: com.fasterxml.jackson.databind.JsonMappingException: Could not resolve type id 'RnnToCnnPreProcessor' into a subtype of [simple type, class org.deeplearning4j.nn.conf.InputPreProcessor]
this is because RnnToCnnPreProcessor is supported in dl4j version 0.4-rc.8 only but the get update function is returning null as it is being called without setting it.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2016-02-22T18:46:38Z'>
		Does this still occur if you override the jackson dependency?
In SBT, this looks like dependencyOverrides ++=Set("com.fasterxml.jackson.core" % "jackson-databind" % "2.4.4")
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2016-02-22T18:51:25Z'>
		Updated dl4j to 0.4-rc.8
down graded Jackson from 2.5.1 to 2.4.4.
getUpdate issue is fixed but still face jackson issues
In addition to that found this specific error.
Error while invoking RpcHandler#receive() for one-way message.
org.apache.spark.SparkException: Could not find CoarseGrainedScheduler or it has been stopped.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2016-02-22T19:08:11Z'>
		This seems like a spark error now. It could be that an executor died.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2016-02-22T19:17:44Z'>
		my bad did some typo in the previous one.
The neural network in VideoClassification requires inputPreProcessor which has RnnToCnnPreProcessor as arguments. These are supported by dl4j to 0.4-rc.8 but when providing that to spark its not able to perform  getUpdate function on the newtork due to the null pointer execption.
when downgrading spark that works but jackson fails.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2016-02-24T15:07:54Z'>
		Found out the bug. dl4j version 0.4-rc.8 has a bug. When we initialize neural network we have to set updater to null and pass the network to the SparkDl4jMultiLayer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ramsrivatsa' date='2019-01-21T09:38:02Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>