<bug id='1242' author='Jydago' open_date='2016-03-08T11:59:21Z' closed_time='2016-05-01T12:36:59Z'>
	<summary>Increasing heap size while training CNN</summary>
	<description>
The memory heap size keep increasing as I train my CNN using spark. My training set is at about 10 mb (around 3000 images), but after training for about 10 epochs, the program always throws some kind of out of memory exception, like Java heap size or GC overhead. I have changed the xmx setting to use 4g, and I have confirmed that the application uses 4g while training by looking at JProfiler connected to IntelliJ. I can unfortunately not include my image data set, as it is medical images that I'm not sure that I can share, but I'll try to include everything else.
I have added build.sbt, sbt.txt, src, stack trace as txt, in the zip file. Also included an image of the profiling of a run instance, where the uppermost value of the y-axis is 4g. (Green is free space and blue is used space). Adding an image of the GC activity too.
Memory:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/17123674/13601233/d96a0818-e52e-11e5-807e-e31253340a11.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

GC:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/17123674/13601279/34986d2e-e52f-11e5-85fd-ce65640ff49d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/files/163095/Memory.Issue.zip&gt;Memory Issue.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Memory Issue v2
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/files/163974/Memory.Issue.zip&gt;Memory Issue.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T15:44:42Z'>
		Any chance for screenshot from jvisualvm (or anything like it) memory sampling tab?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:35:16Z'>
		I haven't used that before, but I'll try to fix it and rerun the program.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:40:45Z'>
		Do you mean visualvm, &lt;denchmark-link:https://visualvm.java.net/&gt;https://visualvm.java.net/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:42:03Z'>
		Any profiler report will be welcome tbh.
JVisualVM is the part of java dirtibution, it's in your bin folder
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:43:48Z'>
		Hmm, do you mean what classes that are taking up space, like double[] and int[]?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:46:42Z'>
		Yes, exactly. I need overall picture of allocations, so i could start my investigation with something in hands.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T18:46:59Z'>
		Alright, will fix that!
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T19:12:49Z'>
		Is there any way we could get an isolated example we can run too?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T21:20:58Z'>
		Sorry, but I'm not sure if I'm allowed to share the images, as they're medical images that I've gotten from a company. I'll ask my supervisor about it tomorrow. At least I've uploaded a new map with the requested pictures of allocations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T21:25:48Z'>
		Thank you very much, updated archive is totally awesome!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-08T21:31:12Z'>
		Thanks! Hope it works out!
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-09T13:48:45Z'>
		Was unfortunately not allowed to send the images to you for testing, but I'll see if I can create an artificial data set that gives the same problem!
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-09T14:30:02Z'>
		Don't worry, as long as we have your source code, images won't be an issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-14T12:48:58Z'>
		Please try the following: Create your model, and then directly save its parameters without any training, and then reload them (&lt;denchmark-link:http://deeplearning4j.org/modelpersistence&gt;http://deeplearning4j.org/modelpersistence&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 shows how to do that) - When reloading the parameters I have found that for some reason the memory usage does not icrease.
Note, that as you didn't do any training yet, you shouldn't try to save the updater.
As can be seen in Issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/eclipse/deeplearning4j/issues/1258&gt;#1258&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the memory requirements went down from peaks of over 10GB and rising to peaks of about 3.5GB.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='Jydago' date='2016-03-14T15:45:17Z'>
		Tried saving the model and then starting a new program to load and train the NN, but still gives the same problem with pretty much the same symptoms as I had earlier. What I can't really wrap my head around is why the GC starts increasing in activity after about an hour and the heap space stays pretty much flat most of the time in the last maybe 20 minutes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-01T22:11:21Z'>
		I'd be curious for an update on this. We fixed some memory leak issues recently.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-02T14:38:10Z'>
		Are the fixes on r3.8 or on the latest snapshot?
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-02T22:50:35Z'>
		Latest.
On Sat, Apr 2, 2016 at 10:38 AM, JohnTheDang &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

wrote:

Are the fixes on r3.8 or on the latest snapshot?
—
You are receiving this because you commented.
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/issues/1242#issuecomment-204727219

		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-03T15:46:51Z'>
		Where can I find the latest snapshot, i.e. what should I add to my pom.xml?
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-03T15:47:26Z'>
		You'll have to build it from source
		</comment>
		<comment id='21' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-03T15:48:17Z'>
		How do I do that?
		</comment>
		<comment id='22' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-03T18:21:22Z'>
		Depends on your OS, for windows you can follow these instructions: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/libnd4j/blob/master/windows.md&gt;https://github.com/deeplearning4j/libnd4j/blob/master/windows.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='23' author='Jydago' date='2016-04-04T08:39:18Z'>
		Uhmm, this looks a bit too advanced for me, is it ok if I wait with testing until the new update is released?
		</comment>
		<comment id='24' author='Jydago' date='2019-01-21T04:53:04Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>