<bug id='1662' author='XilunChen' open_date='2016-06-09T21:21:55Z' closed_time='2016-09-09T22:55:28Z'>
	<summary>ParagraphVectors inferVector does not return vectors</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying to infer the vector for a new document using a trained paragraph vector model, but the infer method does not give me the vector, I checked in function
public INDArray inferVector(List document, double learningRate, double minLearningRate, int iterations)
returns null;
and the new document label is randomly generated, and not included in the vocabulary
How can I get the vector for a new document using inferVector method?
Thanks
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='XilunChen' date='2016-06-10T07:17:31Z'>
		I'm sorry, but inferVector meant to be protected for now. Implementation wasn't finished yet, and will be available in next release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='XilunChen' date='2016-06-10T23:24:09Z'>
		Hi Raver119,
Thanks for the quick reply, looking forward to the next release!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='XilunChen' date='2016-06-11T01:25:47Z'>
		Same here, thanks raver!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='XilunChen' date='2016-07-13T16:25:45Z'>
		To infer a vector for a new document given a trained model is a key functionality that will boost the api usage.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/raver119&gt;@raver119&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do you have an approximate date for the next release?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='XilunChen' date='2016-07-13T16:33:11Z'>
		Sorry, right now main priority is CUDA performance &amp; multi-gpu scaling. After it's finished - i'll get back to NLP.
p.s. and fp16 support...
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='XilunChen' date='2016-09-09T22:55:28Z'>
		Implemented. Example is here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/eclipse/deeplearning4j-examples/pull/234&gt;eclipse/deeplearning4j-examples#234&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Will be merged soon™ and will be available with 0.6.0 release next week.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='XilunChen' date='2019-01-20T19:53:01Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>