<bug id='2572' author='ZhongBaby' open_date='2016-12-24T06:37:02Z' closed_time='2017-01-01T04:55:05Z'>
	<summary>UI server overview tab stuck at loading while model/system tabs are ok</summary>
	<description>
I run the model training, the overview tab of &lt;denchmark-link:http://localhost:9000/train/overview&gt;http://localhost:9000/train/overview&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 display empty charts, and Model and Training Information stuck at loading...
But I switch to model/system tabs they are displaying things like updates per iteration, memory use per iteration.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/8222739/21465637/52378c6a-c9e6-11e6-9ce2-6a103031ae13.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/8222739/21465639/6202f08a-c9e6-11e6-8267-b734d100c5ac.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Here's my &lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/ZhongBaby/9e32eae5c67b0a0ab4b3af2c5d8d7902&gt;gist&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Update1:
I change updater from AdaDelta to Nesterov and the overview tab is ok again.
It seems like when the optimization encounters difficulty, the overview tab will stop drawing.
Yes it's a bug.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ZhongBaby' date='2016-12-28T01:02:06Z'>
		We've seen some issues with NaNs causing problems before (front end JSON parsing chokes on 'NaN' as an invalid number). This was at least partly solved in 0.7.2 (for the model page ratios), but needs to be confirmed for the overview page data.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ZhongBaby' date='2016-12-28T01:14:03Z'>
		thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ZhongBaby' date='2016-12-28T01:18:28Z'>
		I'll re-open this issue until it's tested and confirmed as solved - mainly I'd like to double check NaNs in the score vs. iteration chart.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ZhongBaby' date='2016-12-28T02:40:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ZhongBaby&gt;@ZhongBaby&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 That has nothing to do with this issue. Could you please file a separate issue for feature requests? I'm deleting your comment. It's just not relevant.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ZhongBaby' date='2017-01-01T04:55:05Z'>
		NaNs causing the overview page to not load (while model page still loads) was confirmed and fixed here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/pull/2613&gt;https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/pull/2613&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The above PR will be merged shortly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ZhongBaby' date='2019-01-20T01:20:40Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>