<bug id='4658' author='bholland' open_date='2018-02-14T16:22:36Z' closed_time='2018-08-01T13:06:55Z'>
	<summary>Removing node from VocabCache does not update word indexes</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I wanted to run a PCA on the vocab cache for a TfIdfVector object. Once I had the cache created, I removed all but the top 250 columns (columns are words, rows are documents). In the process of transforming text using the model (vec.transform()), VocabCache returned an index for a word that was larger than 250.
Stepping through the code, it looks like VocabCache does not rebuild an internal index on delete and all rebuild methods are protected.
I would expect that if I remove a node (a VocabWord in this case) that the VocabCache correctly returns the updated index if I call the "word to index" method.
Currently, it will return a positive number if the word is still in the cache after the PCA but the index will be the index of the full dataset.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version Information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please indicate relevant versions, including, if relevant:

Deeplearning4j version - Latest release. I think 3.*.
platform information (OS, etc) - Ubuntu 16.04.
CUDA version, if used - not used
NVIDIA driver version, if in use - not used

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Contributing&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I might be able to contribute. I will have to check with my manager.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bholland' date='2018-08-01T13:06:55Z'>
		Fixed/implemented in my branch. Will be merged soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bholland' date='2018-08-01T15:56:20Z'>
		Oh cool. Thank you!
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Wed, Aug 1, 2018 at 9:08 AM, raver119 ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Closed #4658
 &lt;https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/issues/4658&gt;.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/issues/4658#event-1765170902&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AAXQ8jVNX3gvJ485YNjmbqBIVWprl6sTks5uMag4gaJpZM4SFlhh&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bholland' date='2018-09-21T10:59:09Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>