<bug id='5477' author='ragnarok22' open_date='2018-06-05T18:48:56Z' closed_time='2018-06-14T03:56:36Z'>
	<summary>Crash when I try to get sample the dataset</summary>
	<description>
Hi guys! I have an issue. after load an image dataset i'm trying to get a sample using this:
data.sample(10, true)
data is a DataSet. It throws me the next error:
java.lang.IllegalStateException: Rank is 4 columns() call is not valid
How can I fix it? I use 0.9.1 version
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-05T20:06:27Z'>
		As I can see in the sample() method implementation, the first line called getfeatures().columns(). It seems that the columns() method is not supported for image data set since it is of 4 dimensions
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-05T20:41:20Z'>
		I thinks that the columns in a image dataset is width * height * channels
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-05T20:44:04Z'>
		It's just some legacy method, that was written with regular fully-connected networks in mind.
So it just should be updated for features/labels &gt;2D
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-06T00:44:08Z'>
		how can i do that?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-06T15:35:41Z'>
		as far I can see, this method never work with replacement because Set&lt;Integer&gt; added are queried but never updated
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-07T00:28:50Z'>
		We need to update the code to do that.
In the mean time, you can use the DataSet.asList() + randomly sample using standard java RNG/list ops + DataSet.merge()
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-07T00:41:22Z'>
		Thanks. I will try to do that way. Can you label this to bug and assign it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-07T01:20:26Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ragnarok22&gt;@ragnarok22&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't think people without write access will be able to assign, but we can. Did you want this assigned to you? (i.e., are you planning on submitting a fix?)
Edit: if not, we'll assign it when someone starts working on it. Possibly me, we'll see :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-06-07T01:34:13Z'>
		I would gladly do it, but at this moment I am doing my undergraduate thesis and I do not have much time. Very soon I will be able to help you :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='ragnarok22' date='2018-09-21T19:59:02Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>