<bug id='6060' author='AlexDBlack' open_date='2018-08-03T01:58:47Z' closed_time='2018-08-03T07:22:35Z'>
	<summary>DL4J: MLPMnistSingleLayerExample doesn't work with EMNIST iterator</summary>
	<description>
Starts learning - then divergens.
Could be a tuning issue, but EMNIST and MNIST are pretty close that I wouldn't have expected this...
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2360237/43620100-7b5eb4d6-9714-11e8-9e71-d6caa309505c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-08-03T05:26:34Z'>
		Fixed here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/pull/6061&gt;https://github.com/deeplearning4j/deeplearning4j/pull/6061&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Basic explanation is that the EMNIST dataset is stored in F order, whereas MNIST is stored in C order, consequently needs to be permuted for consistency. The problem is that in doing so, the original values were being modified incorrectly (instead of being 'read only' data).
The spike seen above is right at the start of the second epoch, when the bad/modified data is first used.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-08-04T03:27:56Z'>
		Thanks for the quick turnaround!
Do you know when this will be available as part of the DL4j/ND4j distribution (i.e. available as a maven dependency)?
My understanding is that currently I have to clone/download the latest source code to benefit from this fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-08-04T03:54:02Z'>
		You don't have to build from source - it should be available on snapshots here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://deeplearning4j.org/snapshots&gt;https://deeplearning4j.org/snapshots&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

And yes, also the next release (we're working on it now... rough ETA is about a week or so for that)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-08-04T18:48:50Z'>
		Thank you, it works.
Are there any plans to incorporate the fashion-mnist dataset into DL4?
(&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zalandoresearch/fashion-mnist&gt;https://github.com/zalandoresearch/fashion-mnist&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
I am willing to help if needed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-08-05T03:07:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ai4java&gt;@ai4java&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 submit a PR I guess?  Generally, precooked datasets isn't something that are a top priority for us right now. We're more focused on the internal execution engine right now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='AlexDBlack' date='2018-09-21T10:58:43Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>