<bug id='7029' author='AlexDBlack' open_date='2019-01-17T23:50:55Z' closed_time='2019-01-21T11:29:41Z'>
	<summary>Arbiter with Early Stopping Configuration</summary>
	<description>
From @akhodakivskiy on January 17, 2019 20:28
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Arbiter doesn't work well with Early Stopping Configuration due to Serialization issues. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AlexDBlack&gt;@AlexDBlack&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version Information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please indicate relevant versions, including, if relevant:

1.0.0-beta3
MacOS
CUDA version - not used
NVIDIA driver version - not used

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Contributing&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This commit e3c5432d5af3ba76fc109265dcb723ab3bf58b3e adds early stopping configuration to BasicHyperparameterOptimizationExample. You can see arbiter blowing up during deserialization once you open the browser. Log file is attached.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deeplearning4j/dl4j-examples/files/2770465/out.log&gt;out.log&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Copied from original issue: eclipse/deeplearning4j-examples#804
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AlexDBlack' date='2019-01-25T23:32:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AlexDBlack&gt;@AlexDBlack&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I think there is still a problem with . One of the required parameters is  or .
The former usually has a reference to the DataSetIterator. From what I understand during the serialization of ESC the scoreCalculator will be serialized, and the reference to DataSetIterator will be serialized as well along with all the underlying data (usually resulting in exceptions at this point).
The latter is challenging to serialize because the type has nested template parameters: Supplier&lt;ScoreCalculator&lt;T extends Model&gt;&gt;. At least I didn't manage to figure out how to make the framework to serialize and deserialize my implementation of this interface.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AlexDBlack' date='2019-01-26T02:12:00Z'>
		
From what I understand during the serialization of ESC the scoreCalculator will be serialized, and the reference to DataSetIterator will be serialized as well along with all the underlying data (usually resulting in exceptions at this point).

That's correct, that's why the ScoreCalculatorSupplier exists.

The latter is challenging to serialize because the type has nested template parameters: Supplier&lt;ScoreCalculator&gt;.

That shouldn't be a problem, it should be serializable (assuming your implementation doesn't have any non-serializable fields). Did you run into a specific exception? (I so, post it along with the code for your score calculator)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AlexDBlack' date='2019-02-25T02:39:51Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>