<bug id='1695' author='bdewilde' open_date='2017-12-07T14:31:28Z' closed_time='2017-12-07T15:16:12Z'>
	<summary>AttributeError on pipeline components?</summary>
	<description>
I'm getting a strange error on v2.0.4 that I did not get on v2.0.3, but haven't yet been able to diagnose. Am also having a hard time reproducing it in a simple, isolated way, so apologies for the vague submission.
One error happens when I try to deepcopy a Doc, and a similar one happens when I try to add pipes to a spacy Language. Here's a traceback:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  File "/home/travis/build/chartbeat-labs/textacy/textacy/corpus.py", line 237, in load
    spacy_lang.add_pipe(spacy_lang.create_pipe(name))
  File "/home/travis/virtualenv/python2.7.13/lib/python2.7/site-packages/spacy/language.py", line 217, in create_pipe
    return factory(self, **config)
  File "/home/travis/virtualenv/python2.7.13/lib/python2.7/site-packages/spacy/language.py", line 102, in &lt;lambda&gt;
    'tagger': lambda nlp, **cfg: Tagger(nlp.vocab, **cfg),
  File "pipeline.pyx", line 376, in spacy.pipeline.Tagger.__init__
AttributeError: 'NoneType' object has no attribute 'data'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Similarly, here's the tail end of the deepcopy traceback:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  File "nn_parser.pyx", line 315, in spacy.syntax.nn_parser.Parser.__init__
AttributeError: 'NoneType' object has no attribute 'data'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The most puzzling aspect is that I can run the same code successfully in v2.0.3, so either something changed on your side, or I'm doing something very dumb. Thanks in advance for helping me figure out which. :)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


spaCy version: 2.0.4
Platform: Darwin-16.7.0-x86_64-i386-64bit
Python version: 3.6.0
Models: de, de_core_news_sm, en, en_core_web_sm, es, es_core_news_sm

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bdewilde' date='2017-12-07T15:15:05Z'>
		Ah, so sorry about this – this seems to be related to a bug we intended to fix in v2.0.4 (but didn't – instead, it ended up still broken, but different). So we pushed another fix earlier. Can you try again with v2.0.5?
Problem in a nutshell: The vectors didn't pickle correctly and ended up being deserialized as zeros. Unfortunately, the fix contained a bug, so the vectors then became None, which causes errors like the one above when trying to access vocab.vectors.data.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bdewilde' date='2017-12-07T15:16:12Z'>
		Aha! That explains why this started working 10 minutes ago, when I updated to v2.0.5. 😁
Thanks, Ines!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bdewilde' date='2018-05-08T05:55:25Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>