<bug id='2177' author='chandan2495' open_date='2018-04-03T07:14:27Z' closed_time='2018-04-03T16:30:29Z'>
	<summary>Why are we looking for exactly one attribute in case of set_extension on a doc.</summary>
	<description>



spaCy/spacy/tokens/doc.pyx


         Line 100
      in
      0de599b






 assert nr_defined == 1 





	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='chandan2495' date='2018-04-03T10:24:03Z'>
		Sorry about the lack of a clearer message here – my PR in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/pull/2163&gt;#2163&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 actually addresses this, removes all the random s and replaces them with proper error messages and more information. (See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/pull/2163/files#diff-12839294d4cfa46801ac1f6075166f4bL100&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/pull/2163/files#diff-e05544161ef9df2b97bc6ee9e9732503R221&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this specific case.)
I also just noticed that the way we're checking the arguments here is bad – you should in fact be able to define a getter and setter – just not any other combinations. Will fix this, thanks! 👍
Some more background on this, also in case others come across this issue later: spaCy supports &lt;denchmark-link:https://spacy.io/usage/processing-pipelines#custom-components-attributes&gt;three different types&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 of extension attributes:

Attribute extensions with a default value, e.g. default=False.
Property extensions with a getter and setter.
Method extensions that make the extension attribute callable using the provided method.

When you register an attribute, you'll need to decide which one it should be – for example, you can't mix a getter and a default value or a method and a getter, because this would make it impossible for spaCy to know how to retrieve the value and which function to execute.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='chandan2495' date='2018-05-07T17:52:57Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>