<bug id='2869' author='andifunke' open_date='2018-10-19T18:38:25Z' closed_time='2019-02-27T10:17:54Z'>
	<summary>is_sent_start on first document token should be True instead of None</summary>
	<description>
Hey everyone,
From the documentation of Token.is_sent_start:
"... It also now returns None if the answer is unknown, and fixes a quirk in the old logic that would always set the property to 0 for the first word of the document."
The value of is_sent_start for the first token in a document is now always None instead of 0. Is this the intended behavior? I would argue that True would be more reasonable and consistent. At least it caused some issues to my code when I concatenated several documents and the is_sent_start flag on each first document word was missing.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to reproduce the behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import spacy
nlp = spacy.load('en')
text = "This is the first sentence. This is the second sentence."
doc = nlp(text)
for token in doc:
    print(token.i, token.is_sent_start, token.text)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Info about spaCy&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


spaCy version: 2.0.16
Platform: Linux-4.13.0-38-generic-x86_64-with-debian-stretch-sid
Python version: 3.7.0
Models: en, de

Kind regards,
Andreas
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='andifunke' date='2018-11-29T00:41:53Z'>
		I agree that this seems inconsistent with the naming of the attribute. I had assumed I must've done something wrong somehow when I discovered this was the case and the first word in my document was not the start of a sentence. If this isn't going to be changed, could we at least get a reasoning for why it is the way it is?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='andifunke' date='2019-02-24T21:29:22Z'>
		Sorry for the delay getting to this.
I had it as None so that it's easy to check that nothing has predicted sentence boundaries. Otherwise we can't tell a situation where a model has tried to predict sentence starts and only found the first word of the sentence.
That said, I hadn't thought about the case where multiple documents are being concatenated. That does make me think it would be less confusing to make it just True.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='andifunke' date='2019-03-29T10:42:43Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>