<bug id='2884' author='JulianGerhard21' open_date='2018-10-29T14:12:53Z' closed_time='2018-11-04T14:26:29Z'>
	<summary>Pattern matcher returns wrong match though quantified properly</summary>
	<description>
I have the following matcher:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;self.__matcher.add('Subject', self.__add_subject, [
    {'LOWER': 'mit'},
    {'LOWER': 'dem'},
    {'LOWER': 'betreff'},
    {'IS_ALPHA': True, 'OP': '+'}
])
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Given the following sentence:
"Ich möchte mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag und Noah weitermachen und frage entsprechend nach"
It returns only:
"mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag Noah"
If I use the quantifiers "?" or "*" it is the same. As far as I understood the description, it should return:
"mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag und Noah weitermachen und frage entsprechend nach"
or am I wrong? If I am right, what's currently wrong? What I want to achieve is a phrase with 1-n lower tokens which are specified and then any amount of following tokens.

Python Version Used: 3.6.5
spaCy Version Used: 2.0.16 (latest)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='JulianGerhard21' date='2018-10-30T21:17:14Z'>
		+1
Ran into a similar issue with the wildcard operators. The matching seems to be incorrect, in my case returning all combinations instead of just the greedy match.
To reproduce
import spacy
from spacy.matcher import Matcher

nlp = spacy.load('en_core_web_sm')
doc = nlp('This is a test.')
matcher = Matcher(nlp.vocab)
matcher.add('FOOBAR', None, [{'IS_ALPHA': True, 'OP': '+'}]) 
matches = matcher(doc)
for _, start, end in matches:
    print(doc[start: end])
Output:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;This
This is
is
This is a
is a
a
This is a test
is a test
a test
test
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Info about spaCy&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


spaCy version: 2.1.0a1
Platform: Darwin-17.6.0-x86_64-i386-64bit
Python version: 3.6.6
Models: en_core_web_sm, en
Tried alpha since that had some fixes for Matcher related bugs.

Same code in spaCy version: 2.0.13 gives a different, incorrect result
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;This is
is a
a test
test
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='JulianGerhard21' date='2018-10-31T23:25:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/JulianGerhard21&gt;@JulianGerhard21&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I confirmed that in version 2.1.0a1  the pattern in your example gives the set of all strings starting from "mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag", including the expected  "mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag und Noah weitermachen und frage entsprechend nach".
This seems like the expected behavior as of now. See issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/issues/2569&gt;#2569&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So you will need to do some post-processing to get the result you want.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='JulianGerhard21' date='2018-11-04T14:26:28Z'>
		Yes, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/arunbg&gt;@arunbg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's answer is correct.  will include a completely rewritten implementation of the  engine that resolves problems like this. Since it's a breaking change that causes different behaviour/matches, it'll only be available in the next minor version. But you can already test it in  
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='JulianGerhard21' date='2018-11-04T14:49:15Z'>
		
@JulianGerhard21
I confirmed that in version 2.1.0a1 the pattern in your example gives the set of all strings starting from "mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag", including the expected "mit dem Betreff Kindergeburtstag und Noah weitermachen und frage entsprechend nach".
This seems like the expected behavior as of now. See issue #2569
So you will need to do some post-processing to get the result you want.

Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/arunbg&gt;@arunbg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the investigation. Since I can't use the beta / nightly build, I had to solve it via postprocessing. I figured out that it's more like a dependency parsing problem than something for the matcher as the matcher only indicates certain "to be expected" kind of phrase in the sentence.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ines&gt;@ines&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you too for your comment. I've read &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/releases/tag/v2.1.0a1&gt;this announcement for 2.1.0 nightly&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and I understood the potential "expect different behaviour" thing for the Matcher engine but is there any documentation about what exactly had changed? We are using the Matcher enginge at production level but only on a (imho) flat kind of way - only LIKE_NUM, IS_STOP, and LOWER are used - so it would indeed be interesting to test / read about the changes.
I wish you a nice sunday!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='JulianGerhard21' date='2018-12-04T15:44:58Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>