<bug id='3130' author='davidbren' open_date='2019-01-08T18:48:49Z' closed_time='2019-02-14T19:04:48Z'>
	<summary>Labels being created multiple times</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to reproduce the behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Created a custom NER model the cfg file is showing my entities multiple times
"extra_labels":[
"PAY",
"PAY",
"PAY",
"PAY",
"CPTI",
"CPTI",
"CPTI",
"CPTI",
"CHG_Amts",
"CHG_Amts",
"CHG_Amts",
"CHG_Amts"
],
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Operating System: Windows 7
Python Version Used:  3.6
spaCy Version Used: 2.0.18
Environment Information:

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='davidbren' date='2019-01-08T19:10:22Z'>
		I suspect that This might be due to your data format of list of list as you showed in#3120.
Can you try with list of tuple to see if it helps.
Otherwise share more details on the code you run to get this
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='davidbren' date='2019-01-08T20:58:18Z'>
		My training set is a local json file to read it in I deserialize using the following
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;with open(localFilePath,encoding='utf-8') as f:
     data = json.load(f)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

If I convert to a list of tuples this fails
I re-checked the code  where I add the labels
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;      for _, annotations in trainData:
           for ent in annotations.get('entities'):
               ner.add_label(ent[2])
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

ent[2] = 'PAY' so this seems correct ?
Have you any examples of a local json file of training data ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='davidbren' date='2019-01-09T10:22:49Z'>
		Looks like this is related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/issues/2179&gt;#2179&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. It should be fixed in the latest  already – you can install the latest release from pip and rerun your code to check 
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='davidbren' date='2019-01-09T11:48:13Z'>
		I don't know I am thinking that maybe their is something wrong with my representation as the issue in  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/issues/3120&gt;#3120&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, seems to suggest their is something going on.
By any chance have you any examples of a local file of training data being deserialized, it would really help, even better if you have any that are compatible with json.load()
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='davidbren' date='2019-01-09T15:34:30Z'>
		I reworked the format changing the lists to tuples &amp; it made no difference
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='davidbren' date='2019-03-16T20:00:28Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>