<bug id='392' author='mdda' open_date='2016-05-23T07:45:50Z' closed_time='2016-09-27T11:03:06Z'>
	<summary>Where did Doc.from_orth go?</summary>
	<description>
In spacy/tokens/doc.pyx :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Doc.__init__(self, Vocab vocab, orths_and_spaces=None):
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

orths_and_spaces doesn't appear to do anything.
I'm puzzled, since &lt;denchmark-link:https://spacy.io/docs/tutorials/byo-annotations&gt;https://spacy.io/docs/tutorials/byo-annotations&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 says that  is deprecated in favour of the  version.
(btw :  spaCy looks wonderful!  I'm just having a few teething troubles...)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mdda' date='2016-05-23T08:02:58Z'>
		This slipped between the cracks while I was refactoring. Sorry!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mdda' date='2016-05-23T08:11:50Z'>
		(sorry to ask a continuation question - but you replied to the issue so quickly....)
If I construct a Doc explicitly (my own tokenization, probably the same as spaCy, but can't absolutely guarantee it), I notice that doing :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;spacy_nlp.tagger(doc)
spacy_nlp.entity(doc)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

finds more entities than if I just call .entity(doc).  Presumably, the NER uses the tags as NER boundary hints, etc.
Would NER performance be improved (or changed in any way) if I also include spacy_nlp.parser(doc) in the pipeline?  i.e.  Does the NER make use of dependency information?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mdda' date='2016-05-23T19:52:26Z'>
		The current NER model doesn't use the dependency parse, no. I've always
meant to try that, but never got around to it.
On Monday, May 23, 2016, Martin Andrews &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

(sorry to ask a continuation question - but you replied to the issue so
quickly....)
If I construct a Doc explicitly (my own tokenization, probably the same as
spaCy, but can't absolutely guarantee it), I notice that doing :
spacy_nlp.tagger(doc)
spacy_nlp.entity(doc)
finds more entities than if I just call .entity(doc). Presumably, the NER
uses the tags as NER boundary hints, etc.
Would NER performance be improved (or changed in any way) if I also
include spacy_nlp.parser(doc) in the pipeline? i.e. Does the NER make use
of dependency information?
—
You are receiving this because you commented.
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
#392 (comment)

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mdda' date='2016-09-27T11:03:05Z'>
		The orths_and_spaces argument is now fixed, and the fix will be released in 1.0.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mdda' date='2018-05-09T11:12:11Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>