<bug id='4868' author='bollwyvl' open_date='2020-01-03T02:19:16Z' closed_time='2020-02-11T22:57:44Z'>
	<summary>Include pxd in source tarball</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Feature description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It would be lovely to have the  files included in  official distribution, so that other packages can confidently build against . I'm looking to make a  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/conda-forge/staged-recipes/issues/10517&gt;conda package for neuralcoref&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and my approach of merging the pypi tarball (preferred) and the github tarball (which has the pxd, but probably isn't tested) gives me the willies .
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Could the feature be a custom component or spaCy plugin?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Pretty much would have to be on the mainline. Luckily, I'd imagine it's a one-liner to MANIFEST.in, but I don't know enough about the build chain to know if that's A Bad Idea for some reason... other than size, perhaps? If there's no obvious red flags, I'll PR said line!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bollwyvl' date='2020-01-03T10:34:15Z'>
		Hey,
We definitely intend the pxd to be in the source tarball! The cython api is part of the api, and it's intended to be usable by downstream packages. This is a bug in recent releases after updating our setup logic. We'll get that fixed.
We're also working actively to get neuralcoref into the main library :). If you have time to work on this it's possible we could use your help? I'm travelling today but hopefully I can write more tonight.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bollwyvl' date='2020-01-03T13:42:31Z'>
		Intriguing! I'm more of an amateur packaging puzzle solver than
professional cython hacker (or even spacy power user), but I do have it all
building locally, so at least there's that.

So, always glad to help!  Sure sounds easier than maintaining _n_
additional packages in the long run, as I thought would be required. Getting
the pretrained model pip-installable would help heaps, too.

In the near term, if the pxd are coming back, I won't worry about how ugly
my hack is to get something out.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Fri, Jan 3, 2020, 05:34 Matthew Honnibal ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Hey,

 We definitely intend the pxd to be in the source tarball! The cython api
 is part of the api, and it's intended to be usable by downstream packages.
 This is a bug in recent releases after updating our setup logic. We'll get
 that fixed.

 We're also working actively to get neuralcoref into the main library :).
 If you have time to work on this it's possible we could use your help? I'm
 travelling today but hopefully I can write more tonight.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#4868?email_source=notifications&amp;email_token=AAALCRGNVLOE4LJWUD7C64TQ34ICRA5CNFSM4KCIYS5KYY3PNVWWK3TUL52HS4DFVREXG43VMVBW63LNMVXHJKTDN5WW2ZLOORPWSZGOEIA2QMY#issuecomment-570533939&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AAALCRDMDBND2CJI2EI3223Q34ICRANCNFSM4KCIYS5A&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bollwyvl' date='2020-02-11T22:57:44Z'>
		Should be fixed for the next release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bollwyvl' date='2020-02-11T22:58:55Z'>
		I just saw that Ines had already fixed this on develop when I submitted a fix for master, so yea it should be properly fixed :-)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bollwyvl' date='2020-03-17T13:32:41Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>