<bug id='5754' author='jccaleroe' open_date='2020-07-12T16:09:15Z' closed_time='2020-07-13T12:45:44Z'>
	<summary>Spanish PROPN tag as INTJ</summary>
	<description>
Hello, when I run the POS tagging is Spanish, I am not getting the PROPN tag, instead I get INTJ in the proper names, for example:
INTJ	Alcalde
INTJ	Enrique
INTJ	Peñalosa
If just PROPN tags are in INTJ, I can skip the problem, but if INTJ and PROPN tags are mixed, that is a problem.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to reproduce the behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;nlp = spacy.load("es_core_news_lg")
with open("text_ins_spanish.txt") as f:
    doc = nlp(f.read())

for token in doc:
    print(token.pos_ + "\t" + token.lemma_)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Operating System: CentOS 8
Python Version Used: 3.6.8
spaCy Version Used: 2.3.1

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jccaleroe' date='2020-07-13T10:07:00Z'>
		Thanks for the report! This is indeed a bug in the tag map that maps the token.tag PROPN to the token.pos INTJ. (I think there's a mistake in one token in the AnCora corpus that led to this mapping.) This error should be consistent, so you can correct all the tokens with tag PROPN to have pos PROPN without worrying that some correct examples are mixed in.
I'll release updated versions of the models soon.
If you'd like to fix your installed model in the meanwhile, I've attached an updated tag map, which you can copy to the installed model directory (the attached file tag_map.txt below should overwrite the installed tag map at a path like venv/lib/python3.7/site-packages/es_core_news_lg/es_core_news_lg-2.3.0/tagger/tag_map -- I had to add .txt for github to let me attach it here, but the final name should be tag_map). You can double-check that this assertion holds to check that it was updated as intended:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;nlp = spacy.load("es_core_news_lg")
assert nlp.vocab.morphology.tag_map["PROPN"][74] == 96
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Updated Spanish model v2.3.0 tag map: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/files/4911728/tag_map.txt&gt;tag_map.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>