<bug id='595' author='jirimotejlek' open_date='2016-10-31T12:41:41Z' closed_time='2016-11-03T23:32:14Z'>
	<summary>Adding Lemmatizer Exceptions</summary>
	<description>
I tried to edit exceptions in spacy/data/en-1.1.0/wordnet/verb.exc but it didn't have any effect, spacy is still returning the old lemma. Is there some other way to fix or add the lemmatizer exceptions?
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Operating System: Ubuntu
Python Version Used: 2.7
spaCy Version Used: 0.101.0
Environment Information:

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jirimotejlek' date='2016-11-02T23:01:57Z'>
		Have you checked that the POS tag is being predicted correctly? The exceptions are POS-keyed, so they won't fire if the POS is incorrect.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jirimotejlek' date='2016-11-03T12:39:21Z'>
		Yes, i'm looking for verbs and then for a lemma. Had a problem with a few words (like "Don't feed the dog" is returning lemma "fee" for feed.)
As past tense of fee is very unlikely in my case I went ahead and removed that exception. But SpaCy is still somehow returning "fee".
Is there some cache to rebuild wordnet?
This is an example code:
def get_main_verbs_of_sent(sent):
    """Return the main (non-auxiliary) verbs in a sentence."""
    return [tok for tok in sent
        if tok.pos == VERB and tok.dep_ not in {'aux', 'auxpass'}]

tdoc_itext = textacy.Doc("Don't feed the dog.", lang=u"en")
for sent in doc_itext.sents:
    itext_verbs = get_main_verbs_of_sent(sent)
    for verb in itext_verbs:
        print verb.text
        print verb.pos_
        print verb.lemma_
feed
verb
fee
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jirimotejlek' date='2016-11-03T23:31:49Z'>
		Thanks for the report — turned out to be a deeper problem.
"feed" is being assigned the tag VB, which means it shouldn't be lemmatized at all. The 'VB' tag is supposed to be associated with the morphological feature {verbform: inf}, in the tag map. This wasn't being set on the tokens, due to a bug in the morphological analyser (which is a bit of a mess).
Should be fixed now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jirimotejlek' date='2018-05-09T06:39:11Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>