<bug id='6424' author='forest1988' open_date='2020-11-21T17:24:01Z' closed_time='2020-11-22T21:00:15Z'>
	<summary>Trivial typo in universe/project/self-attentive-parser</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to reproduce the behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I tried to use self-attentive-parser in The spaCy Universe.
However, I got a SyntaxError when I run the example code.
The error occurs In line 6,
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    doc = nlp('The time for action is now. It's never too late to do something.')
                                              ^
SyntaxError: invalid syntax
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I think the problem is that the sentence enclosed in ' ' has It's and contains '.
I've checked the JSON file that contains the contents of Universe, and found that the line contains the sentence is surrounded further out with " ".



spaCy/website/meta/universe.json


         Line 1686
      in
      51232ff






 "doc = nlp('The time for action is now. It's never too late to do something.')", 





By the way, is here the correct place to report any bugs I find in the spaCy Universe and its documentation?
Or should I contact the author directly by referring to the author info in the Universe's documentation?
If here is not the right place, I apologize for the misunderstanding.
Thank you in advance.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


spaCy version: 2.3.2
Platform: Linux-4.15.0-123-generic-x86_64-with-glibc2.10
Python version: 3.8.3

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='forest1988' date='2020-11-21T21:26:27Z'>
		Hi! Thanks for the report - we should indeed fix this. If you find general bugs in a package in the spaCy universe, you can contact the authors directly on their github tracker. But in this case, the issue is with the documentation page of spaCy, so it's fine to report here. I think we can just avoid the issue of quotes in quotes in quotes, and write "It is" instead ;-)
Do you want to make the PR?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='forest1988' date='2020-11-22T00:02:47Z'>
		Thank you for your kind and detailed response!
I now understood that if we find general bugs in the spaCy universe, I can contact the authors directly. I also understood that when it is about the problems with the documentation page of spaCy, it's fine to report here.
Thank you for telling me how to avoid the issue! I will try it soon, and if you don't mind, I'd love to make the PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='forest1988' date='2020-11-22T00:44:45Z'>
		Great - feel free to go ahead!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='forest1988' date='2020-11-22T21:00:15Z'>
		Fixed in PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spaCy/pull/6428&gt;#6428&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - thanks for the report and PR!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='forest1988' date='2020-11-23T05:49:19Z'>
		Thank you again for your kind response!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>