<bug id='1042' author='jiyer2016' open_date='2020-08-28T15:10:50Z' closed_time='2020-08-30T08:16:55Z'>
	<summary>Error in retrieving BENTO if yatai-service uses local disk storage repository for model artifacts (default)</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
This issue happens only if yatai-service uses the default local disk storage repository.
It doesn't happen if configured to use S3 / Minio for storing Model Artifacts.
The call to bentoml retrieve fails from a Remote Node with the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  File "/home/&lt;some_user&gt;/.local/lib/python3.6/site-packages/bentoml/cli/bento_management.py", line 242, in retrieve
    safe_retrieve(bento_service_bundle_path, target_dir)
  File "/home/&lt;some_user&gt;/.local/lib/python3.6/site-packages/bentoml/saved_bundle/loader.py", line 178, in safe_retrieve
    shutil.copytree(bundle_path, target_dir)
  File "/usr/local/lib/python3.6/shutil.py", line 309, in copytree
    names = os.listdir(src)
FileNotFoundError: [Errno 2] No such file or directory: '/home/&lt;some_user&gt;/bentoml/repository/&lt;some_service&gt;/20200828200111_90BFD8'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

It turns out that the path /home/&lt;some_user&gt;/bentoml/repository/&lt;some_service&gt;/20200828200111_90BFD8 is valid on the node that runs the yatai-service.
It seems like bentoml retrieve is looking for that same path on the Remote Node - which wouldn't exist anyway. Why would this happen ? Does it assume than nodes running the yata-service and the remote bento client share the same disk ?
Reproduce**
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Node 1 - bentoml yatai-service-start --no-ui --debug --verbose
Node 1 - Save a Model Service using the API (to local disk storage repository)
Node 2 -  bentoml config set yatai_service.url=
Node 2 - bentoml retrieve &lt;some_service&gt;:latest --target_dir &lt;some_dir&gt;
Node 2 - The call to bentoml retrieve fails with the Error Stack above

Environment:

Python 3.8, BentoML-0.8.4]

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jiyer2016' date='2020-08-30T03:32:18Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiyer2016&gt;@jiyer2016&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - thanks for reporting this. This is a known limitation of YataiService and it is on our roadmap.  For now, we'd recommend using AWS S3 or your own MinIO deployment as the storage for YataiService.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jiyer2016' date='2020-08-30T08:16:52Z'>
		Thanks for confirming - &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/parano&gt;@parano&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
   - I will close this since it is a known issue and you may already have a separate item to track this. Yes, I shall use S3 / MinIO for the actual setup.
Just that the local disk option would be a lot more convenient for demos showcasing the capability to so easily save and distribute a Service across nodes.
BTW - I really appreciate the work you'll have done on making BentoML available as Open Source to the Data Scientists.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>