<bug id='1157' author='gregd33' open_date='2020-10-02T19:38:04Z' closed_time='2020-10-07T18:23:22Z'>
	<summary>ImageInput doesn't exactly return numpy array</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When using the ImageInput adapter, the type of the object is &lt;class 'imageio.core.util.Array'&gt;  rather than &lt;class 'numpy.ndarray'&gt;
To Reproduce

Create a simple service that includes something like:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;@bentoml.api(ImageInput)       
def predict(self, image ):
    if type(image) is np.ndarray:
        return True
    return False
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Run the service with any image

Expected behavior
You will get a false.
Environment:

OS: Ubuntu 16.04
Python 3.7.9
BentoML 0.9.1, numpy 1.19.1, imageio 0.9.1

Additional context
This is a somewhat trivial bug and can easily be solved with an explicit cast to  image = np.array(image) in the service. However, it did cause me to waste much of the day to try to debug a complex bento service (I looked at a lot of other potential causes before ending up here), so I would like to spare others the same pain.
For a fix, I would either update the documentation to state precisely what it returns or cast it to a numpy array in the adapter itself.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gregd33' date='2020-10-07T16:53:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gregd33&gt;@gregd33&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Sorry about you spend the day debuging Bento Service. I know it can be very frustrating.
Like you suggested, It is now explicitly cast as numpy array in the adapters.
My mistake, It seems we always return the image as imageio.core.utils.Array(a subclass of ndarray) instead of numpy.ndarray, I will update the documentation for the adapters.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gregd33' date='2020-10-07T18:04:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bentoml/BentoML/pull/1163&gt;#1163&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gregd33' date='2020-10-07T18:18:59Z'>
		Not a problem and thank you for the fix!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gregd33' date='2020-10-07T18:23:22Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gregd33&gt;@gregd33&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you and really appricate the patients.  Closing this issue, feel free to open for any follow up questions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>