<bug id='1203' author='BorhenJlidi' open_date='2020-10-22T21:55:07Z' closed_time='2020-10-23T17:16:51Z'>
	<summary>onnxruntime-gpu not recognized as a valid onnxruntime python package</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When saving a model for inference (ONNX resnet 50 example), the following warning is outputted :
WARNING - pip package requirementonnxruntime not found in current python environment
This can confuse BentoML users and can possibly drive off new users.
To Reproduce

Install onnxruntime-gpu (doesn't matter prebuilt or compiled from source)
Run onnx resnet50 example

Expected behavior
It shouldn't output such warning
Screenshots/Logs
WARNING - pip package requirementonnxruntime not found in current python environment
Environment:

OS: Ubuntu 20.04
Python Version 3.8.5
BentoML Version 0.92
onnxruntime 1.5.2 (onnxruntime-gpu)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='BorhenJlidi' date='2020-10-22T22:11:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BorhenJlidi&gt;@BorhenJlidi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for reporting.  Right now, it only supports non-gpu version of .  You are right, we should make it more clear to the users.
I think I will 1. make the message more clear and 2. start researching add support for .
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='BorhenJlidi' date='2020-10-22T22:17:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yubozhao&gt;@yubozhao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Just out of curiosity,  when you say it it only supports non-gpu version of  does that mean that it won't work at all or just output the warning?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='BorhenJlidi' date='2020-10-23T19:08:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BorhenJlidi&gt;@BorhenJlidi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  - it's a mistake on our end, BentoML's OnnxModelArtifact assumed any user that is using ONNX will be relying on the  PyPI package whereas some users are using the alternative .
A workaround for you now, is to add onnxruntime-gpu to the @env definition in your BentoService class:
@env(infer_pip_packages=True, pip_packages=["onnxruntime-gpu"])
I will create a github issue for tracking a fix to this issue. Thanks for reporting it! &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BorhenJlidi&gt;@BorhenJlidi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='BorhenJlidi' date='2020-10-23T19:20:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/parano&gt;@parano&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 That's a nice workaround, Thanks! Keep up the amazing work !
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>