<bug id='631' author='jjneojiajun' open_date='2020-05-06T05:15:31Z' closed_time='2020-09-13T08:21:15Z'>
	<summary>botocore.exceptions.ClientError</summary>
	<description>
Hey BentoML Maintainers,
I am currently facing an issue deploying my model to AWS Lambda, although i followed the docs completely. I have received the botocore.exceptions.ClientError indicating there's (NoSuchBucket) when calling the GetBuckAcl Operations and InvalidLocationConstraint when calling the CreateBucket Operations. Any tips in regards to this? Is there like a parameter that i can use to create this bucket?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22229998/81140501-1f3d4280-8f9c-11ea-9b0e-ce2306701b50.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-05-06T19:47:25Z'>
		hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jjneojiajun&gt;@jjneojiajun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 what is the region you are trying to deploy to?
There is an ongoing issue on boto3 that create an S3 bucket will fail for region  that I am not aware,  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/boto/boto3/issues/125&gt;boto/boto3#125&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  I tested deploy lambda with the  region and received the same error as you did.
I am working on a fix for creating S3 bucket for the us-east-1 region.
If you are not deploying to that region, could you provide more info on which region you are deploying to?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-05-07T23:24:21Z'>
		
hi @jjneojiajun what is the region you are trying to deploy to?
There is an ongoing issue on boto3 that create an S3 bucket will fail for region us-east-1 that I am not aware, boto/boto3#125. I tested deploy lambda with the us-east-1 region and received the same error as you did.
I am working on a fix for creating S3 bucket for the us-east-1 region.
If you are not deploying to that region, could you provide more info on which region you are deploying to?

Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yubozhao&gt;@yubozhao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, yes I was trying to deploy to us-east-1 region. So I guess this is part of the bug fix that's required. I will close this thread then. Thank you! :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-06-18T23:11:31Z'>
		I'm still getting this issue after the first deployment to lambda.
Running version 0.8.1 or bentoml.
The first deployment worked for the most part, however subsequent deployments do not.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-06-18T23:23:30Z'>
		cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yubozhao&gt;@yubozhao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you help take a look?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-06-20T00:13:57Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/spencersmith&gt;@spencersmith&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I tested deploying and updating with the quick start example BentoService with  region. Unfortunately, I wasn't able to reproduce the boto3 ClientError about InvalidLocationConstraint error for creating Bucket.
Can you share your boto3 version and what region you are deploying into?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jjneojiajun' date='2020-07-11T17:44:02Z'>
		hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/spencersmith&gt;@spencersmith&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, are you still experiencing this issue?
I think this exact issue(InvalidLocationConstraint with us-east-1 region) should have been fixed in 0.8.1, you might be experiencing a different issue (or our fix did not work). Could you provide the exact error logs if you still have it or if you can still reproduce this issue?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>