<bug id='895' author='jesudasvf' open_date='2020-07-14T15:12:14Z' closed_time='2020-07-18T09:49:06Z'>
	<summary>The CIFAR-10 image classifier prediction fails on Ubuntu 18.04 with bentoml 0.8.3</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
The prediction for the CIFAR-10 image classifier example fails with an error.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Get the CIFAR -10 image classifier from the bentoml gallery examples web page https://github.com/bentoml/gallery/tree/master/pytorch/cifar10-image-classification
Build the bentoml service PytorchImageClassifier
Try to run the PytorchImageClassifier service with the bentoml run command

Expected behavior
The prediction function should have a returned a predicted class value
Screenshots/Logs
To give us more information for diagnosing the issue, make sure to enable debug logging:




Please refer the attached next file for the outputs observed when running the bentoml commands
prj_notes.txt




Environment:

OS: Ubuntu : 18.04.4 LTS (Bionic)
Python/BentoML Version [e.g. Python 3.6.9, BentoML-0.8.3]
Pillow : 7.2.0
pytorch : 1.5.1
torchvision : 0.6.1

Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jesudasvf' date='2020-07-14T17:47:38Z'>
		The handlers import line was changed to




from bentoml.adapters import LegacyImageInput




The bentoml.api line was changed to




@bentoml.api(input=LegacyImageInput)




With the above changes the prediction still gave the same error
Tried with




@bentoml.api(LegacyImageInput)




Still the same error
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jesudasvf' date='2020-07-15T12:58:33Z'>
		The bentoml service file for CIFAR-10 classifier had to be modified as follows:
@bentoml.api(ImageHandler)     changed to




@bentoml.api(ImageInput)




and if in case the pytorch model is trained for GPU the line
outputs = self.artifacts.net(Variable(torch.stack(input_datas)))   changed to




outputs = self.artifacts.net(Variable(torch.stack(input_datas).to('cuda:0'))
the device name should be given properly to select the required GPU device




With the above changes the model predicts with bentoml run cli command
After serving the model predicts using the swagger tool and curl commands
.
The final bentoml service file for cifar-10 image classifier is attached, change the name of the file to .py while using the file.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bentoml/BentoML/files/4925280/cifar_image_classifier.txt&gt;cifar_image_classifier.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jesudasvf' date='2020-07-15T15:16:53Z'>
		Thanks, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jesudasvf&gt;@jesudasvf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! I will update the gallery notebook accordingly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jesudasvf' date='2020-07-18T09:49:06Z'>
		You are welcome &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/parano&gt;@parano&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ! I will close this bug.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>