<bug id='10' author='ghost(ghost)' open_date='2019-11-03T11:34:07Z' closed_time='2019-11-03T12:51:16Z'>
	<summary>Pip can't find spleeter</summary>
	<description>
I can't install this at all with pip. it always says:
ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement spleeter (from versions: none)
ERROR: No matching distribution found for spleeter
whenever I type:
pip install spleeter
Any ideas? This is annoying...
Also, if it means much: I'm using Windows 10 version 1903
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2019-11-03T12:39:28Z'>
		Could you give us more information ? In which context you are running pip ? (Command line, Python distribution, through virtualenv or Conda, into a container, etc ...).
The spleeter package is available on PyPi, so there is no chance that would happen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2019-11-03T12:40:14Z'>
		CMD. I'm running it as administrator. I installed the normal Python release (3.8.0 64-bit)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2019-11-03T12:51:16Z'>
		Closing this issue. I decided to just install Anaconda and use it that way.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2019-11-05T05:08:17Z'>
		@jhm0799 I encountered the same issue and it's caused by your version of python being outside the spleeter reqs of Python &gt;=3.6, &lt;3.8 as listed on its PyPI page (special emphasis on the &lt;3.8 part).
The error message pip gives is really unclear about this being the cause unless you run it with verbose output (pip install spleeter -vvv) to trace the steps it takes to resolve the install command. I installed 3.7.5 and ran the install again and everything worked as expected.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-05-23T06:32:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/batzlerg&gt;@batzlerg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 You're a life saver. Thnx.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-08-23T03:39:47Z'>
		I tried with python 3.7.5 on windows 10 and still get same error
C:\Users\wrayc&gt;pip install sleeter
Collecting sleeter
ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement sleeter (from versions: none)
ERROR: No matching distribution found for sleeter
WARNING: You are using pip version 19.2.3, however version 20.2.2 is available.
You should consider upgrading via the 'python -m pip install --upgrade pip' command.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-08-23T12:24:57Z'>
		Does it work when you spell spleeter correctly?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-09-16T05:38:41Z'>
		Anaconda is of 462 MB :|
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>