<bug id='133' author='ilyakonrad' open_date='2019-11-24T14:42:14Z' closed_time='2019-11-25T14:20:55Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] F tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_fft.cc:436] failed to initialize batched cufft plan with customized allocator:</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm not able to get stems getting F tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_fft.cc:436] failed to initialize batched cufft plan with customized allocator: error when I try to run
spleeter separate -i BillieJean.mp3 -o audio_output -p spleeter:4stems.
What I'm trying to achieve is to just be able to separate stems from the songs. As the result I want to be able to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deezer/spleeter/issues/8#issuecomment-549121231&gt;remove only drum stem&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 so that I can play along with it. I'm not sure if I should train something or I can separate stems right away, so please help me understand what is the correct way of doing this.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Installed using the documentation
Run as spleeter separate -i BillieJean.mp3 -o audio_output -p spleeter:4stems
Got F tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_fft.cc:436] failed to initialize batched cufft plan with customized allocator: error

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

D:\Stems&gt;spleeter separate -i BillieJean.mp3 -o audio_output -p spleeter:4stems
2019-11-24 16:16:12.729386: F tensorflow/stream_executor/cuda/cuda_fft.cc:436] failed to initialize batched cufft plan with customized allocator:

D:\Stems&gt;
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows 10 Enterprise


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
16 GB


Hardware spec
Nvidia GeForce GT 740 / i7 8700K



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I read somewhere that this might be caused by a lack of free space, so (even though I run this command from D drive which has 60 GB of free space) I freed up 10 GB on C drive, which didn't help.
It doesn't matter if I run this in regular cmd or in Anaconda Prompt.
I feel pretty uncomfortable with all these cmd stuff, so I hope you'll be polite. Thanks in advance!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ilyakonrad' date='2020-02-10T09:08:33Z'>
		I'm having this issue right now. How do I fix it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ilyakonrad' date='2020-05-23T16:33:26Z'>
		Same problem here, both with CPU and GPU versions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ilyakonrad' date='2020-08-19T03:16:06Z'>
		Same here, is this issue solved yet?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>