<bug id='157' author='aidv' open_date='2019-12-03T17:33:49Z' closed_time='2019-12-04T04:59:45Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Spleeter crashes at "KMP_AFFINITY"</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

On some songs Spleeter decides to exit too early, rendering nothing.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It's hard to get provide instructions due to potential piracy. I will not share the song I'm trying to process, but basically load a song and it exits at "Affinity" something.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;INFO:spleeter:Audio data loaded successfully

INFO:spleeter:Audio data loaded successfully

OMP: Info #154: KMP_AFFINITY: Initial OS proc set respected: 0-11
OMP: Info #213: KMP_AFFINITY: decoding x2APIC ids.

OMP: Info #276: KMP_AFFINITY: Affinity capable, using global cpuid leaf 11 info
OMP: Info #156: KMP_AFFINITY: 12 available OS procs
OMP: Info #157: KMP_AFFINITY: Uniform topology
OMP: Info #191: KMP_AFFINITY: 1 socket x 6 cores/socket x 2 threads/core (6 total cores)
OMP: Info #215: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc to physical thread map:
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 0 maps to socket 0 core 0 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 1 maps to socket 0 core 0 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 2 maps to socket 0 core 1 thread 0 

OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 3 maps to socket 0 core 1 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 4 maps to socket 0 core 2 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 5 maps to socket 0 core 2 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 6 maps to socket 0 core 3 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 7 maps to socket 0 core 3 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 8 maps to socket 0 core 4 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 9 maps to socket 0 core 4 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 10 maps to socket 0 core 5 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 11 maps to socket 0 core 5 thread 1 
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 16216 thread 0 bound to OS proc set 0

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 23460 thread 1 bound to OS proc set 2

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 8744 thread 2 bound to OS proc set 4

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 19660 thread 3 bound to OS proc set 6

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 18976 thread 4 bound to OS proc set 8
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 26180 thread 5 bound to OS proc set 10

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 5280 thread 6 bound to OS proc set 1
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 26188 thread 7 bound to OS proc set 3

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 26176 thread 8 bound to OS proc set 5

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 10776 thread 9 bound to OS proc set 7

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 22556 thread 10 bound to OS proc set 9

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 1656 thread 11 bound to OS proc set 11

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 5664 thread 13 bound to OS proc set 2

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 26120 thread 14 bound to OS proc set 4

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 17960 thread 12 bound to OS proc set 0

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 17492 thread 15 bound to OS proc set 6

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 24596 thread 17 bound to OS proc set 10

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 9968 thread 16 bound to OS proc set 8

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 4584 thread 18 bound to OS proc set 1

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 14316 thread 19 bound to OS proc set 3

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 21612 thread 20 bound to OS proc set 5

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 19120 thread 21 bound to OS proc set 7
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 25808 thread 22 bound to OS proc set 9

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 25704 thread 23 bound to OS proc set 11

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 18908 thread 24 bound to OS proc set 0

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 25836 thread 25 bound to OS proc set 2

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 24272 thread 26 bound to OS proc set 4
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 22248 thread 27 bound to OS proc set 6

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 24932 thread 28 bound to OS proc set 8

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 20220 thread 29 bound to OS proc set 10

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 19272 thread 30 bound to OS proc set 1

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 14016 thread 31 bound to OS proc set 3

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 10340 thread 32 bound to OS proc set 5
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 3204 thread 33 bound to OS proc set 7

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 3996 thread 34 bound to OS proc set 9
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 20376 thread 35 bound to OS proc set 11

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 7404 thread 36 bound to OS proc set 0

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 3736 thread 38 bound to OS proc set 4

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 21108 thread 37 bound to OS proc set 2
OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 25812 thread 40 bound to OS proc set 8

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 15844 thread 39 bound to OS proc set 6

OMP: Info #251: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 12040 tid 6948 thread 41 bound to OS proc set 10
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows 10


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
16GB



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It's weird that it works on some songs but not on others.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='aidv' date='2019-12-03T19:38:47Z'>
		I have currently identified 42 songs that don't work. That's insane.
Up to 158 songs now. Wow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='aidv' date='2019-12-04T03:06:50Z'>
		Restarting my machone seems to have fixed the issue.
I'd still liketo know if anybody knows what might have caused the issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>