<bug id='163' author='bigboss97' open_date='2019-12-06T00:09:48Z' closed_time='2020-05-10T12:56:49Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Cannot create a file when that file already exists</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I use the option "-o" to specify the output directory. It automatically creates sub-directory with the song title, e.g.
allSongs/Happy Birthday
Beneath that 2 files are created: accompaniment.wav and vocals.wav
For the 2nd song I use the same director and it creates:
allSongs/Jingle Bells/accompaniment.wav
Then it stops with:
FileExistsError: [Errno 17] Cannot create a file when that file already exists:
Jingle Bells/accompaniment.wav was created successfully.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Run spleeter to convert song1 with -o allSongs.
Run spleeter to convert song2 with -o allSongs.
song2/accompaniment.wav created and fails to create vocals.wav.

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

FileExistsError: [Errno 17] Cannot create a file when that file already exists: song2
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Windows 7
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Workaround:

Rename song1/vocals.wav to vocals1.wav
Delete song2 directory.
Rerun spleeter for song2.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bigboss97' date='2019-12-10T05:11:43Z'>
		This "workaround" doesn't work all of the time.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bigboss97' date='2019-12-11T22:58:08Z'>
		Just had the opposite case, vocals was generated and had to rename accompaniment of previous song to workaround.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bigboss97' date='2019-12-20T10:02:52Z'>
		Try making a new folder inside the folder you are working named spleeter and put the song in there. The full command line should look like this:
C:\Users\YourUsername\FolderOfYourMusic&gt;python -m spleeter separate -i spleeter/YourSong.mp3 -p spleeter:2stems -o OutputFolderName
You may have to change folder location in cmd by using cd.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bigboss97' date='2020-01-20T17:47:46Z'>
		I'm using spleeter version 1.4.9 on Windows 10 (haven't tried on another OS yet), and was running into this same problem. Not every time, but most of the time. I made one change to the source code, and after that things worked for me.
in audio/ffmpeg.py I changed line 108 from
os.makedirs(directory)
to this
os.makedirs(directory, exist_ok=True)
Looks like this project is using multiprocessing to create the wav files, and in that case, the check performed on line 107  if not os.path.exists(directory): will not guarantee that the directory is not created, because another process could have created the directory already. In my opinion the check could be removed completely, since the exist_ok option does what that check intends anyway.
When I get a chance to test more thoroughly, I can confirm if this completely fixed the issue or not.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bigboss97' date='2020-01-21T23:19:17Z'>
		I also noticed that the issue varies. You are right, it must be race condition.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>