<bug id='239' author='Christilut' open_date='2020-01-20T15:05:23Z' closed_time='2020-04-05T12:08:59Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] ValueError: Couldn't find trained model at pretrained_models\2stems.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm getting this error sometimes and it's not clear to me why. My current workaround is to delete the temporary folder that contains the stems and to try again. That usually works.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Installed using conda
Run as user
Got ValueError: Couldn't find trained model at pretrained_models\2stems. error

Can't reliably reproduce this yet but it does occur quite often. Maybe it has to do with cancelling the process mid-way. I tried that a bit, but nothing concrete yet.
I'll update this issue if I find out more. Just wanted to let you know that this is going on.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

ValueError: Couldn't find trained model at pretrained_models\2stems.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
32GB


Hardware spec
Ryzen



	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-23T20:22:17Z'>
		you can redownload it by removing the pretrained folder in C:\Users[user name]\pretrained_models
Works with me...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-24T08:19:21Z'>
		Yes but that's not an acceptable solution, that is a workaround... Something during the execution of spleeter is causing this and that should be solved really
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-27T16:38:56Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Christilut&gt;@Christilut&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Are you re-downloading the model each time you run the script ? what is the exact command line you are using ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-27T17:34:23Z'>
		I'm using spleeter in a script and I extract the 2stems.zip contents to the target directory every time before running spleeter to prevent this issue and a re-download.
`${copiedPythonPath} -m spleeter separate -i "${pathFull}" -p spleeter:2stems-16kHz -o "C:\Users\User\AppData\Local\Temp\spleeter_output_dir\results"`
where copiedPythonPath is a copied Python.exe (so I can kill the process based on name), pathFull is the input file.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-27T18:04:34Z'>
		
I'm using spleeter in a script and I extract the 2stems.zip contents to the target directory every time before running spleeter to prevent this issue and a re-download.
`${copiedPythonPath} -m spleeter separate -i "${pathFull}" -p spleeter:2stems-16kHz -o "C:\Users\User\AppData\Local\Temp\spleeter_output_dir\results"`
where copiedPythonPath is a copied Python.exe (so I can kill the process based on name), pathFull is the input file.

If it's already downloaded, you dont need to donwload the stems again.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Christilut' date='2020-01-27T18:07:13Z'>
		Well but that is the current workaround to fix this issue... Something happens to the stem files and replacing them with the original files fixes it temporarily.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Christilut' date='2020-04-05T12:16:09Z'>
		Is this problem fixed?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>