<bug id='293' author='MrPatben8' open_date='2020-03-16T17:07:19Z' closed_time='2020-04-05T12:21:00Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Unknown encoder m4a</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When using the -c option for selecting the m4a encoder for the output files, the process fails. This appears to be related to FFMPEG.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


cd into the directory with song.mp3
run spleeter separate -i song.mp3 -c m4a -p spleeter:4stems -o output 

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

ERROR:spleeter:FFMPEG error: b"ffmpeg version git-2020-03-11-36aaee2 Copyright (c) 2000-2020 the FFmpeg developers\r\n  built with gcc 9.2.1 (GCC) 20200122\r\n  configuration: --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuda-llvm --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt --enable-amf\r\n  libavutil      56. 42.100 / 56. 42.100\r\n  libavcodec     58. 75.100 / 58. 75.100\r\n  libavformat    58. 41.100 / 58. 41.100\r\n  libavdevice    58.  9.103 / 58.  9.103\r\n  libavfilter     7. 77.100 /  7. 77.100\r\n  libswscale      5.  6.100 /  5.  6.100\r\n  libswresample   3.  6.100 /  3.  6.100\r\n  libpostproc    55.  6.100 / 55.  6.100\r\nGuessed Channel Layout for Input Stream #0.0 : stereo\r\nInput #0, f32le, from 'pipe:':\r\n  Duration: N/A, bitrate: 2822 kb/s\r\n    Stream #0:0: Audio: pcm_f32le, 44100 Hz, stereo, flt, 2822 kb/s\r\nUnknown encoder 'm4a'\r\n"
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

| OS                | Windows  |
| Installation type |  pip |
| RAM available     | 16Gb |
| Hardware spec     | Nvidia GTX1070 / AMD FX-6300 |
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MrPatben8' date='2020-03-23T08:47:08Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MrPatben8&gt;@MrPatben8&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

m4a is a container format, I guess you mean aac in which case it should work with -c aac. Best
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MrPatben8' date='2020-03-23T15:03:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mmoussallam&gt;@mmoussallam&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Ah yeah that could be it. In any case the help option is incorrect since it lists m4a as one of the encoder options.
Thanks for your help!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>