<bug id='32' author='syxu828' open_date='2019-11-05T22:10:16Z' closed_time='2019-11-21T15:52:27Z'>
	<summary>Issues when fine tune model</summary>
	<description>
Hi, thanks for sharing your nice work!
I have a question when I tried to fine-tune your model on my dataset.
I feed your released pertained model to the estimator and trained the model with my dataset.
However, the model did not find the parameters for "../../Adam" in the checkpoint.
Do you have any idea about this problem ?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='syxu828' date='2019-11-06T14:32:53Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/syxu828&gt;@syxu828&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for your interest and feedback.
For the sake of shipping lighter models (~ 3x lighter) we stripped out from the graph all the nodes that were useless for inference. That's the case of everything that concerns optimizers. This unfortunately precludes fine-tuning the models. We'll try to publish the full models as quickly as possible. This should not be an issue, keep an eye out!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='syxu828' date='2019-11-06T18:23:52Z'>
		Thanks very much !
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='syxu828' date='2019-11-10T21:57:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/syxu828&gt;@syxu828&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  please share insights into how to do fine tuning
I’m wondering if the instrument layers can go wider.
Eg here’s the flute / trombone / high hat /   kick etc  layers.
16 track / 32 / 64 / 128 / 1024 / etc
Use this orchestral model for this song
Use the rock n roll model for other
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='syxu828' date='2019-11-21T15:52:27Z'>
		We've just released complete models with optimizers parameters for fine tuning in this &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deezer/spleeter/releases&gt;release&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. There is no straightforward way to do fine tuning yet, but you can download manually the model and make the config json file point to it for doing fine tuning.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='syxu828' date='2019-11-21T19:15:03Z'>
		Hi, I just want to see if we can have more performance improvements by introducing more 2stems/4stems dataset.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>