<bug id='324' author='morsik' open_date='2020-04-13T22:25:09Z' closed_time='2020-04-14T12:55:48Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Crash in the middle of separation</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Spleeter crashes in the middle of separation process. At the output directory I've got only part of vocals.wav.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Just install clean Spleeter 1.5.0
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ conda list | grep spleeter
# packages in environment at /home/morsik/.conda/envs/spleeter:
spleeter                  1.5.0            py37hc8dfbb8_0    conda-forge
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Installed using conda install -c conda-forge spleeter
Run as spleeter separate -i ~/Ayreon\ -\ Intergalactic\ Space\ Crusaders\ \(Universe\)-mDjomu33Xzc.webm spleeter:2stems -o output
Got error below.

This is file downloaded from YouTube so I tried reinstalling whole Conda environment (just removed ~/.conda/envs/spleeter and recreated it from scratch along with removing pretrained_models directory to force redownload models) because maybe of some bug. After not fixing this by all of this I tried file that I had previously splitted by Spleeter 1.0 right after release - and it crashed too.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;INFO:spleeter:Downloading model archive https://github.com/deezer/spleeter/releases/download/v1.4.0/2stems.tar.gz
INFO:spleeter:Validating archive checksum
INFO:spleeter:Extracting downloaded 2stems archive
INFO:spleeter:2stems model file(s) extracted
OMP: Info #212: KMP_AFFINITY: decoding x2APIC ids.
OMP: Info #210: KMP_AFFINITY: Affinity capable, using global cpuid leaf 11 info
OMP: Info #154: KMP_AFFINITY: Initial OS proc set respected: 0-7
OMP: Info #156: KMP_AFFINITY: 8 available OS procs
OMP: Info #157: KMP_AFFINITY: Uniform topology
OMP: Info #179: KMP_AFFINITY: 1 packages x 4 cores/pkg x 2 threads/core (4 total cores)
OMP: Info #214: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc to physical thread map:
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 0 maps to package 0 core 0 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 4 maps to package 0 core 0 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 1 maps to package 0 core 1 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 5 maps to package 0 core 1 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 2 maps to package 0 core 2 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 6 maps to package 0 core 2 thread 1 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 3 maps to package 0 core 3 thread 0 
OMP: Info #171: KMP_AFFINITY: OS proc 7 maps to package 0 core 3 thread 1 
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 985669 thread 0 bound to OS proc set 0
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986165 thread 1 bound to OS proc set 1
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986164 thread 2 bound to OS proc set 2
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986203 thread 3 bound to OS proc set 3
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986205 thread 5 bound to OS proc set 5
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986204 thread 4 bound to OS proc set 4
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986206 thread 6 bound to OS proc set 6
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986207 thread 7 bound to OS proc set 7
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986208 thread 8 bound to OS proc set 0
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986216 thread 16 bound to OS proc set 0
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986210 thread 10 bound to OS proc set 2
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986209 thread 9 bound to OS proc set 1
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986212 thread 12 bound to OS proc set 4
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986215 thread 15 bound to OS proc set 7
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986213 thread 13 bound to OS proc set 5
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986211 thread 11 bound to OS proc set 3
OMP: Info #250: KMP_AFFINITY: pid 985669 tid 986214 thread 14 bound to OS proc set 6
ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below)

ffprobe version 4.2 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers
  built with gcc 7.3.0 (crosstool-NG 1.23.0.449-a04d0)
  configuration: --prefix=/home/morsik/.conda/envs/spleeter --cc=/home/conda/feedstock_root/build_artifacts/ffmpeg_1566210161358/_build_env/bin/x86_64-conda_cos6-linux-gnu-cc --disable-doc --disable-openssl --enable-avresample --enable-gnutls --enable-gpl --enable-hardcoded-tables --enable-libfreetype --enable-libopenh264 --enable-libx264 --enable-pic --enable-pthreads --enable-shared --enable-static --enable-version3 --enable-zlib --enable-libmp3lame
  libavutil      56. 31.100 / 56. 31.100
  libavcodec     58. 54.100 / 58. 54.100
  libavformat    58. 29.100 / 58. 29.100
  libavdevice    58.  8.100 / 58.  8.100
  libavfilter     7. 57.100 /  7. 57.100
  libavresample   4.  0.  0 /  4.  0.  0
  libswscale      5.  5.100 /  5.  5.100
  libswresample   3.  5.100 /  3.  5.100
  libpostproc    55.  5.100 / 55.  5.100
spleeter:2stems: Protocol not found

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Fedora 31 with 5.5.13-200.fc31.x86_64


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
16G + 32G SWAP


Hardware spec
i7-8565U



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Tried on &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mDjomu33Xzc&gt;this&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 YouTube video, but also on mp3 file I previously had converted successfully.
I've tried also setting -B tensorflow and -B librosa - both failed wth same error.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='morsik' date='2020-04-14T12:55:48Z'>
		The command spleeter separate -i ~/Ayreon\ -\ Intergalactic\ Space\ Crusaders\ \(Universe\)-mDjomu33Xzc.webm spleeter:2stems -o output you're running is incorrect.
It must be:
spleeter separate -i ~/Ayreon\ -\ Intergalactic\ Space\ Crusaders\ \(Universe\)-mDjomu33Xzc.webm -p spleeter:2stems -o output
(with an extra -pbefore spleeter:2stems) otherwise, spleeter:2stems is considered a second audio to be separated, and ffmpeg is not able to handle it, as stated by the lines ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below) and spleeter:2stems: Protocol not found in the log.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='morsik' date='2020-04-14T15:05:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/romi1502&gt;@romi1502&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I feel so stupid now… I accidentally removed  when using this command taken from my bash history and didn't compared to history.
Thank you!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>