<bug id='364' author='JohnSmith2007' open_date='2020-05-07T19:09:26Z' closed_time='2020-05-10T12:39:02Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] ffprobe error: No such file or directory</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

still trying to get spleeter to stop being a fickle piece of shit. every time i enter the command it keeps saying "No such file or directory", and it keeps confusing the audio file as a directory,, thinking that the audio file dosen't exist, which is bullshit.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

run python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output

Installed using Conda
Run as regular user
Got spleeter: error: unrecognized arguments: o- output

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(base) C:\Users\smcco&gt;python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output
ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below)

ffprobe version 4.2 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers
  built with gcc 9.1.1 (GCC) 20190807
  configuration: --disable-static --enable-shared --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-amf --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt
  libavutil      56. 31.100 / 56. 31.100
  libavcodec     58. 54.100 / 58. 54.100
  libavformat    58. 29.100 / 58. 29.100
  libavdevice    58.  8.100 / 58.  8.100
  libavfilter     7. 57.100 /  7. 57.100
  libswscale      5.  5.100 /  5.  5.100
  libswresample   3.  5.100 /  3.  5.100
  libpostproc    55.  5.100 / 55.  5.100
C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power: No such file or directory
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
16GB


Hardware spec
GPU: nVIDIA GeForce 1050 Ti, Intel UHD Graphics 630, CPU: Intel i5-8300



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This program is still fickle as shit
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-07T20:08:21Z'>
		File names with spaces require the right syntax in order to be accepted, otherwise it will make any command-line program appear fickle.

Get Outlook for iOS&lt;&lt;denchmark-link:https://aka.ms/o0ukef&gt;https://aka.ms/o0ukef&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
&gt;
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


________________________________
From: JohnSmith2007 &lt;notifications@github.com&gt;
Sent: Thursday, May 7, 2020 12:09:50 PM
To: deezer/spleeter &lt;spleeter@noreply.github.com&gt;
Cc: Subscribed &lt;subscribed@noreply.github.com&gt;
Subject: [deezer/spleeter] [Bug] ffprobe error: No such file or directory (#364)


Description

still trying to get spleeter to stop being a fickle piece of shit. every time i enter the command it keeps saying "No such file or directory", and it keeps confusing the audio file as a directory,, thinking that the audio file dosen't exist, which is bullshit.

Step to reproduce

run python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output

  1.  Installed using Conda
  2.  Run as regular user
  3.  Got spleeter: error: unrecognized arguments: o- output

Output

(base) C:\Users\smcco&gt;python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output
ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below)

ffprobe version 4.2 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers
  built with gcc 9.1.1 (GCC) 20190807
  configuration: --disable-static --enable-shared --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-amf --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt
  libavutil      56. 31.100 / 56. 31.100
  libavcodec     58. 54.100 / 58. 54.100
  libavformat    58. 29.100 / 58. 29.100
  libavdevice    58.  8.100 / 58.  8.100
  libavfilter     7. 57.100 /  7. 57.100
  libswscale      5.  5.100 /  5.  5.100
  libswresample   3.  5.100 /  3.  5.100
  libpostproc    55.  5.100 / 55.  5.100
C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power: No such file or directory

Environment
OS      Windows
Installation type       Conda
RAM available   16GB
Hardware spec   GPU: nVIDIA GeForce 1050 Ti, Intel UHD Graphics 630, CPU: Intel i5-8300
Additional context

This program is still fickle as shit

—
You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub&lt;#364&gt;, or unsubscribe&lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ACV5C5AOSNR3WBXMGSC3Z2TRQMBP5ANCNFSM4M3SVEDA&gt;.

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-07T20:41:54Z'>
		ok then, what syntax is it that i need? 'Cause i don't know that much about coding. I'm only using spleeter so i can make multitracks for my customs in Rock Band 3.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-09T18:02:51Z'>
		
File names with spaces require the right syntax in order to be accepted, otherwise it will make any command-line program appear fickle. Get Outlook for iOShttps://aka.ms/o0ukef
…
________________________________ From: JohnSmith2007 notifications@github.com Sent: Thursday, May 7, 2020 12:09:50 PM To: deezer/spleeter spleeter@noreply.github.com Cc: Subscribed subscribed@noreply.github.com Subject: [deezer/spleeter] [Bug] ffprobe error: No such file or directory (#364) Description still trying to get spleeter to stop being a fickle piece of shit. every time i enter the command it keeps saying "No such file or directory", and it keeps confusing the audio file as a directory,, thinking that the audio file dosen't exist, which is bullshit. Step to reproduce run python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output 1. Installed using Conda 2. Run as regular user 3. Got spleeter: error: unrecognized arguments: o- output Output (base) C:\Users\smcco&gt;python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power Rangers Time Force Theme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below) ffprobe version 4.2 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers built with gcc 9.1.1 (GCC) 20190807 configuration: --disable-static --enable-shared --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-amf --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt libavutil 56. 31.100 / 56. 31.100 libavcodec 58. 54.100 / 58. 54.100 libavformat 58. 29.100 / 58. 29.100 libavdevice 58. 8.100 / 58. 8.100 libavfilter 7. 57.100 / 7. 57.100 libswscale 5. 5.100 / 5. 5.100 libswresample 3. 5.100 / 3. 5.100 libpostproc 55. 5.100 / 55. 5.100 C:\Users\smcco\Music\Power: No such file or directory Environment OS Windows Installation type Conda RAM available 16GB Hardware spec GPU: nVIDIA GeForce 1050 Ti, Intel UHD Graphics 630, CPU: Intel i5-8300 Additional context This program is still fickle as shit — You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread. Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub&lt;#364&gt;, or unsubscribehttps://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ACV5C5AOSNR3WBXMGSC3Z2TRQMBP5ANCNFSM4M3SVEDA.

ok then, what syntax is it that i need? 'Cause i don't know that much about coding. I'm only using spleeter so i can make multitracks for my customs in Rock Band 3.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-09T20:28:04Z'>
		Please remember this is open source software where your questions are answered by volunteers, replying twice on an issue and cursing isn't welcome.
Google how to type in file names with spaces into the command line.
Otherwise, delete the spaces from your file like in the example below:
python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\PowerRangersTimeForceTheme.mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o output
Try to work on your coding problem and if it's not interesting to you to solve, then use one of the cheap paid services online like ezstems and have the benefit of a graphical user interface.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>