<bug id='377' author='JohnSmith2007' open_date='2020-05-18T21:12:11Z' closed_time='2020-05-18T22:07:42Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] No such file or directory</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I've been dealing with several errors with this program for the past month, and i thought i finally figured it out. apparently i was wrong. I swear to god, I didn't do anything wrong, i didn't miss any syntax(e's), nothing. I'm starting to think that spleeter dosen't like folders that have spaces.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made\Comin_in_Hot.mp3 -c mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o /output/C:\Users\smcco\Music\

Installed using Conda
Run as regular user
Got C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made\Comin_in_Hot.mp3: No such file or directory error

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(base) C:\Users\smcco&gt;python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made\Comin_in_Hot.mp3 -c mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o /output/C:\Users\smcco\Music\
ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below)

ffprobe version 4.2 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers
  built with gcc 9.1.1 (GCC) 20190807
  configuration: --disable-static --enable-shared --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-amf --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt
  libavutil      56. 31.100 / 56. 31.100
  libavcodec     58. 54.100 / 58. 54.100
  libavformat    58. 29.100 / 58. 29.100
  libavdevice    58.  8.100 / 58.  8.100
  libavfilter     7. 57.100 /  7. 57.100
  libswscale      5.  5.100 /  5.  5.100
  libswresample   3.  5.100 /  3.  5.100
  libpostproc    55.  5.100 / 55.  5.100
C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made\Comin_in_Hot.mp3: No such file or directory
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows


Installation type
Conda


RAM available
16GB


Hardware spec
GPU: nVIDIA GeForce 1050 Ti, Intel UHD Graphics 630 / CPU: Intel i5-8300



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I honestly don't know what to do anymore. I'm starting to feel like i should give up.
At first i thought that it gave me this error because there were spaces in both the file name (Comin in Hot.mp3), and the folder that the mp3 is located in (C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made), so i added replaced the spaces with some underscores in hopes that it would fix it. I was wrong. I even tried making a separate folder just for the file, and took the filename away from the path. But it still wouldn't work. Also, i see that somebody just responded. I never knew that the page would update itself in realtime. Holy shit.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deezer/spleeter/files/4646842/Comin.In.Hot.zip&gt;Comin In Hot.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-18T21:17:32Z'>
		You might be able to get around it '-B tensorflow'?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-18T21:20:31Z'>
		Ok, but where would i put -B tensorflow in the code string?
--&gt; python -m spleeter separate -i C:\Users\smcco\Music\Customs_i've_made\Comin_in_Hot.mp3 -c mp3 -p spleeter:5stems -o /output/C:\Users\smcco\Music\
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-18T21:44:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dankwartrustow&gt;@dankwartrustow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Never mind, just discovered your GUI for Spleeter. Works wonders, and now i don't need to deal with code, something i don't know jack shit about. Thank you so much!!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='JohnSmith2007' date='2020-05-18T21:46:14Z'>
		&lt;!--
/* Font Definitions */
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/font-face&gt;@font-face&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	{font-family:"Cambria Math";
	panose-1:2 4 5 3 5 4 6 3 2 4;}
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/font-face&gt;@font-face&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	{font-family:Calibri;
	panose-1:2 15 5 2 2 2 4 3 2 4;}
/* Style Definitions */
p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal
	{margin:0in;
	margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	font-size:11.0pt;
	font-family:"Calibri",sans-serif;}
.MsoChpDefault
	{mso-style-type:export-only;}
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/page&gt;@page&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 WordSection1
	{size:8.5in 11.0in;
	margin:1.0in 1.0in 1.0in 1.0in;}
div.WordSection1
	{page:WordSection1;}
--&gt;It’s not mine, it’s forked. Okay good luck.  
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>