<bug id='379' author='vsevolodp' open_date='2020-05-19T11:04:36Z' closed_time='2020-05-20T15:03:32Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] not working with cyrillic chars in file name</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When input file name contains Cyrillic chars spleeter fails
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Installed using Anaconda for Windows x64
Run as spleeter separate -p spleeter:4stems -o . -i Песня.wav
Got error 'An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below) - ?????.wav: Invalid argument'

I've tried few code pages with command chcp 65001: 65001, 1251, 866. Same issue.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

ERROR:spleeter:An error occurs with ffprobe (see ffprobe output below)

ffprobe version git-2019-11-22-89aa134 Copyright (c) 2007-2019 the FFmpeg developers
  built with gcc 9.2.1 (GCC) 20191010
  configuration: --enable-gpl --enable-version3 --enable-sdl2 --enable-fontconfig --enable-gnutls --enable-iconv --enable-libass --enable-libdav1d --enable-libbluray --enable-libfreetype --enable-libmp3lame --enable-libopencore-amrnb --enable-libopencore-amrwb --enable-libopenjpeg --enable-libopus --enable-libshine --enable-libsnappy --enable-libsoxr --enable-libtheora --enable-libtwolame --enable-libvpx --enable-libwavpack --enable-libwebp --enable-libx264 --enable-libx265 --enable-libxml2 --enable-libzimg --enable-lzma --enable-zlib --enable-gmp --enable-libvidstab --enable-libvorbis --enable-libvo-amrwbenc --enable-libmysofa --enable-libspeex --enable-libxvid --enable-libaom --enable-libmfx --enable-ffnvcodec --enable-cuvid --enable-d3d11va --enable-nvenc --enable-nvdec --enable-dxva2 --enable-avisynth --enable-libopenmpt --enable-amf
  libavutil      56. 36.100 / 56. 36.100
  libavcodec     58. 62.100 / 58. 62.100
  libavformat    58. 35.100 / 58. 35.100
  libavdevice    58.  9.101 / 58.  9.101
  libavfilter     7. 66.100 /  7. 66.100
  libswscale      5.  6.100 /  5.  6.100
  libswresample   3.  6.100 /  3.  6.100
  libpostproc    55.  6.100 / 55.  6.100
?????.wav: Invalid argument
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
Windows 10 x64 1909


Installation type
Conda


Package
spleeter-gpu



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It works if started with python -m
&gt; python -m spleeter separate -p spleeter:4stems -o . -i Песня.wav
INFO:spleeter:File .\Песня/vocals.wav written succesfully
INFO:spleeter:File .\Песня/drums.wav written succesfully
INFO:spleeter:File .\Песня/bass.wav written succesfully
INFO:spleeter:File .\Песня/other.wav written succesfully
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vsevolodp' date='2020-05-20T15:03:32Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vsevolodp&gt;@vsevolodp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It seems to be just an issue with the encoding in your terminal and not linked to spleeter code itself.
Since you have a workaround for this and we cannot fix on our side, I'm closing this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>