<bug id='530' author='agur' open_date='2020-12-08T23:32:05Z' closed_time='2020-12-10T08:20:02Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Dev setup from scratch isn't working when python 3.9 is installed</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


On a mac, have python 3.9 installed.
But TF 2.3.0 is not found for 3.9 and errors out.
In my case I had deps on 3.9 already in use on the system.  Thus force downgrade from 3.9 to 3.8 is not recommended.
Expected both clean and non intrusive solution is to create a new virtual env for 3.8 and work there in a clean isolated manner.

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Install env / deps with pip install :

(spleeterenv) $ python -m pip install .
Processing /Users/agur/dev/github/agur/spleeter
Requirement already satisfied: setuptools&gt;=41.0.0 in /usr/local/lib/python3.9/site-packages (from spleeter==2.0.2) (50.3.2)
ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement tensorflow==2.3.0 (from spleeter)
ERROR: No matching distribution found for tensorflow==2.3.0
(spleeterenv) $ python -m pip --version
pip 20.3.1 from /usr/local/lib/python3.9/site-packages/pip (python 3.9)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(In steps above)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
MacOS 10.15.7


Installation type
python 3.9, pip / virtualenv


RAM available
32gb


Hardware spec
CPU: 2.6 GHz 6-Core Intel Core i7, GPU: AMD Radeon Pro 5300M



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Got a solution and will submit a fix.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='agur' date='2020-12-10T08:20:02Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/agur&gt;@agur&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks for your comment and suggestion. As we are already mentioning that Spleeter is only compatible with python 3.6 to 3.8 I don't think it's worth mentioning again in the README. Virtualenv is indeed one way to have it work, using our docker images is another one.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='agur' date='2020-12-11T07:14:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mmoussallam&gt;@mmoussallam&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - thanks for your notes.
While this happened on Mac and I have mentioned it on the ticket, then there is nothing mac specific in that use-case and the same can happen not only with 3.9 but with any future non-supported version.   What I wrote for the process is not Mac specific:

Troubleshoot dev env:
In case of already having multiple python versions installed, including 3.9.
Then if you want to explicitly use a 3.8 since TF 2.3.0 isn't on 3.9 (yet).
And we want a clean new virtualenv on 3.8.
Then just instead of: python -m venv spleeterenv use:
/usr/local/opt/python@3.8/bin/python3 -m venv spleeterenv
python -m pip install --upgrade pip

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>