<bug id='88' author='nicholasmswift' open_date='2019-11-14T01:02:26Z' closed_time='2019-11-14T06:01:20Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Colab Runtime Disconnected</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Was having trouble installing for local use, so I decided to try to use the Colab link.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Step to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Opened Colab environment
Replaced the wget command with

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;from google.colab import files
uploaded = files.upload() 
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Ran all steps in order
Uploaded a local mp3 file
Ran the rest of the steps
Got a successful message from the actual separate function, and files exist in the output directory
Tried to listen to the output file and got a "runtime disconnected" error

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

!spleeter separate -i keenanvskel.mp3 -o output/
Output from the split function
INFO:spleeter:Loading audio b'keenanvskel.mp3' from 0.0 to 600.0
INFO:spleeter:Audio data loaded successfully
INFO:spleeter:File output/keenanvskel/vocals.wav written
INFO:spleeter:File output/keenanvskel/accompaniment.wav written
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;!ls output/keenanvskel
accompaniment.wav  vocals.wav
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Then I ran this
Audio('output/keenanvskel/vocals.wav')
And got this response
Runtime Disconnected
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;










OS
My laptop is running MacOS, but using Colab


Installation type
pip


RAM available
Got the green checkmark for both RAM and Disk in the Colab environment


Hardware spec
unsure



&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Not sure if this is an issue with spleeter or with Colab. I love this project conceptually so I was excited to try it out, I saw some other posts online about runtime disconnect errors in Colab, but everything I found seems to only occur if it's running for 15 minutes or more. This whole process was less than 5 minutes, and I've tried multiple times and continually get the same error.
If this is not the correct place for this type of error, or if I am doing something wrong, feel free to close this bug and let me know what next steps I might take.
Will also attach some screenshots of the environment.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11081954/68817684-0e90bd00-0648-11ea-8f55-8228f81970d5.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11081954/68817685-0e90bd00-0648-11ea-8c1b-c6a94dafd747.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11081954/68817686-0e90bd00-0648-11ea-8738-3bec1b194081.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11081954/68817688-13ee0780-0648-11ea-8a8e-c468bd32bf79.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nicholasmswift' date='2019-11-14T06:01:20Z'>
		Not a Google Colab expert, but we provided the colab so people can try it out without installing the environment. Although, I assume since it is free, then colab provides limited resources in term of CPU and RAM, and turn out thet Spleeter is RAM greedy, and depending of the size of your song it is highly possible that you reach colab RAM limit.
We won't provide assistance for this case as it is purely a colab related issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nicholasmswift' date='2019-11-20T13:24:22Z'>
		Just add -c mp3 to separate command and you will be able to play the output, since playing .wav is more consuming
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>