<bug id='1893' author='Werni2A' open_date='2020-08-21T09:21:11Z' closed_time='2020-08-21T11:27:53Z'>
	<summary>NCS2 freezes after inference</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


myriadPlugin =&gt; 2.1
OpenVINO =&gt; 2020.4.0-359-21e092122f4-releases/2020/4
Operating System / Platform =&gt; Ubuntu 18.04.5 LTS
Compiler =&gt; g++ (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0
Problem classification: Inference

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When running an inference on my NCS2 it freezes before the program can end. The strange thing is that I can perform multiple inferences in a row and get correct results but when I want to end my program it freezes. This freeze only happens when I connect the NCS2 directly to a USB3 port, when I connect it over a USB2 extension cable I get the following error after a few seconds:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEvent:264          Condition failed: event-&gt;header.flags.bitField.ack != 1
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEventWithPerf:276  addEvent(event) method call failed with an error: 3
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] XLinkReadData:156     Condition failed: (addEventWithPerf(&amp;event, &amp;opTime))
E: [ncAPI]  [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] getGraphMonitorResponseValue:1879     XLink error, rc: X_LINK_ERROR
E: [global] [    182615] [Scheduler00Thr]  dispatcherEventSend:53        Write failed (header) (err -4) | event XLINK_WRITE_REQ

E: [xLink]  [    182615] [Scheduler00Thr]  sendEvents:1027        Event sending failed
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEvent:264 Condition failed: event-&gt;header.flags.bitField.ack != 1
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEventWithPerf:276   addEvent(event) method call failed with an error: 3
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] XLinkReadData:156      Condition failed: (addEventWithPerf(&amp;event, &amp;opTime))
E: [ncAPI]  [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] getGraphMonitorResponseValue:1879     XLink error, rc: X_LINK_ERROR
E: [global] [    182615] [Scheduler00Thr]  dispatcherEventSend:53        Write failed (header) (err -4) | event XLINK_WRITE_REQ

E: [xLink]  [    182615] [Scheduler00Thr]  sendEvents:1027        Event sending failed
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEvent:264 Condition failed: event-&gt;header.flags.bitField.ack != 1
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] addEventWithPerf:276   addEvent(event) method call failed with an error: 3
E: [global] [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] XLinkReadData:156      Condition failed: (addEventWithPerf(&amp;event, &amp;opTime))
E: [ncAPI]  [    182615] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] getGraphMonitorResponseValue:1879     XLink error, rc: X_LINK_ERROR
E: [global] [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  dispatcherEventSend:53        Write failed (header) (err -4) | event XLINK_CLOSE_STREAM_REQ

E: [xLink]  [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  sendEvents:1027        Event sending failed
E: [global] [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  dispatcherEventSend:53        Write failed (header) (err -4) | event XLINK_CLOSE_STREAM_REQ

E: [xLink]  [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  sendEvents:1027        Event sending failed
E: [global] [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  dispatcherEventSend:53        Write failed (header) (err -4) | event XLINK_RESET_REQ

E: [xLink]  [    182616] [Scheduler00Thr]  sendEvents:1027        Event sending failed
E: [ncAPI]  [    192616] [NCS2_Hello_Worl] ncDeviceClose:1829    Device didn't appear after reboot
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Below I attached my project it is kind of a minimal example to reproduce the problem.
Compile the project with cmake .. &amp;&amp; make in the build folder and execute ./software/build/intel64/Release/NCS2_Hello_World.
After a few seconds you should see the command line output Execution done! where the program is stuck.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/openvinotoolkit/openvino/files/5107921/NCS2_Hello_World.zip&gt;NCS2_Hello_World.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Issue submission checklist&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


 I report the issue, it's not a question


 I checked the problem with documentation, FAQ, open issues, Stack Overflow, etc and have not found solution


 There is reproducer code and related data files: images, videos, models, etc.



	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Werni2A' date='2020-08-21T09:33:52Z'>
		Quick comment on USB2 versus USB3...
When connecting the MyriadX/NCS2 it appears as a USB2 device (high-speed). When you start the application and load the MYRIAD plugin the MyriadX/NCS2 gets reset by the plugin, which means the USB-device disappears from the USB-bus and then appears again, but now it appears as USB3 device, SuperSpeed. The USB device changes to "VSC Loopback Device", with a different product-id/model-id.
If you use a USB2-only cable, or if you use a USB2-capable USB-hub or connect it to a USB2-root-port only, then the MyriadX/NCS2 will fail to switch the mode, initialization will fail.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Werni2A' date='2020-08-21T09:35:02Z'>
		Haven't looked into your attached sample-hello-world, yet...
Have you tried with OpenVINO demos and OpenModelZoo samples, by using "-d MYRIAD" command line parameter? Are these samples working for you, and don't stuck when exiting?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Werni2A' date='2020-08-21T10:30:38Z'>
		First of all thanks for your fast reply. The license plate recognition demo worked without any problems, that's the demo I used as a reference for my Hello World project. Maybe I missed some important command to disconnect from the device but I looked over it a few times and did not find any difference.
Your explanation for USB2/3 makes sense. Interestingly I encountered equivalent error messages on the USB3 port too, but I can't remember what changes I made to get ride of them and result in the freeze. I will try a few different USB ports on my computer maybe I'm lucky and just one USB controller has some issues.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Werni2A' date='2020-08-21T10:49:14Z'>
		When the application exists gracefully then the plugin will reset the MyriadX/NCS2 again, it will disappear from USB bus as USB3 device and will appear again as USB2 device. You can check with "dmesg -w" in a separate terminal or manually call "lsusb" several times to see the two different devices.
Have you installed the udev-rule as described under "&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.openvinotoolkit.org/latest/openvino_docs_install_guides_installing_openvino_linux.html#additional-NCS-steps&gt;https://docs.openvinotoolkit.org/latest/openvino_docs_install_guides_installing_openvino_linux.html#additional-NCS-steps&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
"?
Sometimes... when the application crashes, the MyriadX/NCS2 stays in USB3-loopback mode.
Then the application could fail initializing it again... Maybe that is what you are seeing.
Then you would either need to unplug and plug it again (there are solutions where the MyriadX chip is soldered on a board; then you would need to unpower it, via e.g. a GPIO or separate power-line or turn on/off the reset-pin).
Or you could enforce a reset of the device via the plugin config option "KEY_VPU_MYRIAD_FORCE_RESET" as mentioned "&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.openvinotoolkit.org/latest/openvino_docs_IE_DG_supported_plugins_MYRIAD.html&gt;https://docs.openvinotoolkit.org/latest/openvino_docs_IE_DG_supported_plugins_MYRIAD.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
".
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Werni2A' date='2020-08-21T11:27:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/brmarkus&gt;@brmarkus&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you for your time. The udev-rule did the trick.
I recently updated OpenVino by installing it via apt where I assumed that everything is installed automatically. Would it be possible to also add udev-rule to the apt package?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>