<bug id='1106' author='julianmukaj' open_date='2020-02-17T15:03:56Z' closed_time='2020-06-16T13:56:14Z'>
	<summary>Session states</summary>
	<description>
We deployed a streamlit app to Azure via Docker with Web App on top. We had about 20 users accessing the app at the same time but we noticed weird behaviour with streamlit (images repeating etc), a few performance issues too.
My question is does Streamlit create individual sessions per user, it seems as if every connection from our 20 users was probably coming in as a single session.
I may have answered my question by seeing this gist: &lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/tvst/036da038ab3e999a64497f42de966a92&gt;https://gist.github.com/tvst/036da038ab3e999a64497f42de966a92&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 but just wanted some certainty.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-02-19T00:14:22Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/julianmukaj&gt;@julianmukaj&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
See an explanation &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io/t/crosstalk-between-streamlit-sessions-with-multiple-users/319/2?u=jonathan_rhone&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for how Streamlit handles multiple users. There was a recent bug fix for this behavior, but there's an outstanding &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1096&gt;issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for file uploader.
Could you provide sample code so we can repro your issue?
What weird behavior did you see other than images repeating?
Lastly, could you share the performance issues?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-02-19T10:56:24Z'>
		I can't share the code at the moment sorry, but the side bar just has an image at the top with some progress bars under it.
We saw all the items on the side bar repeating not just the images, they essentially appended beneath each other.
Performance issues were that the re-run of the app was slower than usual when all users were online at once.
Will that bug fix be in master soon?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-04-20T14:31:16Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/julianmukaj&gt;@julianmukaj&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , looks like the fix has been in Streamlit since 0.54.0.  Have you had a chance to try this with the latest version, 0.57.3?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-05-08T01:54:32Z'>
		subscribing
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-06-16T13:56:14Z'>
		No sample code to reproduce or response from the user.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='julianmukaj' date='2020-06-26T23:18:12Z'>
		Hi! I'm also having this huge problem with our application, we are running on streamlit v 0.56. The &lt;denchmark-link:https://farolcovid.coronacidades.org/&gt;application&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 itself has a lot of working on user input, and we notice that people had these problems - eg. selecting a state on  and change some data on  afterwards, and suddently the state value (used as title of a section) changed to another state, and also all the values from it. I think that the sessions are being mixed in someway by the  class.
I'm using a script from &lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/tvst/036da038ab3e999a64497f42de966a92&gt;tvst&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 here to create sessions: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ImpulsoGov/farolcovid/blob/stable/src/session.py&gt;https://github.com/ImpulsoGov/farolcovid/blob/stable/src/session.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>