<bug id='112' author='j4th' open_date='2019-09-16T17:25:55Z' closed_time='2019-10-05T20:15:06Z'>
	<summary>Plotly implementation deprecated with Plotly 4</summary>
	<description>
With version 4, plotly has moved all online features to a new chart-studio package.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Import plotly.express as px

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Plotly should be imported for use with st.plotly_chart()
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Plotly is unable to be imported.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6628275/64979382-773c0300-d86c-11e9-92b4-39fd81b7fb01.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Functions as expected with plotly 3.10.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.45.0
Python version: 3.7.4
Using Conda
OS version: Ubuntu 19.04
Browser version: Chrome 77.0.3865.75

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Not the end of the world as 3.10 is still working; was curious if there is a way to include the necessary version of plotly as a dependency somewhere.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='j4th' date='2019-09-30T17:20:09Z'>
		Hi j4th,
I'm having trouble reproducing the issue, could you provide more detailed reproduction steps?
A larger snippet that results in the error being thrown, or your entire app would be ideal.
With that said, Plotly v4 changed its main package and is accessed differently than in v3.
With v4
import chart_studio.plotly as ply
With v3
import plotly.plotly as ply
Please verify the version you're using and access the Plotly object accordingly. Streamlit apps should work with both versions.
Check version
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import plotly
plotly.__version__
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To install v4
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;pip install chart-studio
pip install plotly==4
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To install v3
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;pip install plotly==3
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Also, looks like you're on version 0.45.0 of Streamlit, feel free to update to 0.46.0 with pip install --upgrade streamlit if there's no blockers on your end.
Let us know if you're still having issues afterwards.
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='j4th' date='2019-10-05T20:15:06Z'>
		Hey, thanks for the response, and sorry for the delay on my end!
Tried to reproduce, and am unable to; must have been something funky with my environment (or my brain).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>