<bug id='1179' author='bballamudi' open_date='2020-03-04T18:43:29Z' closed_time='2020-05-26T16:58:16Z'>
	<summary>The url wont launch Streamlit app on browser unless computer is restarted</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I now need my computer restarted to get the url generated from the terminal to run the Streamlit app on the browser. To test the server I tried other similar applications like jupyter notebooks with urls from terminal and they run fine in browsers. Streamlit app however wont run unless I restart the computer.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Run the command `streamlit run app.py' in the terminal
Copy the url link on the browser
The Streamlit app should launch

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Expected the url to launch the Streamlit app as before.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The url generated in the terminal when copied in the browser wont run the streamlit app.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

yes, this was working just fine a while ago.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.53.0
Python version: 3.7.6
Using virtualenv
OS version: Win 10
Browser version: all browsers (IE, Firefox 68.5.0esr (64-bit))

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This issue emerged only now. It was running fine just a while ago where as soon as I hit the command `streamlit run app.py' it would lauch the app on IE browser. I'm working on st.cacheing so I wonder if it has anything to do? I tried browser cookie clearing to no avail.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bballamudi' date='2020-05-11T06:41:40Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bballamudi&gt;@bballamudi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I have been trying to reproduce your issue without luck.
Can you provide the script you were running when you had this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bballamudi' date='2020-05-11T18:52:42Z'>
		So far I can only reproduce this problem when the default browser is set to Internet Explorer, which might be related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1429&gt;#1429&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If &lt;denchmark-link:https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/4028606/windows-10-change-your-default-browser&gt;changing the default browser in Windows&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is possible, I would recommend doing so.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bballamudi' date='2020-05-12T21:51:38Z'>
		Hello i had an issue that might be the root cause of this:
-when i run it from console, and the close it without stopping the service, sometimes the python process will get stuck, when i run it again, it will open a second process, hence both processes will run on the same port, this i will make the application crash.
-There are 2 solutions for this, killing the process from task manage or restart the PC
Hope this helps
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bballamudi' date='2020-05-22T10:47:41Z'>
		Useful info, thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/josh3028&gt;@josh3028&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 !
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bballamudi' date='2020-05-26T16:58:16Z'>
		So, there are two issues potentially at play here:


Internet Explorer is not supported by Streamlit.  This is the most likely cause of the OP's problem and should be solved by changing the default browser to something else.  Edge will work.


It's possible there are zombie python processes being generated when the console is closed without stopping Streamlit.  I didn't see this myself, but @josh3028 did and it could be an explanation for how the OP saw the problem resolve upon reboot.


For now, I recommend:


Change default browser in Windows to something non-IE until we have a chance to figure out how to solve #1429


Give Streamlit a proper shutdown (control-C) before closing the terminal.


In case of failure to do a proper shutdown, follow @josh3028 's advice to kill the process from the task manager (or, failing this, restart the PC).


		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>