<bug id='1252' author='hertzmann' open_date='2020-03-24T20:48:46Z' closed_time='2020-03-26T18:22:55Z'>
	<summary>Streamlit fails to run after pip installation on Windows 10 Anaconda</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I've run pip install streamlit on Anaconda on Windows, but then streamlit hello fails to run ("command not found" type errors, "streamlit is not recognized as an internal or external command", etc).
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Install Anaconda on Windows 10
pip install streamlit
streamlit hello

I've tried in Anaconda Powershell (both as user and admin), cmd.exe, and creating an Anaconda  environment and then running the terminal in that environment.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is my first time installing streamlit on Windows.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: (get it with $ streamlit version)

This fails to run, but I just installed streamlit for the first time just now.

Python version: (get it with $ python --version)

I get different answers in different shells. The Anaconda Environment terminal is Python 3.7.7. The Anaconda PowerShell python version is 3.7.6

OS version:
Windows 10 Home version 1903, OS Build 18362.720

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Path info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

From reading forum comments, it sounds like this could be caused by my PATH. I don't see any Python or Anaconda-related directories in my user PATH or system PATH enviornment variables or PSModulePath.
In PowerShell, running echo $Env:Path shows that it includes C:\ProgramData\Anaconda3{,mingw-w64\bin,\usr\bin,bin,Scripts,\Library\bin,condabin} and more.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-24T22:22:33Z'>
		Update: I got it to run by manually locating streamlit.exe in \Users\&lt;username&gt;\AppData\Roaming\Python\Python37\Scripts. So I guess I have to add that directory to some path variable. (I saw on the forums that someone else had this problem and they had to manually add their path as well.)
I spent a lot of time stuck on this and it seems like it needs to be fixed in the installer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-25T20:22:32Z'>
		Thanks for the update &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hertzmann&gt;@hertzmann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. We'll get someone on this bug as quickly as we can.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-26T15:33:19Z'>
		Looks like &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/60866205/python-streamlit-run-issue&gt;this user ran into a similar issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-26T15:41:27Z'>
		This issue was also discussed on the Streamlit forums, and this was basically the solution to my problem:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io/t/getting-an-error-streamlit-is-not-recognized-as-an-internal-or-external-command-operable-program-or-batch-file/361/10&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io/t/getting-an-error-streamlit-is-not-recognized-as-an-internal-or-external-command-operable-program-or-batch-file/361/10&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-26T17:10:34Z'>
		I also see in that link that apparently there's a message that prints out during installation that explains this. Maybe it should be highlighted and emphasized more, and reappear if you try rerunning pip. There are so many messages that print when one runs pip or similar installers that I never read them, except possibly the very last message printed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='hertzmann' date='2020-03-26T18:22:55Z'>
		Superceded by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1262&gt;#1262&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>