<bug id='1318' author='BNNorman' open_date='2020-04-07T09:50:39Z' closed_time='2020-04-08T09:42:58Z'>
	<summary>Uber Demo: InternalHashError: Type aliases cannot be used with isinstance().</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Type here a clear and concise description of the bug. Aim for 2-3 sentences.
Trying the example code at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/blob/develop/docs/tutorial/create_a_data_explorer_app.md&gt;https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/blob/develop/docs/tutorial/create_a_data_explorer_app.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:
Copied and pasted the full code from the end of the MD into PyCharm 2019.2 ran streamlit run UBER.py (my name for it) in a pycharm terminal window
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain what you expect to happen when you go through the steps above, assuming there were no bugs.
Expected to see the NY Uber histogram.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The web page is present with the expected heading followed by the InternalHashError: Type aliases cannot be used with isinstance().
Explain the buggy behavior you experience when you go through the steps above.
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
This is too long to capture it all in one go but after line 2 in the traceback it looks like everything is internal to streamlit.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15849181/78651506-5692d380-78b8-11ea-992b-2bca29d050fc.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
yes / no
Unknown - my first foray into streamlit.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: (get it with $ streamlit version) 0.57.3
Python version: (get it with $ python --version) 3.5
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? PyCharm 2019.2
OS version: Windows 10 OS Build 18362.720
Browser version: Firefox 74.01 (64 bit)

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

numpy 1.18.2
pandas 0.24.2
altair 4.0.1
If I comment out the st.cache decorator I get a new error:-
TypeError: 'ellipsis' object is not iterable which appears to originate from st.bar_chart(hist_values)
Should I log a bug report for that too?
If needed, add any other context about the problem here. For example, did this bug come from &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or another site? Link the original source here!
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/blob/develop/docs/tutorial/create_a_data_explorer_app.md&gt;https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/blob/develop/docs/tutorial/create_a_data_explorer_app.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Copied and pasted code from end of that page.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='BNNorman' date='2020-04-07T13:05:31Z'>
		This works ok on my RPi4 (Buster) after installing streamlit- but I do most of my coding on a windows PC so would like it to work on that platform too.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='BNNorman' date='2020-04-07T23:36:40Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BNNorman&gt;@BNNorman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I just tried on my Windows 10 VM with python 3.8, running streamlit from the command prompt and didn't experience any issues.
I also had:
numpy==1.18.2
pandas==1.0.1
altair==4.1.0
Could you share the full stack trace?
Also, let's throw a few things at the wall and see what sticks :)
Could you update your pandas version?
Could you try with python version &gt;= 3.6?
Could you update your altair version?
Could you try running streamlit from the command prompt?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='BNNorman' date='2020-04-08T09:42:58Z'>
		Thank you for your prompt reply - what a morning ducking and diving with Windows - good news - Uber example now working from MSDOS command line - the remaining problem is getting it to work within PyCharm (which seems to fail to install upgrades to some packages, although it said it did, hmm)
I installed python 3.8, numpy 1.18.2, pandas 1.0.3 altair 4.1.0, streamlit 0.57.3.
Now to see what I can do with my own datasets.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>