<bug id='1350' author='puntium' open_date='2020-04-14T20:30:55Z' closed_time='2020-04-22T23:00:26Z'>
	<summary>High DPI pyplot() image is not preserved in UI</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If I render a matplotlib chart with pyplot() passing a dpi=NNN parameter, the contents of the plot render as if the correct dpi were set, but the resulting image available in the streamlit UI remains 72 dpi.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Render a matplotlib chart passing the dpi parameter. e.g. st.pyplot(dpi=300). Also note the matplotlib figure size specified.
Click on the "wide mode" expansion icon in the streamlit UI
Right click on the chart and download the image.
Open image in Preview on app, and inspect dimensions/dpi. Note that resulting image does not have dimensions as expected by figure size and dpi parameter.

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Image rendered should have more pixels. If width x height was 3in by 3in, and dpi=300 was passed, I should get 900x900 pixel image.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I get a smaller image. Chart appears to be rendered as if dpi settings were set (i.e. some fixed pixel size elements appear smaller at higher dpi parameter values) but the result image is still low res. It appears to be scaled down for display?
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Unknown.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.57.2
Python version: 3.6.7
Pipenv
OS version: Ubuntu 18.04.1 LTS
Browser version: Chrome Mac 80.0.3987.163

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='puntium' date='2020-04-22T23:00:25Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/puntium&gt;@puntium&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for the detailed report!
I think this is a duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/796&gt;#796&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - basically, we're not doing the right thing with large (or high-DPI) plots, and are instead compressing the images before sending them to the browser.
I'm going to close this because it's a duplicate of something we're already tracking, but feel free to re-open if you think I've made a mistake!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='puntium' date='2020-04-22T23:15:26Z'>
		Yes looks like the same root issue. Thanks for triaging!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>