<bug id='1428' author='amruta01' open_date='2020-05-08T20:33:37Z' closed_time='2020-06-16T13:17:19Z'>
	<summary>Heatmap</summary>
	<description>
Unable to load heat map from the cache?
When I rerun the heatmap, it says heatmap ... done! But I had to refresh the cash to render it
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='amruta01' date='2020-05-09T16:01:42Z'>
		I'm also having trouble displaying a heat map. In my case, I'm seeing a message that says
"Make this Notebook Trusted to load map: File -&gt; Trust Notebook" however, there is no "File" button.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='amruta01' date='2020-05-11T22:29:18Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/amruta01&gt;@amruta01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BKJackson&gt;@BKJackson&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Could you provide sample code that we can copy/paste and run to reproduce your issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='amruta01' date='2020-05-12T13:47:41Z'>
		Thanks folks.

We are good for now. We could fix the bug!

Best Regards,
Beju


804 822 2079 (mobile)
202 609 9818 (office)

&lt;denchmark-link:http://www.amrutainc.com&gt;www.amrutainc.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Amruta Inc provides data-driven insights and user-friendly software to
improve revenue, profitability, safety, compliance and reputation for
commercial and governmental clients, worldwide.
This email message (including any attachments) is for the use of the
intended recipient(s) only. It may contain confidential or proprietary
information and may be subject to confidentiality protections. If you are
not an intended recipient, you may not review, copy or distribute this
message. If you received this message in error, please notify the sender
and delete this message (including any attachments) from your system.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Mon, May 11, 2020 at 6:29 PM Jonathan Rhone ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Hi @amruta01 &lt;https://github.com/amruta01&gt; , @BKJackson
 &lt;https://github.com/BKJackson&gt; ,

 Could you provide sample code that we can copy/paste and run to reproduce
 your issue?

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#1428 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AE6BWCWVS3KR34RW2IBHJPDRRB34ZANCNFSM4M4OH3YA&gt;
 .



		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>