<bug id='1458' author='narquette' open_date='2020-05-16T02:01:16Z' closed_time='2020-05-28T20:17:18Z'>
	<summary>Running Stream Lit in Windows Sub-linux doesn't work</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I've installed the streamlit module in my virtual environment and attempt to run hello which cause an error to be produced.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Go to Ubuntu App in Start / Program
Activate Virtual Environment (e.g. conda activate virtual environment)
Run command "stream lit hello"
cd

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

You will run the default streamlit application (hello)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Any eror messsage is received (see below
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
yes / no
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.59.0
Python version: 3.7.5
Using Conda? Yes
OS version: Window 10 running Windows Sub Linux
Browser version:

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here. For example, did this bug come from &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or another site? Link the original source here!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='narquette' date='2020-05-18T14:14:57Z'>
		At the risk of being pedantic, did you actually submit stream lit hello? If so, there's no space between stream and lit. If not, let me know and I'll try this myself in Windows
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='narquette' date='2020-05-18T15:12:39Z'>
		Hello,

Good morning. I put in the command streamlit hello and nothing happened.

Thanks,

Nick
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Mon, May 18, 2020 at 9:15 AM Randy Zwitch ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 At the risk of being pedantic, did you actually submit stream lit hello?
 If so, there's no space between stream and lit. If not, let me know and
 I'll try this myself in Windows

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#1458 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AFDCFMV3DPLKP4GIVUCQ4DLRSE7HDANCNFSM4NCWMJOQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='narquette' date='2020-05-18T16:32:56Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/narquette&gt;@narquette&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it seems to have worked for me. When you say "nothing happened", are you saying that your terminal doesn't show any commands or that a browser window doesn't pop up? If it's the browser window, that should be expected, since WSL is its own sandbox, it can't pop up a browser in Windows.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2762787/82237363-82679700-9903-11ea-9e71-7c6c8e68be2f.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='narquette' date='2020-05-19T01:01:03Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/narquette&gt;@narquette&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, could you provide the output of your terminal, and any error messages you received?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='narquette' date='2020-05-19T01:19:51Z'>
		It seems to work on my personal computer but not my work computer.

Here is a screenshot of the error message.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.screencast.com/t/wqGKromkfDI&gt;https://www.screencast.com/t/wqGKromkfDI&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Thanks,

Nick
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Mon, May 18, 2020 at 11:33 AM Randy Zwitch ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Hi @narquette &lt;https://github.com/narquette&gt;, it seems to have worked for
 me. When you say "nothing happened", are you saying that your terminal
 doesn't show any commands or that a browser window doesn't pop up? If it's
 the browser window, that should be expected, since WSL is its own sandbox,
 it can't pop up a browser in Windows.

 [image: image]
 &lt;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2762787/82237363-82679700-9903-11ea-9e71-7c6c8e68be2f.png&gt;

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.


 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#1458 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AFDCFMWZDNMZEMZGVTWR2TLRSFPMRANCNFSM4NCWMJOQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='narquette' date='2020-05-19T12:55:08Z'>
		I wonder if what you are seeing is this bug: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/pull/1434&gt;#1434&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If so, if you upgrade Streamlit, the problem might fix itself (with version 0.60.0 of Streamlit, released in the last day or so)
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='narquette' date='2020-05-28T20:17:18Z'>
		Closing this issue, as upgrading Streamlit should resolve your issue. If this is still an issue after upgrading, please comment and I can re-open the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>