<bug id='1530' author='ajinkya933' open_date='2020-06-03T14:57:14Z' closed_time='2020-06-16T16:13:48Z'>
	<summary>Network URL missing from console output</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When streamlit application is run on Ubuntu terminal. it shows two types of URL. Local URL and NetworkURL. But, in my case the NetworkURL is completely missing from the terminal output. Here is a sample output I get
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/17012391/83651699-663c4900-a5d7-11ea-8969-e6015a11b6ca.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Type here a clear and concise description of the bug. Aim for 2-3 sentences.
Network URL is missing from terminal output
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

streamlit run my app.py
where my app.py is:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import streamlit as st
st.write("hello world")
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Network URL should appear through which users not on my wifi connection should be able to access the streamlit app.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;



Streamlit version: Streamlit, version 0.60.0


Python version: Python 3.6.10 :: Anaconda, Inc.


Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? : Conda


OS version:
Distributor ID:	Ubuntu
Description:	Ubuntu 18.04.4 LTS
Release:	18.04
Codename:	bionic


Browser version: chrome


&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

cat  ~/.streamlit/config.toml
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Below are all the sections and options you can have in ~/.streamlit/config.toml.

[global]

# By default, Streamlit checks if the Python watchdog module is available and, if not, prints a warning asking for you to install it. The watchdog module is not required, but highly recommended. It improves Streamlit's ability to detect changes to files in your filesystem.
# If you'd like to turn off this warning, set this to True.
# Default: false
disableWatchdogWarning = false

# Configure the ability to share apps to the cloud.
# Should be set to one of these values: - "off" : turn off sharing. - "s3" : share to S3, based on the settings under the [s3] section of this config file. - "file" : share to a directory on the local machine. This is meaningful only for debugging Streamlit itself, and shouldn't be used for production.
# Default: "off"
sharingMode = "off"

# If True, will show a warning when you run a Streamlit-enabled script via "python my_script.py".
# Default: true
showWarningOnDirectExecution = true

# Level of logging: 'error', 'warning', 'info', or 'debug'.
# Default: 'info'
logLevel = "info"


[client]

# Whether to enable st.cache.
# Default: true
caching = true

# If false, makes your Streamlit script not draw to a Streamlit app.
# Default: true
displayEnabled = true


[runner]

# Allows you to type a variable or string by itself in a single line of Python code to write it to the app.
# Default: true
magicEnabled = true

# Install a Python tracer to allow you to stop or pause your script at any point and introspect it. As a side-effect, this slows down your script's execution.
# Default: false
installTracer = false

# Sets the MPLBACKEND environment variable to Agg inside Streamlit to prevent Python crashing.
# Default: true
fixMatplotlib = true


[server]

# List of folders that should not be watched for changes. This impacts both "Run on Save" and @st.cache.
# Relative paths will be taken as relative to the current working directory.
# Example: ['/home/user1/env', 'relative/path/to/folder']
# Default: []
folderWatchBlacklist = []

# Change the type of file watcher used by Streamlit, or turn it off completely.
# Allowed values: * "auto" : Streamlit will attempt to use the watchdog module, and falls back to polling if watchdog is not available. * "watchdog" : Force Streamlit to use the watchdog module. * "poll" : Force Streamlit to always use polling. * "none" : Streamlit will not watch files.
# Default: "auto"
fileWatcherType = "auto"

# If false, will attempt to open a browser window on start.
# Default: false unless (1) we are on a Linux box where DISPLAY is unset, or (2) server.liveSave is set.
headless = false

# Immediately share the app in such a way that enables live monitoring, and post-run analysis.
# Default: false
liveSave = false

# Automatically rerun script when the file is modified on disk.
# Default: false
runOnSave = false

# The port where the server will listen for client and browser connections.
# Default: 8501
port = 8501

# The base path for the URL where Streamlit should be served from.
# Default: ""
baseUrlPath = ""

# Enables support for Cross-Origin Request Sharing, for added security.
# Default: true
enableCORS = false

# Max size, in megabytes, for files uploaded with the file_uploader.
# Default: '50'
maxUploadSize = 50


[browser]

# Internet address where users should point their browsers in order to connect to the app. Can be IP address or DNS name and path.
# This is used to: - Set the correct URL for CORS purposes. - Show the URL on the terminal - Open the browser - Tell the browser where to connect to the server when in liveSave mode.
# Default: 'localhost'
serverAddress = "localhost"

# Whether to send usage statistics to Streamlit.
# Default: true
gatherUsageStats = true

# Port where users should point their browsers in order to connect to the app.
# This is used to: - Set the correct URL for CORS purposes. - Show the URL on the terminal - Open the browser - Tell the browser where to connect to the server when in liveSave mode.
# Default: whatever value is set in server.port.
serverPort = 8501


[mapbox]

# Configure Streamlit to use a custom Mapbox token for elements like st.deck_gl_chart and st.map. If you don't do this you'll be using Streamlit's own token, which has limitations and is not guaranteed to always work. To get a token for yourself, create an account at https://mapbox.com. It's free! (for moderate usage levels)
# Default: "pk.eyJ1IjoidGhpYWdvdCIsImEiOiJjamh3bm85NnkwMng4M3dydnNveWwzeWNzIn0.vCBDzNsEF2uFSFk2AM0WZQ"
token = "pk.eyJ1IjoidGhpYWdvdCIsImEiOiJjamh3bm85NnkwMng4M3dydnNveWwzeWNzIn0.vCBDzNsEF2uFSFk2AM0WZQ"


[s3]

# Name of the AWS S3 bucket to save apps.
# Default: (unset)
#bucket =

# URL root for external view of Streamlit apps.
# Default: (unset)
#url =

# Access key to write to the S3 bucket.
# Leave unset if you want to use an AWS profile.
# Default: (unset)
#accessKeyId =

# Secret access key to write to the S3 bucket.
# Leave unset if you want to use an AWS profile.
# Default: (unset)
#secretAccessKey =

# The "subdirectory" within the S3 bucket where to save apps.
# S3 calls paths "keys" which is why the keyPrefix is like a subdirectory. Use "" to mean the root directory.
# Default: ""
keyPrefix = ""

# AWS region where the bucket is located, e.g. "us-west-2".
# Default: (unset)
#region =

# AWS credentials profile to use.
# Leave unset to use your default profile.
# Default: (unset)
#profile =
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ajinkya933' date='2020-06-16T16:13:48Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ajinkya933&gt;@ajinkya933&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
The reason is because you're setting values for browser.serverAddress, browser.serverPort and server.port in your config.toml. If you remove those values it will work as you expect.
I realize that you're setting them to the default values, so this behavior is unexpected. I filed issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1588&gt;#1588&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to address this.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ streamlit hello --browser.serverAddress=localhost --browser.serverPort=8501 --server.port=8501

  You can now view your Streamlit app in your browser.

  URL: http://localhost:8501
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ streamlit hello

  You can now view your Streamlit app in your browser.

  Local URL: http://localhost:8501
  Network URL: http://192.168.1.252:8501
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>