<bug id='1605' author='asemic-horizon' open_date='2020-06-18T15:05:36Z' closed_time='2020-06-19T01:49:10Z'>
	<summary>Radio buttons that swap out large sections of content sometimes don't work</summary>
	<description>
This is again a bug that's hard to provide a minimum example for. I'm (mis?)using radio buttons as a "main menu" of sorts,  like this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42865953/85036877-0c04c180-b15b-11ea-97a7-d1889e9a04de.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

These button trigger entirely different pages from there on.
Sometimes, after operating the app for a while, the radio buttons won't work. I know it's not a problem with some ongoing process for three reasons (1) helpful runner icon (2) I have plenty of logging to monitor the app from its CLI output and (3) it helps to try another button and try again the one you wanted.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I've seen this bug happen consistently in v0.58. More recent versions break my app thoroughly (see below) and I haven't used it long enough.
One would have to figure a kind of minimum complexity example that still reaches a threshold of how much content is swapped by a radio button. I'm not a very good bug-reporter.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm not sure if this is a regression. I have only seriously used 0.58 because more recent versions are awful with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1440&gt;this other bug&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Other notes&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is a poor bug report, and I initially chose not to post it and just live with the behavior, but since I mentioned a "wider reliability story" in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1440&gt;other bug issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I thought I'd give another example.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='asemic-horizon' date='2020-06-18T19:42:54Z'>
		Based on your picture above of the radio box, is this the repo in question that has the issues, so that we can try and reproduce?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/asemic-horizon/sursis&gt;https://github.com/asemic-horizon/sursis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='asemic-horizon' date='2020-06-19T01:49:10Z'>
		It is.
You're correct that this isn't a bug report, but a complaint instead. This isn't proper behavior in this kind of situation. I don't know what came over me.
I'll do the work of coming up with something that happens in a simple example in the most recent version of Streamlit in the coming days. Sorry for the annoyance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='asemic-horizon' date='2020-06-19T16:17:19Z'>
		No worries &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/asemic-horizon&gt;@asemic-horizon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, happens to all of us. I edited down my message as well, because it was more aggressive than I really deserved to be.
Ultimately, we do want to help, so if you can tell us how to reproduce the issue, then we can try and figure out what the proper solution is.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>