<bug id='1625' author='raghavdixit99' open_date='2020-06-24T10:38:12Z' closed_time='2020-08-07T00:14:25Z'>
	<summary>while caching the body of the function, Streamlit encountered an object of type `builtins.function`, which it does not know how to hash.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/34462078/85540646-df5a1980-b634-11ea-9b10-1be60db19184.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


# Summary

Type here a clear and concise description of the bug. Aim for 2-3 sentences.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Go to '...'
Click on '....'
Scroll down to '....'

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain what you expect to happen when you go through the steps above, assuming there were no bugs.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain the buggy behavior you experience when you go through the steps above.
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
yes / no
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: (get it with $ streamlit version)
Python version: (get it with $ python --version)
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex?
OS version:
Browser version:

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here. For example, did this bug come from &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or another site? Link the original source here!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='raghavdixit99' date='2020-08-07T00:14:25Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/raghavdixit99&gt;@raghavdixit99&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
I know it's been a minute since you filed this bug.  This one looks more like an error within the function you're trying to cache.  Most likely one of the functions that reference other python scripts is the culprit.
Since I can't see the rest of your code I don't know how to diagnose where the error is, but I'm fairly certain based on the error message (even though it looks like a hashing error) that the problem lies in trying to hash bytecode with a broken reference somewhere.
Apologies again for the delay in response.
If it seems like this response is off-base and it still seems like a Streamlit bug, let us know and we'll reopen the ticket.   And if you do so, please include text code blocks instead of screenshots so it's easier to read and help you out!
Cheers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='raghavdixit99' date='2020-08-07T04:46:27Z'>
		There are other issues about  causing 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1590&gt;#1590&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/1618&gt;#1618&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>