<bug id='2008' author='Laksh1997' open_date='2020-09-17T08:23:00Z' closed_time='2020-12-03T18:50:04Z'>
	<summary>St File Uploader doesn't work over Kubernetes for 0.66, but does for 0.61.0</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

See title
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:
st.file_uploader(...)
works fine locally but on Kubernetes it just does nothing even after a file is dragged onto it.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Yes
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: (get it with $ streamlit version) 0.66.0
Python version: (get it with $ python --version) 3.7
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? Conda
OS version: Linux
Browser version: Chrome

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here. For example, did this bug come from &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or another site? Link the original source here!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Laksh1997' date='2020-09-26T22:12:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karriebear&gt;@karriebear&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you have any ideas on what may have changed between these versions?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Laksh1997' date='2020-09-29T03:18:24Z'>
		Between &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/compare/0.61.0...0.66.0&gt;0.61 and 0.66&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we fixed a bug for when a session is disconnected and added the deprecation warning.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Laksh1997&gt;@Laksh1997&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is your deployed instance publicly available? If not, do you mind taking a quick screen recording or sharing some screenshots? Additionally, can you share your code or a small reproducible sample? We've been working with apps on a Kubernetes environment and have been able to upload files successfully. Pardon the mess but see &lt;denchmark-link:https://s4a.streamlit.io/karriebear/home-locator/master/main.py/+/&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Laksh1997' date='2020-09-30T21:32:22Z'>
		I've encountered an issue with this as well previously, using Kubernetes with multiple replicas. I was able to have it fixed by using sticky sessions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Laksh1997' date='2020-09-30T22:51:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Laksh1997&gt;@Laksh1997&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 echoing Karrie's question - is your deployed instance publicly accessible? If not, could you please share the Kubernetes manifest files with us?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Laksh1997' date='2020-12-03T18:50:04Z'>
		Hey, I'm closing this issue since it's been inactive for over 30 days. Feel free to reopen if you're still experiencing it and have some more info to add.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>