<bug id='2027' author='rmartin16' open_date='2020-09-22T14:42:03Z' closed_time='2020-09-23T00:17:50Z'>
	<summary>Multiselect and SelectBox Options with Long Text Leads to Overlapping Text Due to Poorly Formatted Wrapping</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Since v0.67.0, options with long text for Multiselect and Selectbox selectors overlap each other when the text starts wrapping.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/387848/93896635-2650bd00-fcbf-11ea-8fc4-2b7c27166186.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is easiest to replicate in the sidebar (or make the browser window smaller):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;options = ['long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text',
           'long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text',
           'long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text',
           'long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text long text']
st.sidebar.selectbox(label='label', options=options)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The options will be legible and pretty in the dropdown regardless of string length.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Options are not legible and the functionality is not usable for options with long text.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
yes
This was likely caused by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/pull/1888&gt;#1888&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.67.0
Python version: Python 3.8.3
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? no...
OS version: CentOS 7
Browser version: Firefox 80.0.1

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rmartin16' date='2020-09-22T22:13:02Z'>
		+1
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rmartin16' date='2020-09-23T00:17:50Z'>
		Exalate commented: karriebear commented: Thanks for pointing this out! We just put out a patch addressing this. Please upgrade to 0.67.1 to get the latest.
For additional context, we are now enforcing one line select items and truncating them with an ellipsis at the end. We think it makes the most sense for this type of component and fits with how most other selects in smaller displays work. Longer Multiline options probably deserve a richer UI component to handle this specific use case (suitable for perhaps a custom component). For more details see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/pull/2031&gt;#2031&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rmartin16' date='2020-09-23T01:18:08Z'>
		That's unfortunate...but fair. Thanks for pushing out a fix so quickly!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>