<bug id='2227' author='lighteternal' open_date='2020-10-20T11:27:00Z' closed_time='2020-10-20T17:56:14Z'>
	<summary>Stuck on " HTTP request sent; waiting for response. " terminal screen after running any streamlit script</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I had been using streamlit without issues for a couple of months. Suddenly, when I try to launch any app (even streamlit hello), a new screen (lynx-like) appears on the terminal, with the following message: HTTP request sent; waiting for response.
The app is not accessible via network (it's on a remote server so I can't test locally).
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Set up a clean environment and install streamlit dependencies
Run streamlit hello

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I should be able to access the running app via network.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The following screen pops up and the app is not accessible via network.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22905968/96579028-d3c6e880-12de-11eb-8c7d-bcba0c23c3bb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: Streamlit, version 0.65.0
Python version: Python 3.6.9
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? Pip
OS version: Ubuntu 18.04
Browser version: Any

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I also attach the output I get from the terminal right after running the hello app (the lynx-like screen shown above pops up right after, but I can see the logs as soon as I Ctrl+C. Everything looks fine I think:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22905968/96579741-07564280-12e0-11eb-92ba-bfac04a2184f.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Moreover, while the app is running, the browser seems to be in a waiting stage forever, but as soon as I kill it I get the This site can’t be reached screen appears
I have already tested:

different streamlit versions
server reboot
different virtual envs
checking connectivity by setting a simple HTTP server
different ports
But nothing has solved this issue.

Edit: Weirdly enough, when I run the "hello" or any other app, the  command reports the following processes:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22905968/96601056-4d200480-12fa-11eb-8a6f-771ec30100b3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Should the third one be there?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lighteternal' date='2020-10-20T17:56:14Z'>
		Found the root of the problem.
For anyone having this issue on a remote machine:
On your terminal, create a config file with: streamlit config show &gt; ~/.streamlit/config.toml
Then, go to the .toml file and change the headless argument to true:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# If false, will attempt to open a browser window on start.
# Default: false unless (1) we are on a Linux box where DISPLAY is unset, or (2) server.liveSave is set.
headless = true
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Closing this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>