<bug id='2393' author='debparth' open_date='2020-11-28T15:40:01Z' closed_time='2020-12-02T17:23:36Z'>
	<summary>Cuda out of memory</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm trying a Efficientdet model but whenever I try to feed the uploaded image to the model then it gives me Cuda out of memory error. If I try to feed the image without using streamlit i.e. without normally running the code then it doesn't show any error.
This error never happened before when I run the code and feed the image normally (i.e. without using streamlit).
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Created app.py and running it
Uploading the image using streamlit
Scroll down you'll get an error

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If everything goes right then the image should have been feed to model and my model have given me the new image.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/53347017/100519306-fce36000-314b-11eb-8921-181cae8e1fe7.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I did try it using Yolov5 and Yolov4 model model before and it works correctly but not with this model. Doesn't understand why!?
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.71.0
Python version: 3.6.9
Using Colab
Browser version: Edge

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='debparth' date='2020-12-01T21:00:54Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/debparth&gt;@debparth&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks for opening this issue! We would like to reproduce this issue on our end. Can you share some toy code(and data) which demonstrates this problem? Without code its hard to debug on our side
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='debparth' date='2020-12-02T16:00:41Z'>
		Thank you for your reply. The error got solved. The reason was I previously loaded 2 another models which were consuming the memory. After clearing them out, it is working correctly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='debparth' date='2020-12-02T17:23:36Z'>
		Glad to hear that! Closing
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>