<bug id='2434' author='debparth' open_date='2020-12-08T18:01:23Z' closed_time='2020-12-09T13:09:46Z'>
	<summary>Error when deploying streamlit app</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Getting the below error when trying to deploy streamlit.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I think it should have been deployed without any issues.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The error is:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/53347017/101522035-8577b280-393b-11eb-98b5-37422167f4c3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.71.0
Python version: 3.6.9
Browser version: Edge

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I thought that the error might be because of the model which I'm loading in cuda (since, there is no displaying like where it go wrong so..) thus, I changed that to cpu but still the error is coming when deployed.
Repo link: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/debparth/detr_with_streamlit&gt;https://github.com/debparth/detr_with_streamlit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='debparth' date='2020-12-08T23:49:25Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/debparth&gt;@debparth&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 !  I could not find your deployed app, so I forked your repo and deployed from the fork at &lt;denchmark-link:https://share.streamlit.io/amey-d/detr_with_streamlit/main/app.py&gt;https://share.streamlit.io/amey-d/detr_with_streamlit/main/app.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
I noticed the app was crashing on Streamlit sharing platform with a segmentation fault (SIGSEGV).  The error disappeared when I upgraded to the latest opencv-python version.  In order to get the app working, I also had to include a couple of OS packages in a packages.txt file.
You can look at my commits at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Amey-D/detr_with_streamlit&gt;https://github.com/Amey-D/detr_with_streamlit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  Also, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io/t/importerror-libgl-so-1-cannot-open-shared-object-file-no-such-file-or-directory-opencv-error/7031/3&gt;this thread&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for errors related to .
Hope this helps, and let us know if you have more questions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='debparth' date='2020-12-09T13:09:46Z'>
		Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Amey-D&gt;@Amey-D&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for your help. Can you tell me how did you find out the error and, when I'm trying your link and uploading an image it throws me back an ModuleNotFoundError and that's my fault that I didn't add one more package in it.
Now, after making those changes it is working perfectly fine except that I'm not able to use GPU when I try to use it. It just gets disconnect and then the same error from before shows up... So, is there any different way to use GPU or we can't!?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='debparth' date='2020-12-09T20:13:31Z'>
		
Can you tell me how did you find out the error

I had to look up in the internal logs to figure out the error. We are adding this to the product feature roadmap so that it will be easier for app developers to debug such errors.

I'm not able to use GPU when I try to use it. It just gets disconnect and then the same error from before shows up

It's very likely that your app crashes when it tried to use GPU.

is there any different way to use GPU

At present we do not support GPUs on the Streamlit sharing platform.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>