<bug id='297' author='djouallah' open_date='2019-10-07T11:35:45Z' closed_time='2019-11-07T23:32:55Z'>
	<summary>add print to pdf</summary>
	<description>
I know the whole point is to show interactive visuals, but it would be very useful to have an option export to PDF,  a lot of users that all what they want just a pdf of the report.
very good product by the way
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-11T19:17:15Z'>
		And maybe to other static formats like HTML that can be converted by &lt;denchmark-link:https://pandoc.org/&gt;Pandoc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 into any format imaginable.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-11T19:19:49Z'>
		As Streamlit is so easy to use and Python such amazing power for creating visualizations i could imagine doing an interactive presentation app just as quick as the usual power point presentation. So some way of controlling that layout for screen, pdf and paper would be awesome.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-15T23:09:06Z'>
		Yeah this would be great. Printing via the browser does not seem to work at the moment: only the first page gets printed using chrome's print menu.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-24T23:29:21Z'>
		
Printing via the browser does not seem to work at the moment: only the first page gets printed using chrome's print menu.

This used to work. Must have regressed recently. My guess is this is related to the DOM changes we did when implementing the sidebar a month or two ago.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/297&gt;#297&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-24T23:31:06Z'>
		Also, just wondering: would feature &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/351&gt;#351&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 solve your problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-25T15:45:22Z'>
		In my enterprise sharing to s3 would not be a valid option.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='djouallah' date='2019-10-30T21:45:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MarcSkovMadsen&gt;@MarcSkovMadsen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/351&gt;#351&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is about saving to a local folder, no S3  . The folder would contain a bunch of html, css, js, and data files, and you'd have to run a local HTTP server to see them (for example, with ). We could also create a Streamlit command to view that folder.
Would that solve your problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='djouallah' date='2019-11-08T16:22:05Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tvst&gt;@tvst&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . Nope save to html would not solve the problem. Users can open pdf files not html.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='djouallah' date='2020-11-18T21:38:41Z'>
		dears, is this solved?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='djouallah' date='2020-11-19T01:10:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/easimadi&gt;@easimadi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

We did have a pull request that fixed the issue as it was opened a year ago.  If you're experiencing something similar now, would you mind opening a new bug report?  You can reference this issue as well if you think it will help.
The reason is there have been significant changes in the streamlit code since this bug was opened, and our policy is to open new bugs if an older issue has been closed for more than three months.
Thanks so much!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>