<bug id='365' author='svilupp' open_date='2019-10-10T18:42:18Z' closed_time='2020-02-25T18:17:21Z'>
	<summary>Plotly Choroplet loses interactivity when st.sidebar.slider is added (st.slider is fine)</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When st.sidebar.slider is added map-based plotly charts will lose their interactivity.
I've tested multiple types and it does not affect simple charts (eg, bar chart), but it does affect map-like charts (eg, choropleth, line geo, scatter geo)
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Just run the attached code
Try hovering over various charts when st.sidebar.slider(s) are present - it won't work for the below 3 charts

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When hovering over all plotly charts, you should be able to see a hover box with additional info about each data point + you can move the focus with your mouse pointer and zoom in and out
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When hovering over the bottom 3 charts with st.siderbar.slider enabled, charts are completely flat (like if the JS events weren't working)
When you change the sliders into st.slider or comment them out, it will start working again.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

no
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.47.4
Python version: 3.6.5 (but same behaviour tested also on 3.7)
Using Conda


Plotly: 4.0.0 (but found the same behaviour also with 4.1.1 and 4.1.0)




Plotly express: 0.3.1 (but found the same behaviour also with 0.4.1)


OS version: Windows 10
Browser version: Chrome Version 77.0.3865.90

Uploaded python script
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/files/3714071/plotly_example.zip&gt;plotly_example.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='svilupp' date='2019-10-14T02:26:27Z'>
		Thanks for the bug report!
Weirdly, I can reproduce the issue both with and without the sidebar -- so long as there are any sliders on the app. (I haven't tested other widgets)
We'll look into this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='svilupp' date='2020-02-25T18:17:20Z'>
		Fixed here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/pull/1047&gt;#1047&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>