<bug id='408' author='ohallaatme' open_date='2019-10-14T18:12:26Z' closed_time='2020-05-11T08:27:22Z'>
	<summary>matplotlib not recognized, runs fine on local machine</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

matplot lib is installed successfully on my windows 10 machine and works fine with Jupyter notebooks and my local venv/IDE. When I try to use it with Streamlit, I get the following error:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/36905130/66773027-ace00600-ee83-11e9-9a37-8bd107be59ed.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Bug produced simply by including import matplotlib.pyplot as plot in code. Using Python 3.7.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Would expect no errors.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain the buggy behavior you experience when you go through the steps above.
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

matplotlib has not worked for me, I have not even tried to display a graph, it is just in the header.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.48.1
Python version: 3.7
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex? Conda
OS version: Windows 10
Browser version: Google Chrome Version 77.0.3865.90 (Official Build) (64-bit)

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ohallaatme' date='2020-04-05T17:42:09Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ohallaatme&gt;@ohallaatme&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , can you run  in your shell with the  activated and share the results?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ohallaatme' date='2020-05-11T06:52:34Z'>
		I haven't been able to reproduce this using the latest streamlit (0.59.0) and python 3.7 on Windows 10 + Conda.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ohallaatme' date='2020-05-11T08:27:22Z'>
		Revisiting to wrap up: so, the problem as written was that matplotlib as written was not available to streamlit.  Streamlit doesn't automatically install matplotlib, and it's not totally clear whether the script was being run within an environment where matplotlib was installed.
Due to the age of this bug I think we should close this.  A new bug can be opened if something similar is seen.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>