<bug id='496' author='asw-v4' open_date='2019-10-22T13:43:26Z' closed_time='2020-02-14T20:24:38Z'>
	<summary>Blank Screen with no change to code</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Streamlit fails to automatically load a window upon running from console. When manually navigated too, shows a blank window (besides the streamlit menu in the top right). Code has been running flawlessly, with no issues, then just decides not to laod.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

To be able to view my streamlit dashboard
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Can only see a blank white screen.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This used to work. CODE HAS NOT CHANGED, and previously worked fine. No syntax errors within the code. It has now stopped displaying my dashboard.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='asw-v4' date='2019-10-22T13:48:30Z'>
		This often requires several restarts to both the terminal and browser to function
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='asw-v4' date='2019-10-22T15:03:32Z'>
		@adam-ward-v4 could you explain step by step how to reproduce this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='asw-v4' date='2019-10-22T15:45:36Z'>
		Unfortunately, it doesn't seem like there is a step by step way to trigger this.
Ill have run my program from console streamlit run main.py
and it wont always auto load the webbrowser. I have to manually navigate to the location via the webbrowser. Once loaded onto the page, i then need to do the following:
Ctrl -C
streamlit run main.py
This then refreshes the page and loads my streamlit dashboard correctly. However, when i make any changes to my code, I am required to perform the following again, even though i have the re-run on save option enabled:
Ctrl -C
streamlit run main.py
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='asw-v4' date='2020-02-14T20:24:38Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/asw-v4&gt;@asw-v4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I'm going to close this since it is a fairly old report at this point, with numerous changes having gone into the Streamlit codebase since this was filed.
However, if you are still seeing this issue, we can reopen it -- we'll need to know your operating system, the version of python you're using, and what browser you're using in order to properly understand it.
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='asw-v4' date='2020-03-04T10:06:15Z'>
		This happened with me when I updated the Server.py file to enable static file download. It worked for a while and then started showing blank page.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>