<bug id='533' author='imneonizer' open_date='2019-10-25T07:21:41Z' closed_time='2019-10-30T11:10:38Z'>
	<summary>comments get printed on the UI by default</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Comment vs. strings&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I believe that sreamlit is providing convenience by automatically writing the strings which are not assigned to any variable bu this is causing a trouble even comments are get written on the front end ui.
steps to reproduce: check this code
import streamlit as st
import pandas as pd

st.title('Streamlit Flaws')
st.subheader('Please Fix this')

"""
comment\n 
should not be\n
printed\n
"""

def write_html(html):
    st.markdown(html, unsafe_allow_html=True)

write_html("""
&lt;!Doctype html&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;inside html&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;this string is fine&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when strings are enclosed inside these
```three quotation marks``` and passed as a parameter to a function they work as
string if they are directly written then they are treated as
comments do note the difference please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
""")
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13932346/67551263-1f73a000-f726-11e9-9c0b-ad4bb113ac46.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='imneonizer' date='2019-10-28T03:51:37Z'>
		Thanks for posting this.  Was wondering why triple double-quote comments were being rendered.  I thought triple single-quote comments should be allowed to render, but not triple double-quotes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='imneonizer' date='2019-10-30T11:10:32Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/imneonizer&gt;@imneonizer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pybokeh&gt;@pybokeh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks for the bug report!
Stepping back for a sec, Python allows you to type statements that don't actually do anything. For example:
a = 10
a  # This doesn't do anything, but it's valid Python.
By default, Streamlit uses these "dead" statements as a magic notation to easily render to your app. So you can do things like:
a = 10
a  # This will render

"foo"  # This will render

# This will render
"""
Hello
"""

x = "my string"  # This will not render
This is a feature we call &lt;denchmark-link:https://streamlit.io/docs/api.html&gt;magic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. As described in the Streamlit docs, you can turn it off by adding the following to your config file (~/.streamlit/config.toml):
[runner]
magicEnabled = false

I thought triple single-quote comments should be allowed to render, but not triple double-quotes.

Python bytecode does not differentiate between different notations you can use to create a string. To the Python bytecode, all methods are just "string". So Streamlit can't tell by looking at the bytecode whether a string was initialized with single quotes, double quotes, or multi-line single/double quotes.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If you allow me to be pedantic for a sec , triple-quote notation isn't actually meant to be used for comments in Python. The only way to create comments in Python is with  (which means Python actually does not support multi-line comments). Quotes / triple-quotes are only meant to be used to define string literals. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/a/7057988&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/a/7057988&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more info.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='imneonizer' date='2019-10-30T16:44:49Z'>
		So in case if I wanted to use both magics and triple quote multil ine comments, is there any work around.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='imneonizer' date='2019-11-05T21:54:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tvst&gt;@tvst&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the edumacation :-)  I swore I thought in the docs, the tutorials had used triple single quotes for magics, which is why I thought there was a distinction between single vs double quotes.  Anyways, I will remember to just use # for multi-line comments then as opposed to triple quotes for mult-line comments.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='imneonizer' date='2020-11-03T21:49:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/imneonizer&gt;@imneonizer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 found out you can cheat a bit by doing this
my_comment = '''
Please don't print this to the UI
'''
by setting it to a variable it's not "dead" anymore and streamlit magic won't render it. It's a hack, but a workable one. It'd be nice to turn it off I agree.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='imneonizer' date='2020-11-06T14:44:37Z'>
		I think that what streamlit does is right because in a jupyter notebook if you type out only a docstring in a code cell, it shows the output.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Code&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

"""This is a docstring.""" 
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Output&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is a docstring.
is rendered by a jupyter notebook as supposedly text to be printed and it displays it.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>