<bug id='609' author='vinpatel' open_date='2019-11-02T13:16:18Z' closed_time='2020-02-14T20:20:44Z'>
	<summary>Certificate issue on all demos</summary>
	<description>
URLError: &lt;urlopen error [SSL: CERTIFICATE_VERIFY_FAILED] certificate verify failed (_ssl.c:749)&gt;
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vinpatel' date='2020-02-14T20:20:44Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vinpatel&gt;@vinpatel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I'm sorry no one responded to this in a timely manner.  Your issue was likely due to some common Python weirdness (see also &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/374&gt;#374&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ).
Since this is a fairly old report at this point and numerous Streamlit changes have gone in since this was filed, I'm going to close it.  Please file a new bug if you are seeing this behavior again.
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='vinpatel' date='2020-06-14T15:10:50Z'>
		For those who this problem persists: -
Python 3.6 on MacOS comes with its own private copy of OpenSSL. That means the trust certificates in the system are no longer used as defaults by the Python ssl module. To fix that, you need to install a certifi package in your system.
You may try to do it in two ways:

Via PIP:
pip install --upgrade certifi
If it doesn't work, try to run a Cerificates.command that comes bundled with Python 3.6 for Mac:
open /Applications/Python\ 3.6/Install\ Certificates.command

One way or another, you should now have certificates installed, and Python should be able to connect via HTTPS without any issues.
Hope this helped.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='vinpatel' date='2020-09-19T06:43:22Z'>
		This did not work for me. I am in a virtualenv and have streamlit installed in it. After successfully install certifi and relaunching streamlit hello, I still see this issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='vinpatel' date='2020-10-04T07:48:59Z'>
		URLError: &lt;urlopen error [SSL: CERTIFICATE_VERIFY_FAILED] certificate verify failed: self signed certificate in certificate chain (_ssl.c:1056)&gt;
I have installed the required certificates still the same issue persists. Any other solution for this?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>