<bug id='610' author='tylerwolf35' open_date='2019-11-02T19:57:10Z' closed_time='2019-11-20T10:22:55Z'>
	<summary>&amp;gt;2k requests being blocked by uBlock Origin.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Type here a clear and concise description of the bug. Aim for 2-3 sentences.

2k requests are being blocked by uBlock Origin.

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

What are the steps we should take to reproduce the bug:

Have uBlock Origin installed
Run Streamlit
Look at uBlock Origin

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain what you expect to happen when you go through the steps above, assuming there were no bugs.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Explain the buggy behavior you experience when you go through the steps above.
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
yes / no
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: (get it with $ streamlit version): Streamlit 0.49.0
Python version: (get it with $ python --version): Python 3.7.4
Using Conda? PipEnv? PyEnv? Pex?: Conda Python, installed Streamlit with pip.
OS version: Ubuntu 18.04.3 (WSL)
Browser version: Firefox 70.0.1 (64-bit)

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tylerwolf35' date='2019-11-15T00:07:59Z'>
		My guess is that the Streamlit server was not connected when this happened.
When the server disconnects (for example, if you ctrl-c out of it) the browser tries pinging the server every second to see if it can reconnect. This is how Streamlit apps are able to automatically reconnect to the server when it's restarted.
So if an app is disconnected for 30min, you should see ~2k "ping" requests being made.
Now, the part that doesn't make sense to me is why uBlock would be blocking those pings.
Can you provide some more info?

Is the Streamlit app running on the same machine as your browser?
What's the URL in the address bar?
Can you post a HAR file? (See instructions)

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tylerwolf35' date='2019-11-20T10:22:55Z'>
		Closing due to inactivity.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>