<bug id='704' author='komodovaran' open_date='2019-11-17T21:30:09Z' closed_time='2020-02-14T20:05:08Z'>
	<summary>Installed with Conda: The environment is inconsistent</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm experiencing several packages that cannot be installed, as long as Streamlit is installed.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Make a conda environment and activate it
Install Streamlit via the environment's pip
Try to install anything else using conda install (not pip), and Conda will get stuck trying to solve the problem.

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Collecting package metadata (current_repodata.json): done
Solving environment: - 
The environment is inconsistent, please check the package plan carefully
The following packages are causing the inconsistency:

  - pypi/pypi::streamlit==0.50.2=pypi_0
failed with initial frozen solve. Retrying with flexible solve.
Solving environment: failed with repodata from current_repodata.json, will retry with next repodata source.
Collecting package metadata (repodata.json): done
Solving environment: / 
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Workaround (not ideal)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Uninstall streamlit
Use Conda as normal
Install streamlit when done installing through Conda
(pip seems to be unaffected, but conda is preferred for nasty packages, e.g. tensorflow-gpu)

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.50.2
Python version: 3.7.3
Conda version 4.7.12
OS version: Ubuntu 19.10

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;edit&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I realized this is related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/conda/conda/issues/8490&gt;conda/conda#8490&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which doesn’t seem to have any fix at the moment. Why was this package pulled from Conda?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='komodovaran' date='2019-11-20T21:47:20Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/komodovaran&gt;@komodovaran&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,  thanks for the report. I tried to repro but with no success. These are the steps I followed.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;docker pull continuumio/anaconda
docker run -i -t continuumio/anaconda /bin/bash
pip install streamlit
conda install botocore
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I also tried to switch the default debian distribution in continuumio/anaconda with Ubuntu 19.10, but still I could not repro.
That said, I think it is a good idea on our end to create a conda package for Streamlit. This will make it unnecessary to use pip to install Streamlit and may solve other problems that may arise because of  and  interactions. Here is the link to the FR: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/streamlit/streamlit/issues/725&gt;#725&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
On side note, installing Streamlit in a virtualenv may help your specific case.
Best,
Matteo
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='komodovaran' date='2020-02-14T20:05:08Z'>
		Closing since this report is fairly old vis-a-vis the latest versions of Streamlit.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>