<bug id='959' author='Nisargbharambe' open_date='2020-01-13T19:46:54Z' closed_time='2020-01-14T21:33:29Z'>
	<summary>Laptop Freeze</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Laptop Freezing out when I run an streamlit based program.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Streamlit was supposed to give the output for the code mentioned below.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I have a tried running a the following streamlit code.
After executing till 'line f', streamlit is in the execution process of the last 2 statements and continues to do so until the laptop freezes out completely, without producing the output.
Dataset being used:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://azuremlsampleexperiments.blob.core.windows.net/datasets/PdM_telemetry.csv&gt;https://azuremlsampleexperiments.blob.core.windows.net/datasets/PdM_telemetry.csv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;from __future__ import absolute_import, division, print_function, unicode_literals

import tensorflow as tf
import streamlit as st
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv('PdM_telemetry.csv')

st.title('Predictive Analysis using Keras')
st.markdown('Here, we are going to use telemetry and machines dataset')

st.markdown("Let's take a glance at the dataset:")
st.dataframe(data.head())
st.markdown("Let's take a look at the stats of the dataset")
st.dataframe(data.describe())
#st.write(data.info())

import matplotlib.pyplot as plt
import numpy as np
import seaborn as sns

st.markdown('Lets check if there are any missing values :')  #Line f
st.write('The type :',type(data.isna()) )
st.dataframe(data.isna())
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

That is, did this use to work the way you expected in the past?
no
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.52.2
Python version: 3.7.5
Using pip
OS version: pop-os 19.10
Browser version: Firefox 72.0.1

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If needed, add any other context about the problem here. For exmaple, did this bug come from &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.streamlit.io&gt;https://discuss.streamlit.io&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or another site? Link the original source here!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Nisargbharambe' date='2020-01-14T19:55:02Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Nisargbharambe&gt;@Nisargbharambe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , I was able to reproduce your issue.  Thanks for including your data!  We'll be looking into this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Nisargbharambe' date='2020-01-14T21:33:29Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Nisargbharambe&gt;@Nisargbharambe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
So it seems that currently, Streamlit has some issues serializing this particular dataframe.  So when it gets to this line of code, the server-side streamlit app runs out of memory causing your laptop to freeze:

st.dataframe(data.isna())

We're right now working on improvements to serialization by using Apache Arrow instead of our own serialization routines.  We're expecting this replacement to speed up transmission of data from Python to the browser by quite a lot.
What you can do right now: I'd suggest doing st.dataframe on a smaller piece of the dataframe, e.g. data.isna().head()) or some other smaller cross-section or analyzed subset of your data.
Let me know if this helps. I'm going to close your issue since we are implementing serialization improvements already.  Thanks for the reporting the bug!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>