<bug id='961' author='cornelg7' open_date='2020-01-13T22:34:40Z' closed_time='2020-05-12T19:42:12Z'>
	<summary>Always rerun doesn't work with VSCode</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Summary&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The "Always re-run" button doesn't seem to work when editing files with VSCode. It only appears the first time after I refresh localhost (and edit my file), which is normal. But, for any further source code edits I need to manually re-run the file (press R inside localhost).
This works as intended while editing the file with other file editors (tested on Notepad++, Notepad).
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Create new basic main.py file:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import streamlit as st
st.title('My first app')
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Start server:
streamlit run main.py --server.port=80
Open main.py in VSCode and edit it
Click on Always re-run (the file re-runs and displays the edit)
Edit main.py in VSCode again (this time the file doesn't re-runs)

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The result in localhost should have updated based on the edited source code.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual behavior:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The localhost generated file doesn't automatically re-run after editing the main.py file in VSCode.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://camo.githubusercontent.com/5c067a5d7f501ad2c38588ecf2422ffe8e5615ef8cdee6f062444d2311098fa8/68747470733a2f2f692e696d6775722e636f6d2f336356466471592e676966&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Is this a regression?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is my first time using streamlit.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Debug info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Streamlit version: 0.52.2
Python version: 3.7.4
Using Conda 4.8.1, with pip 19.2.3
OS version: Windows 10
Browser version: Google Chrome 79.0.3945.117

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I followed this: &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.streamlit.io/getting_started.html#import-streamlit&gt;https://docs.streamlit.io/getting_started.html#import-streamlit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cornelg7' date='2020-01-15T18:02:45Z'>
		Thanks for the report, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cornelg7&gt;@cornelg7&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
!
I can repro this on Windows 10/VSCode 1.4.1. Probably a watchdog issue? We'll triage it and take a look soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='cornelg7' date='2020-05-12T19:42:12Z'>
		Hi guys,
After a significant investigation in which I did see failure to re-run in VSCode on multiple platforms, I tried to modify the watchdog code that's triggered in streamlit/watcher/util.py to see if we were seeing a race condition -- the MD5s kept comparing as equal even when the file appeared to be modified.
Long story short, I don't think we can mess with this code without causing other problems.
There are a lot of different strategies by which editors touch files and OSes update the information on those files.  It looks like [previous versions of?] VSCode may have a strategy wherein the file modified date changes a few significant moments before the contents of the file change.
If we change how we monitor the files just for VSCode I think we may get problems elsewhere.
The recommendation on this problem should be to upgrade VScode.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='cornelg7' date='2020-05-12T19:46:17Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nthmost&gt;@nthmost&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , which version of VSCode does this work for?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='cornelg7' date='2020-05-13T21:29:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jrhone&gt;@jrhone&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Works in VSCode version 1.45
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='cornelg7' date='2020-05-14T13:05:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cornelg7&gt;@cornelg7&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tconkling&gt;@tconkling&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you confirm that upgrading VSCode to 1.45 fixes the issue for you?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>