<bug id='1108' author='nbowon' open_date='2020-02-19T14:49:04Z' closed_time='2020-02-21T15:31:07Z'>
	<summary>0.8.2, 0.8.1 version is not compatible with Mac OS version &amp;lt; 10.15</summary>
	<description>
Describe the feature and the current behavior/state.
I'm using Mac OS 10.14.6 version and I cannot install 0.8.2 or 0.8.1 version with pip
Seems 0.8.2 is only compatible with Mac OS version 10.15.x
Could you make 0.8.2 version of tensorflow-addons compatible with Mac OS 10.14.x?
Relevant information

Are you willing to contribute it (yes/no): no
Are you willing to maintain it going forward? (yes/no): yes
Is there a relevant academic paper? (if so, where): no
Is there already an implementation in another framework? (if so, where): no
Was it part of tf.contrib? (if so, where): I'm not sure

Which API type would this fall under (layer, metric, optimizer, etc.)
Who will benefit with this feature?
anyone who are using Mac OS 10.13, 10.14 version
Any other info.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-19T15:50:54Z'>
		Thanks for the issue! So the reason for this is when we switched builds to GitHub actions we didn't notice that the MacOS environment was running 10.15. Previously we had built for 10.13.
Simple fix just need to copy TF-IO's strategy:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/io/blob/master/.github/workflows/build.yml#L81-L82&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/io/blob/master/.github/workflows/build.yml#L81-L82&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T01:45:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nbowon&gt;@nbowon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you please try to install  and see if it works. The pip package is still labeled as 10.15 but I'm not sure if pip prevented you from installing it or if the package crashed on older versions.
Re-opening this until it's confirmed to be fixed. Once it is we will create a 0.8.3 patch release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T03:07:25Z'>
		I can install tfa-nightly,
when I try
"pip install tfa-nightly"
"tfa-nightly-0.8.0.dev20200125" is installed.
I still cannot install 0.8.2 version
I'm not sure how can I resolve this..
I guess that there is no 10.13 or 10.14 labeled package for 0.8.2 or above version in pypi
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T03:13:51Z'>
		As a short term option you can build Addons from source:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/addons#installing-from-source&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/addons#installing-from-source&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

We'll continue to work to get the packages fixed though. Please follow along with this issue.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yongtang&gt;@yongtang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 just FYI it appears that TF-IO packages are being built against 10.15 as well since moving to GitHub actions:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://pypi.org/project/tensorflow-io-nightly/#files&gt;https://pypi.org/project/tensorflow-io-nightly/#files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T03:24:22Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/seanpmorgan&gt;@seanpmorgan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks! I think the issue happens in setup tools. As  creates the package with  shown up in the filename of  created. May need to look into setuptools package to see if there is a ways to pass the expected name instead. Otherwise the build may have to happen on macOS 10.13.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T03:39:52Z'>
		Looks like there is a --plat-name in setup tools that could be used to specify a different platform:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Options for 'build' command:
....
  --plat-name (-p)   platform name to build for, if supported (default: macosx
                     -10.15-x86_64)
  --compiler (-c)    specify the compiler type
....
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T04:42:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/seanpmorgan&gt;@seanpmorgan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I created a PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/addons/pull/797&gt;#797&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for tensorflow/io. Think it might work on add-on as well.
Still need to find out a way to sanity check to make sure the generated binary works on 10.13.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T06:21:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nbowon&gt;@nbowon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 seanpmorgan Thanks. I'm trying to use it by building from source.
I hope it will be resolve soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-20T18:55:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/seanpmorgan&gt;@seanpmorgan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 adding the following line will resolve the issue on addon:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;--plat-name macosx_10_13_x86_64
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-22T13:01:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nbowon&gt;@nbowon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 When you get a chance could you try pip installing  and seeing how it works now. Packages look to support 10.13 now:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://pypi.org/project/tfa-nightly/#files&gt;https://pypi.org/project/tfa-nightly/#files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='nbowon' date='2020-02-22T14:11:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/seanpmorgan&gt;@seanpmorgan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I can install tea-nightly-0.9.0.dev20200222 version and it is labeled with machos_10_13
looks like it worked.
Thank you
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>