<bug id='184' author='jwdinius' open_date='2020-03-22T19:43:20Z' closed_time='2020-03-28T16:11:42Z'>
	<summary>PrimalDualSolver states arma::mat deprecated type to be removed in 2.10.0, but still present in 2.11.5</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Problem location&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/ensmallen/blob/2.11.5/include/ensmallen_bits/sdp/primal_dual.hpp&gt;https://github.com/mlpack/ensmallen/blob/2.11.5/include/ensmallen_bits/sdp/primal_dual.hpp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Description of problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The comments below indicate the interface should have been removed by now. (2.11.5 &gt; 2.10.0)
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;/**
 * PrimalDualSolver is a primal dual interior point solver for semidefinite
 * programs.
 *
 * PrimalDualSolver can optimize semidefinite programs.  For more details, see the
 * documentation on function types included with this distribution or on the
 * ensmallen website.
 *
 * @tparam DeprecatedSDPType Type of SDP to solve.  This parameter is deprecated
 *      and will be removed in ensmallen 2.10.0.
 */
template&lt;typename DeprecatedSDPType = SDP&lt;arma::mat&gt;&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The documentation should be updated to reflect when the interface will actually be deprecated.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jwdinius' date='2020-03-22T20:57:29Z'>
		It looks like we should remove it then.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jwdinius' date='2020-03-22T21:06:33Z'>
		It looks like removal will break the sdp unit tests.  Maybe add -Wdeprecated-declarations to catch this type-of thing when building tests?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jwdinius' date='2020-03-24T01:58:34Z'>
		Ack, I think that we failed on this one.  Should have opened an issue and tacked it onto a 2.10.0 milestone or something.
Anyway, I think this is a good issue for someone new who's looking to contribute.  But, this will break reverse compatibility, so we'll have to release 2.12.0 as a change.  Basically the task is to remove the deprecated template parameter to PrimalDualSolver, remove the ens_deprecated methods, and update the tests in tests/ that use it, then ensure that the documentation is still up to date (and all the tests work :)).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jwdinius' date='2020-03-24T03:09:41Z'>
		I'll give it a whack tomorrow or Wednesday.  I'm looking to use the interface anyways.  :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>