<bug id='227' author='Blakjak88' open_date='2020-09-28T03:38:50Z' closed_time='2020-11-18T13:44:00Z'>
	<summary>VCPKG Version Out of Date</summary>
	<description>
I installed ensmallen using vcpkg but discovered that the "upgraded" version is quite out of date.
vcpkg installs 2.11.2
Latest version is 2.14.2
I found this problem as I could not get my code to compile with EarlyStopAtMinLoss using a callback function. When I checked the header file there was no callback function constructor.
I manually changed the version number in my vcpkg CONTROL file but should this not be taken care of automatically with every new release?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-10-05T01:40:26Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Blakjak88&gt;@Blakjak88&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for the report.  I think this should be reported to the vcpkg repository, because we can't do too much about it here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg&gt;https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

For instance, here's the issue where someone originally requested ensmallen to be added to vcpkg: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg/issues/5015&gt;microsoft/vcpkg#5015&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I've asked them to bump the version of mlpack before; they're typically pretty responsive and helpful. 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-10-12T03:10:59Z'>
		I reported it to VCPKG about a week ago. Not sure if it is updated yet.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-10-12T11:31:00Z'>
		Thanks for doing that &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Blakjak88&gt;@Blakjak88&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! Do you have a link to the bug report? 
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-10-12T13:04:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Here is the link to the mlpack update request.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg/issues/13877&gt;microsoft/vcpkg#13877&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-10-12T13:06:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  ... and here is the request for ensmallen update.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/vcpkg/issues/13879&gt;microsoft/vcpkg#13879&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Blakjak88' date='2020-11-11T13:43:56Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>