<bug id='16' author='mmortazavi' open_date='2019-08-14T06:41:56Z' closed_time='2019-09-14T20:04:42Z'>
	<summary>Windows 10 Requires normalize.css!</summary>
	<description>
Thanks for the great tool; well-done, and I will be looking forward to trying out new features.
One note for Windows 10 Users. After following the instructions and successfully installing the make-sense I couldn't view it in the browser (e.g. Google Chrome). Basically npm start in Windows 10 Ubuntu results in the following error in the browser:
Error: Cannot find module '@csstools/normalize.css' nodejs
Although the message is self-explanatory, but I was struggling a bit since I have had zero experience with Node.js. Finally I figured one need to install normalize.css simply:
npm install normalize.css
Maybe it is best that README to be updated.
And you are good to go, Happy labelling!!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T07:15:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mmortazavi&gt;@mmortazavi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 For clarity, you're talking here about running locally on Windows 10 by the Ubuntu bash console?
Thanks a lot for the information, I admit that the whole application has been developed so far on Linux and Mac, and so far, on Windows 10, we were running only the online version.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T07:41:35Z'>
		
@mmortazavi For clarity, you're talking here about running locally on Windows 10 by the Ubuntu bash console?

Yes, exactly.

Thanks a lot for the information, I admit that the whole application has been developed so far on Linux and Mac, and so far, on Windows 10, we were running only the online version.

Noted. Thanks for sharing your work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T07:50:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mmortazavi&gt;@mmortazavi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Great, I understand everything. In this situation, I will put an appropriate note in README.md. As I understand, simple  is all you need to solve the problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T08:06:16Z'>
		Well, you know when you wanna make something work you try different things. The only step that was preceded before npm install normalize.css --save was to upgrade npm to the latest, whether it was relevant, I am not sure (your judgement, I found out about upgrading in another project repo):
npm install -g npm@latest
And restarted the system for changes to be effective, somewhere it was suggested!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T08:28:19Z'>
		Sure, I've been in a situation like this more than once or twice. In my opinion npm install normalize.css --save addition should be enough. Once again, thank you very much for drawing attention to these problems!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-14T09:32:20Z'>
		The information has been added to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SkalskiP/make-sense/blob/develop/README.md&gt;README.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in the develop version and will appear in the master with the next releas. It's visible in the section: Set Up the Project Locally.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-28T23:15:47Z'>
		hi
can u give the local environmental setting? I installed npm and try to run, still have the same error
Cannot find module '@csstools/normalize.css'
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-29T05:08:43Z'>
		Did you install npm install normalize.css --save as well?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-08-29T15:20:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yyuuliang&gt;@yyuuliang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 In your case, does this problem occur on Windows or Linux?
My settings I work with:
OS: Linux Mint 19.1 Tessa
brawser: Chrome 72
npm: 6.7.0
node: v11.10.1
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-12T15:05:39Z'>
		Hi! I have exactly the same issue on Ubuntu 18.04.3. I cloned repo, move to make-sense dir, than installed npm (by apt), then npm install and npm start the error occured:
Error: Cannot find module '@csstools/normalize.css'
then i tried npm install normalize.css --save
the error was still the same. Then npm install normalize.css npm install -g npm@latest npm install --save react-redux, npm install redux-devtools.
I have also one warning, no idea if it matters:
redux-devtools@3.5.0 requires a peer of react-redux@^4.0.0 || ^5.0.0 || ^6.0.0 but none was installed.
Anyone solved something like that?
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-12T17:06:22Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nieszkodzi&gt;@nieszkodzi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It seems that this error occurs more often than we suppose. We will try to fix the bug, but it is a problem because only a small percentage of users complain about it.  In this situation, the issue is reopened, as the problem has not been solved.
In this situation I ask you to give me the exact version of npm and node you are using. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yyuuliang&gt;@yyuuliang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you also share the version numbers you are using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-12T18:00:23Z'>
		My npm version is 3.5.2 and my node version is 8.10.0

czw., 12 wrz 2019, 19:06 użytkownik Piotr Skalski &lt;notifications@github.com&gt;
napisał:
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


 @nieszkodzi &lt;https://github.com/nieszkodzi&gt; It seems that this error
 occurs more often than we suppose. We will try to fix the bug, but it is a
 problem because only a small percentage of users complain about it. In this
 situation, the issue is reopened, as the problem has not been solved.

 In this situation I ask you to give me the exact version of npm and node
 you are using. @yyuuliang &lt;https://github.com/yyuuliang&gt; Could you also
 share the version numbers you are using?

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#16?email_source=notifications&amp;email_token=AKLZ4TPWJO4HXA7JCCHTZ3TQJJZJBA5CNFSM4ILRRX42YY3PNVWWK3TUL52HS4DFVREXG43VMVBW63LNMVXHJKTDN5WW2ZLOORPWSZGOD6SSP2Y#issuecomment-530917355&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AKLZ4TN5EXM6HQ6STLGD4UDQJJZJBANCNFSM4ILRRX4Q&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-12T21:15:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nieszkodzi&gt;@nieszkodzi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! We conducted tests to try to recreate your environment and we also failed to run the application. Please update the node and npm versions. This should ensure the proper launch of the application. npm: 6.7.0, node: v11.10.1
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-13T11:10:48Z'>
		Now I updated node to v12.10.0 and npm to 6.10.3, delete all repo, cloned it again, made all instructions one more time and it's working :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-13T14:56:49Z'>
		I'm very pleased to hear that! Then add to README the information that such versions are required to ensure proper local operation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='mmortazavi' date='2019-09-14T20:04:40Z'>
		I have added a new description to README, in this situation I am closing the issue again.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>