<bug id='36' author='yyuuliang' open_date='2019-08-29T00:09:51Z' closed_time='2019-09-04T18:07:15Z'>
	<summary>If there is only points annotation, the exported csv contains nothing.</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
I load an image, make points annotation, then export the csv file. There is nothing inside the csv file.
I then draw a bounding box on the same image, then export the points. This time the csv file contains the points locations.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Load an image
make some points annotations
export the points to a csv file

Expected behavior
The csv file should contains points locations even if there is no bounding box.
Screenshots
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
Desktop (please complete the following information):

OS:  Ubuntu 16
Browser: Chrome
Version: 70

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yyuuliang' date='2019-08-29T06:41:15Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yyuuliang&gt;@yyuuliang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have verified and of course you're right. The error will be corrected in the near future, as it has high priority.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yyuuliang' date='2019-08-29T15:24:46Z'>
		The problem has been solved. The improved version of the application will be available on the production with the next release. Currently, the patches are available on the developer instance: &lt;denchmark-link:https://develop.makesense.ai/&gt;https://develop.makesense.ai/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I would be very grateful if you could verify whether the effect is as intended.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yyuuliang' date='2019-08-29T22:49:29Z'>
		I have verified this and it works now, thanks for the fix!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yyuuliang' date='2019-08-30T07:55:35Z'>
		Task is for now In Test and I will move it to done, after another release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yyuuliang' date='2019-09-04T18:06:59Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yyuuliang&gt;@yyuuliang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! Due to the large amount of bugs that we have managed to fix recently, we decided to make a small release marked with the tag . The same applies to this issue, which is now available at &lt;denchmark-link:https://makesense.ai&gt;https://makesense.ai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Happy Labelling!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>