<bug id='40' author='RaccoonForever' open_date='2019-09-03T14:13:23Z' closed_time='2019-09-04T18:08:04Z'>
	<summary>Scrolling label</summary>
	<description>
I have 8 different labels.
When I add more than 20 (more or less, it depends on the screen) boxes on one image. If I add one more bounding box. I won't be able to scroll down to all labels. I'll be able to pick only first ones.
See the screenshot linked. I have more labels under wheat but I can't access them.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4057852/64180789-ab272980-ce65-11e9-932f-535732bfb857.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

**Desktop **

OS: Windows 10
Browser : Firefox
Version : 60.0.2 (32 bits)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RaccoonForever' date='2019-09-03T15:20:25Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RaccoonForever&gt;@RaccoonForever&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It seems that because a dopdown containing your labels is always placed below the record you are editing, there are some problems when the record is too low. And the dropdown can't fit. A possible fix should not be difficult. I think we will publish it with the next release. Thank you for drawing attention to this problem. I'll keep you informed of any progress.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='RaccoonForever' date='2019-09-03T19:16:40Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RaccoonForever&gt;@RaccoonForever&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Improvements have been made. They are currently available on the developer instance. &lt;denchmark-link:https://develop.makesense.ai/&gt;https://develop.makesense.ai/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I encourage you to test and possibly further comments. The patch will enter the production instance with the next release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='RaccoonForever' date='2019-09-04T10:04:30Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SkalskiP&gt;@SkalskiP&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks for your answer and for your quick improvement !
It works like a charm on the test environment !
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='RaccoonForever' date='2019-09-04T15:19:54Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RaccoonForever&gt;@RaccoonForever&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! I'm super happy to have managed to fix it!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='RaccoonForever' date='2019-09-04T18:08:02Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RaccoonForever&gt;@RaccoonForever&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! Due to the large amount of bugs that we have managed to fix recently, we decided to make a small release marked with the tag . The same applies to this issue, which is now available at &lt;denchmark-link:https://makesense.ai&gt;https://makesense.ai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Happy Labelling!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>