<bug id='85' author='kfezer' open_date='2018-04-03T16:35:24Z' closed_time='2018-08-19T14:24:22Z'>
	<summary>Headless Mode?</summary>
	<description>
This is more of an enhancement or question:
Can RLCoach run in a headless environment? This would enable faster run-times. Right now I get the error:
File "/home/u6770/.conda/envs/coach/lib/python3.5/site-packages/pyglet/gl/glx_info.py", line 84, in have_version
raise GLXInfoException('pyglet requires an X server with GLX')
pyglet.gl.glx_info.GLXInfoException: pyglet requires an X server with GLX
Can that dependency be dropped and made optional in the setup script?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kfezer' date='2018-04-23T06:55:19Z'>
		Are you getting this error during the installation of Coach?
If you get this when running Coach, which environment are you running?
In any case, it should be possible to run Coach in a headless environment
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kfezer' date='2018-04-26T21:33:47Z'>
		Sorry for the lack of update.
So I'm specifically referring to getting this running on the DevCloud to use as a research platform:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://software.intel.com/en-us/ai-academy/tools/devcloud&gt;https://software.intel.com/en-us/ai-academy/tools/devcloud&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Right now, the workaround is to build a virtual environment to enable the GLX renderer. This might be the only solution as the renderer is needed to detect the collisions (which is something I didn't think about.)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kfezer' date='2018-05-10T17:41:41Z'>
		Hi, I am also interested on running RLCoach on Intel DevCloud. Since it is a cluster I am not sure about how can I install RLCoach dependencies without root access and also how can I see the video of the agents improving over time. Could someone help me with this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kfezer' date='2018-06-05T23:54:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/felipheggaliza&gt;@felipheggaliza&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I (by I I mean a bunch of awesome colfax people) got it working. It's not great as it's single node-mode (currently RLCoach doesn't run distributed) and no video, but you can export the gifs via the -g modifier.
I think I'll post instructions soon so that you can at least try. I'll update here when I do. Feel free to message me or email: &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:karl.fezer@intel.com&gt;karl.fezer@intel.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kfezer' date='2018-08-19T14:24:21Z'>
		Hi Karl,
Is there anything else missing here? AFAIK, coach does run on a headless setup. Rendering might be tricky, but that's a general issue, which I think is unrelated to Coach.
I'm closing the issue now. Please reopen it if there's anything else missing from Coach side, so we can fix it.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>