<bug id='55' author='jochemstoel' open_date='2019-09-05T00:16:56Z' closed_time='2019-10-26T00:37:29Z'>
	<summary>[Windows] Clear GPU cache before/after run</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
The second or third time I run this application prebuilt version, I receive an error that CUDA is out of memory.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Download and extract binaries for Windows
Install the endpoints using dreampower.exe
Run dreampower.exe a few times on different images
See error

Expected behavior
I expect the cache of my GPU to be cleared after the process is finished and/or before it starts.
Enviroment

Version: latest
OS: Windows 10 x64
GPU: NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1050

Additional context
RuntimeError: CUDA out of memory. Tried to allocate 36.00 MiB (GPU 0; 2.00 GiB total capacity; 564.01 MiB already allocated; 17.85 MiB free; 15.99 MiB cached)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jochemstoel' date='2019-09-23T15:41:08Z'>
		With the new --disable-persistent-gan normally clean all CUDA memory after each GAN. Using this option should avoid this bug.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/private-dreamnet/dreampower/blob/d691f02cb5970158cc379f26dea40de3731aa11d/transform/gan/__init__.py#L79-L83&gt;https://github.com/private-dreamnet/dreampower/blob/d691f02cb5970158cc379f26dea40de3731aa11d/transform/gan/__init__.py#L79-L83&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Before I add this as a global clean up at this end of all executions the same way, if somebody can validate the option actually fix this.( I am not the tight env to reproduce the bug. : linux and no gpu).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jochemstoel' date='2019-09-25T00:33:56Z'>
		The bug described only happens occasionally. It only failed to clear GPU cache occasionally, not at all consistently so there is no real way for me to measure if your --disable-persistent works besides using it every time and seeing over a period of time if it stopped failing every now and then.
How do you suggest I test this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jochemstoel' date='2019-09-25T04:53:29Z'>
		Maybe script that run the command again and again times in loop.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jochemstoel' date='2019-10-25T05:31:07Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>