<bug id='74' author='fallingdungeon' open_date='2019-11-12T08:46:17Z' closed_time='2019-11-15T20:23:14Z'>
	<summary>`GLIBC_2.25' not found</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
[6983] Error loading Python lib '/media/pixiepox/ssd_storage/DreamPower/libpython3.7m.so.1.0': dlopen: /lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libc.so.6: version `GLIBC_2.25' not found (required by /media/pixiepox/ssd_storage/DreamPower/libpython3.7m.so.1.0)
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

I am currently on DeepinOS 15.11
Whatever command I try to run is met with this error.
PS - I tried the software on Ubuntu and Mint previously and it worked 100% fine.


If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42859799/68655878-d3629100-0556-11ea-854e-34bed3824777.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Enviroment (please complete the following information):

Version [1.2.2]
OS: [DeepinOS]

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-12T16:53:47Z'>
		Can you try:

make a back-up of the file: '/media/pixiepox/ssd_storage/DreamPower/libpython3.7m.so.1.0
remove the file:  '/media/pixiepox/ssd_storage/DreamPower/libpython3.7m.so.1.0

The idea is that your OS comes with the library already and the above should make it use that library instead of the one included in the dreampower package.
if that throws an error that the library can't be found, then restore the file.
and report back here :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-13T10:18:43Z'>
		I made backup of the above mentioned file and deleted it from the DreamPower folder. I ran the basic run command again but was met with another error. Attaching screenshots.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42859799/68754596-fe1f1900-062c-11ea-8ec9-5d2fb7fcb434.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thank you for responding (^_^)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-13T12:42:55Z'>
		can you try installing python 3.7?
you can also join our chat:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://chat.dreamnet.tech/&gt;https://chat.dreamnet.tech/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

making solving this issue a bit easier :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-14T15:47:18Z'>
		I am sorry, but I can't figure out how to install the latest python on linux. God, it was just simple installer on Windows. I found out that DeepinOS ships with python 3.5. I am searching and reading articles on how to install the latest python. Will report back once I do. Thank you and sorry for my incompetence.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-15T19:02:11Z'>
		I am sorry, I couldn't figure out if I had successfully installed the latest python. I tried many guides from the internet but my results weren't exactly what they mentioned it would be. Nevertheless, I couldn't get dreampower to work. It kept throwing the same error.
I ended up distro hopping back to Ubuntu now. Everything works as it should. Thank you guys and you can close the issue if you want.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='fallingdungeon' date='2019-11-15T20:23:14Z'>
		ok, glad to hear it works now.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>