<bug id='1045' author='ghost(ghost)' open_date='2020-03-16T06:41:05Z' closed_time='2020-08-18T01:27:45Z'>
	<summary>Update the greedy tuner to consider the conditional search space</summary>
	<description>
I just started using Autokeras ver 1.0.2 in anaconda with Python 3.7 and tensorflow-gpu ver. 2.1.0 on Windows 10. I have a dual RTX Titan (NVlinked) setup and using Spyder ver. 4.0.1
I wanted to do some simple binary classification for RGB images:
clf = ak.ImageClassifier()
clf.fit(x_train, y_train, epochs=10)
Training starts ok but after 3 trials, this happens:
INFO:tensorflow:Oracle triggered exit
I have tried different image datasets, including the MNIST example dataset but the exit trigger still happens after 3 trials, regardless of the val_acc. I can't figure out what is stopping Autokeras from continue to train beyond 3 trials (default is 100 trials?).
Looks like similar issue to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keras-team/autokeras/issues/997&gt;#997&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

but problem is it is happening for version 1.0.2
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-03-17T16:27:43Z'>
		This might because of the greedy tuning algorithms have some bugs. You can try to use the AutoModel API and use random search as tuner.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2020-05-13T04:16:35Z'>
		I am having the same problem. I downgraded my AutoKeras from 1.0.2 to 1.0.1, set my max_trials=10, epochs=1 (for testing purposes) and I was still getting the Oracle error. BUT if I set the max_trials=12 and I set metrics=['accuracy'] then it would complete all 12 trials without any issues. This also works without metrics=['accuracy'], but it seems to error out at iteration 20 instead of 10. This was also with kernel restarts in-between each max_trial test. I am unsure what this means, but hopefully, it helps in the debugging process.
Unfortunately, there is a bug in 1.0.1 that makes it difficult to get the best model. clf.get_best_model does not choose the best one. To obtain all models found by AutoKeras one needs to do the following:
`max_trials=12
clf=ak.ImageClassifier(max_trials=max_trials, metrics=['accuracy'])
clf.fit(X_train, y_train, epochs=1, verbose=0)
found_models = clf.tuner.get_best_models(max_trials)
for model in found_models:
print(model.evaluate(X_test, y_test))`
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>