<bug id='926' author='Min-seong-son' open_date='2020-01-25T09:48:47Z' closed_time='2020-04-04T00:59:03Z'>
	<summary>How to load best model with same accuracy?</summary>
	<description>
Hi :)
I want to load best model with same accuracy. (ImageClassifier)
So, In Training Part,
clf = ak.ImageClassifier( directory='/home/son/PycharmProjects/Project/SkinModel20192/')
clf.fit(train_input, train_label, validation_split=(1/9))
And In Load Part,
autokeras_model = tf.keras.models.load_model('/home/son/PycharmProjects/Project/SkinModel2019/my_skinmodel2019.h5')
But After Running Load Part, I got lower Accuracy result than Training result...
And I found one way of increasing accuracy,
autokeras_model.fit(train_input, train_label, validation_split=1/9, batch_size=32)
That is retraining in Load part using Same Train data set. As a result, It had a good effect. But I think It is inefficient way. I want to get same accuracy without retraining.
So, I want to know the reason of problems (e.g : can not load hyperparameter or weights) and solution.
Also, After exporting best model, Some files (oracle.json, trail.json, checkpoint etc / The picture is uploaded) are generated.. But I do not know how to use this file when I load the best model..
I would be happy if somebody could provide me with some help.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/60286567/73119219-00451280-3fa2-11ea-9f8a-86f8d83c2806.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/60286567/73119220-00dda900-3fa2-11ea-984a-399a5940da7b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Min-seong-son' date='2020-01-26T06:32:51Z'>
		@Min-seong-song I believe this is because the processor is not exported. Tensorflow 2.1 has just released the preprocessing layers which enables a Keras model to contain preprocessors. We will support it in the next release of AutoKeras. Thank you
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Min-seong-son' date='2020-01-27T23:45:24Z'>
		Thank you and I hope next version will be released ASAP :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Min-seong-son' date='2020-03-28T00:40:41Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>