<bug id='1384' author='anujdutt9' open_date='2019-03-14T18:16:54Z' closed_time='2019-03-22T22:26:50Z'>
	<summary>Model.Classify() gives GL_INVALID_OPERATION: Object cannot be used because it has not been generated.</summary>
	<description>
To get help from the community, we encourage using Stack Overflow and the &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow.js&gt;tensorflow.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;TensorFlow.js version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

1.0.0
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Browser version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Google Chrome:  Version 73.0.3683.75 (Official Build) (64-bit)
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I followed the steps from Google Codelab: &lt;denchmark-link:https://codelabs.developers.google.com/codelabs/tensorflowjs-teachablemachine-codelab/index.html#0&gt;https://codelabs.developers.google.com/codelabs/tensorflowjs-teachablemachine-codelab/index.html#0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The given example works fine, but when I made some changes to the example for my Blog with multiple images, it gives this error:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11924142/54380667-695db900-4662-11e9-8f94-dc0afd338649.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

As you can see, when I click on the first image, it works fine. Loads the model, does classification, displays the results. As I click on a second image, it gives these errors. This seems to be happening on this Windows Laptop [Dell  Inspiron, Windows 10] with this Version of Chrome only as I am also testing the same thing on a MacBook Pro with the exact same version of Chrome without any errors.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Code to reproduce the bug/link to feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

You can check my Blog here [https://anujdutt9.github.io/TFjs-ImageClassifier.html] and look for errors in the console. Also, you can find the complete code for this here [https://github.com/anujdutt9/anujdutt9.github.io/blob/master/TFjs-ImageClassifier.html].
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-14T22:03:24Z'>
		I came to this repo to open up an issue with exactly the same error message. In my project I am using tfjs 1.0.0, mobilenet 1.0.0 and knn 1.0.0 to classify images from a webcam stream. I can train for about 30sec before exactly the error from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/anujdutt9&gt;@anujdutt9&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 happens. Not sure if related but maybe it helps narrowing down the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-15T14:48:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dsmilkov&gt;@dsmilkov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Possibly related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/1381&gt;#1381&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Like that issue, this one is also Windows.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-18T15:22:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zugende&gt;@zugende&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Are you also on Windows? Can you share basic info about the computer (model, GPU card, windows version). Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-19T20:22:39Z'>
		Can you run tf.ENV.set('WEBGL_PACK', false) right after you load the TF.js library and let me know if it helps so we can narrow down the problem. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-20T18:45:49Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dsmilkov&gt;@dsmilkov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. "tf.ENV.set('WEBGL_PACK', false)" This somehow seems to solve the problem. I don't see that error anymore on the Windows machine. Maybe I'll wait for others to confirm the same as well.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zugende&gt;@zugende&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Did you get a chance to try &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dsmilkov&gt;@dsmilkov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 's solution ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-21T17:32:04Z'>
		Thanks! That's helpful to us. We are waiting for a windows machine and will look into this asap.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-21T18:41:40Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dsmilkov&gt;@dsmilkov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I had another demo that was working perfectly till yesterday and suddenly today it broke. I have fixed it but thought it might be good to share as it might help someone else.
This is the link to the demo for doing Linear Regression in the browser:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://anujdutt9.github.io/TFjs-LinearRegression.html&gt;https://anujdutt9.github.io/TFjs-LinearRegression.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Earlier when I was importing tfjs 0.15.3, it was working fine till yesterday but suddenly today it started giving an error saying:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11924142/54776761-2746f100-4be7-11e9-9c1e-751bde71f99d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I got this error when I am importing TensorFlow.js using the following line of code:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;&lt;script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@tensorflow/tfjs@0.15.3/dist/tf.min.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Today, I changed it to the following after getting the error above:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;&lt;script src="https://unpkg.com/@tensorflow/tfjs"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

and it works fine now.
So, I don't know what changed in between these two imports within last couple of days, but the previous import broke the working demo yesterday while the latter import fixed it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-22T19:37:37Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/anujdutt9&gt;@anujdutt9&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I checked out your demo in Chrome on a Lenovo Yoga (Intel Graphics 520) running Windows 10 and was unable to reproduce the error, even with  set to . Would you mind trying your demo again and seeing whether the tfjs version bump (we're now at ) somehow resolved your issue? Could you also make sure that you're only loading one instance of the library (make sure you don't a warning in the console with 'webgl backend was already registered')?
Let me know - thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-22T20:38:54Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/annxingyuan&gt;@annxingyuan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for your response. Yes, I changed the import link for the library and the demo works now. I think the tfjs version bump was the trick maybe. If I go back to 0.15.3, then some issues happen. But the new one looks good. Thanks 
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='anujdutt9' date='2019-03-22T22:26:50Z'>
		Glad to hear it :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>