<bug id='1798' author='rsaeta' open_date='2019-08-06T21:46:17Z' closed_time='2019-08-12T21:21:44Z'>
	<summary>[Codelab]: Making Predictions from 2D Data</summary>
	<description>
To get help from the community, we encourage using Stack Overflow and the &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow.js&gt;tensorflow.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;TensorFlow.js version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Browser version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

On step 4. Define the model architecture of the &lt;denchmark-link:https://codelabs.developers.google.com/codelabs/tfjs-training-regression/index.html#3&gt;tensorflow.js codelabs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the code block for  has a different output layer than the line-by-line walkthrough. The code-block will actually not produce any visualization when trying to train the model in the next pages. However, the line-by-line (omitting  field) fixed the problem.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Code to reproduce the bug / link to feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-08T20:59:38Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rsaeta&gt;@rsaeta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for reporting the issue , i was able to reproduce the issue.Will take a look.
with 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43972606/62737745-68e50680-b9e5-11e9-840e-0f6c9605589d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

without 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43972606/62737883-ced18e00-b9e5-11e9-922f-8988f5c20958.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-09T15:36:02Z'>
		Hi. useBias is true by default for dense layers, we have a note about that on the &lt;denchmark-link:https://codelabs.developers.google.com/codelabs/tfjs-training-regression/index.html#3&gt;model definition page&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, so after explaining it we no longer include it in the calls. Note that omitting it is not the same as changing it to false (which we do not do).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rthadur&gt;@rthadur&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it looks like unlike &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rsaeta&gt;@rsaeta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, in both cases (useBias being present and being omitted) you were able to train the model and get a visualization?
Does the output in each case stay consistent? (because of random initialization you can get different results on different runs). I was not able to get a consistent difference between using useBias and not using it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-09T17:02:59Z'>
		I honestly tried to do this again and could not reproduce the same error. The actual behavior I saw was that it was not showing a visualization for MSE/loss when going through iterations of training. It would adjust the x-axis but no line was showing up.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-09T17:30:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes i was able to train the model and get a visualization in both cases, but output is not consistent.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-12T21:00:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rsaeta&gt;@rsaeta&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 let us know if you were able to get resolve this ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-12T21:04:19Z'>
		Yes I was able to resolve this, but still not quite sure of root cause. Can close if cannot reproduce as I cannot either.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='rsaeta' date='2019-08-12T21:21:44Z'>
		Thanks for the update. I'm going to close this for now as the original issue cannot be reproduced.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>