<bug id='2194' author='nikhilwbhatia' open_date='2019-10-11T22:52:42Z' closed_time='2019-10-22T19:48:55Z'>
	<summary>convInfo undefined when fitting downloaded model for transfer learning</summary>
	<description>
To get help from the community, we encourage using Stack Overflow and the &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow.js&gt;tensorflow.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Tensorflow.js 1.2.8&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Chrome 77.0.3865.90&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Getting "backend_webgl.ts:2088 Uncaught (in promise) TypeError: Cannot read property 'filterHeight' of undefined" when trying to fit downloaded model to training data.
My code does the following:

Downloads mobilenet
Modifies the model by freezing all but the last couple layers and adds a custom output layer (https://imgur.com/a/PFqPHsz)
Attempts to train the modified model layers with images + corresponding labels (https://imgur.com/a/yEoMWMl)

Modifying and freezing the model work fine (I've confirmed these work by checking the model summary), but attempting to fit the model leads to the error seen below (it seems that convInfo is undefined, but I'm unsure how to debug the root cause).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13323318/66689017-35c62a00-ec57-11e9-9205-9f4321e75f3b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Any help on this issue would be much appreciated!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-21T16:45:41Z'>
		
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/nikhilwbhatia/9754701c26fe4937936f32920f7d62e5&gt;https://gist.github.com/nikhilwbhatia/9754701c26fe4937936f32920f7d62e5&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia/spectrogram-audio-classification/blob/isolate_audio/frontend/src/TestView.js&gt;https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia/spectrogram-audio-classification/blob/isolate_audio/frontend/src/TestView.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-21T17:59:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia&gt;@nikhilwbhatia&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for reporting this! BTW I noticed that you're on 1.2.8 of tfjs - curious whether you still se the issue with 1.2.11 (the latest version)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-21T21:18:56Z'>
		I downgraded to 1.2.8 after experiencing a different issue when fetching Mobilenet (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/2170&gt;#2170&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). I don't think the fix for &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/2170&gt;#2170&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 has hit production yet so I can't test if 1.2.11 would solve the current issue, but if you think it might I can fork master and try it? Thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-21T21:21:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia&gt;@nikhilwbhatia&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 If you wouldn't mind trying that out it would be great! We phased in support for fused ops over several versions so I'm hoping master will just work for you. Keep me posted.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-22T19:50:00Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia&gt;@nikhilwbhatia&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - this should be fixed with the next release of core. Feel free to reopen if you still encounter it then.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-22T20:58:56Z'>
		Hi Ann, thanks for the update! Apologies for my unfamiliarity with github/npm but I'm having some trouble installing/importing tfjs from the master branch in my react app.
I tried  (which complained about tfjs' package.json missing a name and version), so I forked the repo and added my own name/version to the package.json (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia/tfjs&gt;https://github.com/nikhilwbhatia/tfjs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), and then did .
This worked and I can see tfjs in my node_modules, but I'm unable to import this package (import * as tf from 'tfjs';) from my react app. Getting the following error: Module not found: Can't resolve 'tfjs' in '/Users/nikhilbhatia/spectrogram-audio-classification/frontend/src', which I believe implies it couldn't find tfjs in my node_modules and is looking in src instead.
Is this the correct process for installing/importing tfjs from the master branch rather than from a standard npm release? (I know this is not really a tfjs question but thank you again for your help).
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-24T03:12:20Z'>
		Running into the same issue as well, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/annxingyuan&gt;@annxingyuan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , do you know when there will be a next release for core ? If it's going to take a long time, are there any instructions on how to build a local version?
I've tried doing the npm run publish-local in each of the *-core,-layers,-converter,-data packages, but then I run into:
tf-core.esm.js:17 Uncaught (in promise) TypeError: Nt.makeTensor is not a function at Sn (tf-core.esm.js:17) at kn (tf-core.esm.js:17) at o (tf-core.esm.js:17)
So I'm not sure if I did it correctly. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-24T09:23:28Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faceshape&gt;@faceshape&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - yes to build a local version of core, cd into the tfjs-core directory and run:
yarn build &amp;&amp; rollup -c
Then you should find a copy of tf-core.js in your local dist directory.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='nikhilwbhatia' date='2019-10-25T03:38:38Z'>
		I still had the Nt.makeTensor is not a function problem, but when I tried just building tfjs/ directly and including that output from dist, it worked. Thanks, looking forward to the next release!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>