<bug id='2637' author='shadow111' open_date='2020-01-03T15:40:11Z' closed_time='2020-01-27T16:21:59Z'>
	<summary>Unhandled promise rejection: Error: Out of memory]</summary>
	<description>
Hello,
I'm using Tensorflow js for react Native,
I have converted a Tensorflow Model to TensorflowJs and try to load it from a URL with tf.loadGraphModel using TFJS for react native, the problem is i get this :
TFJS : last version
TFJS for react native: last version
[Unhandled promise rejection: Error: Out of memory]
- node_modules\@tensorflow\tfjs-core\dist\io\io_utils.js:328:30 in concatenateArrayBuffers
- node_modules\@tensorflow\tfjs-core\dist\io\http.js:234:95 in &lt;unknown&gt;
- ... 12 more stack frames from framework internals
i'm not using a physical device im' using the emulator , with 4GB of RAM.
My TFJS model is a shared model and have a size of 275 MB, i don't understand what could be the problem either it's the model size or something wrong with TFJS for react.
Thanks for your help
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='shadow111' date='2020-01-06T19:20:52Z'>
		Could you specify which device emulator you are using (iOS or android)? It looks like you are hitting a limit on the amount of memory that the app can use.
Are you able to use tfjs-react-native to load other models (like mobilenet)? If so then I suspect the model is too big for the device/os you are emulating.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='shadow111' date='2020-01-07T13:45:45Z'>
		I'm using android emulator , yes i can load other models,  i have reduced my model size to 70MB and when i try to laod it using tf.loadLayersModel(bundleResourceIO(modelJson, modelWeights)) the app just crushed
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='shadow111' date='2020-01-07T14:37:26Z'>
		It could be an issue with the configuration of the VM, could you try this on a physical device?
Without more to go on it just looks like your VM is running out of memory. To rule out tfjs-react-native, you could try initializing a new Uint8Array(73400320) that is 70MB large and see if you are able to allocate that much memory.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='shadow111' date='2020-01-27T16:21:59Z'>
		Closing this due to lack of activity. Feel free to re-open if you are able to initialize the array described above without crashing.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>