<bug id='2784' author='DanielOnye123' open_date='2020-02-23T05:22:11Z' closed_time='2020-05-19T07:05:59Z'>
	<summary>Import tfjs-react-native not working on EXPO CLI Project</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43086384/75103988-e0b8fe00-55d0-11ea-9dd9-6e62514cc905.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I'm getting this error when I try to run my React-Native program on the web or android. I followed the steps on the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/tree/master/tfjs-react-native&gt;tfjs-react-native documentation &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 but I'm still having issues with my program.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;TensorFlow.js version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

tfjs-react-native
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Browser version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

package.json
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43086384/75104035-be73b000-55d1-11ea-8d91-dc78510221b7.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Code to reproduce the bug / link to feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is the code causing the error
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43086384/75104049-04307880-55d2-11ea-9ae1-8a959aa953ed.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I even removed the tfjs-react native import and it compiles so I don't know what to do
If you would like to get help from the community, we encourage using Stack Overflow and the &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow.js&gt;tensorflow.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag.
GitHub issues for this repository are tracked in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues&gt;tfjs union repository&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Please file your issue there, following the guidance in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/blob/master/ISSUE_TEMPLATE.md&gt;that issue template&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-25T18:35:17Z'>
		From your error it looks like you are using webpack (as opposed to metro) to bundle your app. I think you need to configure webpack to process .js files (or even that specific js file) with the JSX loader (or some transformer that can consume jsx syntax).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-25T23:14:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43086384/75296162-6ec3fd00-57fa-11ea-987c-82259f2f3c0c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


I noticed I'm using babel.config.js rather than webpack.config.js. I've tried to look upon adding a babel-loader in this config file and I'm honestly lost on the process. Would you happen to know how to do so?
      
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T12:30:16Z'>
		It doesn't seem related to JSX syntax because other JSX components are being rendered properly. The problem occurs as soon as I import @tensorflow/tfjs-react-native.
From the , could it be related to this: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/TypeScript/issues/30650&gt;microsoft/TypeScript#30650&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I am using Expo Managed app.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T15:26:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DanielOnye123&gt;@DanielOnye123&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't know how to do this. I haven't been using webpack in concert with RN apps.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/muditgoel01&gt;@muditgoel01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't think its related to typescript as the files in the package are already transpiled to JavaScript. In this case it may be that the bundler is configured to assume all components are in files with the .jsx extension. Are you able to load JSX components that are within .js files?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T15:28:26Z'>
		I would suggest asking on Stack Overflow or the Expo forums for more info on configuration options for the setup you are using. It could be a recent change in expo.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T15:33:12Z'>
		Could you test this by
1. removing the import of the library
2. Make a small react component in a file with a .js extension
3. import and render that component
If that works, then it helps narrow down where a configuration issue may be.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T20:26:33Z'>
		I'm able to import and render without the tfjs-react module. I do believe this could be a configuration issue because I tested this on an Expo managed app with typescript configuration and the import worked
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T20:52:51Z'>
		Downgrading to "@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native": "0.1.0-alpha.2" works fine.
"@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native": "0.1.0-alpha.3" also gives same error.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T21:11:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DanielOnye123&gt;@DanielOnye123&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 are you able to import a JSX component that is in a .js file?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-26T21:25:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes. I am able to
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-27T23:48:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DanielOnye123&gt;@DanielOnye123&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Were you getting this unexpected token error in your project only when doing  ()? Webpack is used for running react-native apps in the browser with expo. You shouldn't be hitting this specific error when running on Android.
Try running expo customize:web in the root of the project, then select the webpack.config.js option to generate the webpack config file. Add the following to the webpack.config.js file and try re-running the app.
const createExpoWebpackConfigAsync = require('@expo/webpack-config');
const path = require('path');

module.exports = async function(env, argv) {
  const config = await createExpoWebpackConfigAsync(env, argv);
  
  config.module.rules.push({
    test: /\.(js|jsx)$/,
    include: [path.resolve(__dirname, "node_modules/@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native")],
    use: {
      loader: 'babel-loader',
      options: {
        presets: [
          ['@babel/env', { modules: 'commonjs' }], 
        ],
      }
    }
  });
  return config;
};
I was able to get my managed Expo JS app working on the web with this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-28T05:34:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/43086384/75513060-8a2d3480-59c1-11ea-8ea9-2c6468f09ac1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thank you. It's working on the web, but ironically it's not working on the android. I keep getting this error above. I checked out this other documentation with a similar issue: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/2400&gt;Issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, but his solution didn't work for me as I don't have typescript config
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-28T05:54:40Z'>
		That  file will be removed from the dist directory in the next tfjs release (with  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/commit/fb163f7f1f8cbb953a856f1621d8b1bad44afd04&gt;fb163f7&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) as it shouldn't even be there. For a quick fix, just delete that typescript file:
rm -f node_modules/@tensorflow/tfjs-converter/dist/src/data/compiled_api.ts
Then metro should stop complaining.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-02-28T19:07:19Z'>
		Thank you so much! It's working on both platforms. My last question is: Does the "fetch" method imported from tfjs-react native support local fetches? e.g locally fetching a picture
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-03-13T11:59:10Z'>
		Hi, I don't have experience with ReactNative/NodeJs and just tried everything you explained here, but still, have the same problems. Can you please, provide the example code?. I am running on MacOs, node 13, expo cli. - My hello world RN app is working, but when I add your code - I got the same errors.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-03-13T19:11:40Z'>
		Doesn't seem like fetch supports local afaik. Might have to use expo-file-system to load local images for now.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/motya770&gt;@motya770&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Which error are you getting? I have a barebones TF.js typescript expo managed project that can load fine for me (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pvaneck/tfjs-react-native-app&gt;https://github.com/pvaneck/tfjs-react-native-app&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) if you want to check that out.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-04-30T23:49:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pvaneck&gt;@pvaneck&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fetch seems to be working fine in ios but fails on android
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-05-01T17:48:56Z'>
		Hi, I just switched to Flutter, much simpler, much more predictable results )
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='DanielOnye123' date='2020-05-19T07:05:59Z'>
		Looks like this has been resolved. +1 to the comment on using something like expo-file-system to read local files. Feel free to leave a comment/file a new issue if this is still unresolved.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>