<bug id='2978' author='shiyingZhang90' open_date='2020-03-27T18:23:29Z' closed_time='2020-04-23T22:55:12Z'>
	<summary>'conv2dDerInput' kernel may not be implemented yet in the wasm backend.</summary>
	<description>
To get help from the community, we encourage using Stack Overflow and the &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/tensorflow.js&gt;tensorflow.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;TensorFlow.js version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

"@tensorflow/tfjs": "^1.5.2",
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Browser version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Chrome: Version 80.0.3987.106 (Official Build) (64-bit)
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I try to use hand pose and face mesh model in same javascript, so I write hand pose code in to the demo code of face mesh. Yet, I won't get any hand pose result since I get the error "Error: 'conv2dDerInput' not yet implemented or not found in the registry. Did you forget to import the kernel?"
I'm wondering whether it's due to face mesh is using wasm backend and conv2dDerInput is not implemented there yet? Can this be a feature request? Or how should I merge face mesh and hand pose together?
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Code to reproduce the bug / link to feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please refer to my modified demo code in face mesh -- &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/shiyingZhang90/chatroulette/blob/conv2dDerInput/src/components/facemesh_index.js&gt;https://github.com/shiyingZhang90/chatroulette/blob/conv2dDerInput/src/components/facemesh_index.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

you can reproduce it by just replace index.js in facemesh demo to this code. Thanks
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='shiyingZhang90' date='2020-04-02T22:59:24Z'>
		I have this same issue with my custom models not being able to run on the WASM backend
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='shiyingZhang90' date='2020-04-23T22:55:12Z'>
		There is already issue opened to track missing kernel &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/2822&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , will close this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='shiyingZhang90' date='2020-04-24T03:49:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rthadur&gt;@rthadur&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 That &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/2822&gt;issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is not for missing kernels, its for tracking the work we are doing around modularising existing kernels and ops.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='shiyingZhang90' date='2020-08-04T18:51:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

can you please guide me when can you fix this conv2dDerInput issue? (Really appreciate your support and fix here).
(I would believe this issue happening in tfjs-core.js file).
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='shiyingZhang90' date='2020-08-06T15:49:37Z'>
		Could you make a new issue detailing your tfjs, tfjs-backend-wasm version and steps to reproduce? We've added quite a few kernels in wasm since this issue was filed including Conv2DBackpropInput (the updated name for this kernel), so i'd make sure you are on the latest version.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>