<bug id='3885' author='piecemakerz' open_date='2020-09-06T04:08:07Z' closed_time='2020-10-26T18:46:21Z'>
	<summary>tfjs-react-native: Error ‘func is not a function’</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;TensorFlow.js version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

"@tensorflow/tfjs": "^2.3.0"
"@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native": "^0.3.0"
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Describe the problem or feature request&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Hi. I'm trying to run tfjs-react-native project &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/blob/master/tfjs-react-native/integration_rn59/components/webcam/realtime_demo.tsx&gt;realtime_demo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with my android smartphone, but I'm stuck with TensorCamera.
My project directory is &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/piecemakerz/tfjs-example&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and if you need more files to inspect error just ask. The error I’m getting is this.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22445243/92317932-f65bb580-f040-11ea-9448-c5874a1296ec.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

When I debugged my project, I found out that when TensorCamera triggers onReady and calls handleImageTensorReady, the first argument of handleImageTensorReady - which is images - are not passed properly thus undefined. That's why my code gets stuck when const imageTensor = images.next().value; is called.
I'm using bare workflow with react-native-unimodules attached manually, but just to check I also tried using &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri/tfjs-expo-managed-example&gt;expo-managed-example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. It throws the same  error.
What is causing this problem? Is it because the testing device I'm using too old to run tensorflow modules? Plz help.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;ps1.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm sure this error is not related to loading tensorflow models (blazeface, posenet) because when I comment out all model-related codes from the demo project, I still get same func is not a function error.
I'm sure TensorCamera is the problem because when I changed TensorCamera to ordinary Camera module from "expo-camera", no error occurred.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;ps2.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I've borrowed Galazy S20 from one of my friends and test the project, and I got the some error. The problem was not with smartphone itself.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-07T04:09:21Z'>
		After days of research, I found out it was problem with version. In my project where error occurred, I just installed packages using yarn, so I used "@tensorflow/tfjs": "^2.3.0" and     "@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native": "^0.3.0".
When I changed my module dependencies (in package.json) as listed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/blob/master/tfjs-react-native/integration_rn59/package.json&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, finally everything started to work correctly.
I'm kind of beginner to react-native, so I don't know which modules resulted crush exactly. Maybe most recent version of tfjs-react-native broke capabilities with some libraries. Hope Amazing contributers of this repo finds out error soon and fit it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-09T16:28:15Z'>
		Same problem over here - how to fix this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-09T16:31:23Z'>
		Same for me, the  TensorCamera component does not render properly and give the error described above.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    "@tensorflow/tfjs": "^2.3.0",
    "@tensorflow/tfjs-automl": "^1.0.0",
    "@tensorflow/tfjs-react-native": "^0.3.0",
    "expo-av": "^8.4.0",
    "expo-camera": "^8.3.1",
    "expo-gl": "^8.4.0",
    "expo-gl-cpp": "^8.4.0",
    "expo-image-manipulator": "^8.2.1",
    "expo-permissions": "^9.1.0",
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-14T09:40:31Z'>
		I had the same issue then I upgraded tf-backend-webgl and it worked.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-14T13:40:17Z'>
		I think we have a bug in 2.3.0, so I would suggest downgrading to an earlier version until our next release is out (should be this week).
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-14T13:52:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the quick info, we are working around this issue for now, looking forward to the bugfix release
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-20T22:41:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 were you referring to the recent 2.4.0 release? Unfortunately just updating tfjs from 2.3.0 to 2.4.0 did not fix this for me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-28T09:57:41Z'>
		Having the same issue. Interestingly, upgrading to tfjs 2.4.0 and to the newest expo-camera, expo-gl and expo-gl-cpp packages solved the issue for a while, but then I had the laptop shutdown while the react native server was running, restarted the laptop, built the app again and the issue returned.
It's a far fetch correlation and I've tried deleting node modules folder and cleaning up android builds thinking something got corrupted, but to no avail.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-09-29T14:28:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Snupas&gt;@Snupas&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rohail0&gt;@rohail0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  or anyone else still seeing this, would you be able to post a link to a minimal reproduction of this as a github repo (using 2.4.0)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-06T15:01:13Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed in 7 dyas if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-07T15:12:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tafsiri&gt;@tafsiri&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sorry for the delay, forked the repo to try to expose this on the test integration_rn59 app. All I did was update most of the libraries to newer versions. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rohail0/tfjs/tree/bug-func-is-not-function/tfjs-react-native/integration_rn59&gt;https://github.com/rohail0/tfjs/tree/bug-func-is-not-function/tfjs-react-native/integration_rn59&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Also, as a note, I've only tested this on Android so that's the only one I've updated in that branch.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-09T15:58:30Z'>
		This should be fixed in the just released 0.4.0. Thanks for reporting and please let us know if this doesn't resolve the issue for you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-19T18:02:17Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed in 7 dyas if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-26T18:46:20Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please @mention us if this needs more attention.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='piecemakerz' date='2020-10-26T18:46:22Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/3885&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/3885&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>