<bug id='3961' author='HemantKumar01' open_date='2020-09-23T10:45:19Z' closed_time='2020-10-22T17:02:19Z'>
	<summary>bodyPix not working even a little bit correct</summary>
	<description>
Please make sure that this is a bug. As per our
GitHub Policy,
we only address

System information

Have I written custom code (as opposed to using a stock example script provided in TensorFlow.js):no
OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04):windows 7 ultimate i7 36000 intel hd built in graphics
Mobile device (e.g. iPhone 8, Pixel 2, Samsung Galaxy) if the issue happens on mobile device:
TensorFlow.js installed from (npm or script link):npm install @tensorflow/tfjs
TensorFlow.js version (use command below):
Browser version:chrome 85.0
Tensorflow.js Converter Version: ^2

Describe the current behavior
I am using bodypix in node.js using electron-framework. I am using simple example given on github with this backend.
It is not detecting any human on any simple video I have tried. If I reduce the segmentation threshold  then also it is detecting completely wrong(walls in the video). However once through script tag(only once in 10 tries) it has detected humans exactly right with a console message of "hello seems that you are trying node. Try installing...."
Describe the expected behavior
It should simply detect humans as in the demo site using webcam
Standalone code to reproduce the issue
You can reproduce the problem by loading a video, drawing it to a canvas on video play per second and then using bodypix on the canvas to output mask data to another canvas
Other info / logs If including tracebacks, please include the full
traceback. Large logs and files should be attached.
Sometimes give vertex and shader not linked(something else like this) error. Once it worked with the same settings giving a console message starting with hello, looks like you are using node.... other times no error
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-09-23T17:22:00Z'>
		@HemantKumarProgrammer we do not have Windows machine to reproduce the error , I tried on my Mac and could not reproduce, It is working as expected.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-09-24T02:09:57Z'>
		
@HemantKumarProgrammer we do not have Windows machine to reproduce the error , I tried on my Mac and could not reproduce, It is working as expected.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rthadur&gt;@rthadur&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I dont know but even using script tag, it is not working. Once it worked exactly the right way. Maybe it is a server problem. Or I don't have a gpu, just inbuilt native Intel hd graphics, is it a problem.
I have @tensorflow/tfjs , @tensorflow/tfjs-node,
@tensorflow/tfjs-convertor,@tensorflow/tfjs -core installed along with bodypix. However while installing tfjs-node it is trying to install some other build tools which were not installed due to an error,saying latest visual studio needed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-01T02:34:18Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed in 7 dyas if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-01T04:19:11Z'>
		Is a GPU must for using tensorflow bodypix? Then it may be the reason for this issue because I dont have a gpu, just inbuilt intel hd graphics , which is not very good
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-08T05:01:14Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed in 7 dyas if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-08T15:32:32Z'>
		Just writing this to avoid being stalled.
Progress: thinking to try again, maybe after 10-15 days
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-15T16:12:17Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed in 7 dyas if no further activity occurs. Thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-22T17:02:18Z'>
		Closing as stale. Please @mention us if this needs more attention.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='HemantKumar01' date='2020-10-22T17:02:21Z'>
		Are you satisfied with the resolution of your issue?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=Yes&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/3961&gt;Yes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfaP12TRhd9xSxjXZjcZFNXPGk4kc1-qMdv3gc6bEP90vY1ew/viewform?entry.85265664=No&amp;entry.2137816233=https://github.com/tensorflow/tfjs/issues/3961&gt;No&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>