<bug id='5206' author='superhez' open_date='2018-08-10T04:11:07Z' closed_time='2019-03-01T23:20:58Z'>
	<summary>Why does learning speed gradually drop?</summary>
	<description>
In my experiments, learning speed started from around 28 s/epoch and gradually dropped from then on. At the time of 3000 epochs, it's already slower than 60 s/epoch. Same phenomenon had happened in another totally different task. Could anybody tell me the reason? Appreciate for help.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='superhez' date='2018-08-13T08:45:47Z'>
		Related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chainer/chainer/issues/2554&gt;#2554&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='superhez' date='2018-08-13T08:46:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/superhez&gt;@superhez&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Does it happen on GPU? or it's happening with CPU?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='superhez' date='2018-08-14T12:18:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mitmul&gt;@mitmul&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Appreciate for your help. The problem happens on a GPU platform (GTX1080Ti x1, CPU: Xeon E5-2640 v4 x2, 32GB memory, 256GB SSD). Both tasks meet the same problem,. One is training a CNN model for super-resolution, another is training a complete different model for semantic segmentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='superhez' date='2018-08-20T08:47:37Z'>
		Thanks for the issue report. What version of Chainer and CuPy are you using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='superhez' date='2018-08-28T00:59:36Z'>
		Sorry for my late response.  The current versions are: chainer 3.5.0, cupy 2.5.0. ,but similar trouble also happened when I used chainer 1.23.0 long ago. Both are on GPU platforms.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='superhez' date='2018-12-18T22:41:59Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed after 30 days if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='superhez' date='2019-01-30T21:36:26Z'>
		This issue is closed as announced. Feel free to re-open it if needed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='superhez' date='2019-03-01T23:20:54Z'>
		This issue is closed as announced. Feel free to re-open it if needed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>