<bug id='12923' author='YKritet' open_date='2019-06-06T11:38:37Z' closed_time='2019-06-10T12:52:32Z'>
	<summary>Unable to release GPU memory after training a model (OOM)</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
On a Google Colab notebook with keras(2.2.4) and tensorflow(1.13.1) as a backend, I am trying to tune a CNN, I use a simple and basic table of hyper-parameters and run my tests in a set of loops.
My problem is that I can't free the GPU memory after each iteration and Keras doesn't seem to be able to release GPU memory automatically. So every time I get a Ressource Exhausted : Out Of Memory (OOM)
I did some digging up and run into this function that reassembles different solutions that have been suggested to solve this problem (didn't work for me though) :
def reset_keras():
    sess = get_session()
    clear_session()
    sess.close()
    sess = get_session()

    try:
        del model # this is from global space - change this as you need
    except:
        pass

    print(gc.collect()) # if it's done something you should see a number being outputted

    # use the same config as you used to create the session
    config = tf.ConfigProto()
    config.gpu_options.per_process_gpu_memory_fraction = 1
    config.gpu_options.visible_device_list = "0"
    set_session(tf.Session(config=config))
The only thing that i didn't fully grasp is the "same config as you used to create your model " since with Keras we don't chose explicitly a certain configuration. I get by for one iteration, some times two, but I can't go beyond. I already tried to change the batch_size and for the moment I am unable to afford for a machine with higher performances.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='YKritet' date='2019-06-06T17:39:45Z'>
		Please fill the issue template &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keras-team/keras/issues/new/choose&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Could you update them if they are relevant in your case, or leave them as N/A?  Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='YKritet' date='2019-06-10T07:27:45Z'>
		Done! follow the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keras-team/keras/issues/12929&gt;link&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='YKritet' date='2019-06-10T12:52:32Z'>
		Thanks for filling the template in the new issue. I am closing this issue here as this is duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keras-team/keras/issues/12929&gt;#12929&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Thanks
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>