<bug id='195' author='jorgemf' open_date='2018-10-03T23:06:50Z' closed_time='2018-10-09T12:08:16Z'>
	<summary>Error uploading a file with the notebook interface</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When trying to upload a file in a notebook nothing happens.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Start a notebook and try to upload a new file. Nothing happens.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The file should be uploaded into the notebook.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-07T20:19:30Z'>
		The error message is misleading, you cannot upload files while a notebook is running, you need to stop the notebook before uploading.
I am not sure why the server is not sending the correct error message anymore.
I updated the error message to indicate that either the user does not have write access or a notebook is currently running.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-08T07:15:39Z'>
		I am not talking about the polyaxon-cli, but the notebook interface. I can navigate, create files but not uploading new files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-08T10:48:33Z'>
		I think you are seeing a similar issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/polyaxon/polyaxon/issues/194&gt;#194&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that you have with the cli for large files, I also think it is related to this &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/polyaxon/polyaxon/issues/200&gt;#200&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
It was a bit hard to debug, but it was related to some ingress annotations. I just tested the fix for both uploading very large code files and uploading with the notebook interface and they both work now. The fix will be released today.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-08T12:16:56Z'>
		I tried with small files too. So not sure. I will test it again with the new version and update you with the results. If it is working I will close the issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-08T13:09:31Z'>
		Doing some more tests before releasing, as the release has a data migration, I will update this issue once the new version is released.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-08T13:38:17Z'>
		You are right, you are probably having a different issue, I was able to upload a file with the current version. So I think this issue is not related to the other upload issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-09T12:08:16Z'>
		Seems it is working now with the new version
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>