<bug id='215' author='jorgemf' open_date='2018-10-18T09:50:00Z' closed_time='2018-11-01T14:43:37Z'>
	<summary>Resume experiments doesn't work in finished experiment groups</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When all the experiments of an experiment group have finished, none of the experiments can be resumed. The status of the "new experiments" stay as created.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Create a group of experiments and wait until all the experiments have finished
Try to resume any of the experiments

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

New experiments should be created and executed , currently they are only created.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T09:55:30Z'>
		Can you provide what platform version are you running?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T10:17:19Z'>
		The latest: 0.2.8
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T10:19:01Z'>
		What experiment group type are you running can you put in the spec for the hptuning section?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T10:20:02Z'>
		I am using matrix. My problem is with the command polyaxon experiment -xp XX resume -u -f xxxx
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T10:21:05Z'>
		I know, but I need to know first why the group is not starting the experiment, and then I will check the resume command after.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-18T10:27:58Z'>
		It might be related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/polyaxon/polyaxon/issues/211&gt;#211&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 but resume always fails in a group with all the experiments inside the group finished (I haven't tested with failed experiments, it might happen to). I also tested in 0.2.7 and it also happens there
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='jorgemf' date='2018-10-26T13:36:13Z'>
		Yes you are right, it does not work, I know what's the issue, and I will try to fix it ASAP, thanks for reporting.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='jorgemf' date='2018-11-01T14:43:36Z'>
		Feel fee to reopen, it should be possible to do this operation starting from next release 0.3.0.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>