<bug id='281' author='sakinaljana' open_date='2018-11-30T09:16:38Z' closed_time='2018-11-30T15:36:30Z'>
	<summary>Got empty files when downloading experiment outputs</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Here's the bug, you want to download outputs coming from specific experiment (Let's named it as exp#2), however the downloaded file is contain nothing (it's expected to have some model files).
To give you context, this experiment is resumed from previous experiment (Let's named it as exp#1) where the last state is failed.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I found the bug using following steps

I'm running exp#1 (original experiment) which yield several ML models as the outputs.
After long running, exp#1 got failed.
I'm trying to resume the experiment which trigger new experiment (exp#2) &lt;-- is it expected to spawn new experiment instead using the same experiment?
Finally, the exp#2 job is done. I'm trying to download outputs from exp#2 to explore the model output offline. Unfortunately, i got empty downloaded files.
When trying download output from original experiment (exp#1), I'm able to download the output successfully (contains some ML models).

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Refer to To Reproduce steps, during step 4, it should download files contain several ML models instead empty files.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Personal Notes&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I make following hypothesis for this bug:

since resumed experiment create new experiment but not new output dir, it will refer to the old output dir.
However, when click download output, it'll refer to the new output dir, hence will download empty files.

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm using the latest polyaxon version (0.3.3) run on top of GKE.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sakinaljana' date='2018-11-30T15:36:29Z'>
		This is fixed and will be part of next release 0.3.4.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sakinaljana' date='2019-01-24T07:59:41Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Want to follow up this. just to be sure, When we resume the experiment, how we treat the output:

will it copy the output from resumed experiment to the new experiment? or
The new experiment will refer to the output from old (resumed) experiment?

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sakinaljana' date='2019-01-24T09:55:55Z'>
		resume appends outputs to the old experiment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sakinaljana' date='2019-03-05T04:29:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I still have the same issue with 0.4.1. We use GCS for the outputs storage. Do you think if the issue ptentially occurs with GCS?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sakinaljana' date='2019-03-05T08:55:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yu-iskw&gt;@yu-iskw&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes cloud storages don't have these options yet, you can file a new issue to track the progress on that.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>