<bug id='412' author='martmull' open_date='2019-03-28T14:07:07Z' closed_time='2019-03-29T12:45:29Z'>
	<summary>Encountering issue to pull private docker image from Dockerhub</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Unclear documentation&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Hello,
Polyaxon is working fine when It pulls a public docker image stored on Dockerhub.
However, it fails when it tries to pull it from a private repository on Dockerhub.
I followed &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/polyaxon/polyaxon/blob/master/docs/configuration/private-registries.md&gt;this documentation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and I reinstalled Polyaxon adding the Dockerhub credentials in the  file such as:
privateRegistries:
  - host: "https://registry-1.docker.io/v2/"
    user: "&lt;USER_ID&gt;"
    password: "&lt;PASSWORD&gt;"
but I can't make it work. It shows me this error:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/29927851/55164677-61c30780-516c-11e9-8930-cbda39806411.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I also tried using this registry "&lt;denchmark-link:https://index.docker.io/v1/&gt;https://index.docker.io/v1/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
", with and without the protocol, I always encounter the same issue.
Do you have any idea why Polyaxon cannot access the private docker image? Or am I missing something?
Thank you very much,
and by the way, Polyaxon is awesome!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='martmull' date='2019-03-28T14:10:39Z'>
		I will check/reply with instruction later today or tomorrow, but I could not help not commenting on the styles. you can hard refresh your browser's tab to get latest js/css: ctr+shift+r or cmd+shift+r.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='martmull' date='2019-03-28T14:16:48Z'>
		
you can hard refresh your browser's tab to get latest js/css: ctr+shift+r or cmd+shift+r.

done
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='martmull' date='2019-03-28T14:17:13Z'>
		
I will check/reply with instruction later today or tomorrow

Thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='martmull' date='2019-03-29T12:45:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martmull&gt;@martmull&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this is a bug or rather a regression from the docker client. I was able to reproduce it, I also made a fix, it will be part of the next release v0.4.3 coming end of this week/early next week.
Thanks for reporting 👍
N.B. the right way to reference docker hub registry is https://index.docker.io/v1/. I will probably make a separate integrations section for docker hub to make it clear for future references.
Closing the issue since a fix was already made.
UPDATE: new section specific to dockerhub &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.polyaxon.com/integrations/dockerhub/&gt;https://docs.polyaxon.com/integrations/dockerhub/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='martmull' date='2019-03-30T14:50:58Z'>
		Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>