<bug id='422' author='lgeiger' open_date='2019-04-08T10:25:10Z' closed_time='2019-05-22T11:41:30Z'>
	<summary>Support latest version of jupyter lab</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Feature motivation&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It would be great to be able to run the latest version of Jupyter Lab on Polyaxon.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Feature description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

As noted in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/polyaxon/polyaxon/issues/310#issuecomment-464721403&gt;#310 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 currently only Jupyter Lab version  is supported. This is due to an issue which prevents Jupyter Lab from loading the correct CSS file.  is now quite old, and there are already alpha releases for version 1.0.0 available, so it would be great to support the latest versions too.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-08T13:37:31Z'>
		It should work if the bug is fixed, you jut need to update your Polyaxonfile to install the version you want to use.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-08T13:42:42Z'>
		
It should work if the bug is fixed

Sorry for the confusion. I tried it yesterday with the latest version and the bug is still present. Or am I missing something?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-08T14:30:07Z'>
		Can you share your Polyaxonfile to reproduce the bug.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-08T14:48:00Z'>
		
Can you share your Polyaxonfile to reproduce the bug.

If I use this file:
version: 1

kind: notebook
backend: lab

build:
  image: python:3.7-slim
  build_steps:
    - pip install jupyterlab --no-cache-dir
Jupyter Lab will look like this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13285808/55733205-55b13280-5a15-11e9-987f-9c22e4e49f4e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Downgrading to Jupyter Lab version 0.33.12 solves the CSS issue.
Thanks for the help! Polyaxon has been a huge improvement to our deep learning workflow. Keep up the great work!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-08T16:01:39Z'>
		I just tried with latest release candidate and it seems the issue is still there, not sure why.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jupyterlab/jupyterlab/issues/4662&gt;jupyterlab/jupyterlab#4662&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-26T13:24:21Z'>
		The error seems to come from the css path. css loads properly when 'local' is removed in the css path.
Hope it helps.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45968685/56810655-1f5a1c80-6837-11e9-8a3d-7c0800a6713b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45968685/56810656-1f5a1c80-6837-11e9-8569-70115a1f9731.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-26T14:24:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Derka0&gt;@Derka0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did you change the local in browser or did you manage to update Polyaxon to handle that? A PR would be more than welcome.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-26T14:45:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Unfortunately I changed the path in the browser, I'll do a PR as soon as I have some time
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='lgeiger' date='2019-04-30T11:48:47Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have been looking at the error, I coudn't quite locate it.
It seems like that a discrepancy occurs between polyaxon notebook spawner and Jupyter Lab when a notebook is created. The Jupyter Lab "themes_url" variable that contain the path to the css variable seems wrong.
Do you have any hint to direct me towards where this can occur?
Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='lgeiger' date='2019-05-03T10:23:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Derka0&gt;@Derka0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 unfortunately I have no idea why that path is causing an issue, I will also need to do a deep-dive to explore a possible solution.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='lgeiger' date='2019-05-07T13:21:49Z'>
		It seems that the introduction of the light/dark following the version 0.33 creates the problem. I hope it helps
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='lgeiger' date='2019-05-22T11:41:30Z'>
		There's an issue in the recent versions of jupyterlab for serving and detecting base paths in the IThemesManager plugin, it does not handle : for parsing paths, an issue was submitted.
Since this is a blocker for serving any version of JupyterLab, a fix/workaround is made in Polyaxon until that issue is fixed.
Closing this issue for now, the fix will be part of the v0.5 release.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>