<bug id='768' author='dasturge' open_date='2020-05-12T21:13:36Z' closed_time='2020-05-12T21:35:00Z'>
	<summary>polyaxonfile: input defaults override hptuning fields</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

if a parameter is included both an input and as a part of the hptuning matrix if appears to ignore the search space and take on the default input value.  The behavior is not obvious and doesn't seem to have a practical use case.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

here's an example running over a "search_param" field.  Though the linspace is from 0.0 to 0.2, the job will batch 9 instances with search_param=0.1
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;inputs:
  - {name: search_param, type: float, is_optional: True, default: 0.1}
  - {name: learning_rate, type: float, is_optional: True, default: 0.001}

hptuning:
  concurrency: 3
  matrix:
    search_param:
      linspace: 0.0:0.2:9

params:
  learning_rate: 0.001

run:
  cmd:  python main_pipeline.py \
          --search-param={{ search_param }} \
          --learning-rate={{ learning_rate }} \

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The hptuning should override default values of the inputs, or, the polyaxonfile should not pass validity checks for conflicting hptuning matrix and input fields and should crash.  In any case there shouldn't be a "grid search" over a constant.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

batching from polyaxon-cli on Ubuntu 16.04 to a kubernetes cluster.  I can look up more information if this seems to be an environment specific bug.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dasturge' date='2020-05-12T21:17:14Z'>
		This is a bug, I will try to see if I can reproduce in v1 otherwise I will close the issue as fixed in v1.
Thank you for reporting.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dasturge' date='2020-05-12T21:35:00Z'>
		Thanks for opening this issue, I just tested the example and it's actually working as expected in latest version v1.0.89.
v1.1 will be available to everyone during this month with several fixes including this one. Closing the issue for now.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>