<bug id='883' author='lgeiger' open_date='2020-07-06T10:55:21Z' closed_time='2020-07-06T12:38:18Z'>
	<summary>Typo in CLI command of "New Project" tip</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When creating a new project from the UI, Polyaxon shows the following dialog:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13285808/86585954-786b2780-bf87-11ea-8fe9-441972533dac.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It recommends to run polyaxon project create -h for more information, but the command fails with:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ polyaxon project create -h
Usage: polyaxon project create [OPTIONS]
Try "polyaxon project create --help" for help.

Error: no such option: -h
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Try to run polyaxon project create -h as mentioned in the tip.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The tip should recommend using polyaxon project create --help which will give the desired output.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Polyaxon CE v1.1.0
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mouradmourafiq&gt;@mouradmourafiq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I would've made a PR to fix this typo, but I couldn't find the UI code of Polyaxon. Is the UI currently not open-source or am I just missing something?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lgeiger' date='2020-07-06T11:56:21Z'>
		Should be fixed for today's release 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lgeiger' date='2020-07-06T12:37:42Z'>
		
@mouradmourafiq I would've made a PR to fix this typo, but I couldn't find the UI code of Polyaxon. Is the UI currently not open-source or am I just missing something?

The UI is currently a free non open-source project, it's used for both products, not sure when it will be possible to make it as an installable for the commercial product, so we can open-source the core. For now we removed all code duplication.
For users who want a 100% open-source  project, they need to turn-off the flag uiEnabled: false
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lgeiger' date='2020-07-06T12:49:19Z'>
		Sounds good, I was just wondering whether I missed something.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lgeiger' date='2020-07-06T12:51:04Z'>
		The wording in the docs has been changed as well in several places prior to the v1.1 release to something like this Polyaxon CE is our free community edition based on Polyaxon open-source tools
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>