<bug id='1875' author='tailaiw' open_date='2020-09-08T20:02:38Z' closed_time='2020-11-23T20:10:15Z'>
	<summary>container_log_level does not work in TensorFlow estimator</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
Parameter container_log_level does not work in TensorFlow estimator
To reproduce
I have a TensorFlow estimator built roughly as follows
import logging
from sagemaker.tensorflow import TensorFlow
estimator = TensorFlow(
        sagemaker_session=sagemaker_session,
        entry_point="my_entry_point.py",
        source_dir=my_source_dir,
        role=my_role,
        instance_count=1,
        instance_type="ml.p3.2xlarge",    
        framework_version="2.1",
        py_version="py3",
        checkpoint_s3_uri=my_checkpoint_s3_uri,
        container_log_level=logging.WARNING)
I expect now logs lower than WARNING will be included in the training job logs. However, a lot of INFO level logs are observed. Particularly, a lot of INFO logs related to frequent checkpoint uploading (from instance to S3) are observed, which makes the entire log super long. I tried logging.ERROR and no luck either.
Expected behavior
No log except WARNING and ERROR level ones should be observed.

If applicable, add screenshots or logs to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/29800495/92522270-1bd4f480-f1e4-11ea-827c-1c33934a8d9e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

System information
A description of your system. Please provide:

SageMaker Python SDK version: 2.5.1
Framework name (eg. PyTorch) or algorithm (eg. KMeans): TensorFlow
Framework version: 2.1
Python version: 3.7
CPU or GPU: GPU
Custom Docker image (Y/N): N

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tailaiw' date='2020-09-20T22:48:13Z'>
		logger config in sagemaker-training-toolkit does not seem to be configured correctly with log levels: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aws/sagemaker-training-toolkit/blob/master/src/sagemaker_training/logging_config.py#L39&gt;https://github.com/aws/sagemaker-training-toolkit/blob/master/src/sagemaker_training/logging_config.py#L39&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

With the above logic, as long as logging level &gt;= logging.INFO, boto3 and s3transfer will ALWAYS have logging.INFO and botocore will always have logging.WARN.
We should pass the log_level as it is to training-toolkit's logger configure
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tailaiw' date='2020-11-23T20:10:15Z'>
		Fix is merged. Closing the issue.  Feel free to reopen if the problem still persists.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>