<bug id='1410' author='berlino' open_date='2020-10-23T14:56:48Z' closed_time='2020-10-28T10:05:40Z'>
	<summary>(Web Interface) Aggregation of bar chart does not work</summary>
	<description>
hi, there:
I found that the aggregation option of bar chart seems not work for me. Below is a screenshot
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2403596/97018943-a2048a80-1547-11eb-972d-003d506036e3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Changing Agg to mean/min/max does not make any difference. I guess wandb is only loading the metric from the final step. But in some cases (my previous plots weeks ago), the option worked, i.e., doing aggregation across steps.
I do have the metric from different runs, and the line plot is working properly, see below
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2403596/97019183-eb54da00-1547-11eb-84b0-b470e1deab0b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='berlino' date='2020-10-23T14:56:50Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.87. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='berlino' date='2020-10-23T22:15:30Z'>
		Hi there, it looks like grouping isn't on for these bar charts. The aggregation works across summary metrics, so summary values from multiple different runs. It doesn't work for aggregating values across a time series for a metric from a single run. Is that what you were expecting?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='berlino' date='2020-10-24T11:04:34Z'>
		Hi, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cvphelps&gt;@cvphelps&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the response!
Yes, I'm expecting aggregating across a time series from a single run. Is there anyway I can do this? I guess it would be  a common function that we need to select a best step/checkpoint from a single run.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='berlino' date='2020-10-28T10:05:40Z'>
		I figured it out that I need to write the info using wandb.run.summary.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>