<bug id='323' author='cpoptic' open_date='2019-04-30T15:29:07Z' closed_time='2019-05-18T17:28:27Z'>
	<summary>trying to see model Visualizations under the web portal:  "No Access .  You do not have permission to view this page."</summary>
	<description>

Weights and Biases version:
Python version:
Operating System:

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

under https://app.wandb.ai  \ 
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What I Did&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Clicking on the "Visualizations" pane under "Project Workspace" no longer lets me see the visualizations that I could two weeks ago. What changed?  Why can I not see the visualizations?

No Access .  You do not have permission to view this page.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T15:29:10Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.52. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T15:36:47Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cpoptic&gt;@cpoptic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 what project are you trying to access?  Can you add a link to the specific page you're seeing this on?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T15:47:34Z'>
		All of them, actually:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://app.wandb.ai/chris-poptic/olive-sentence-classification?workspace=user-chrispoptic&gt;https://app.wandb.ai/chris-poptic/olive-sentence-classification?workspace=user-chrispoptic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://app.wandb.ai/chris-poptic/free-metrics-project?workspace=user-chrispoptic&gt;https://app.wandb.ai/chris-poptic/free-metrics-project?workspace=user-chrispoptic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I can see the table of Runs, but the Visualizations are blocked. Weird.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T15:55:28Z'>
		Weird, try going to &lt;denchmark-link:https://app.wandb.ai/logout&gt;https://app.wandb.ai/logout&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 then login again.  The olive-sentence-classification project doesn't have any metrics to visualize, but I was able to visualize on free-metrics-projects.  Can you add a screenshot of the error if you see it again?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T17:25:09Z'>
		So I logged out and logged back in, and all is fine; visualizations are back.
However, now, when I try to add a WandB param in Jupyter Lab notebook, config.embedding_configuration = document_pooled_embeddings
it hangs that cell indefinitely.  Any idea why?
I am forced to halt the Jupyter kernel.  Oddly, when I reconnect to the kernel after the keyboard interrupt, the config is showing that the param was actually correctly added to config.  For example:
config.keys()   shows:
odict_keys(['embedding_configuration'])
I just don't understand why trying to add a config param causes Jupyter to freeze.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T18:36:19Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cpoptic&gt;@cpoptic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it's sounds like a bug with our jupyter integration.  Try setting config when you call init, i.e. .  I'll look into the jupyter issue and track progress in the other issue you filed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T19:47:34Z'>
		Another aspect of this Jupyter integration bug I noticed:  When I have several lines declaring a config variable in the same cell and execute that cell, the kernel hangs of course.  But after interrupting it and running config.keys(), it will have successfully added the first line of that cell to the config variable, but not the subsequent ones.  It only adds the first.  So for example, if the cell contains:
config.mini_batch_size = 32
config.anneal_factor = 0.5
config.patience = 5
config.max_epochs = 1000
only the the config.mini_batch_size variable will be added to config.  Strange behavior.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='cpoptic' date='2019-04-30T20:33:46Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vanpelt&gt;@vanpelt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , thanks, but I was definitely using the two-step process on a project in a Jupyter Lab notebook a few weeks ago, where you define    .  and then in the next cell add each hyperparam to be tracked with  . e.g. 
But frustratingly, today this procedure no longer appears to work.
So I don't think that's the solution.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='cpoptic' date='2019-05-01T03:56:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cpoptic&gt;@cpoptic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 totally agree, there was a regression that was introduced, it's not a long term fix.  We'll get a fix out likely early next week, until then hopefully the single line solution can be a bandaid.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='cpoptic' date='2019-05-01T18:19:07Z'>
		Ok, yeah the workaround I discovered was:

putting each config.hyperparam declaration in a separate Jupyter cell,
executing that cell,
the notebook freezes,
stopping the kernel,
restarting the kernel,
and then executing the next cell.

Then repeating this process for each of the ~dozen config params, which is clearly suboptimal, but it works.
I'm more confused what changed recently in the WandB/Jupyter notebook interface, as this bug definitely did not exist a few weeks ago.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>