<bug id='340' author='Microsheep' open_date='2019-05-20T14:53:58Z' closed_time='2020-11-29T13:34:28Z'>
	<summary>Default debug.log path permission problems on servers</summary>
	<description>

Weights and Biases version: 0.8.0
Python version: 3.7
Operating System: ubuntu 18.04

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Default debug.log path might have permission problems on servers.
If two different users are using wandb on the same server, the default log location might collide and produce a permission problem which requires the first user or admin to resolve this.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What I Did&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;wandb login XXX

wandb: ERROR Failed to set up logging: [Errno 13] Permission denied: '/tmp/wandb-debug.log'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I think this can easily be avoided if default debug.log path includes a timestamp
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wandb/client/blob/master/wandb/__init__.py#L66&gt;https://github.com/wandb/client/blob/master/wandb/__init__.py#L66&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

For example
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;cur_time = datetime.now().strftime("%Y%m%d-%H%M%S")
GLOBAL_LOG_FNAME = os.path.join(tempfile.gettempdir(), f"wandb-debug-{cur_time}.log")
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Could submit a PR if needed.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Microsheep' date='2019-05-20T14:54:01Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.82. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Microsheep' date='2019-05-20T17:17:33Z'>
		It should just overwrite the previous debug log.  It looks like your "/tmp" directory is not writable.  I can update the code to use tempfile.gettempdir() which should return a writable directory.  Until then you can specify a directory with WANDB_DIR=/home/username/tmp
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Microsheep' date='2019-05-20T18:21:20Z'>
		I think the problem is that another user using wandb had created the file '/tmp/wandb-debug.log' first.
As a second user, that file will not be writable.
tempfile.gettempdir() returns a writable dir, but os.path.join(tempfile.gettempdir(), 'wandb-debug.log') is not writable.
Adding the timestamp by default just makes it harder for users to collide.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Microsheep' date='2019-05-20T19:08:25Z'>
		I see, but it's at the cost of making it hard to find the debug log as well as keeping lots of debug logs hanging around.  I thought tempfile.gettempdir() would return a different directory for each user.  I suppose I could see if the file exists and use a different name if it does.  For your usecase, it seems like setting WANDB_DIR to something unique for each user would fix this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Microsheep' date='2020-11-26T14:24:09Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Microsheep&gt;@Microsheep&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 due to the inactivity of this thread it is only fair if we knew whether you have the fix for your solution by now. We would rather want this thread closed if the solution to your issues are met. Cheers 
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Microsheep' date='2020-11-29T13:34:28Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ariG23498&gt;@ariG23498&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I think we can close this issue for now.
To prevent collisions under /tmp/ for different users on shared servers, we have already adopted guidelines to set directories according to usernames.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;username = pwd.getpwuid(os.getuid()).pw_name
config.wandb_dir = f"/tmp/wandb_{username}/"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The original question mainly occurs when setting up the environment for the first time.
We opted to add the environment variable WANDB_DIR even for wandb login.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>