<bug id='468' author='yaroslavvb' open_date='2019-08-02T14:38:17Z' closed_time='2020-12-02T03:22:10Z'>
	<summary>wandb.config is None sometimes</summary>
	<description>
I'm launching 16 processes on 2 machines through mpirun and wandb.config is None for 14 of these processes which crashes wandb.config ... = ... lines
I got around this crash by adding checks like below
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;if wandb.confg is not None:
  wandb.config['key'] = ...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Surprisingly that worked, so I'm confused why wandb.config would be None but leave the rest of the logging infrastructure functional.
Here are all 16 runs -- &lt;denchmark-link:https://app.wandb.ai/yaroslavvb/imagenet18/groups/enable_efa_spawn-i9d&gt;https://app.wandb.ai/yaroslavvb/imagenet18/groups/enable_efa_spawn-i9d&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Not sure if related, but this co-occurred with me changing the launching mode of additional data crunching processes to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cybertronai/imagenet18_/blob/6a423eb57a90a9c9c19d0043fb07f3120f0d7e6f/training/dataloader.py#L41&gt;spawn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yaroslavvb' date='2019-08-02T14:38:19Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.95. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yaroslavvb' date='2019-08-07T17:46:24Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yaroslavvb&gt;@yaroslavvb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'm about to push a new release that prints a better error message in this case.   will be uninitialized until  is called.  With my fix, you'll get an exception when attempting to set or access attributes on an uninitialized config object.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yaroslavvb' date='2019-08-07T17:48:43Z'>
		I could imagine a different approach where we just print a warning saying nothing will be saved until wandb.init is called.  I'm not a fan of this as it could lead to really unexpected behavior.  Was wandb.init being called in the spawned processes?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yaroslavvb' date='2019-08-14T15:43:44Z'>
		Yes, wandb init was being called in a spawned process. Wandb.config caching instead of hard crash is is a little more convenient and a little more bug-prone, don't really have an opinion which one is better
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yaroslavvb' date='2020-12-01T14:20:21Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yaroslavvb&gt;@yaroslavvb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Is this ticket still relevant?
Could you give this a go with the latest release of wandb?

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>