<bug id='554' author='psinger' open_date='2019-09-16T20:41:42Z' closed_time='2020-12-03T04:05:00Z'>
	<summary>wandb.log delayed</summary>
	<description>
I am running wandb.log({"loss":loss}, step=epoch) at the end of every epoch. However, the logs are delayed 1-2 epochs in each iteration. This means that I am seeing the logs for the first epoch only on the platform when the second or third epoch is finished. Unfortunately, after stopping the code the last epochs are then not in the logs and are missing.
Any ideas?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='psinger' date='2019-09-16T20:41:44Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.64. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='psinger' date='2019-09-16T21:02:59Z'>
		That is concerning, can you link a URL of a run where this is happening?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='psinger' date='2019-09-16T21:21:57Z'>
		I quickly made an example demonstrating this:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;for i in range(5):
    wandb.log({"loss": i}, step=i)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://app.wandb.ai/ph_singer/test/runs/folififw?workspace=user-ph_singer&gt;https://app.wandb.ai/ph_singer/test/runs/folififw?workspace=user-ph_singer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='psinger' date='2019-09-17T00:18:42Z'>
		Thank you for sample, I have reproduced this in a notebook environment and am working on a solution.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='psinger' date='2019-10-10T08:40:46Z'>
		I am also seeing the same issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='psinger' date='2019-10-10T11:02:09Z'>
		This is indeed a major bug to me that needs to be fixed asap. Any updates on it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='psinger' date='2019-10-10T23:03:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/psinger&gt;@psinger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/raubitsj&gt;@raubitsj&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is looking into this.  Apologies for the delay, we'll get a patch out ASAP.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='psinger' date='2019-10-11T17:59:53Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/psinger&gt;@psinger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vadapalliravikumar&gt;@vadapalliravikumar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the long term fix is a bit more involved but we better understand the underlying issue.  The problem is we use the  argument to decide when to push metrics to the server (only when it increases).  Unfortunately in jupyter we don't handle the final step properly and this also creates a delay in metrics being pushed until the step increases.  The quick fix is to not specify step and instead use the  argument if you need to rollup metrics in a single step.  i.e.
wandb.log({"acc": 0.5}, commit=False)
# Some other code
wandb.log({"val_acc": 0.6, "custom_step": 32})
Every time wandb.log is called without a step argument or with commit=False we increment an internal step counter and push the metrics to the server.  If you want to keep track of a different step counter you can pass it into log just like any other metric.  We then allow you to change the x-axis in the UI to any metrics you've logged that are monotonically increasing.
I know this is unfortunate.  We're working on a big overhaul of our backend that should address these issues and make for a cleaner api.  And again, apologies for not getting back to you sooner on this one.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='psinger' date='2020-05-02T12:13:04Z'>
		Hi, any updates on this? I seem to be running into the same issue (using wandb version 0.8.32)
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='psinger' date='2020-05-02T17:30:13Z'>
		We made some improvements to the jupyter integration in 0.8.35.  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/numpee&gt;@numpee&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you provide us with an example notebook exhibiting the behavour you're seeing?  I just created a &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/13yktq4kmYlbOQ7txvWYy04VO5hLV1DBY?usp=sharing&gt;colab&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that asserts all metrics are being logged in the simple case.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='psinger' date='2020-05-03T08:58:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vanpelt&gt;@vanpelt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Here's a simple code that I tried on my jupyter:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import wandb
wandb.init(project='rand_project')

# New cell:
i = 0
val = i * 2
wandb.log({'test': val}, step=i)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

When I run the last cell repeatedly while increasing the value of i (by 1), the log only appears after I've run a few extra increments - no matter how long I wait. I've attached a screenshot of my jupyter code &amp; output below:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/29429992/80909675-131b7000-8d65-11ea-9b8a-8b5b353ce5ac.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I've noticed a couple of weird things:

when printing the run.history(), only the steps that didn't display the "Upgrade wandb"  warning were logged.
The last log has step 3 with a logged value of 8, which seems to be a merged from i=3 and i=4? This is weird and it's not something that I've encountered when actually using wandb for my experiments.

So I understand that this thread is somewhat focused on jupyter, but I usually just run wandb through a python file. In previous versions (around October/November last year) I noticed that every single log was delayed by 1 step, and the final step never logged. Now, after upgrading to 0.8.32, it seems that although all steps are always logged, they always seem to be delayed, no matter how much time passes between the logging steps (my loggging steps are usually 5~15 minutes apart). While I feel that this is not an app-breaking bug, it is a slight nuisance (in an otherwise amazing app). Whenever I need instant feedback on my model's performance, I end up relying more on the terminal output than I do on the wandb client.
Again, not the biggest issue in the world, but definitely needs to be mentioned. I've just upgraded to 0.8.35, so I'll check again and see if anything has changed :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='psinger' date='2020-05-03T17:32:26Z'>
		Please try this again with 0.8.35 we made some big changes to the Jupyter integration that *should fix your issues.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='psinger' date='2020-12-03T04:05:00Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/numpee&gt;@numpee&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/psinger&gt;@psinger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

In the past year we've majorly reworked the CLI and UI for Weights &amp; Biases. We're closing issues older than 6 months. Please comment to reopen.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>