<bug id='562' author='alberduris' open_date='2019-09-19T07:28:39Z' closed_time='2020-12-03T04:08:04Z'>
	<summary>Can't save model, h5py returned error: Not JSON serializable</summary>
	<description>

Weights and Biases version: 0.8.10
Python version: 3.6.1
Operating System: Windows 10

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I was running a training script with wandb integration on Windows with the python train.py command instead of the required wand run python train.py (this is because while developing on Pycharm, the run option just executes that command).
I expect wandb to do nothing more than displaying the warning message:
wandb: ERROR To use wandb on Windows, you need to run the command "wandb run python &lt;your_train_script&gt;.py"
But instead more errors start to appear, as the mentioned in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wandb/client/issues/557&gt;#557&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and this one:
wandb: ERROR Can't save model, h5py returned error: Not JSON Serializable: &lt;dtype: 'string'&gt; 
I expect that if you are on Windows but run the training script just with the python train.py command, wandb only alert you about how to correctly do it in Windows, but not try to do anything else, as it is known in advance that it won't work.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What I Did&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;py -3 Train-NNLM.py

wandb: ERROR To use wandb on Windows, you need to run the command "wandb run python &lt;your_train_script&gt;.py"
wandb: ERROR wandb.init hasn't been called, can't configure run
wandb: ERROR Can't save model, h5py returned error: Not JSON Serializable: &lt;dtype: 'string'&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='alberduris' date='2019-09-19T07:28:41Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.89. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='alberduris' date='2020-12-03T04:08:04Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alberduris&gt;@alberduris&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

In the past year we've majorly reworked the CLI and UI for Weights &amp; Biases. We're closing issues older than 6 months. Please comment to reopen.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>