<bug id='563' author='kdmcdrm' open_date='2019-09-19T13:36:26Z' closed_time='2020-12-01T03:48:21Z'>
	<summary>Plotly conversion fails for multiple subplots</summary>
	<description>
wandb --version &amp;&amp; python --version &amp;&amp; uname

Weights and Biases version: 0.8.10
Python version: 3.6.5
Operating System: Linux

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I export a number of figures at the end of training showing a variety of metrics by threshold, etc. I tried doing this with the standard logging syntax but I found that most plots that were complicated resulted in plotly UserWarnings indicating that it does not know how to handle them. Plotly version 3.6.1. I found this specifically with a precision and recall figure that contained two subplots, there were other errors but I didn't track them. Is there a way to handle this or would I need to convert my plotting to Plotly to avoid the conversion step?
I tried switching to exporting them as images but I found the space provided on the run page for media is too small to see each plot.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kdmcdrm' date='2019-09-19T13:36:28Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.64. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kdmcdrm' date='2020-10-20T05:31:04Z'>
		Im having the same problem. Wandb makes some mistakes when converting from matplotlib to plotly. For example the subplot titles are missing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kdmcdrm' date='2020-10-20T16:18:04Z'>
		Currently there are 3 options if matplotlib to plotly conversion isn't working for you.

User our new custom charts functionality:
https://docs.wandb.com/library/log#custom-charts
https://docs.wandb.com/app/features/custom-charts/walkthrough
Convert your plots to Plotly charts explicitly and log them with wandb.Plotly.
Convert the matplotlib objects to images with wandb.Image(figure_or_plot)

Plotly has deprecated their official matplotlib to plotly conversion logic.  We may release a custom matplotlib conversion library in the future.  Our custom charting logic is using the same underlying engine as &lt;denchmark-link:https://altair-viz.github.io/&gt;Altair&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 so we may have a deeper integration with altair in the future as well.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>