<bug id='613' author='Danmou' open_date='2019-10-15T07:49:09Z' closed_time='2019-11-01T22:36:52Z'>
	<summary>Step deleted in patched tensorboard log</summary>
	<description>
When a summary is added through the patched tensorboard summary writer, the step is always removed before calling wandb.log. This results in the following warning:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;wandb: WARNING wandb.log called without a step keyword argument.  Pass the same step that tensorboard is using to avoid data loss see:
wandb: WARNING https://docs.wandb.com/docs/integrations/tensorboard.html#custom-metrics
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The warning only gets printed once, so I originally thought the warning was only due to logging the graph without a step, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wandb/client/issues/571&gt;#571&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, but in fact the step passed to  is always ignored.
I tracked down the problem to the following lines:



client/wandb/tensorboard/__init__.py


        Lines 162 to 163
      in
      b90c8a8






 if "step" in kwargs: 



 del kwargs["step"] 





Why is it like this? I don't really mind that wandb does its own step counting, but it's a bit confusing and the warning is downright misleading if this is the intended behaviour.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Danmou' date='2019-10-15T07:49:11Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.77. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/wandb/client&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Danmou' date='2019-10-15T16:38:33Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Danmou&gt;@Danmou&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I have a branch that removes this warning we’ll be releasing soon.  There are a few reasons we keep our own step counter

A run can have multiple tfevent files with different global_steps
If a user sets sync_tensorboard=True and also wants to call wandb.log to send custom artifacts this makes it simpler.
Tensorboard steps can go backwards, currently our step counter must increase

Our integration adds a “global_step” key for each tensorboard namespace.  In the UI you can choose any step you’ve logged as an x-axis for your charts.
We’re working on an overhaul of our metrics backend to address these issues.
Here’s my branch fixing the log error / better handling multiple tfevent namespaces: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wandb/client/pull/596/files&gt;https://github.com/wandb/client/pull/596/files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Danmou' date='2019-11-01T22:36:47Z'>
		We made some quick fixes in 0.8.14 and this message will no longer be displayed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>