<bug id='113' author='ngoodman' open_date='2017-09-13T15:27:55Z' closed_time='2017-09-13T19:29:47Z'>
	<summary>tests failing in dev</summary>
	<description>
CI tests are currently failing for multiple reasons including linting, a cubo test, and an error due to dependence on visdom. these need fixing asap, so that we can at least be at our basal somewhat useful testing state.
(when did cubo get added??)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T15:42:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ngoodman&gt;@ngoodman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 not sure where you're seeing that...? cubo is not in dev afaik. current build errors in dev seem to be all due to statistical fluctuations
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T16:12:04Z'>
		looking at the CI widget on the front page / readme. perhaps this is pointing at the wrong thing? where are you looking?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T16:15:19Z'>
		i think that's the right place to look but you have to be careful about which branch build you're looking at? currently the dev travis build times out sometimes... (on top of statistical failures) this sad state of affairs should be improved with tests running in parallel
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T17:11:47Z'>
		well, we're beyond my expertise, but there is something wonky -- i'm looking at dev, and it's not just a timeout. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/neerajprad&gt;@neerajprad&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ideas?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T17:35:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ngoodman&gt;@ngoodman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinjankowiak&gt;@martinjankowiak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - This is the dev branch last build - &lt;denchmark-link:https://travis-ci.com/uber/pyro/builds/54418443&gt;https://travis-ci.com/uber/pyro/builds/54418443&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. You can access this from &lt;denchmark-link:https://travis-ci.com/uber/pyro/branches&gt;https://travis-ci.com/uber/pyro/branches&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and going to the link from . I do wonder if there is a more prominent way to display this, will look into that. The link check passes, but it seems like we timed out on the tests. I will cut out a separate task for this, and get to it asap since this will slow up development.
As a side-note, one way to keep the travis dash clean would be to fork the repo and merge PRs from the forked repo (for instance, I have all my branches on &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/neerajprad/pyro&gt;https://github.com/neerajprad/pyro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, so they will not show up on travis).
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T17:41:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinjankowiak&gt;@martinjankowiak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jpchen&gt;@jpchen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - There is something funny in . I was under the impression that the test suite as a whole is taking more than two hours and timing out, but looks like it is mostly this test. Did you guys see this before?
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;tests/test_tracegraph_klqp.py F.
No output has been received in the last 10m0s, this potentially indicates a stalled build or something wrong with the build itself.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T17:45:48Z'>
		No output has been received in the last 10m0s never happened until a few days ago.
the longer running inferential tests are all in test_tracegraph_klqp or test_conjugate_gaussian_models. all that's needed to make timeout less of an issue is (i) break-up some of the tests into smaller pieces and (ii) parallelize things.
i can do (i) where appropriate
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T17:53:43Z'>
		I created &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with sub-tasks specified. Let me profile the tests first and if there are any that are taking too long individually, I'll follow up. I'll parallelize the test runs as well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T18:27:28Z'>
		so to elaborate on above, yes travis is a little misleading. the embedded link takes you to the latest travis build and you have to select the right branch.

As a side-note, one way to keep the travis dash clean would be to fork the repo and merge PRs from the forked repo

i prefer not to do that because i do want travis to run tests for branches i push even before merging since you get that for free when you push.
The problem with testing serially is that any error will abort the test suite. Depending on how big an effort parallelizing and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is, the immediate temporary measure we can do is to separate out the long integration tests so they dont get run in pytest. These models using tracegraph_klqp are pretty standalone so the submitter can run them locally before submitting a PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T18:48:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinjankowiak&gt;@martinjankowiak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is looking into splitting up the slow tests, which should help parallelize. I will report on the profiling after that (profiling itself will take a couple of hours).

the immediate temporary measure we can do is to separate out the long integration tests so they dont get run in pytest.

I would also prefer that we have a set of fast tests for every PR, and then have longer running integration tests that can be run on a daily frequency or so. Will look into how we can set that up. However, leaving it up to the devs to run it locally will mean that they rarely get run (specially since these are really slow). We can remove these tests for now though, until we fix this slowness.

i prefer not to do that because i do want travis to run tests for branches i push even before merging since you get that for free when you push.

The tests will get run on every push once a PR is in, but not on private branches which do not have an associated PR. I am not sure if it is a good idea to use travis resources for that instead of locally testing (our local tests should be much faster though!).
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='ngoodman' date='2017-09-13T19:29:47Z'>
		ok, i understand what the deal with is for the readme link (even if it makes me a little cranky). i think the more general issues are understood and underway. so i'm closing this in favor of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
thanks for the rapid exploration!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>