<bug id='138' author='neerajprad' open_date='2017-09-21T03:09:26Z' closed_time='2017-09-22T07:21:54Z'>
	<summary>Integration tests crashing due to a dependency issue</summary>
	<description>
A number of integration tests have started failing recently with the following exception due to some changes introduced in the latest version of networkx (refer to &lt;denchmark-link:https://networkx.github.io/documentation/networkx-2.0/reference/algorithms/generated/networkx.algorithms.dag.topological_sort.html?highlight=topological_sort#networkx.algorithms.dag.topological_sort&gt;topological sort documentation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for the latest version). This underscores the need to start using  (also mentioned in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/pull/133&gt;#133&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with regards to reproducibility). In this case, we may need to specify a lower version in  or modify our code appropriately.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/fritzo&gt;@fritzo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/martinjankowiak&gt;@martinjankowiak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - what do you guys think?
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;E           TypeError: topological_sort() got an unexpected keyword argument 'reverse'
pyro/infer/tracegraph_kl_qp.py:106: TypeError
____________ GaussianChainTests.test_elbo_nonreparameterized_N_is_7 ____________
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T03:10:26Z'>
		Acc. to the docs - tldr: start using the built-in reversed() function instead.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T03:18:37Z'>
		i see i guess they did some sort of upgrade

2017-09-20 20:10 GMT-07:00 Neeraj Pradhan &lt;notifications@github.com&gt;:
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


 Acc. to the docs - tldr: start using the built-in sorted() function
 instead.

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#138 (comment)&gt;, or mute
 the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AVFMghjKCni9ks7TBiU9rPqDdo9XV3i_ks5skdOjgaJpZM4Pevcp&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T03:48:05Z'>
		Yes, this is with version 2.0 which was recently released.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T04:06:41Z'>
		A good first step is to add a pip freeze line to our .travis.yml to aid our debugging of future issues like this. A second step might be to pin all versions of libraries in setup.py to &gt;=patch &lt;major (i think). That should suffice, as long as all our dependencies adhere to semver.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T07:58:07Z'>
		this is mostly a problem for backwards incompatible releases. in general, i think we should be supporting the latest versions of all dependencies and libraries, so we should set &gt;= and stay away from &lt; when possible at least for dev. we can change it for release, but catching these here (in dev) is what's supposed to happen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-21T17:46:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jpchen&gt;@jpchen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 That sounds reasonable, to specify only  requirements. It would be a good idea with releases to also include one or both of  (conda) and  (pip).
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='neerajprad' date='2017-09-22T07:21:53Z'>
		Closed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/pull/139&gt;#139&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the current failures in dev are do to stochasticity
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>