<bug id='1682' author='mileslucas' open_date='2018-12-22T04:54:09Z' closed_time='2018-12-24T04:44:20Z'>
	<summary>[bug] No pyro.optim</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Issue Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Pyro does not have an optim module
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

For any bugs, please provide the following:

OS and python version. Windows 10 python 3.7
PyTorch version, or if relevant, output of pip freeze. pytorch 1.0.0
Pyro version: output of python -c 'import pyro; print pyro.__version__' pyro 0.3.0

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Code Snippet&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Provide any relevant code snippets and commands run to replicate the issue.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import  pyro.optim
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

AttributeError: module 'pyro' has no attribute 'optim'
In the repository code it looks like pyro.optim is not being imported in pyro/__init__.py
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mileslucas' date='2018-12-24T04:27:50Z'>
		I am unable to replicate this issue on my Mac with python 3.7. Are you able to import other pyro modules, e.g. pyro.poutine or pyro.infer?

In the repository code it looks like pyro.optim is not being imported in pyro/init.py

That only implies that it is not imported by default when you do from pyro import *, but the usual package discovery rules should apply. My guess is that the issue is with the pyro.optim.__init__.py file, in particular with the most recent addition: import pyro.optim.multi. That creates an issue because pyro.optim has not yet been imported and throws an AttributeError. I'm not sure why I am not able to replicate it on my system though. If you also see this on our dev branch, could you try commenting that line out and seeing if import pyro.optim works?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mileslucas' date='2018-12-24T04:44:20Z'>
		I can't reproduce this either...
I bet you I messed up my namespace somewhere within the Jupyter Notebook I was playing with. Sorry for the bother!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>