<bug id='328' author='null-a' open_date='2017-10-24T10:29:21Z' closed_time='2017-10-26T00:13:24Z'>
	<summary>map_data requires batch_size arg in both model and guide</summary>
	<description>
To use data sub sampling (using map_data) we have to specify the batch_size arg in both model and guide, even though specifying this in the guide only is sufficient. (For SVI at least.)
(If no batch_size is given in the model, it appears that no sub-sampling happens (in the model). If a batch_size is given that doesn't match the batch_size in the guide then things appear to work, so I guess sub-sampling happens reusing indices from the guide, and batch_size is ignored.)
ETA: This also appears to be true of iarange.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='null-a' date='2017-10-24T16:30:14Z'>
		What is the desired behavior? My guess is that &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/uber/pyro/blob/dev/pyro/__init__.py#L205&gt;the short-circuiting logic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is preventing the model  from being replayed as you expect, but I'm unclear what the desired behavior is.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='null-a' date='2017-10-25T08:08:26Z'>
		
What is the desired behavior?

As a user, when I want to enable sub sampling, it would be good to only have to specify the batch size in one place. (I think this makes sense because I never want batch sizes to differ across the model and guide, for now at least.) Personally, I suspect that batch size should eventually be given as a parameter of inference rather than via the model and/or guide (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/issues/236&gt;#236&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), but in the meantime, having to only specify it in the guide would be an improvement.
Right now we're in a slightly awkward situation where (for SVI at least) the batch size I give in the guide controls subsampling, but I have to pass some batch size to the model otherwise no sub sampling occurs, and inference dies because of the differing batch sizes. However, it does't matter what value I pass in the model, since the batch size from the guide controls the batch size. This is potentially confusing, because I might start tweaking the batch size in the model and see no effect.
I'm reopening this issue since this is still the case after &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pyro-ppl/pyro/pull/330&gt;#330&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 afaict.
(This isn't high priority for me.)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>