<bug id='1354' author='SantiHM23' open_date='2020-04-03T14:15:20Z' closed_time='2020-04-17T14:19:07Z'>
	<summary>Polygons to bounding boxes</summary>
	<description>
Hi!
In the task I am doing, I run a person detector before using your tool in order to already have most of the bounding boxes that I will need for annotation, and I save them in a .json file in the proper format and upload them. When uploading the file, the bounding boxes are uploaded as polygons instead of boxes. Actually, if I manually draw a box in the CVAT, save it, download as a json and re-upload that same file without modifying anything, the bounding boxes are also uploaded as polygons instead of boxes. Is there anyway to upload them as boxes? From what I have read in the documentation and the issues, I understand that it is much more convenient for using interpolation, which is something I believe I will need in order to mantain the identity of the person through consecutive frames.
Thank you for your help!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T15:03:11Z'>
		Hello. I suppose that you are using COCO format. In this format annotations are imported as polygons if there is segmentation field not empty, otherwise they are imported as boxes if there is bbox field. Try to leave only bbox field or use another format, for instance - Pascal VOC. If there are any troubles with these options, you can try to use Datumaro to prepare annotations in CVAT format and import them.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T15:15:45Z'>
		Hi! When uploading it with the segmentation field empty and having the coordinates [x,y,width,height] for the bbox field, the bounding boxes would directly not appear. I will try with other formats as you suggested. Thsank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T15:29:22Z'>
		Is it possible that coco annotations have no image info? File should contain either image names or correct frame ids.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T16:00:29Z'>
		I have the file with both image names and ids, and the annotations linked to those image ids, and still nothing appears on screen.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T16:19:43Z'>
		Please also check if annotations have labels and the task has same labels defined.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T16:27:02Z'>
		Yes to both. Maybe it is a problem on how to leave "segmentation" field empty. I tried with:
"segmentation": [[]],
"segmentation": [],
"segmentation": ,
"segmentation": "",
Maybe it should be done in a different way, or not writing that field at all?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-03T16:43:41Z'>
		The implementation is &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/blob/develop/datumaro/datumaro/plugins/coco_format/extractor.py#L148&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/blob/develop/cvat/apps/dataset_manager/bindings.py#L204&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, so it can be checked where it actually fails to import annotations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='SantiHM23' date='2020-04-17T14:19:07Z'>
		Tried to reproduce and failed - if segmentation is [], annotations are imported as rectangles. Closing, feel free to reopen if the issue persists.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>