<bug id='1417' author='thirdeye-callum' open_date='2020-04-17T09:25:01Z' closed_time='2020-05-23T19:16:04Z'>
	<summary>Request frames with variable resolution</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My actions before raising this issue&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


 Read/searched the docs
 Searched past issues

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Our team have been using CVAT for the past couple of months with great success. Our workflow is roughly:

Add new videos to a file share
Create a new task per new video using the REST API
Annotate
Collate annotations by querying the REST API

However, now that our annotators are working remotely we are having some issues with image load times. We have tried a few different quick fixes out:

Ask the annotators to open several tabs at a time so that the client gets a chance to download images ahead of time
Use the develop branch where batch image downloads have been added
Reduce video resolution

For us reducing video resolution seems to have the biggest impact, however, it introduces some complexity in managing our data:

when we lower the resolution of our videos (using ffmpeg etc.) I'm concerned about potentially dropping frames and having two sets of videos that are slightly out of sync
If we later need higher resolution images to annotate objects in the background we will have to upload additional jobs for the same videos and write scripts to pass the annotations around

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Possible Solution&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A potential solution might be to implement an option in the REST API that allows you to set a desired (or maximum) resolution when requesting frames. The server would  decode, resize, and encode the image before returning it.
If this solution seems like a sensible idea, our team are happy to try take a look at it, however, it would be really helpful if we could get some suggestions on where to start (what files to look at etc.)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='thirdeye-callum' date='2020-04-23T09:25:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thirdeye-callum&gt;@thirdeye-callum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , could you please try in develop uncheck the checkbox below:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/40690625/80082507-26585f80-855d-11ea-9a32-4aa199e44090.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It will force to use video chunks instead of chunks with images and should resize images automatically. Please try to create a task using the option and report your experience. Is it better?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='thirdeye-callum' date='2020-05-23T19:16:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thirdeye-callum&gt;@thirdeye-callum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , I will close the issue. If it is a problem, don't hesitate to re-open.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>