<bug id='1580' author='savan77' open_date='2020-05-21T20:33:58Z' closed_time='2020-06-25T14:47:29Z'>
	<summary>Annotations Don't Get Updated If We Run Automatic Annotation Again</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My actions before raising this issue&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


[* ] Read/searched the docs
[ *] Searched past issues

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If you run automatic annotation the first time, then it works fine. But if you run automatic annotation again and go back to the annotation page, then the bounding boxes aren't updated. You have to refresh the page to force the updates. Ideally, when we go to the annotation page after running the automatic annotation it should have new annotations.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Current Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Currently, after running the automatic annotation, it does not get updated automatically. We have to refresh the page manually.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Possible Solution&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Not sure. I confirmed put_task_data is being called but it still doesn't show annotations.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to Reproduce (for bugs)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Run Automatic Annotation first time
Go to the annotation page, you will see your annotations.
Run automatic annotation again
Go to the annotation page, you won't see updated annotations even though clean old annotation button was selected.

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I am just trying to automatic annotation multiple times.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Git hash commit (git log -1): Develop branch
Docker version docker version (e.g. Docker 17.0.05): Using in Development Mode
Are you using Docker Swarm or Kubernetes? None
Operating System and version (e.g. Linux, Windows, MacOS): Linux
Code example or link to GitHub repo or gist to reproduce problem:
Other diagnostic information / logs:
  
Logs from `cvat` container



&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Next steps&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

You may &lt;denchmark-link:https://gitter.im/opencv-cvat/public&gt;join our Gitter&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 channel for community support.
This problem has already been discussed with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/azhavoro&gt;@azhavoro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 on Gitter.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='savan77' date='2020-05-22T12:16:42Z'>
		Related issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/openvinotoolkit/cvat/issues/1424&gt;#1424&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Automatic annotation isn't matter. The problem is single page application doesn't request new annotations from the server when open task again (all data are stored in a browser for the latest opened task, even when you have gone to task list).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>