<bug id='1857' author='rnekk2' open_date='2020-07-06T10:15:05Z' closed_time='2020-10-28T14:37:14Z'>
	<summary>Some annotations are not saving randomly</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My actions before raising this issue&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


[ Done] Read/searched the docs
[Done ] Searched past issues

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When we save the annotations for a specific task it should save all annotations
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Current Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When we save annotations randomly it is failing to save annotations for some images. . We are having to redo those images
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to Reproduce (for bugs)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It is happening very randomly.
1.
1.
1.
1.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When we try to look back at the work we are doing, we are seeing some annotations are not being saved.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;



Git hash commit (git log -1):
cheling@cheling-ubuntu1604:~/cvat$ git log -1
commit 80ed45b
Author: zhiltsov-max zhiltsov.max35@gmail.com
Date:   Tue Jun 30 06:07:20 2020 +0300
Allow attributes in COCO format (#1782)

allow attributes in coco
update changelog
update cli
update coco cli



Docker version docker version (e.g. Docker 17.0.05):  5:19.03.13-0ubuntu-xenial


Are you using Docker Swarm or Kubernetes?
No


Operating System and version (e.g. Linux, Windows, MacOS): Ubuntu 16.04


Code example or link to GitHub repo or gist to reproduce problem:


Other diagnostic information / logs:

Logs from `cvat` container



&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Next steps&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

You may &lt;denchmark-link:https://gitter.im/opencv-cvat/public&gt;join our Gitter&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 channel for community support.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-06T12:37:01Z'>
		Hello, can you describe which format do you use and which annotations are missing? Is it whole images or just some annotations?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-06T15:04:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhiltsov-max&gt;@zhiltsov-max&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we use bounding box annotations. The process we use is pre annotate our dataset with our custom object detection model and build the annotations XML file and upload to CVAT. After that we use CVAT to fix any false positives. What we are seeing is randomly even though we are making changes to the false positive bounding boxes and save. It is saving successfully without any issues. When we look at our previous images, we are seeing randomly for some images the changes we made previously are not showing up. It is still showing the same false positives as before.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-06T15:21:36Z'>
		If I understand correctly, you are fixing annotations, then saving them, and then UI shows old annotations? What about exporting annotations at this point? Can you compare the files and check if the annotations changed?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-06T15:26:22Z'>
		That is correct. Let me compare the annotation files and get back to you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-13T05:38:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhiltsov-max&gt;@zhiltsov-max&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have verified. The issue is the annotations are not saving after making the changes. Does not seem like a UI issue. I downloaded the annotation file and uploaded to another task with the same images. The changes are not reflecting.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-13T14:09:41Z'>
		Ok, could you specify which format are you using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-13T17:12:08Z'>
		We are using CVAT XML bounding box annotations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-21T04:21:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhiltsov-max&gt;@zhiltsov-max&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any update on this ? We are also seeing sometimes once we save the annotations it shows as saved but when I open a new tab and see those changes are not being reflected.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-21T07:17:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rnekk2&gt;@rnekk2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , could you please help us to reproduce it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-26T05:33:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It is happening very randomly. I have a screen recording to show the issue we are seeing. It is 32 MB. Is there a way to send you the screen recording as the max size of file to attach is only 10 MB.
Here is the CVAT version information:
Server version: 1.1b0
Core version: 3.1.1
Canvas version: 2.0.1
UI version: 1.6.2
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-28T14:42:33Z'>
		I think you can convert it to a gif animation and greatly reduce the size. It feels like some server or UI problem, can you check the server and  the browser console for errors?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bsekachev&gt;@bsekachev&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/azhavoro&gt;@azhavoro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, please, take a look.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='rnekk2' date='2020-07-28T14:47:32Z'>
		Let's start with a GIF. It would be great also to see bodies of requests that sent to the server when you save annotations and the issue is reproduced.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='rnekk2' date='2020-08-16T18:50:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rnekk2&gt;@rnekk2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Any updates here?
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='rnekk2' date='2020-10-28T14:37:14Z'>
		Closing as no response for a long time.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>