<bug id='1944' author='thomasstats' open_date='2020-07-28T06:00:29Z' closed_time='2020-07-30T13:14:20Z'>
	<summary>Returning to job list for a task and attempting to start another job results in infinite loading screen.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My actions before raising this issue&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


 Read/searched the docs
 Searched past issues

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Being able to return to the job list for a task and start a new job without an infinite loading screen.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Current Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

After returning to the job list while working on a job, clicking on another job loads the UI but infinitely loops the loading screen.  When checking the cvat logs, the most recent entry is the last action performed before returning to the job list, no actions such as clicking on the new job appear.  Upon checking the console and the HAR data there doesn't appear to be any errors, and HAR produces one request to git/repository/get/.  This was reproduced with multiple users on different machines.  However, all was done on the same VM.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to Reproduce (for bugs)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Start a job in a task with multiple jobs.  In our case we had a thousand images in a task split into 100 images per job.
Press the back arrow to return to the job list, or hit task and enter the job list from the task menu.
Select a different job that is assigned to you from the job list
UI loads and infinitely shows the loading screen.
To be able to load the job you have to go back to the job list, refresh the page (F5 or refresh button), and then enter the job.

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I would say this is likely a minor issue, because it currently has a work around, but it is a bit of an annoyance for the annotators.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Your Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Git hash commit (git log -1):  Release 1.0.0 (#1335)
Docker version docker version (e.g. Docker 17.0.05): 19.03.8
Operating System and version (e.g. Linux, Windows, MacOS):  Ubuntu 18.04

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='thomasstats' date='2020-07-28T12:13:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thomasstats&gt;@thomasstats&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Hi, could you please try to reproduce using develop branch? I cannot
Also we will release 1.1.0-beta at the end of July
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='thomasstats' date='2020-07-29T04:42:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bsekachev&gt;@bsekachev&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 loaded develop branch on my personal computer, uploaded a task with multiple jobs, and can confirm that the problem still exists.  Is there by chance anything I could gather for you that would help you diagnose this problem further?  Like I said previously the console, cvat logs, and HAR data all seem to be rather useless.  I'm curious if it's a client side js problem.
Edit:  Actually now, I've gone back again and tried to enter a job a second time without refresh and I'm getting "Error during fetching a job" with 100 printed in the console, log attached.  A page appears that says "Sorry, but this job was not found".  When I attempt to do it again and again this 100 continually increments by 100.  For instance the 6th time I've attempted the number appears as 600.  It's still worth noting that if I refresh the job list it works again with no issues.   The CVAT logs still only show the most recent successful load, and no errors.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/files/4992628/localhost-1595998122401.log&gt;localhost-1595998122401.log&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='thomasstats' date='2020-07-29T08:43:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thomasstats&gt;@thomasstats&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Hmm.. I was able to reproduce it, but reproducing isn't stable for me.
Okay, let's assign bug label, I suppose it is a client issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='thomasstats' date='2020-07-30T09:30:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thomasstats&gt;@thomasstats&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I expect the fix above will resolve the issue
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>