<bug id='2072' author='ncbkr' open_date='2020-08-24T13:09:49Z' closed_time='2020-09-04T07:54:43Z'>
	<summary>Dataset repository URL does not support gitlab subgroup repositories</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My actions before raising this issue&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


 Read/searched the docs
 Searched past issues

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Our teams and projects are organized in gitlab groups and subgroups. The URL of the repository I wanted to use for task synchronization follows this pattern: git@gitlab.com:&lt;group&gt;/&lt;subgroup&gt;/&lt;repo&gt;.git. As this is a valid repository URL, I expected this to work as described in the User Guide.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Current Behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When I try to submit the task via the UI, an error message appears, telling me that the remote repository could not be read and that I should make sure I added an ssh key to git.
In order to further investigate, I tried to clone the very same repository from within the cvat docker container. The repository was successfully set up.
I then searched logs/cvat_server.log and found this line: cmdline: git clone -v git@gitlab.com:&lt;group&gt;/&lt;subgroup&gt;.git. So the URL I provided was cut off after the subgroup and the repository name was ignored, resulting in an invalid repository URL.
The function &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/blob/07de7141edbc980031da857579128088f7a4630a/cvat/apps/git/git.py#L75&gt;_parse_url&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 confirmed this assumption. In the repository pattern, there are only capturing groups for user and repository
For me, the best solution would be if the url parsing could be extended in order to support also gitlabs groups and supgroups structure. At least there should be a better error message telling me that the repository url I want to use is not supported, The presented error was not helpful for finding the solution in my case.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


In the UI click "create task"
enter any title
add any label
upload some local images
expand advanced configuration
for dataset repository URL enter an URL following this pattern: git@gitlab.com:&lt;group&gt;/&lt;subgroup&gt;/&lt;repo&gt;.git
click "submit"

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Because of this issue we are currently not able to stick to our project structure. For us, this causes additional efforts in administrating repositories, users and roles as the dataset repository will have to live outside our groups &amp; subgroups structure.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Git hash commit (git log -1): 07de714
Docker version docker version (e.g. Docker 17.0.05): 19.03.6-ce

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ncbkr' date='2020-08-24T15:26:17Z'>
		Hi, could you please update your CVAT? Seems this issue was fixed already with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/openvinotoolkit/cvat/issues/1651&gt;#1651&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ncbkr' date='2020-09-04T07:54:43Z'>
		I will close the issue. Do not hesitate reopen it if you still experience the problem
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>