<bug id='36' author='Yeah-Kun' open_date='2018-08-20T03:25:57Z' closed_time='2018-10-15T09:27:24Z'>
	<summary>The login page at localhost:8080 have Bad Request</summary>
	<description>
I am using Ubuntu 16.04.
I followed the tutorial and installed it successfully, but on the second day, when I ran the docker, it couldn't open the page, showing the 400 status code（Bad Request）, how can I fix this?
The output of the docker-compose up -d command was:
Creating network "cvat_default" with the default driver
Creating cvat_db ... done
Creating cvat_redis ... done
Creating cvat ... done
And the output of docker logs cvat:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/files/2301043/logs.txt&gt;logs.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-20T08:13:41Z'>
		HI &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yeah-Kun&gt;@Yeah-Kun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Thank you for the report. Could you please insert here output of docker ps | grep cvat command?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-20T11:37:56Z'>
		HI &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
This is the information  what you need.
ffe3f099af46        cvat                   "/usr/bin/supervisord"   9 hours ago         Up 2 minutes        0.0.0.0:8080-&gt;8080/tcp, 8443/tcp, 0.0.0.0:80-&gt;8080/tcp   cvat
ba6e707eb525        redis:4.0.5-alpine     "docker-entrypoint.s…"   9 hours ago         Up 2 minutes        6379/tcp                                                 cvat_redis
d92ae96756d6        postgres:10.3-alpine   "docker-entrypoint.s…"   9 hours ago         Up 2 minutes        5432/tcp                                                 cvat_db
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-20T12:28:42Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yeah-Kun&gt;@Yeah-Kun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Let's do one more experiment:

docker-compose down (it will delete container and any broken files if you have any)
Inside https://github.com/opencv/cvat/blob/master/supervisord.conf file please replace apache log level from INFO to DEBUG (it will do logging from apache module more verbose)
docker-compose up -d --build (rebuild and run containers with changes above)
Go to 'http://localhost:8080/' and report results. If the problem still exists please attach logs again.

Additional questions:

Did you do any source code modifications? (except INFO -&gt; DEBUG)

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-20T16:03:08Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I have done the steps you said, but there is still this problem.
I just follow the steps in the tutorial and  never modified the code before.
Here is the logs:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/files/2303073/cvat_logs.txt&gt;cvat_logs.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-21T09:54:55Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yeah-Kun&gt;@Yeah-Kun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Thanks for your patience. To be honest I don't know a reason of the issue. I can reproduce BAD REQUEST only if I try to access the server using my hostname instead of localhost (without modifying ALLOWED_HOSTS).
Let's do the latest attempt with TRACE8 log level for Apache:

Run docker-compose down (it will delete container and any broken files if you have any)
Inside https://github.com/opencv/cvat/blob/master/supervisord.conf file please replace apache log level from INFO to TRACE8 (it will do logging from apache module more verbose)
Run docker-compose up -d --build (rebuild and run containers with changes above)
Go to 'http://localhost:8080/'.
Send us logs

Also it makes sense to clean cookies and/or try another browser. I hope these two experiments will give us some hints to root cause the problem. It is especially strange that you had working configuration and next day it didn't work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-08-24T05:12:06Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
I am also thanks for your patience, your attitude makes me feel surprised.
This is the log what you need, I hope it will help you to figure the problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/files/2317096/cvat_logs.txt&gt;cvat_logs.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-09-20T03:20:57Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yeah-Kun&gt;@Yeah-Kun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
To be honest we still cannot reproduce the problem. Could you please try to clean cookies and/or try another browser (another version, without any extensions)? I hope these two experiments will give us some hints to root cause the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2018-10-15T09:27:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Yeah-Kun&gt;@Yeah-Kun&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
If you still have the problem don't hesitate to open the issue again. For now, I will close it because nobody reports a similar issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2019-03-04T02:52:09Z'>
		Hi, I am having this same problem. I have tried the suggestions here but to no avail. I also tried using a different browser, in incognito and after clearing the cache. Could we reopen the issue? Thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2019-03-04T04:26:46Z'>
		You maybe can check your The docker config the local ip
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2019-03-04T11:53:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kmstumpf&gt;@kmstumpf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , you can use gitter.im/opencv-cvat for such questions. In general you need to provide more information. For example, logs of your CVAT instance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Yeah-Kun' date='2019-09-23T12:35:11Z'>
		the problem occurs when you try to access via ip address . it works fine with localhost:8080
i was trying to connect to cvat from another system so i used ip address and got the error bad request (400)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>