<bug id='39' author='wronk' open_date='2018-08-27T10:33:48Z' closed_time='2018-10-01T15:25:21Z'>
	<summary>UI becomes slow after 300-400 annotations</summary>
	<description>
I'm labeling large satellite images with hundreds to a few thousand objects of interest.
I noticed that after about 300-400 annotations, the UI slows down. It might take the program ~1 sec to become responsive again after creating a new bbox. After about 800-1000 annotations, it's nearly unusable -- adding an annotation might require ~5 seconds before it will register. For now, I'm just cropping my large images into smaller pieces as a workaround, but it'd be a lot nicer to add all annotations to a single large image (as raw satellite imagery often comes in fairly long strips). I'm using a 2017 MacBook pro to do the labeling.
I don't know enough about the backend to suggest a fix, but happy to answer questions if it's helpful.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='wronk' date='2018-08-27T11:24:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wronk&gt;@wronk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
We will look at the problem. If you can provide us your image + annotation file it will help us to reproduce it easily on our side. Probably our tool isn't optimized for such cases. Need to check how to improve it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='wronk' date='2018-08-27T11:26:52Z'>
		Also I remember that we had similar problems for semantic/instance segmentation and Boris fixed similar issues. If it is the case the problem will be fixed with next major release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='wronk' date='2018-08-28T18:14:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for checking into this. Here are both files -- let me know if you have any problems or need more help.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/cvat/files/2329336/CVAT_issue_39_example_case.zip&gt;CVAT_issue_39_example_case.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='wronk' date='2018-09-20T03:00:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bsekachev&gt;@bsekachev&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Could you please look at the problem? Was it fixed already?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='wronk' date='2018-09-21T16:52:37Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wronk&gt;@wronk&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,

I can reproduce your performance problems on the latest version of CVAT.
I cannot upload your annotation file as is because a lot of coordinates for bounding boxes are out of image size. My guess that huge image resolution can be a reason for that. Did you crop the attached image or it has original size?

We will work to resolve both problems. Thanks for your feedback.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='wronk' date='2018-09-25T12:46:54Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nmanovic&gt;@nmanovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I think I've gotten this working. I do have 2 versions of the image, but I think I have the correct one included here. I was able to remake the task with the included files.
I did have an issue where I had to manually change the version tags in the annotation file to get it to sync properly to a newly created task. Specifically, these lines in the xml file need to match the task you create (e.g., task 25) on your cvat instance:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  &lt;meta&gt;
    &lt;task&gt;
      &lt;id&gt;25&lt;/id&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        &lt;segment&gt; 
         &lt;id&gt;25&lt;/id&gt;
          &lt;start&gt;25&lt;/start&gt;
          &lt;stop&gt;25&lt;/stop&gt;
          &lt;url&gt;http://localhost:8080/?id=25&lt;/url&gt;
        &lt;/segment&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Let me know if that fixes it for you
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>