<bug id='708' author='Vafilor' open_date='2020-11-06T23:09:46Z' closed_time='2020-12-11T19:51:59Z'>
	<summary>onepanel ui: going from 0 workspaces to creating a new one - the new one does not immediately show up. You have to refresh the page.</summary>
	<description>
This issue includes a couple of parts

When we create a workspace, the UI still believes there are no workspaces at all, so it doesn't update.


This can be fixed by making a request to check if there any workspaces if there are none whenever we do a poll. Note - we can't update the "any workspaces" flag in the poll because there might be filters applied. If there are no filters, it can be.


When we delete a workspace, the status goes to terminating and eventually terminated. So there is a time delay between clicking delete and the eventual delete.


This can be fixed by updating the "any workspaces" flag when we have 0 results and we have no filter.
Alternatively, we could implement a state and keep track of things like - did that one workspace get deleted, etc. However, this is a bit more involved and error prone.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Vafilor' date='2020-11-06T23:09:48Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label kind/bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.61. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/onepanelio/core&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Vafilor' date='2020-11-09T21:53:57Z'>
		Another similar issue to this:

Going from 1 to 0 Workspaces, the last Workspace remains unless you refresh

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Vafilor' date='2020-11-09T23:47:46Z'>
		Also, when going from 1 to 0, this should show the call to action empty view vs "No workspaces found":
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1211823/98609734-d3e55300-22a2-11eb-8283-f158c44f34ae.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Vafilor' date='2020-11-25T19:17:36Z'>
		There is code in place for this. More testing is needed to make sure performance isn't impacted.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>