<bug id='2' author='zhampel' open_date='2019-08-26T22:31:41Z' closed_time='2019-09-10T17:12:04Z'>
	<summary>Unidecode module error when unit-testing</summary>
	<description>
After installing dependencies, including apex then the reinstall.sh script, but upon trying out the unit tests, I received an error for missing module unidecode. A simple pip install unidecode solved this, with all tests subsequently running successfully. The error prior to successful tests is attached, and computer details for completeness below.
Is this issue something to be ameliorated in the install procedure or setup file?
CentOS Linux release 7.5.1804 (Core)
Linux version 3.10.0-862.14.4.el7.x86_64 (&lt;denchmark-link:mailto:mockbuild@kbuilder.bsys.centos.org&gt;mockbuild@kbuilder.bsys.centos.org&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) (gcc version 4.8.5 20150623 (Red Hat 4.8.5-28) (GCC) ) &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/NeMo/issues/1&gt;#1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 SMP Wed Sep 26 15:12:11 UTC 2018
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/moconnor725/NeMo/files/3543309/Unidecode_Error.txt&gt;Unidecode_Error.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zhampel' date='2019-08-27T02:30:26Z'>
		which Python version are you using? I thought Python 3.6 and 3.7 come with unicode.
Another difference with our specified requirements is that you use CentOS instead of Ubuntu, but I doubt that it the source of this particular issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zhampel' date='2019-08-27T16:27:31Z'>
		I am using Python 3.6.5, and yes, unfortunately the setup is CentOS :(
I just made a virtualenv, then ran the reinstall script which should have installed things appropriately via the setup.py script, right? That is, after installing PyTorch and apex of course.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zhampel' date='2019-08-27T21:34:50Z'>
		yes, vitualenv should do the trick. But again, we only tested on Ubutntu.
A more stable route might be using our latest Pytorch docker container from &lt;denchmark-link:https://ngc.nvidia.com&gt;https://ngc.nvidia.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>