<bug id='72' author='ikvision' open_date='2020-05-02T01:36:05Z' closed_time='2020-05-02T07:05:23Z'>
	<summary>[BUG] Each obj file's faces are different in demo.py</summary>
	<description>
Thanks for your great research and very well maintained code.

Operating system and the version - Ubuntu 18
Python version, 3.7
Any txt diff between two obj file reveals the difference

When running the demo code with --save_obj the faces are different for every frame.
One should expect that v (vertices) section should be different as the body moves. But the f (faces) section should remain constant as the smpl faces are given by from lib.models.smpl import get_smpl_faces.
Trimesh seems to calculate the faces for each frame and therefor each obj file has a different f (faces) section in 


VIBE/lib/utils/renderer.py


         Line 86
      in
      2ba005c






 mesh.export(mesh_filename) 





Trimesh is a general tool trying to optimize the mesh for and is not aware of SMPL consistency needs. I didn't find a way to avoid those optimizing faces in Trimesh. But a simple solution in VIBE code would be to overwrite the f section by get_smpl_faces values for each frame.
I think this consistency would simplify the conversion to an animation file (as fbx file)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ikvision' date='2020-05-02T01:49:05Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ikvision&gt;@ikvision&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
It is something related to trimesh package, commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mkocabas/VIBE/commit/e7b1cff7a7b991ab703f2cfd60304e1b470fbacf&gt;e7b1cff&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 should solve this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ikvision' date='2020-05-02T03:42:38Z'>
		Wow, thank you for the quick fix
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ikvision' date='2020-05-11T03:41:33Z'>
		how are you doing the conversion to an fbx file?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ikvision' date='2020-05-11T18:45:01Z'>
		@Primate92587 conversion the fbx is a feature request &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mkocabas/VIBE/issues/1&gt;#1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 not yet implemented
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>