<bug_data>
<bug id='453' author='mjpost' open_date='2018-06-22T13:41:56Z' closed_time='2018-09-19T16:55:51Z'>
 	<summary>pip installs test/ and contrib/ directories</summary>
 	<description>
 When installing via pip, it creates a sockeye/ directory (as it should), but also creates our test/ and contrib/ directories, e.g.,
 &lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ ls /usr/local/lib/python3.6/site-packages
 [snip]
 contrib/
 sockeye/
 test/
 &lt;/denchmark-code&gt;
 
 Our setup.py script has "test" in the ignore list but it is clearly not being ignored. We shouldn't be including these files.
 	</description>
 	<comments>
 		<comment id='1' author='mjpost' date='2018-06-22T14:57:12Z'>
 		thanks for bringing this up! We should make sure to not include the test package and consider renaming contrib to sockeye_contrib as we're otherwise polluting people's site-packages with a very generic package name.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='2' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-15T16:23:22Z'>
 		Following up on this: what would it entail if we rename contrib to sockeye_contrib? We'd need to update the imports from contrib (i.e. sacrebleu), but would it break anything or anyone else?
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='3' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-15T23:06:08Z'>
 		Autopilot should be fine with a batch find-and-replace contrib -&gt; sockeye_contrib.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='4' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-16T12:30:08Z'>
 		I don't see any problems, but what's the reason for this change? Just a preference?
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='5' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-16T13:32:24Z'>
 		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mjpost&gt;@mjpost&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  the reason is this issue that you created :) installing a generically named package called 'contrib' to users' site-packages doesn't sound like a good idea.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='6' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-17T00:38:48Z'>
 		Oh, I see, you’re still installing contrib. Another option would be to remove contrib entirely. I don’t think autopilot needs to be included (you could turn it into its own separate pypi module), and sacrebleu could also be used only via import as a standard external module.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='7' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-17T07:37:50Z'>
 		There is more things in contrib than autopilot and sacrebleu and if I remember correctly we had talked about a separate install of sacrebleu and concluded that it would make things more complicated.
 If renaming contrib to sockeye_contrib would be an option, I would suggest even go further and just move contrib into sockeye: sockeye.contrib.{autopilot,sacrebleu,rouge,vis_tool}
 This would lead to a single folder created during pip install for users.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='8' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-17T08:47:09Z'>
 		would this work with sacrebleu? Either sockeye_contrib or merging everything into one package sounds good. I think I'd slightly favor keeping a separate folder.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='9' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-18T07:07:29Z'>
 		ok, I'll create a PR with the rename to sockeye_contrib
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='10' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-18T07:20:07Z'>
 		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/awslabs/sockeye/pull/537&gt;#537&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='11' author='mjpost' date='2018-09-18T14:04:28Z'>
 		Sounds good to me.
 		</comment>
 	</comments>
 </bug>
<commit id='3353487d805a111dc3559dead1a3a56303ffe9ae' author='Felix Hieber' date='2018-09-16 15:27:45+02:00'>
 	<dmm_unit complexity='None' interfacing='None' size='None'></dmm_unit>
 	<modification change_type='MODIFY' old_name='setup.py' new_name='setup.py'>
 		<file_info nloc='103' complexity='10' token_count='561'></file_info>
 		<modified_lines>
 			<added_lines>57,111,125</added_lines>
 			<deleted_lines>110,124</deleted_lines>
 		</modified_lines>
 	</modification>
 </commit>
</bug_data>
