<bug id='1232' author='cristianmtr' open_date='2020-07-17T11:15:15Z' closed_time='2020-07-17T12:02:12Z'>
	<summary>Cannot create Cortex cluster even though I have the permissions</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

0.18.1
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I am trying to spin up the cluster with cortex cluster up. However I am getting the message
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;[✖]  AWS::EKS::Cluster/ControlPlane: CREATE_FAILED – "User: XXXXXXX is not authorized to perform: eks:CreateCluster on resource: XXXXXXXXXcluster/cortex (Service: AmazonEKS; Status Code: 403; Error Code: AccessDeniedException; Request ID: XXXXXXXX)"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

My manager has given me all the permissions for eks in AWS.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Configuration&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;# cluster.yaml

# AWS credentials (if not specified, ~/.aws/credentials will be checked) (can be overridden by $AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID and $AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY)
aws_access_key_id: ***
aws_secret_access_key: ***

# optional AWS credentials for the operator which may be used to restrict its AWS access (defaults to the AWS credentials set above)
cortex_aws_access_key_id: ***
cortex_aws_secret_access_key: ***

# EKS cluster name for cortex (default: cortex)
cluster_name: cortex

# AWS region
region: us-east-1

# S3 bucket (default: &lt;cluster_name&gt;-&lt;RANDOM_ID&gt;)
# note: your cortex cluster uses this bucket for metadata storage, and it should not be accessed directly (a separate bucket should be used for your models)
bucket: # cortex-&lt;RANDOM_ID&gt;

# list of availability zones for your region (default: 3 random availability zones from the specified region)
availability_zones: # e.g. [us-east-1a, us-east-1b, us-east-1c]

# instance type
instance_type: t3.medium

# minimum number of instances (must be &gt;= 0)
min_instances: 1

# maximum number of instances (must be &gt;= 1)
max_instances: 1

# disk storage size per instance (GB) (default: 50)
instance_volume_size: 50

# instance volume type [gp2, io1, st1, sc1] (default: gp2)
instance_volume_type: gp2

# instance volume iops (only applicable to io1 storage type) (default: 3000)
# instance_volume_iops: 3000

# whether the subnets used for EC2 instances should be public or private (default: "public")
# if "public", instances will be assigned public IP addresses; if "private", instances won't have public IPs and a NAT gateway will be created to allow outgoing network requests
# see https://docs.cortex.dev/v/0.18/miscellaneous/security#private-cluster for more information
subnet_visibility: public  # must be "public" or "private"

# whether to include a NAT gateway with the cluster (a NAT gateway is necessary when using private subnets)
# default value is "none" if subnet_visibility is set to "public"; "single" if subnet_visibility is "private"
nat_gateway: none  # must be "none", "single", or "highly_available" (highly_available means one NAT gateway per availability zone)

# whether the API load balancer should be internet-facing or internal (default: "internet-facing")
# note: if using "internal", APIs will still be accessible via the public API Gateway endpoint unless you also disable API Gateway in your API's configuration (if you do that, you must configure VPC Peering to connect to your APIs)
# see https://docs.cortex.dev/v/0.18/miscellaneous/security#private-cluster for more information
api_load_balancer_scheme: internet-facing  # must be "internet-facing" or "internal"

# whether the operator load balancer should be internet-facing or internal (default: "internet-facing")
# note: if using "internal", you must configure VPC Peering to connect your CLI to your cluster operator (https://docs.cortex.dev/v/0.18/guides/vpc-peering)
# see https://docs.cortex.dev/v/0.18/miscellaneous/security#private-cluster for more information
operator_load_balancer_scheme: internet-facing  # must be "internet-facing" or "internal"

# CloudWatch log group for cortex (default: &lt;cluster_name&gt;)
log_group: cortex

# additional tags to assign to aws resources for labelling and cost allocation (by default, all resources will be tagged with cortex.dev/cluster-name=&lt;cluster_name&gt;)
tags:  # &lt;string&gt;: &lt;string&gt; map of key/value pairs
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

cortex cluster up
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Cluster should be created.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cristianmtr' date='2020-07-17T12:02:12Z'>
		It seems like I didn't have the right permissions after all. AWS is very confusing 😠 Sorry for posting here
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>