<bug id='1448' author='dakshvar22' open_date='2020-10-14T23:00:07Z' closed_time='2020-11-26T21:45:20Z'>
	<summary>Number of process started on replica do not match processes_per_replica</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

0.20.0
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I have set processes_per_replica to 5, but when the API goes live on my replica, only three processes are started for it. I particularly request for GPU as the config shows below. Since, i am using g4dn.xlarge instance the total GPU memory available at disposal is 16 GB. Each process should take up 2.2 GB and hence when the 3 processes start I can see that around 7GB is still free to be occupied. The cortex logs also do not indicate any errors because of which processes may not be able to start.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Configuration&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;- name: ###
  kind: RealtimeAPI
  predictor:
    type: python
    path: predictor.py
    processes_per_replica: 5
    threads_per_process: 1
    image: dakshvar22/cortex_custom:hub
  compute:
#    cpu: 1
    gpu: 1 # this is optional, since the api can also run on cpu
    mem: 14G
  autoscaling:  # (aws only)
    min_replicas: 1  # minimum number of replicas (default: 1)
    max_replicas: 4  # maximum number of replicas (default: 100)
    init_replicas: 1  # initial number of replicas (default: &lt;min_replicas&gt;)
    window: 10s
    upscale_stabilization_period: 10s
    max_upscale_factor: 2
  update_strategy:
    max_surge: 0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deliahu&gt;@deliahu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 This could be model dependent and hence I may not be able to give a perfect reproducible setup for it. What would be the best way to help debug this?
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Number of processes started equal the number of processes_per_replica
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Actual behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Number of processes started is always equal to just 3 irrespective of whatever number I set for processes_per_replica&gt;=3
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dakshvar22' date='2020-10-15T02:42:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dakshvar22&gt;@dakshvar22&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have a few follow up questions:

Would you be able to post your API's logs? If they include sensitive information, you can also email them to us at dev@cortex.dev.
How are you determining how many processes are running?
If you set processes_per_replica to 2, do you get 2 processes?
If you run a different model, e.g. examples/pytorch/iris-classifier, are you able to get 3 processes?

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dakshvar22' date='2020-11-16T16:30:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dakshvar22&gt;@dakshvar22&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this still an issue for you, or has it been resolved?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dakshvar22' date='2020-11-26T21:45:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dakshvar22&gt;@dakshvar22&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'll go ahead and close this issue now, feel free to reach out if are still running into this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>