<bug id='1593' author='nellaG' open_date='2020-11-24T10:14:44Z' closed_time='2020-11-25T14:41:55Z'>
	<summary>submitted the job request with "workers: 20" but only 5 spot instances are running</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

0.22.1
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

hello,
when I'm submitting the job request with workers value above 5, only 5 spot instances are running and remaining quantity of requested workers are in pending status. (e.g. when workers is 20, only 5 workers are running and 15 workers are pending)
I checked AWS EC2 spot worker autoscaling group via AWS console, when the job is submitted, the desired capacity is set to 5. (not 20)
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Configuration&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;cortex.yaml
- name: 
  kind: BatchAPI
  predictor:
    type: python
    path: predictor.py
    image: cortexlabs/python-predictor-gpu:0.22.1
    env:
      ENV: aws
  compute:
    mem: 2G
    gpu: 1
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;cluster.yaml
instance_type: g4dn.xlarge
min_instances: 0
max_instances: 200
instance_volume_size: 30
instance_volume_type: gp2
spot: true
spot_config:
    instance_distribution: [g4dn.xlarge]
    on_demand_base_capacity: 1
    on_demand_percentage_above_base_capacity: 0
    on_demand_backup: true # recommended for production clusters
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ cortex cluster info
aws region:                                    ap-northeast-2
availability zones:                            [ap-northeast-2a, ap-northeast-2c]
instance type:                                 g4dn.xlarge
min instances:                                 0
max instances:                                200
use spot instances:                            yes
spot instance distribution:                    [g4dn.xlarge]
spot on demand base capacity:                  1
spot on demand percentage above base capacity: 0
spot instance pools:                           1
on demand backup:                              yes
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


configure max_instances above 5
submit the job with workers above 5
get the job info with cortex get {api_name} {job_id}

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

all of requested workers are should be running  concurrently
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Actual behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

only 5 workers are in running and remaining is pending
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Screenshots&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(optional)
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Stack traces&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(error output from cortex logs &lt;api name&gt;)
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;&lt;paste stack traces here&gt;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(optional)
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Suggested solution&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(optional)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-24T16:40:02Z'>
		Was your  setting initially set to 5 and then you used the  command to raise the  to 200? If this is the case, then you've encountered the bug &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cortexlabs/cortex/issues/1567&gt;#1567&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. This bug affects  command and doesn't update the maximum cluster size correctly. The fix for this bug will in v0.23 (the next release).
In the meantime, it would be great if you could spin up a new cluster cortex cluster up -c cluster.yaml using cortex 0.22.1 with the min/max set to the desired values and try submitting the job again. Let us know how it goes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-24T20:20:22Z'>
		Following up on this, the fix for the  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cortexlabs/cortex/issues/1567&gt;#1567&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 was included in the 0.22.1 patch release. So the previous scenario may not apply to you.
I tried to reproduce the issue using your configuration, a g4dn.xlarge cluster on us-west-2 but it worked as expected for me. When I submitted a job requesting 10 workers (each worker requiring 1 gpu), my autoscaling group desired capacity changed to 10.
Given that I can't reproduce the issue, you can help me investigate this bug by running the command  the next time you encounter this issue. This command will export information about the current state of your cluster to a zip file. It would be great if you can email the zip file to me at &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:vishal@cortexlabs.com&gt;vishal@cortexlabs.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 so that I can investigate the issue in greater detail.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-25T02:28:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vishalbollu&gt;@vishalbollu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes. of my cluster was set to 5 initially as you said, and after  was set to 200 manually via AWS EC2 auto scaling group console. When I checked cluster info using  , I checked that  was set to 200 correctly. Should I not have set the  value using AWS Console?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-25T04:50:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nellaG&gt;@nellaG&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes that is correct: because there are a few places where the max instances must be updated, it should be done via the cortex CLI. I don't think you'll have to spin down your cluster to fix it, you should be able to do one of the following:
If you have a &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.cortex.dev/install#configure-cortex&gt;cluster configuration file&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, update  in the file, and run:
cortex cluster configure --config cluster.yaml
If you don't have a cluster configuration file, it will prompt you to specify max instances when you run:
cortex cluster configure
Let us know if that resolves it for you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-25T07:03:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deliahu&gt;@deliahu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
   I just updated  value using  command, and now everything works fine. Thanks for your help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nellaG' date='2020-11-25T14:41:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nellaG&gt;@nellaG&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that's awesome! Let us know if you have any other questions/issues down the line. In the meantime, I'll close this ticket.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>