<bug id='184' author='Siegelcpp' open_date='2020-07-24T02:43:25Z' closed_time='2020-08-01T20:58:40Z'>
	<summary>ImportError: cannot import name '_ciphey_core_py' from partially initialized module 'cipheycore'</summary>
	<description>
I installed ciphey under macos 10.15.5 and encountered such an error. How to solve it? I installed it according to the steps in the document.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/44493013/88356466-7c29e700-cd9a-11ea-8e5b-c22eca8a76c9.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-07-24T02:43:27Z'>
		Issue Label Bot is not confident enough to auto-label this issue. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/Ciphey/Ciphey&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-07-25T10:28:02Z'>
		Hey!
Can you try installing Ciphey's release candidate?
python3 -m pip instal lciphey==5.0.0rc9
:D
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-07-25T20:27:04Z'>
		Just a note: I am having problems building cipheycore for macos python 3.7. If the problem persists with the rc, try running on python 3.8 (if possible).
I am in the process of overhauling the build system (again), as windows builds are completely failing
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-07-26T05:13:19Z'>
		
嘿!
您可以尝试安装Ciphey的候选发行版吗？
python3 -m pip instal lciphey==5.0.0rc9
：D

Thanks for your suggestion, I have tried it and it still doesn't work

嘿!
您可以尝试安装Ciphey的候选发行版吗？
python3 -m pip instal lciphey==5.0.0rc9
：D

Thank you for your suggestions, I have tried it and it still doesn’t work. Looking forward to your updates, this is a very promising tool
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-07-31T22:45:34Z'>
		I have fixed macos builds for python versions 3.7 and 3.8. Installing the latest ciphey (v5.0.0rc10) should give you something that works better
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-08-01T02:42:34Z'>
		This is pretty cool, thanks for the update and I'll build it right away
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Siegelcpp' date='2020-08-01T20:58:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Siegelcpp&gt;@Siegelcpp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 We've just pushed version 5 (), which definitely should not have this problem. Please feel free to reopen this issue if we have  screwed up and this still exists there!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>