<bug id='518' author='547y4m' open_date='2020-10-26T07:21:27Z' closed_time='2020-10-27T12:16:49Z'>
	<summary>Missing underscores while decoding a Atbash string.</summary>
	<description>

 Have you read our Wiki page "Common Issues &amp; Their Solutions"?
----&gt;Yes

Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
-----&gt; Underscores are neglected while outputting decoded string which is encoded with atbash cipher.
Plaintext
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ciphey -t "Tizmg_nv_zxxvhh_gl_gsv_nzk_kovzhv"
Result 'Grant me access to the map please' (y/N): y
Format used:
  atbash
  reverse
  atbash
  leet
  atbash
  reverse
Final result: "Grant me access to the map please"

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Version

OS/Distro: [Kali Linux 2019.2]
Python version: [Python 3.7.5rc1]
Ciphey versions: [Version: 5.5.2, Version: 0.3.1, Version: 0.3.26]
Did you use Docker?
-----&gt;No

Verbose Output
[https://gist.github.com/547y4m/bbebeea865dfe7f63f4269466071edef]
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:


What input did you use?
"Tizmg_nv_zxxvhh_gl_gsv_nzk_kovzhv"


What flags / arguments did you use?  (-t)
ciphey -t "Tizmg_nv_zxxvhh_gl_gsv_nzk_kovzhv"


Expected behavior
I expect that output would be with underscores, but they are missing.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-26T07:21:30Z'>
		Issue-Label Bot is automatically applying the label bug to this issue, with a confidence of 0.74. Please mark this comment with 👍 or 👎 to give our bot feedback!
Links: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marketplace/issue-label-bot&gt;app homepage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://mlbot.net/data/Ciphey/Ciphey&gt;dashboard&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hamelsmu/MLapp&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for this bot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-26T11:35:43Z'>
		This isn't really a bug. It's a result of the leetspeak decoder and not the atbash decoder. The atbash decoder doesn't get rid of punctuation or special characters. You can test this with
ciphey -t "Tizmg_nv_zxxvhh_gl_gsv_nzk_kovzhv" -C regex -p regex.regex=Grant_me
The leetspeak decoder replaces underscores with spaces because people usually use underscores to represent spaces. I don't see the problem with your example because it does use underscores as spaces in between words.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-26T11:43:35Z'>
		I admit it but while testing same with cyberchef  atbash module it outputs with underscores. So, just feeled that it's any kindof bug or something.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-26T11:50:02Z'>
		Well, what do you suggest we should change? Is there a situation that you can think of that would actually make this a problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-26T13:34:18Z'>
		Yes, you should if it can be easily fixed because i don't think that adding underscores requires much manipulation in code. And as a ciphey contributor/lover i would like that it will perform well and beats other competitor.
The situation/scenario happens with me yesterday, that even i get the decoded text but my flag format is wrong and i have to shift on cyberchef from ciphey to get the correct flag which is really disappointing as a ciphey user. Great tools focuses on every small to big errors.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='547y4m' date='2020-10-27T12:16:49Z'>
		This problem is because "hello_my_name_is_bee" isn't English unless you take away the underscores. Per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Ciphey/Ciphey/wiki/Common-Issues-&amp;-Their-Solutions#ciphey-runs-forever--cant-decrypt-this-input&gt;our wiki&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this is expected behaviour that will change with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Ciphey/Ciphey/wiki/Checkers,-explained#entropy-coming-soon&gt;our new checkers&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 
In the first wiki page, I talk about why CyberChef can decode that string and Ciphey can't:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/10378052/97300628-a0d8a380-184e-11eb-86a3-198cf9f3ea9b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

And in the 2nd wiki page, I describe how we're going to solve the problem of not being able to decode that string:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/10378052/97300677-b057ec80-184e-11eb-8a28-b74ab92dfd50.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>