<bug id='11962' author='jiajinyu' open_date='2018-08-01T06:06:35Z' closed_time='2019-05-08T22:35:41Z'>
	<summary>Distributed and local train have different results when training a wide-deep network.</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

We see small but noticeable difference of outputs when we trained a wide-deep network. The difference only happened when we have both deep and wide parts of the network. We only used one worker and have the local command as  OMP_NUM_THREADS=4 MXNET_CPU_WORKER_NTHREADS=24 python train.py some_other_params and  distributed command as OMP_NUM_THREADS=4 MXNET_CPU_WORKER_NTHREADS=24  incubator-mxnet/tools/launch.py  -n 1 --launcher=local python  train.py some_other_params --kvstore dist_async
To find out where the diff occurs, we have code like this to log the values/states
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;suffix = 'single' if args.kvstore is None else args.kvstore
mod.save_params('module-train-checkpoint-{}-{}.params'.format(suffix, nbatch))
mx.nd.save('batch_{}_{}_inputs.ndarray'.format(nbatch, suffix), batch.data)
mod.forward(batch)
outputs = mod.get_outputs()[0]
mx.nd.save('batch_{}_{}_outputs.ndarray'.format(nbatch, suffix), outputs)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

What we see is that both params and inputs are the same, but the outputs from distributed and local train are different, which is really strange to me.
May I ask how to debug and check from here? Thanks.
P.S. This doesn't occur in the wide deep model in the MXNet example
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jiajinyu' date='2018-08-01T18:23:13Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this issue.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nswamy&gt;@nswamy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you please add labels: Question, Bug, Distributed
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jiajinyu' date='2018-08-03T00:02:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiajinyu&gt;@jiajinyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Could you please provide a minimum reproducible code?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jiajinyu' date='2018-08-03T01:13:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nswamy&gt;@nswamy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for working on it. The whole program is mixed with our custom logic like new data parser etc. so it is very hard to provide a minimum  reproducible code.
All I am asking is some suggestions from the community on how to further debug the issue. For an example, what states/variables of which class I should check to find out the root cause of the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jiajinyu' date='2018-11-27T20:51:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiajinyu&gt;@jiajinyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Have you tried kvstore dist_syn?, and when you say difference how much of a difference do you observe?
If you can share a reproducible example it would be great.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jiajinyu' date='2019-04-11T19:38:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiajinyu&gt;@jiajinyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you try &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/vrakesh&gt;@vrakesh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's suggestions and let us know if you still see different/inconsistent outputs ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jiajinyu' date='2019-05-08T22:35:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jiajinyu&gt;@jiajinyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Close this issue due to lack of response. Please feel free to reopen it if problem persist.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>