<bug id='15200' author='ThomasDelteil' open_date='2019-06-10T22:57:50Z' closed_time='2019-09-30T16:20:38Z'>
	<summary>Broken Sidebar on website API for master</summary>
	<description>
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/versions/master/api/python/index.html&gt;https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/versions/master/api/python/index.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3716307/59232215-60648100-8b98-11e9-877c-7ccb03277b30.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

vs
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3716307/59232225-6f4b3380-8b98-11e9-8341-84cda489ad99.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-10T22:57:53Z'>
		Hey, this is the MXNet Label Bot.
Thank you for submitting the issue! I will try and suggest some labels so that the appropriate MXNet community members can help resolve it.
Here are my recommended labels: Doc
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-10T22:58:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aaronmarkham&gt;@aaronmarkham&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-12T17:18:52Z'>
		Bad news
I tested a variety of build configurations.

In settings, I turned the artifacts feature on and off.
I built all versions plus using 1.5.x to see if a recent cut had a similar problem. It does not. 1.5.x looks fine.
I built a variation of master with a different name and the nav is broken.


I tested changing the &lt;denchmark-link:http://34.201.8.176/versions/1.4.1/api/python/index.html&gt;default version to 1.4.1 and it works&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or see the &lt;denchmark-link:http://34.201.8.176/&gt;root working and test the dropdown&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-12T19:03:43Z'>
		I tried rolling back to some older commits and found the site to work.
Then after trying many older commits I decided to look at the s3 previews coming out of CI for anything in  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/commits/master/docs&gt;history&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. This is very strange - the previews have broken navs then working navs in no obvious order.

broken: http://mxnet-ci-doc.s3-accelerate.dualstack.amazonaws.com/PR-14987/8/api/python/index.html
working: http://mxnet-ci-doc.s3-accelerate.dualstack.amazonaws.com/PR-15111/2/api/python/index.html
working: http://mxnet-ci-doc.s3-accelerate.dualstack.amazonaws.com/PR-15156/4/api/python/index.html
working: http://mxnet-ci-doc.s3-accelerate.dualstack.amazonaws.com/PR-15185/1/api/python/index.html
broken: http://mxnet-ci-doc.s3-accelerate.dualstack.amazonaws.com/PR-15205/1/api/python/index.html

Maybe something was going on with CI (and still is?).
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T00:44:13Z'>
		Have you tried to rebuild one of those commits locally?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T00:51:28Z'>
		I built every commit backwards until I narrowed it down to this one:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/pull/14987&gt;#14987&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Should I revert this commit? I can't see how it would be causing the issues, but the commit just prior comes out ok.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T16:04:52Z'>
		I noticed that the content is in the page, but not visible. I don't know why this bug would only affect master, but I imagine the solution is in the javascript that moves the sidebars around.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/docs/_static/js/sidebar.js&gt;https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/docs/_static/js/sidebar.js&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This area of code is the source of several bugs - from the footer overlapping content when the page toc is too short to not opening the page you expect.
I pointed the website default to 1.4.1 to lessen the disruption for users for now. I don't think I should do a revert on the commit I narrowed down to because the changes wouldn't have this kind of impact. It has to be something else.
I think we need someone to focus on the core issue - the js hacks on the theme and try to fix those directly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T16:24:24Z'>
		Could it be the changes from HTML to md in the links?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T16:29:02Z'>
		Can you try to use the browser Dev tools and debug keepExpand to see why the links are not generated? Could be that they don't come from sphynx from a quick look I didn't see anything obvious with the markdown vs HTML.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-06-13T21:43:37Z'>
		Yes. It seems like there are quite a few bugs in there - variables that should be tracking what's an API page that are undefined. Seems to be less a doc problem and more a front-end engineering problem to me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-26T21:14:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aaronmarkham&gt;@aaronmarkham&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


I noticed that the content is in the page, but not visible

Well. I tried to compare the working V1.4.1 vs master
Here's the console output
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Ideal Condition. V1.4.1&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/10992635/61981685-2ec04180-afaf-11e9-88ce-95cb2b2c24c6.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Master&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Div &lt;div class="sphinxsidebar leftsidebar"&gt; exists. But the content is missing.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/10992635/61981676-2b2cba80-afaf-11e9-8b99-4724fdd24dfa.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Any idea what am I missing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-26T21:22:45Z'>
		I don't know much about sphinx.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/docs/_static/mxnet-theme/layout.html&gt;https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/docs/_static/mxnet-theme/layout.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This seems to reference localtoc: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sphinx-doc/sphinx/blob/master/sphinx/themes/basic/localtoc.html&gt;https://github.com/sphinx-doc/sphinx/blob/master/sphinx/themes/basic/localtoc.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Which seems to be missing. So I guess the toc is not being generated correctly. Let me generate the docs and see if there's some error message with the TOC.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-26T23:36:52Z'>
		I think the problem is in sidebar.js  that component is loaded dynamically in JS. It has to be debugged with the browser dev tools. I would recommend side to side debugging with 1.4 and 1.5 to find out what's the problem.
A breakpoint in render_lefttoc or render_left_helper...   from sidebar.js
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-27T01:11:31Z'>
		I think the problem is in the generated html,is missing the element ul class "current" so the selector gets an empty text. Looks like generation problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-27T01:26:41Z'>
		It's quite puzzling, I have look at many places, compared with 1.4.1 and don't find the root cause.
We are using the same sphinx version, the templates are not changed...  but somehow the left sidebar is not generated properly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-27T02:10:57Z'>
		Yup. Went through the steps you mentioned, (breakpoints, comparison with previous version, debug)
But missing the root cause..
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-29T18:18:05Z'>
		We need to bisect, to find out when it was broken. I have a script to do that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-29T18:44:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/larroy&gt;@larroy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Not sure if it is worth the effort. We're hoping to launch a refactored website soon and we won't be using any of this old js or sphinx theme. But, if it's easy and you want to try... don't let me stop you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-07-29T21:26:23Z'>
		OK, I have other things to do, I thought this was important for the release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='ThomasDelteil' date='2019-09-30T16:20:37Z'>
		New site makes this a moot issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>