<bug id='15206' author='aaronmarkham' open_date='2019-06-11T00:30:51Z' closed_time='2019-10-19T17:04:08Z'>
	<summary>markdown to html link converter fails on links within tables</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The converter for markdown links to html links used in the website doesn't work for links in tables.
This has been causing broken links.
Take for example this table in the build from source guide:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/versions/master/install/build_from_source.html#installing-mxnet-language-bindings&gt;https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/versions/master/install/build_from_source.html#installing-mxnet-language-bindings&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

At the moment these links are broken. They should have been converted but were not. The links are fixed by hardcoding them to be .html links. I did this in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/pull/15205&gt;#15205&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. But, then browsing this file on github will make those links broken. I chose website &gt; github. Anyway this conversion tool or feature needs to be looked into to see if we can't fix it for when links are in tables.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='aaronmarkham' date='2019-06-11T00:30:54Z'>
		Hey, this is the MXNet Label Bot.
Thank you for submitting the issue! I will try and suggest some labels so that the appropriate MXNet community members can help resolve it.
Here are my recommended labels: Doc
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='aaronmarkham' date='2019-06-15T00:51:05Z'>
		I researched this problem and found that there's an upgrade to recommonmark compared to what we're using.
On a test server:
I upgraded recommonmark to v0.5.0 and ccommonmark&gt;=0.7.3 which ends up being 0.9.0.
I successfully build, but saw many new warnings (which will fail in CI). Aside from this, the upgrade still didn't fix the links in markdown tables. It looks like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rtfd/recommonmark/issues/3&gt;table support has been requested since 2015&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
We need another utility with better features, or just don't use markdown tables. Neither sounds appealing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='aaronmarkham' date='2019-06-15T00:55:01Z'>
		Also, we've been having issues with recommonmark for a long time:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MXNET-958&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MXNET-958&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Maybe an alternative package is the right way to go.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='aaronmarkham' date='2019-10-19T17:04:07Z'>
		Moot issue
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>