<bug id='16762' author='vexilligera' open_date='2019-11-08T16:24:19Z' closed_time='2019-11-11T03:30:00Z'>
	<summary>Windows build from source failure</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(A clear and concise description of what the bug is.)
I followed the official tutorial for building MXNet with CUDA 9.2 from source using Visual Studio 2017 on Windows Server 2016.
The compilation was successful, however I encountered this linking error:
LINK : fatal error LNK1248: image size (894C8000) exceeds maximum allowable size (80000000) [C:\incubator-mxnet\build\mxnet.vcxproj]
Is there any setting I can tweak to fix this? Thanks.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Error Message&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(Paste the complete error message, including stack trace.)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(If you developed your own code, please provide a short script that reproduces the error. For existing examples, please provide link.)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://mxnet.apache.org/get_started/windows_setup.html&gt;Follow this tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(Paste the commands you ran that produced the error.)




&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;What have you tried to solve it?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;





&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

We recommend using our script for collecting the diagnositc information. Run the following command and paste the outputs below:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;curl --retry 10 -s https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dmlc/gluon-nlp/master/tools/diagnose.py | python

# paste outputs here
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vexilligera' date='2019-11-08T16:33:05Z'>
		Issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/issues/16033&gt;#16033&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 suggests using the Release configuration to reduce the image size, which I think it already is as in the tutorial. I also noticed the MinSizeRel configuration but was not sure what that means.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='vexilligera' date='2019-11-10T15:47:18Z'>
		the all cuda arch make a too big image size.not use all arch,choose it with you gpu.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='vexilligera' date='2019-11-11T03:30:00Z'>
		
the all cuda arch make a too big image size.not use all arch,choose it with you gpu.

Thank you, that should work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='vexilligera' date='2019-12-06T14:30:25Z'>
		I encounter the same problem with -DCUDA_ARCH_LIST=Common. But then when I change to -DCUDA_ARCH_LIST=Pascal I can compile and link it on windows. It would be good to let people know how to compile for a specific gpu card
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>