<bug id='16926' author='Wallart' open_date='2019-11-27T15:28:24Z' closed_time='2019-11-28T07:51:58Z'>
	<summary>autograd.is_training() does not work on hybridized networks.</summary>
	<description>
Hello everyone,
I might have found an issue about autograd.is_training().
I've implemented a transformer. At training time my network is returning predictions and attention weights for plotting. During inference it's only returning predictions. After the training phase I'm doing validation on a new dataset. Here is a basic description of the problem
Training loop core :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;with autograd.record():
  output, attn_w_1, attn_w_2 = transformerNet(someInputs)
  # loss compute, backward, trainer step, etc.
output = transformerNet(someInputs)
# compute validation score
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Transformer hybrid_forward end :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;if autograd.is_training():
   return logits, attn_w_1, attn_w_2
return logits
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Everything is working fine except when I hybridize the network. During validation autograd.is_training() is always true and the method returns 3 variables instead of 1.
I am using MXNet 1.5.1. Is this behavior normal. If so it should be added to hybridize() documentation
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Wallart' date='2019-11-28T07:51:58Z'>
		Hybridization traces the input during the first forward pass to the hybridized network. Afterwards it will re-use the computational graph established during the initial trace.
To solve your issue, simply create two instances of your network. Both should share parameters and both can be hybridized. Just use one of them for training, the other one for validation.
You're very welcome to submit a PR that clarifies the documentation.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Wallart' date='2019-11-28T07:56:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Wallart&gt;@Wallart&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/issues/16932&gt;#16932&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 be helpful? Please comment there if you have any concerns.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Wallart' date='2019-12-02T08:51:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/leezu&gt;@leezu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you for your answer. Yes, it would be helpful.
I will submit a PR to clarify the documentation
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>