<bug id='17819' author='rbavery' open_date='2020-03-11T23:51:54Z' closed_time='2020-03-17T18:20:32Z'>
	<summary>Why is nvcc not installed along with cuda in mxnet docker builds?</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying to reproduce this repository: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/msracver/FCIS&gt;https://github.com/msracver/FCIS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which depends on an older version of mxnet, 1.4.1. I've using &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/layers/mxnet/python/1.4.1_gpu_cu80_py2/images/sha256-d069471816ee1184bfffb644b173c17cf0d9a80f54448a669ee8defa6beeea38?context=explore&gt;https://hub.docker.com/layers/mxnet/python/1.4.1_gpu_cu80_py2/images/sha256-d069471816ee1184bfffb644b173c17cf0d9a80f54448a669ee8defa6beeea38?context=explore&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

But when I try to compile FCIS's custom operators I get an error that nvcc is not found in my PATH, because it is not installed in the usual location at /usr/local/cuda/bin (there is no bin folder in the cuda directory).
Here is my Dockerfile. The build completes but the step sh init.sh fails because there is no nvcc to compile the custom operators
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;FROM mxnet/python:1.4.1_gpu_cu80_py2 as mxnet

RUN apt-get update

RUN apt-get install -y --fix-missing git build-essential

RUN pip install Cython \
    &amp;&amp; pip install opencv-python==3.2.0.6 \
    &amp;&amp; pip install easydict==1.6 \
    &amp;&amp; pip install hickle \
    &amp;&amp; cd /home \
    &amp;&amp; git clone https://github.com/msracver/FCIS.git \
    &amp;&amp; apt-get install -y libopenblas-dev

RUN cd /home/FCIS \
    &amp;&amp; sh ./init.sh

RUN pip install pillow matplotlib pyaml jupyterlab scipy scikit-image \
    &amp;&amp; mkdir /home/code \
    &amp;&amp; mkdir /home/data
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rbavery' date='2020-03-13T21:01:49Z'>
		Did you verify the problem exists for the latest (1.6 or master) docker images?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rbavery' date='2020-03-17T18:20:32Z'>
		I need to use older docker versions to reproduce the FCIS repo, but I fixed the issue by going back to version .12 where nvcc is included in the builds.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rbavery' date='2020-03-17T19:54:20Z'>
		I understand you need an older release for FCIS. However, if you believe nvcc should be distributed in mxnet containers, it would be good to verify if this is still a problem so that it can be fixed for new versions of mxnet.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>