<bug id='19579' author='m-ky' open_date='2020-11-23T13:12:52Z' closed_time='2020-11-25T13:08:01Z'>
	<summary>mxnet_75.dll chosen, even if there is newer mxnet_86.dll present</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

MXNet 1.8.0.rc2, Windows 10, Cuda 11, NVIDIA RTX 3090, C++ build from source
After build there are several mxnet_XY.dll, where X is cuda major and Y minor version. For RTX 3090 mxnet_86.dll should be used.
However this dll is not chosen, instead it tries to select mxnet_75.dll.
This causes:

Either mxnet_75.dll is there, which causes PTX compilation to start, if mxnet_75.dll contains PTX code (even if there is mxnet_86.dll that can be used right away).
Or mxnet_75.dll is not there, which crashes program on first use of any mxnet function (nullpointer).

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Error Message&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Either unnecessarily builds PTX code (if it is present), or crashes on nullpointer exception when mxnet_75.dll is not present.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Build C++ package from source on Windows using Cuda 11.
MXNET_CUDA_ARCH can be auto (on RTX 3090 this means sm86), or all.
The use any mxnet function from C++.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;What have you tried to solve it?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

In file tools/windowsbuild/warp_dll.cpp, there is function find_version() that should return which mxnet sm version should be used.
Third line in that function should be changed to:
int version = 86;
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

MXNet 1.8.0.rc2, Windows 10, Cuda 11, NVIDIA RTX 3090, C++ build from source
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='m-ky' date='2020-11-23T18:34:40Z'>
		
C++ build from source

If you're only interested in running on a single GPU architecture, you can just set USE_SPLIT_ARCH_DLL=0
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='m-ky' date='2020-11-24T14:38:32Z'>
		Thank you for response.
I actually use multiple GPU architectures and need the splitting functionality.
My fix seems to work fine, I just wanted to let people know that there is bug.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='m-ky' date='2020-11-24T18:41:05Z'>
		Ok, great! Would you open a PR with the fix?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='m-ky' date='2020-11-25T13:08:01Z'>
		After some looking I found that it is already fixed in master:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/pull/19410&gt;#19410&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I will ask to merge this fix to 1.8.0
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>