<bug id='5748' author='KeLipeng' open_date='2017-04-09T15:25:14Z' closed_time='2018-08-21T23:44:43Z'>
	<summary>MXNet fcnxs examples: GPU memory usage varies during training.</summary>
	<description>
When training the fcnxs examples, the GPU memory varies from 3GB to the MAX GPU Memory, which looks like a GPU memory leak problem. Did anybody get the same issue?
Also, how can we see the feature map when testing on an image? I mean, how can I see a specific layer's output without defining it as the output in the symbol file.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-04-10T03:23:17Z'>
		
Same here. It's related to the image size. the symbols are bound each time a new image coming.
The monitor is what you looking for. Or you can define some simple debug symbol.

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-04-10T08:39:25Z'>
		Thanks, I got it. It is the image size that varies the GPU memory usage. (I forget that the input size varies)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-04-11T03:46:52Z'>
		Similar issue regarding feature map: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/issues/5150&gt;#5150&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-04-12T00:35:03Z'>
		Thanks, Haibin, I found that before, but actually I am looking for some
method that could enable me to monitor the feature maps without predefining
it as output in symbol file.

Lipeng
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Tue, Apr 11, 2017 at 11:47 AM, Haibin Lin ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Similar issue regarding feature map: #5150
 &lt;#5150&gt;

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#5748 (comment)&gt;, or mute
 the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AZrAF4lZRRvJE9j__avpGypHlGmYuNruks5ruve_gaJpZM4M4Dkk&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-09-29T18:19:07Z'>
		This issue is closed due to lack of activity in the last 90 days. Feel free to ping me to reopen if this is still an active issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='KeLipeng' date='2017-12-30T00:26:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/orgs/apache/teams/mxnet-committers&gt;@apache/mxnet-committers&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: This issue has been inactive for the past 90 days. It has no label and needs triage.
For general "how-to" questions, our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.mxnet.io/&gt;user forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (and &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.gluon.ai/&gt;Chinese version&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) is a good place to get help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='KeLipeng' date='2018-03-20T16:23:55Z'>
		Proposed Label: Bug, Memory, Performance, Example
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='KeLipeng' date='2018-08-17T19:17:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/KeLipeng&gt;@KeLipeng&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it looks like you now understand the primary issue of variable gpu memory usage, so going to request for this issue to be closed. Just to confirm, you were seeing this effect because the input images were of different sizes, leading to different sized feature maps and thus different amounts of memory used.
With regards to the secondary question related to inspecting feature maps. You have to specify it as an output to your model with Module API. What problem does this cause? But with Gluon API (before hybridizing) you can inspect feature maps and kernels really easily. Since you have access to the array values you can calculate summary statistics, plot images, etc. Also I'd recommend &lt;denchmark-link:https://mxnet.incubator.apache.org/tutorials/vision/cnn_visualization.html&gt;this tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for visualizing CNNs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='KeLipeng' date='2018-08-17T19:20:47Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yzhliu&gt;@yzhliu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 should be good to close this issue, thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>