<bug id='7273' author='thirdwing' open_date='2017-07-31T20:44:02Z' closed_time='2020-01-13T14:47:54Z'>
	<summary>[R] call im2rec in R</summary>
	<description>

No description provided.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='thirdwing' date='2017-08-06T15:02:44Z'>
		This is indeed needed. Currently we can create the rec files using python but to be able to stay completely in R is an advantage. All we need is a To-Do list to outline the work to be done to be able to create the rec files from R.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='thirdwing' date='2017-08-06T20:53:58Z'>
		I think this shouldn't be too hard. I always used the C++ version of im2rec from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/tools/im2rec.cc&gt;https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/tools/im2rec.cc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='thirdwing' date='2017-08-08T13:42:57Z'>
		Yes, it should not be that difficult but im2rec depends on opencv and this is not available in R. Can someone please confirm?
As far as I can see we need to export the functions MXRecordIOWriterCreate,MXRecordIOReaderReadRecord,MXRecordIOWriterWriteRecord and MXRecordIOReaderFree to R. And this is done in mxnetR is by registering these functions using something like MXNET_REGISTER_IO_ITER. See ~\src\io\iter_image_recordio_2.cc (line 599).
If we are able to adapt this then it should be fairly simple to write the im2rec function in R.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='thirdwing' date='2017-08-08T15:06:14Z'>
		First, OpenCV is optional. It is not available in the pre-built pkg. However, you can add OpenCV support when compiling from source.
Second, I don't think we need to implement  in R, since we have a &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/blob/master/tools/im2rec.cc&gt;C++ implementation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. We just need to call it from R. This is almost done in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/thirdwing/mxnet/tree/iss7273&gt;https://github.com/thirdwing/mxnet/tree/iss7273&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='thirdwing' date='2017-09-26T14:48:17Z'>
		This breaks compiling the R package even if USE_OPENCV=0 is used in config.mk. Since using OpenCV is optional, I think the R package and imports should respect the settings in config.mk.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='thirdwing' date='2017-10-20T11:34:34Z'>
		I agree with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/areobe&gt;@areobe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. This killed the R bindings on a system with no OpenCV.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='thirdwing' date='2018-09-05T18:53:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sandeep-krishnamurthy&gt;@sandeep-krishnamurthy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 please label - "Feature Request"
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='thirdwing' date='2020-01-13T14:47:53Z'>
		Let's track the bugs introduced by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/pull/7389&gt;#7389&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 separately. I opened &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apache/incubator-mxnet/issues/17282&gt;#17282&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Currently this feature request of this issue has been implemented, though breaking other use-cases that were previously supported.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>