<bug id='90' author='CT-Yang' open_date='2017-05-15T17:43:48Z' closed_time='2018-05-23T14:32:17Z'>
	<summary>Bounding Box line dissapear</summary>
	<description>
As I mentioned in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tzutalin/labelImg/issues/87&gt;#87&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 's second problem.
Last time I meet this problem at computer A.This issue happened after I had used labelImg for a while. When I change to computer B, the problem disappeared, but after few days, this problem happened again.
It seems like after using for a while, the problem will happen.
Can you give me some clue about what will cause this problem?
And does anyone have the same issue like me? It will be appreciated that you share your way to solve this problem.
Thanks.

OS:Ubuntu 16.04.2 LTS
PyQt version: 4

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CT-Yang' date='2017-05-18T04:11:02Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CT-Yang&gt;@CT-Yang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Do you have more clue about this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CT-Yang' date='2017-05-18T13:26:32Z'>
		I mention in advance here:
Here I only have one computer B with Ubuntu OS and labelImg software.  My group members(include me) all used other software(ex: MobaXterm) to access computer B and label the images.This is our current situation.
Just one observation I can share with u:
Before this problem happened, I opened the labelImg one night,  then after I labeled some images, I didn't terminate it, so I still keep the program running.
Next day, my partners open labelImg again but find that problem happen again and tell me. I go to see but due to I still opened the program so in my labelImg window, I still can see the box line.
Even we change to another directory to label, I still can see the box line. But everyone who re-open labelImg can't see the box line anymore.
I am now still not close the labelImg, so until now,only me can see the box line.
This is the only observation I have, hope it can help u to find the bug, tks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CT-Yang' date='2017-05-31T07:07:08Z'>
		I find the way to solve the problem.
When we meet the problem, we can just go to "edit"-&gt;"box line color"-&gt;"restore Defaults"
And the box line will appear again.
It seems like the box line settings change and end up this problem, but all my group member didn't modify the box line color setting, so I still can't figure out why it changed the settings without human modification.
But no matter what, we find out the solution.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CT-Yang' date='2018-05-23T14:32:17Z'>
		I believe this issue has been resolved. Please pull the latest code/binary and let us know if you continue to experience it.
Thanks,
-Vlad
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>