<bug id='84' author='mfojtak' open_date='2019-06-19T07:44:46Z' closed_time='2019-06-26T10:57:41Z'>
	<summary>AdamWarmup cannot be serialized in SavedModel</summary>
	<description>
Describe the Bug
The following warning is thrown when trying to export the model using
tf.keras.experimental.export_saved_model(model, 'saved_model/', custom_objects = bert.get_custom_objects())
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;This model was compiled with a Keras optimizer (&lt;keras_bert.optimizers.warmup.AdamWarmup object at 0x7f8eedb0ada0&gt;) but is being saved in TensorFlow format with `save_weights`. The model's weights will be saved, but unlike with TensorFlow optimizers in the TensorFlow format the optimizer's state will not be saved.

Model was compiled with an optimizer, but the optimizer is not from `tf.train` (e.g. `tf.train.AdagradOptimizer`). Only the serving graph was exported. The train and evaluate graphs were not added to the SavedModel
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Version Info

 I'm using the latest version

Minimal Codes To Reproduce
tf.keras.experimental.export_saved_model(model, 'saved_model/', custom_objects = bert.get_custom_objects())
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mfojtak' date='2019-06-19T08:07:43Z'>
		Why don't you use model.save('xxx')?
Besides, I don't think it's a big problem since the optimizer will run in minimal lr (default is 0) if the states are loaded. You'll either do prediction with the model without the optimizer or rebuild the optimizer for further training.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mfojtak' date='2019-06-19T09:14:52Z'>
		I am using export_saved_model to be able to use the model in tensorflow serving.
It won't even export the training and evaluate graphs if the AdamW is there.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mfojtak' date='2019-06-19T09:59:38Z'>
		I don't think you need the training and evaluation graphs for serving. However, you can re-compile the model at any time:
model.compile(optimizer=tf.train.AdamOptimizer(), loss='sparse_categorical_crossentropy')
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mfojtak' date='2019-06-24T10:19:00Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>