<bug id='364' author='lscrd' open_date='2019-06-19T17:49:41Z' closed_time='2019-07-20T09:34:27Z'>
	<summary>"echo" no longer works with 0.20</summary>
	<description>
The following program fails to compile with 0.20 and with the development version:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import arraymancer
echo [1.0, 2.0].toTensor
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

It seems to be a known issue (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mratsim/Arraymancer/issues/348&gt;#348&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mratsim/Arraymancer/issues/355&gt;#355&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) and it is supposed to have been solved. But, for me, with the current versions, it is still present.
I use stable and development versions built with "choosenim" on a Linux Manjaro.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-01T23:09:07Z'>
		I guess you are using the latest stable version of Arraymancer, devel works.
I will release a new stable version with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mratsim/Arraymancer/pull/349&gt;#349&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 included.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-02T08:37:46Z'>
		Thanks for your answer.
Unfortunately, for me, it doesn’t work with the development version and I get exactly the same error message. In case there was something wrong in my installation, I uninstalled both versions and reinstalled them with no success.
Have you any idea what would cause this different behavior?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-19T00:02:28Z'>
		I've released a new stable version: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mratsim/Arraymancer/releases/tag/v0.5.1&gt;https://github.com/mratsim/Arraymancer/releases/tag/v0.5.1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, hopefully it should work with 0.20.0, 0.20.2 and devel.
Do you still have the issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-19T10:52:12Z'>
		Good news: the program compiles, so the issue seems to be solved.
Bad news: the program doesn’t link. I get an error: Undefined reference to "NIM_UNLIKELY".
Also, in "arraymancer.nimble" the version number is still 0.5.0 instead of 0.5.1, so installation with nimble overwrites the previous 0.5.0 release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-19T16:06:25Z'>
		good catch, I've bumped the versions to v0.5.2.
Regarding NIM_UNLIKELY, it should be defined in nimbase.h
see: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nim-lang/Nim/blob/v0.20.2/lib/nimbase.h#L444-L455&gt;https://github.com/nim-lang/Nim/blob/v0.20.2/lib/nimbase.h#L444-L455&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
That's very strange.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lscrd' date='2019-07-19T20:25:28Z'>
		Thanks for the information. It helped me to find the problem. In the cache directory, I once made a copy of "nimbase.h" in a cache directory and this was this old version which was used.
So, forget it. It was my mistake. Thanks for this new version.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>