<bug id='146' author='kgeis' open_date='2019-12-13T01:16:52Z' closed_time='2019-12-19T22:28:58Z'>
	<summary>typo: selelectWithoutLabel</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
The text tag has a parameter selelectWithoutLabel. It should be selectWithoutLabel. I am hesitant to offer a pull request because a change could break users' existing solutions. A deprecation strategy is suggested, and I'm not sure how to do that with your code.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Visit https://labelstud.io/tags/text.html
See spelling

Expected behavior
The label should be selectWithoutLabel.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kgeis' date='2019-12-16T08:30:09Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kgeis&gt;@kgeis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Hi! I'm not sure about default state is .
The main reasons:

The logic for all tags should be the same for future HOC.
The main task of markup data is to separate different labels &amp; entities.

But I think it's a good idea to create more concise names of parameters for tags. For example change selectWithoutLabel to emptyLabel (or similar).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kgeis' date='2019-12-16T08:34:47Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/shevchenkonik&gt;@shevchenkonik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I don't understand your comment. I'm just saying that the parameter name has an extra "le" in it. Maybe this makes it more clear: 
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kgeis' date='2019-12-16T08:58:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kgeis&gt;@kgeis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 haha I did not notice typos :)
Yes, you are right about deprecation strategy and in the the current version we can leave a selelectWithoutLabel and add new one as selectWithoutLabel (and add TODO comment):
/** TODO */
if (!self.selelectwithoutlabel || !self.selectwithoutlabel) /** ... */;
In the next major release, we will update the logic of this tag and will add major release note.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kgeis' date='2019-12-19T22:28:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kgeis&gt;@kgeis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for reporting. That was fixed in the latest release
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>