<bug id='217' author='guneemwelloeux' open_date='2020-02-17T17:36:03Z' closed_time='2020-05-18T18:04:10Z'>
	<summary>Labelling page does not work with HTTPS redirect</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
After deploying the app behind a HTTPS-redirecting proxy, the Labelling page does not work anymore.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Deploy the app behind NGINX, configured to redirect HTTP to HTTPS requests
Go to Labelling
See error in console:
Mixed Content: The page at 'https://label.mydomain.dev/' was loaded over HTTPS, but requested an insecure resource 'http://label.mydomain.dev/api/projects/1/next/'. This request has been blocked; the content must be served over HTTPS.

Expected behavior
The app should follow all the redirects and the api call should succeed, the scheme being conserved at each step of the way.
Environment (please complete the following information):

OS: macOS
Browser Chrome
Version 80.0.3987.87

Additional context
I believe the redirect issued by label-studio upon calling "api/projects/1/next" is not taking the scheme into account, when it should
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='guneemwelloeux' date='2020-02-25T15:56:37Z'>
		There is no easy way to support HTTPS in Label Studio. I suggest you may try to do the following modifications in server.py file:

SSLify flask app using

from flask_sslify import SSLify
...
sslify = SSLify(app, permanent=True)

Add certificates to SSL context while running app, i.e. when app.run is launched, add

app.run(
            host='0.0.0.0',
            port=input_args.port,
            debug=input_args.debug,
            ssl_context=(
                'fullchain.pem',
                'privkey.pem'
            )
        )
Hope this helps!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='guneemwelloeux' date='2020-03-04T10:37:04Z'>
		This solution may work when we do ssl termination at the app, what if we want to do the ssl termination at loadbalancer?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='guneemwelloeux' date='2020-04-06T06:52:12Z'>
		The solution proposed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/niklub&gt;@niklub&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 works when the app does the SSL termination. However, since in my case is behind a reverse proxy (traefik), the optimal soution would be to conserve the scheme for every call. Any suggestions?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>