<bug id='306' author='RenJinan' open_date='2020-06-02T04:01:10Z' closed_time='2020-09-28T12:19:56Z'>
	<summary>A bug in audio related task</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
In the audio task, when I click the audio waveform, the audio playing pointer does not move to the position of my mouse pointer, resulting in that every time I want to listen to a part in the middle, I always listen from the beginning.
To Reproduce

Go to 'labeling'
Click on waveform
See error that the audio playing pointer does not move to the position of my mouse pointer

Expected behavior
the audio playing pointer move to  the position of my mouse pointer.
Environment:

OS: Windows 10
Browser: chrome
Version: 0.7.0

Additional context
This problem does not exist in the ’interface preview‘ in the ‘Setup’, but it will appear when labeling.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RenJinan' date='2020-06-02T15:38:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hlomzik&gt;@hlomzik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='RenJinan' date='2020-06-05T22:14:04Z'>
		Hey, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RenJinan&gt;@RenJinan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! It sounds strange, especially if it works in preview. Could you please provide your config? How long is your audio? And what the error do you see? Screenshots or browser console output would be very helpful.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='RenJinan' date='2020-06-06T03:45:47Z'>
		Thank you very much for your reply! My configuration file is the same as the official sample, but the problem still exists. I made a GIF to show this problem and look forward to your help.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/50946537/83935225-33b66a00-a7ea-11ea-9ed8-5a51168bd23e.gif&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Hey, @RenJinan! It sounds strange, especially if it works in preview. Could you please provide your config? How long is your audio? And what the error do you see? Screenshots or browser console output would be very helpful.

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='RenJinan' date='2020-06-08T19:12:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hlomzik&gt;@hlomzik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 have you any ideas?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='RenJinan' date='2020-06-09T13:30:22Z'>
		No ideas sadly :(
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RenJinan&gt;@RenJinan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do you have errors in browser console?
I checked this config in LSF, it works well. I'll check in LS soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='RenJinan' date='2020-07-08T12:26:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RenJinan&gt;@RenJinan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 have you tried to use AudioPlus tag?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='RenJinan' date='2020-09-28T12:20:14Z'>
		I hope it's fixed after 0.7.3 release.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>