<bug id='360' author='yaochenglouis' open_date='2020-07-16T07:53:07Z' closed_time='2020-09-28T13:04:54Z'>
	<summary>tasks loading error on gcloud run</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
deployed on google cloud with the one click button on readme.md page, a cloud run instance is successfully created. but it seems that this instance is always denied to read a gs bucket file. every time i click on tasks it shows following error:
Tasks loading error
Error calling the IAM signBytes API: b'{\n "error": {\n "code": 403,\n "message": "The caller does not have permission",\n "status": "PERMISSION_DENIED"\n }\n}\n'
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Go to 'TASKS' and configure cloud bucket correctly
TASKS will show the correct number of images in cloud bucket
give allUsers cloud admin permission
refresh page tasks to see error

Expected behavior
i suppose i should have seen images but there wasn't any
Screenshots
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
Environment (please complete the following information):

OS: ubuntu
Browser chrome
Version [e.g. 22]

Additional context
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yaochenglouis' date='2020-07-16T19:07:43Z'>
		Can you tell more about this step: "give allUsers cloud admin permission"?
What permissions were before this step? Can you send screenshot - where do you change these permissions in gcloud?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yaochenglouis' date='2020-07-17T10:51:44Z'>
		
Can you tell more about this step: "give allUsers cloud admin permission"?
What permissions were before this step? Can you send screenshot - where do you change these permissions in gcloud?

Thanks for your reply.
After the one click deployment on gcloud, I created a task based on my gs bucket right away without changing any permission policy of anything. The IAM 403 denied error appeared right after that.
I supposed that "The caller does not have permission" was due to lack of permission for the requested gs bucket so I changed permission configuration in my gs bucket page and let allUsers to be Cloud Storage Admin (so my gs bucket went public, and normally any request from anyone should be accepted and not denied. ). That didn't work.
I've also looked into the permission config page of cloud run but I don't know what to do
Basically, I don't know what permission is required by LabelStudio to load and show my images on gs bucket
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yaochenglouis' date='2020-08-03T22:17:37Z'>
		@fishyboy Have you managed to do something about this problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yaochenglouis' date='2020-09-28T13:04:54Z'>
		I hope you've fixed this issue. By the way we've added some improvements in 0.7.4 release relative to s3 access rights (region problems).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>