<bug id='427' author='andreaferretti' open_date='2020-09-17T10:40:07Z' closed_time='2020-09-24T16:44:22Z'>
	<summary>Task page shows completion that was never created</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
Every new task shows some kind of completion, even before starting labeling anything.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Import some tasks
Open any task
Under completions, see New completion Created undefined by Awesome User

Expected behavior
The completion list should be empty

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1962818/93459950-d2229300-f8e2-11ea-9d66-10ceb5fdf894.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='andreaferretti' date='2020-09-18T08:01:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/andreaferretti&gt;@andreaferretti&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It's not a bug, LS creates new one completion automatically. It doesn't store on backend side and it's temporary to immediately start annotations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='andreaferretti' date='2020-09-18T08:59:04Z'>
		I understand. It is still strange to see that, though, for various reasons:

who is Awesome user?
the completion looks like any real completion (for instance, it can be deleted, it can be set as ground truth)
it is not clear that the completion is empty (my first istinct was to try and figure out what was in there)

I suggest to not show this temporary completion on the frontend side, even if it is necessary to create it for technical reasons
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='andreaferretti' date='2020-09-19T13:27:33Z'>
		


who is Awesome user



I've removed Awesome user, and now it's a little bit clearly:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/501780/93668376-8b749a80-fa94-11ea-8208-e0ccf25dbb63.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

2 &amp; 3.

the completion looks like any real completion
it is not clear that the completion is empty

But it has a blue point at the left and name "New completion".
Yes, it's a little bit confusing, I think we will rework this mechanics in future.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='andreaferretti' date='2020-09-21T08:52:23Z'>
		Thank you, this is already much more clear
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>