<bug id='441' author='kir4h' open_date='2020-09-25T14:56:25Z' closed_time='2020-09-25T17:32:36Z'>
	<summary>Docker image v0.7.4 unavailable</summary>
	<description>
Opening this issue, not exactly a bug but I guess it's the best category out of the 3 (not using the template because it doesn't make sense)
I was taking a look at the versioning and noticed:

Version 0.7.4 is tagged in the repository but not available on Docker Hub. Is this on purpose?
Version 0.7.5 is not yet tagged, currently there is only a release branch; however, version 0.7.5 is available on Docker Hub. Is this correct? (wondering if some kind of suffix should be added if this is still based on a release branch)

Thank you for the clarifications!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T15:10:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kir4h&gt;@kir4h&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes, it's some confusion in docker tags. But as far as I remember the latest tag is 0.7.4 version.
0.7.5 is not officially released yet, it's only a release candidate for tests.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T15:18:45Z'>
		Yup, that's what it looks like from the repository point of view; but I think 0.7.4 should be pushed so that anyone using docker can use the latest stable version (and maybe relabeling current 0.7.5 to 0.7.5rcx like it was done in the past with 0.7.2)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T15:33:21Z'>
		Yes, it's a good point and we missed it unfortunately
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T16:34:48Z'>
		Out of curiousity: Are those images manually built/pushed? Checking Github Actions I don´t see any docker related stuff. I wouldn´t mind rebuilding and pushing the missing version but this should be done by someone with the required priviledges in Docker Hub
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T16:39:51Z'>
		Yes, now it's manually. But before we had auto-builds, they was broken because of npm install into dockerhub problems.
By the way, I pushed 0.7.4.post0 build.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kir4h' date='2020-09-25T17:32:30Z'>
		
By the way, I pushed 0.7.4.post0 build.

thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>