<bug id='460' author='nopper' open_date='2020-10-20T17:47:47Z' closed_time='2020-11-06T14:06:48Z'>
	<summary>Unable to annotate relations locally: Label studio entity panel is missing</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
I am unable to use relations annotations, both using latest pip version of label-studio or using the cloned github repository.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

pip install label-studio
label-studio init test &amp;&amp; label-studio start test
Connect to  http://0.0.0.0:8080/ via browser.
Click on Setup your label config.
Click on Relations among entities and confirm on the dialog box by clicking on Proceed.
On the interface preview on the right you will see the text Note: To manage relations you need Label Studio entity panel to be shown.

Expected behavior
I am expecting to see relation annotation pane as I see in the label-studio playground site.

What I see locally:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/129937/96624440-08ea2f80-130d-11eb-9463-e880fd17435d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

What I see on the official playground site:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/129937/96624332-e48e5300-130c-11eb-8425-aa840f3c9edc.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nopper' date='2020-10-20T21:06:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nopper&gt;@nopper&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you show your screen entirely?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nopper' date='2020-10-20T22:17:46Z'>
		I've just checked this in latest LS version, everything looks ok..
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nopper' date='2020-10-21T13:40:00Z'>
		Sure here's the screenshot of the full page:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/129937/96727686-a39d4980-13b3-11eb-9225-1716b3b8bd10.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nopper' date='2020-10-21T13:49:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nopper&gt;@nopper&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 But it's Setup page, you don't need to make a labeling here. Use Labeling or Tasks page, after you setup the project.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nopper' date='2020-10-21T14:00:32Z'>
		Ok then my bad.
I was a confused by the fact that this was working in the Setup page on the playground site, but not locally in the Setup page. Therefore I didn't even bother saving the setup because I thought something was off.
I would probably add a clarification in the Setup page, if what you will see in the labeling phase will be different then what I am seeing in the project/Setup phase.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='nopper' date='2020-10-21T14:02:27Z'>
		Yes, it's a good point to write about it. Thank you, I think we will add it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='nopper' date='2020-11-06T14:06:48Z'>
		We've added Result panel on the Setup page in 0.8.0.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>