<bug id='687' author='tbenthompson' open_date='2019-09-11T16:17:18Z' closed_time='2019-11-05T15:23:44Z'>
	<summary>Support min_gain_to_split and max_delta_step</summary>
	<description>
These are two useful parameters in LightGBM that we are using in our non-spark models. max_delta_step controls the maximum output of a tree leaf. min_gain_to_split sets the minimal gain to perform split. Both can be useful for regularization purposes.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tbenthompson' date='2019-09-11T16:20:02Z'>
		More generally, is there some way to support the full range of LightGBM parameters in pyspark by just passing through a parameters dictionary? Many of these parameters don't affect (I think!) the sparkification and parallelization and I wonder if mmlspark can avoid replicating the full parameters API.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tbenthompson' date='2019-09-16T21:54:07Z'>
		hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tbenthompson&gt;@tbenthompson&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  sorry about the issue you are having.  There is a hacky way to add parameters by putting them on any of the string fields (pass the original value, then a space, followed by param_name=param_value).  However, for now I would prefer to actually have users tell me what parameters should be on the learner since LightGBM in mmlspark is still relatively new.  I do agree it would be nice to add optional parameters through a parameter dictionary at some point, but I'm not sure if that point is now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tbenthompson' date='2019-09-17T00:17:38Z'>
		I just found max_bin_by_feature to be missing and it would be a useful parameter for me
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tbenthompson' date='2019-11-05T15:39:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tbenthompson&gt;@tbenthompson&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chris-smith-zocdoc&gt;@chris-smith-zocdoc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 PR has been merged to add min_gain_to_split, max_delta_step and max_bin_by_feature, thank you for the feedback!
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tbenthompson' date='2019-11-05T16:11:28Z'>
		Thanks so much!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='tbenthompson' date='2020-11-05T23:01:02Z'>
		Hi, all I want to know how I can set these parameters (max_bin_by_feature, min_gain_to_split) when using mmlspark LightGBM. Looking at the docs here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://mmlspark.blob.core.windows.net/docs/0.18.1/pyspark/mmlspark.lightgbm.html&gt;https://mmlspark.blob.core.windows.net/docs/0.18.1/pyspark/mmlspark.lightgbm.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, none of those parameters are listed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>