<bug id='11195' author='justKidrauhl' open_date='2020-03-20T10:05:17Z' closed_time='2020-03-20T17:49:29Z'>
	<summary>Failed to execute any maven operation to Alluxio</summary>
	<description>
Alluxio Version:
What version of Alluxio are you using?
v2.1
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
Failed to execute any maven operations on Windows.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior (as minimally and precisely as possible)
I'm using Intellij IDEA2019.3.3 and Maven 3.6.3 on Win10.
I tried to run "maven clean" but failed. The error info is "Failed to execute goal org.codehaus.mojo:exec-maven-plugin:1.4.0:exec"
I found out there's a linux instruction "rm".

A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
I checked out Alluxio's website and found this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/28786663/77153465-c4778680-6ad4-11ea-8d00-348b208b7f6b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So 

Describe the impact and urgency of the bug.
Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='justKidrauhl' date='2020-03-20T10:09:19Z'>
		If it's feasible to build alluxio on Windows, I also want to know how to fix the problem：
"Failed to execute goal org.codehaus.mojo:exec-maven-plugin:1.4.0:exec".
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='justKidrauhl' date='2020-03-20T17:49:29Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/justKidrauhl&gt;@justKidrauhl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Alluxio does not currently support any windows platforms. You'll need to build and run Alluxio on a Linux or MacOS-based operating system.
Another option which you can try (but is not supported), is to compile directly through the command line using &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10&gt;WSL&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You can also try using VirtualBox to launch a CentOS/Ubuntu VM which you can then install IntelliJ and maven on.
Hope this helps. I'm closing this issue because we don't support windows, and I don't think that we will. If you still have issues compiling on other platforms you can re-open this issue
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>