<bug id='12126' author='TrafalgarZZZ' open_date='2020-09-22T04:51:37Z' closed_time='2020-11-11T23:54:50Z'>
	<summary>loadMetadata can't return immediately after all the metadata is loaded</summary>
	<description>

What version of Alluxio are you using?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/tree/branch-2.3-fuse&gt;https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/tree/branch-2.3-fuse&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
I mount an Aliyun OSS including about 3.8 million small files on Alluxio, after then I run the alluxio fs loadMetadata -R / to load metadata of all the files in my OSS.
What confuses me is that before the alluxio fs loadMetadata -R / return, I run the followiing command:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;bash-4.4# alluxio fsadmin report metrics | grep Master.TotalPaths
Master.TotalPaths  (Type: GAUGE, Value: 3,804,850)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

And the value "3804850" is exactly the number of all my files in my OSS. So it seems to me all the metadata has already been loaded, however, the alluxio fs loadMetadata -R / command still won't return until about 10min later.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior (as minimally and precisely as possible)
Try to load metadata of large amount of files and run the report metrics to check Master.TotalPaths
Expected behavior
A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
The loadMetadata command should return as soon as the job is done
Urgency
Describe the impact and urgency of the bug.
Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='TrafalgarZZZ' date='2020-09-23T03:03:55Z'>
		this may be related to client-side calculating results streamed from master
We may need bring back some previous change from
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/3272/files&gt;https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/3272/files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/8546/files&gt;https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/8546/files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='TrafalgarZZZ' date='2020-11-11T23:54:50Z'>
		this should be fixed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/12421&gt;#12421&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>