<bug id='8947' author='apc999' open_date='2019-05-01T05:15:42Z' closed_time='2019-05-08T20:58:54Z'>
	<summary>Docker does not work with certain property keys</summary>
	<description>
Alluxio Version:
2.0.0-SNAPSHOT
Describe the bug
$ bin/alluxio runClass alluxio.cli.GetConfKey ALLUXIO_MASTER_MOUNT_TABLE_ROOT_OPTION_AWS_ACCESSKEYID
alluxio.master.mount.table.root.option.aws.accesskeyid
and alluxio.master.mount.table.root.option.aws.accesskeyid will not work but only alluxio.master.mount.table.root.option.aws.accessKeyId will work
To Reproduce
passing ALLUXIO_MASTER_MOUNT_TABLE_ROOT_OPTION_AWS_ACCESSKEYID as the property to docker
Expected behavior
We should have one way to pass the property
Urgency
High
Additional context
One solution might be making Alluxio properties case independent by fixing alluxio.conf.PropertyKey#isValid and alluxio.conf.PropertyKey#fromString
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='apc999' date='2019-05-02T07:31:03Z'>
		As an alternative solution, instead of relying on camel case I think we should always . between words as is convention for (probably) &gt; 90% of the property keys. I think we should follow the same convention for all keys.
While not affected by the casing of the characters I'm specifically thinking about tiered storage keys that use level0, level1, etc.. instead of level.0, level.1...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='apc999' date='2019-05-02T17:27:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ZacBlanco&gt;@ZacBlanco&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , I discussed this issue with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aaudiber&gt;@aaudiber&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , another approach might be just pass all properties to   through env variable like ,  or . Then we don't need to modify the code but only the recommended way to run docker.
Independently, we agree with you that, we should have the same convention to name all keys.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='apc999' date='2019-05-03T16:13:51Z'>
		Looks like there are some keys that must be in mixed cases 


alluxio/shell/src/main/java/alluxio/cli/GetConfKey.java


         Line 31
      in
      12d159a






 .put("AWS_ACCESSKEYID", "aws.accessKeyId") 





I think we should just use JAVA_OPTS for everything.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='apc999' date='2019-05-06T23:12:20Z'>
		Created &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Alluxio/alluxio/pull/8993&gt;#8993&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to support spaces in environment variables, and also recommend using  for everything
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='apc999' date='2019-05-08T20:58:54Z'>
		Both 1.8 branch and master branch have this fix. Close this ticket now
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>