<bug id='196' author='vapaunic' open_date='2019-05-21T14:01:29Z' closed_time='2019-05-23T17:16:01Z'>
	<summary>typos and minor corrections in 02_multilabel_classification notebook</summary>
	<description>


Rename multilabel to multi-label for consistency. Multilabel occurs in many places throughout the notebook, like the title and the first subtitle. It looks like in other notebooks, or even in this one, hyphenation is used, e.g. multi-label, multi-class, single-label, etc., so keep to that format for consistency.


This notebook contains multiple instances of term fastai. Consider renaming to fast.ai for consistency.  E.g “This section that covers training a model with fastai is very … “ and “ Unlike traditional accuracy, fastai does not …” etc


from fastai.vision import * … consider importing only needed objects, to follow best practices in python code.


Typo: Lets should be changed to  let’s. There are many instances of lets in the notebook, find them all and correct them to let’s. E.g. “Lets set that directory to our path variable … “, “Lets break down the code:” etc.


Typo in classification in “Since this is a multilabel classificaiton problem, each image can be associated to multiple labels.”


Typo in formats in “This is one of the most common data formast for multilabel …“


In “lets use fast.ai's data block apis”, I’d also suggest using APIs instead of apis, since this is an abbreviation.


Reword “Finally we'll normalize the databunch (normalize(imagenet_states) to the imagenet parameters.” to “Finally, we'll normalize the databunch (normalize(imagenet_states) to the ImageNet parameters.”


Typo “accuries” in “While hamming and zero-one accuries are a common evaluation metric for … ”


	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vapaunic' date='2019-05-23T17:16:01Z'>
		thanks, i believe i can close this with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/computervision-recipes/pull/198&gt;#198&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, pls reopen if that is not the case.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>