<bug id='499' author='chennebe' open_date='2020-02-17T22:55:07Z' closed_time='2020-02-19T18:35:36Z'>
	<summary>[BUG] 22_deployment_on_azure_kubernetes_service.ipynb - AKS deployment fails</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Running classification notebook 22 fails at cell 9 while trying to deploy service. It returns an InvalidDeploymentTemplate error, specifying that the regional cores quota was exceeded:
[{'error': {'code': 'BadArgument', 'message': 'InvalidTemplateDeployment: Details: RequestId: 9618e9b6-5a5e-4b84-92c0-2b7b69144777\nError code: 'InvalidTemplateDeployment'. Target: ''. Message: 'The template deployment 'caae618f-2c9f-4619-b088-48ba57333c1f' is not valid according to the validation procedure. The tracking id is '9618e9b6-5a5e-4b84-92c0-2b7b69144777'. See inner errors for details.'\n    Error code: 'QuotaExceeded'. Target: ''. Message: 'Provisioning of resource(s) for container service imgclass-aks-cpu9fe63651 in resource group docs-aml failed. Message: {\n      "code": "QuotaExceeded",\n      "message": "Provisioning of resource(s) for container service imgclass-aks-cpu9fe63651 in resource group docs-aml failed. Message: Operation could not be completed as it results in exceeding approved Total Regional Cores quota. Additional details - Deployment Model: Resource Manager, Location: eastus2, Current Limit: 4, Current Usage: 0, Additional Required: 12, (Minimum) New Limit Required: 12. Submit a request for Quota increase at https://aka.ms/ProdportalCRP/?#create/Microsoft.Support/Parameters/%7B%22subId%22:%2221e79250-290a-42ea-95b6-46401877475b%22,%22pesId%22:%2206bfd9d3-516b-d5c6-5802-169c800dec89%22,%22supportTopicId%22:%22e12e3d1d-7fa0-af33-c6d0-3c50df9658a3%22%7D by specifying parameters listed in the ‘Details’ section for deployment to succeed. Please read more about quota limits at https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-supportability/regional-quota-requests.. Details: "\n     }. Details: '\n'}}]
Note: This was tested using the free azure credits/subscription, maybe this is contributing to the error?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;In which platform does it happen?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Tested on Linux and Windows machines.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;How do we replicate the issue?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Run through classification notebook 20 and 22.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior (i.e. solution)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Other Comments&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='chennebe' date='2020-02-19T18:35:35Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chennebe&gt;@chennebe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - as you correctly noted above, the error is caused by not having enough regional cores quota.
Message: Operation could not be completed as it results in exceeding approved Total Regional Cores quota. Additional details - Deployment Model: Resource Manager, Location: eastus2, Current Limit: 4, Current Usage: 0, Additional Required: 12, (Minimum) New Limit Required: 12. Submit a request for Quota increase.
We'll close this issue for now, but if you continue to see this issue with a different subscription, feel free to open another one.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>