<bug id='1881' author='lhk' open_date='2020-03-22T16:40:17Z' closed_time='2020-03-23T23:21:54Z'>
	<summary>alignment indices out of range for sequence of tokens</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I would like to use the predicted alignment to match tokens in the in- and output.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

To get alignments, I have modified the hub_utils and changed the following line:



fairseq/fairseq/hub_utils.py


         Line 133
      in
      42f65d6






 return [self.decode(hypos[0]['tokens']) for hypos in batched_hypos] 





I replaced the line with the following code, which will return not only the tokens, but also the alignment:
        return list(zip([self.decode(hypos[0]['tokens']) for hypos in batched_hypos], [hypos[0]['alignment'] for hypos in batched_hypos]))
With this change, the following code will work:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import torch

en2fr = torch.hub.load('pytorch/fairseq', 'transformer.wmt14.en-fr', tokenizer='moses', bpe='subword_nmt')

en = "The sky had changed from clear, sunny cold, to driving sleet and mist. Wrapping myself in my shaggy jacket of the cloth called bearskin, I fought my way against the stubborn storm."
en_tokens = en2fr.tokenize(en)

fr, alignment = en2fr.translate(en, beam=1, print_alignment=True)
fr_tokens = en2fr.tokenize(fr)

en_tokens = en_tokens.split()
fr_tokens = fr_tokens.split()

for a,b in alignment:
    if a&gt;=len(en_tokens) or b&gt;=len(fr_tokens):
        print('out of range')
        continue
    print(en_tokens[a], fr_tokens[b])

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Some of the alignments make sense. For example, it is matching:

clear clair
sunny ensoleillé

But most of the time it outputs "out of range"
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Alignment indices that are not out of range for the tokens. This doesn't necessarily mean that the alignments make perfect sense. But I would expect them to be at least valid for the given data.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


fairseq Version: 0.9.0
PyTorch Version: 1.4.0
OS: Linux
How you installed fairseq: pip
Python version: 3.7.6
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.1 and 7.5
GPU models and configuration: T2000 (mobile gpu)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lhk' date='2020-03-22T17:13:47Z'>
		Here is an easier way to reproduce, execute the following in the terminal:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;curl https://dl.fbaipublicfiles.com/fairseq/models/wmt14.v2.en-fr.fconv-py.tar.bz2 | tar xvjf -
MODEL_DIR=wmt14.en-fr.fconv-py
fairseq-interactive \
    --path $MODEL_DIR/model.pt $MODEL_DIR \
    --beam 5 --source-lang en --target-lang fr \
    --tokenizer moses \
    --bpe subword_nmt --bpe-codes $MODEL_DIR/bpecodes
    --print-alignment
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

As an example, you can enter "There is a bird in the tree"
This produces the alignments: 0-0 0-1 1-2 3-3 3-4 3-5 4-6 6-7 6-8
Curiously, my hacky code version produces different alignments:
(3, 0), (1, 1), (1, 2), (3, 3), (3, 4), (5, 5), (4, 6), (6, 7), (6, 8)
But in both cases, the alignments contain 6-8 and this is out of range for the given tokens.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lhk' date='2020-03-22T21:42:12Z'>
		It's because it's removing the target side BPE when printing. If you comment out the decode_fn line in interactive.py then you get:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;There is a bird in the tree
S-0     There is a bird in the tree
H-0     -0.17229345575966476    Il y a un ois@@ eau dans l&amp;apos; arbre
P-0     -0.8115 -0.1816 -0.0239 -0.0831 -0.0740 -0.0003 -0.0617 -0.1506 -0.0053 -0.3309
A-0     0-0 0-1 1-2 1-3 3-4 3-5 4-6 6-7 6-8
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I'll submit a fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lhk' date='2020-03-23T17:58:48Z'>
		Hi, thanks for the quick answer and help, this is awesome :)
I've added a similar workaround to my local fairseq installation, also outputting both the original and detokenized hypo.
But to be honest, it's not that useful. I would like to use the alignment for further text processing and having the bpe in there is a problem. If the text still contains those weird @@ encoding symbols, it's just not readable.
Is it possible to get an alignment for the detokenized version?
I've read up on your bpe code, but as far as I can see, it's completely independent of anything alignment related. Is there maybe a way to get some kind of tracing, which token ends up becoming which in the detok version?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lhk' date='2020-03-23T20:14:15Z'>
		Hm, after looking at some translations, it seems as if BPE only ever adds @@, potentially more than once.
In fact, the bpe has a bpe_symbol member that seems to be constant.
So does this perform only a single step of bpe?
Can I just merge tokens that end on the bpe_symbol and adjust the alignment accordingly?
And sorry for the off-topic question, but why are you doing this?
I've debug-stepped through the encoding code. It seems to do dictionary lookups for the bpe coded tokens.
This is completely new to me, so far I only had code like this:
raw text -&gt; sequence of tokens -&gt; sequence of dictionary indices -&gt; sequence of embedding vectors -&gt; model
Doesn't bpe interfere with the dictionary lookup e.g. embedding ?
If there is a paper that enlarges on this, I would be very interested.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lhk' date='2020-03-23T23:21:35Z'>
		Here is the original paper that introduced BPE: &lt;denchmark-link:https://arxiv.org/abs/1508.07909&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1508.07909&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. It's pretty widely used these days in machine translation because it allows you to represent a much larger vocabulary without training a separate embedding for every word variant. For example, instead of having an embedding for , , , you might have one for  and then a few for common suffixes (, , ). The  symbol just means that the token is a non-terminal BPE token, so can safely be removed.
Re: alignment, you might look into the paper &lt;denchmark-link:https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.02074&gt;Jointly Learning to Align and Translate with Transformer Models&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. The reference implementation for this is in fairseq: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pytorch/fairseq/tree/master/examples/joint_alignment_translation&gt;https://github.com/pytorch/fairseq/tree/master/examples/joint_alignment_translation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. One thing I noticed from that paper is in Section 5.1 they write:

For all setups and models used in this work, we learn a joint source and target Byte-Pair-Encoding (BPE, Sennrich et al. (2016)) with 32k merge operations. We observe that even for statistical alignment models sub-word units are beneficial. To convert the alignments from sub-word-level back to word-level, we consider each target word as being aligned to a source word if an alignment between any of the target sub-words and source sub-words exists."

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lhk' date='2020-03-24T07:33:33Z'>
		Ah that makes sense.
Ok, then I‘ll be able to adjust the alignment accordingly.
And thanks a lot for the papers
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>