<bug id='2068' author='rmovva' open_date='2020-04-27T05:31:19Z' closed_time='2020-05-04T16:23:49Z'>
	<summary>Issue loading BART-large model finetuned on CNN-DM dataset</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying to load bart.large.cnn finetuned weights according to the README:
bart = torch.hub.load('pytorch/fairseq', 'bart.large.cnn')
But I'm getting the following error that indicates an off-by-one shape mismatch between the trained weights and the weights that the model architecture is expecting:
RuntimeError: Error(s) in loading state_dict for BARTModel: size mismatch for decoder.output_projection.weight: copying a param with shape torch.Size([50265, 1024]) from checkpoint, the shape in current model is torch.Size([50264, 1024]).
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


fairseq Version (e.g., 1.0 or master): master
PyTorch Version 1.5
OS (e.g., Linux): Linux
How you installed fairseq (pip, source): pip
Python version: 3.7.6
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.2

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rmovva' date='2020-04-27T16:39:09Z'>
		Same error here. Hopefully what I see can help to narrow down the issue a bit.
I have two machines, one works, one doesn't.

Machine 1: Works. I initially setup BART (i.e. download model/cache) on this in Feb/Mar 2020.
Machine 2: Throws error. I setup BART on this in the past week. However, it works if I overwrite fairseq cache with Machine 1's cache.

[Cause?] Since machine 2 works when I overwrite the fairseq cache with machine 1's copy (dated Mar 10).  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pytorch/fairseq/files/4540794/fairseq_cache_1.zip&gt;fairseq_cache_1.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

is a copy of the working cached fairseq from machine 1, unsure which commit it is.
[Env] Machine 1 (no error):

fairseq Version (e.g., 1.0 or master): master
PyTorch Version 1.5.0
OS (e.g., Linux): Linux
How you installed fairseq (pip, source): Not installed. There is cache showing version 0.9.0 in setup.py. Cached files dated Mar 10, 2020.
Python version: 3.6.9
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.2

[Env] Machine 2 (same error as rmovva)

fairseq Version (e.g., 1.0 or master): master
PyTorch Version 1.4.0
OS (e.g., Linux): Linux
How you installed fairseq (pip, source): Not installed. Cached files dated Apr 25, 2020. setup.py version is 0.9.0
Python version: 3.6.10
CUDA/cuDNN version: 10.2

[Temporary Fix] If you cannot wait to use BART (like me), try overwrite ~/.cache/torch/hub/pytorch_fairseq_master with a copy of fairseq from Mar 10, 2020 (I didn't test this) or the content from zip file (this is an unsafe practice, use at your own risk).
[Misc]

Machine 1 received a conda environment update and GPU driver reinstall in the past week.
I also diff the model.pt from fbaipublicfiles.com and machine 1's cache, they are identical.

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rmovva' date='2020-05-01T19:22:48Z'>
		Same issue any clue when this can be resolved ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rmovva' date='2020-05-04T16:23:49Z'>
		Fixed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pytorch/fairseq/commit/7a6519f84fed06947bbf161c7b66c9099bc4ce53&gt;7a6519f&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>