<bug id='1791' author='prabhat00155' open_date='2019-09-09T20:52:29Z' closed_time='2019-09-09T22:01:24Z'>
	<summary>cast to string not implemented in onnxruntime</summary>
	<description>

Cast(&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/master/docs/Operators.md#Cast&gt;https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/master/docs/Operators.md#Cast&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) op defined in the onnx spec describes conversion of numeric tensors to string tensors, whereas onnxruntime doesn't seem to implement this(See 
).
This is needed to support multiple types of input in Scikit's OneHotEncoder converter.
System information

ONNX Runtime version (you are using): 0.5.0

Describe the solution you'd like
Cast to support conversion of numeric tensors to string tensors. For example:
[[1, 2, 3], [3, 4, 5]] -&gt; [['1', '2', '3'], ['3', '4', '5']]
Describe alternatives you've considered
Currently, we just support multiple inputs of same type.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='prabhat00155' date='2019-09-09T21:12:57Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/prabhat00155&gt;@prabhat00155&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
I think that specific error message is mis-leading. If you look closely, that comes under the 'MLFLoat16' section. I think what they meant to write was "Casting to strings from float16 is not supported yet."
Casting to/from strings is supported (atleast looking at the code)-



onnxruntime/onnxruntime/core/providers/cpu/tensor/cast_op.cc


         Line 93
      in
      75f241d






 inline void CastFromStringData(const Tensor* in, Tensor* out, const TensorShape&amp; shape) { 








onnxruntime/onnxruntime/core/providers/cpu/tensor/cast_op.cc


         Line 72
      in
      75f241d






 inline void CastToStringData(const Tensor* in, Tensor* out, const TensorShape&amp; shape) { 





Does this help ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='prabhat00155' date='2019-09-09T21:16:03Z'>
		Do you mean to say casting from int to string is supported? I was getting error when I tried to do that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='prabhat00155' date='2019-09-09T21:19:17Z'>
		It does seem to be. (I didn't implement Cast - just answering based on what I see in the code). What is the error you are getting ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='prabhat00155' date='2019-09-09T22:01:01Z'>
		I had a loop where I was converting all the inputs to string. The input were of types string and int, and on further debugging I found out that it was string inputs that caused the error, not int.
RuntimeError: Method run failed due to: [ONNXRuntimeError] : 1 : GENERAL ERROR : /Users/vsts/agent/2.155.1/work/1/s/onnxruntime/core/providers/cpu/tensor/cast_op.cc:413 virtual onnxruntime::common::Status onnxruntime::Cast&lt;std::__1::basic_string &gt;::Compute(onnxruntime::OpKernelContext *) const [T = std::__1::basic_string] Unexpected 'to' argument value: 8
Stacktrace:
I think I should put a check for input type and type-cast only int inputs. Thanks for your help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='prabhat00155' date='2019-09-09T22:14:06Z'>
		No problem. Thanks for pointing out the incorrect error message.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>