<bug id='1810' author='dashesy' open_date='2019-09-11T19:51:38Z' closed_time='2019-09-11T20:59:11Z'>
	<summary>RuntimeError: Method run failed due to: [ONNXRuntimeError] : 2 : INVALID_ARGUMENT : Non-zero status code returned while running Node:  Status Message: 'axes' has an out of range axis</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
After adding random names to exported model and checking the node the issue is with exported unsqueeze with axes of -1. The node is not added in my code
Urgency
Workaround is to use non-negative axis number
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): 16.04
ONNX Runtime installed from (source or binary): pip
ONNX Runtime version: 0.4
Python version: 3.5

To Reproduce
torch.stack((bbs0, bbs1, bbs2, bbs3), dim=-1)
Expected behavior
Run unsqueeze  with axis -1
Additional context
Sent the model
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dashesy' date='2019-09-11T20:10:36Z'>
		torch.stack was adding the unsqueeze, changed to dim=4 as workaround but -1 is valid axis
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dashesy' date='2019-09-11T20:46:14Z'>
		that is true. will fix, thanks for the info.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dashesy' date='2019-09-11T20:59:10Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dashey&gt;@dashey&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Actually ONNX opset-10 Unsqueeze doesn't support negative axes.
Please see here - &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/rel-1.5.0/docs/Operators.md#Unsqueeze&gt;https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/rel-1.5.0/docs/Operators.md#Unsqueeze&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Only in current master, it is supported - &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/master/docs/Operators.md#Unsqueeze&gt;https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/master/docs/Operators.md#Unsqueeze&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. So when ORT supports opset-11, we will make sure to adhere to spec for Unsqueeze-11.
Closing this ORT currently adheres to spec for Unsqueeze-10. (opset 11 is not yet supported in ORT)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dashesy' date='2019-09-26T14:29:48Z'>
		hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hariharans29&gt;@hariharans29&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I hit the same problem. I use python, how can I fix it since if the pip installed version is not latest and the custom builded is for c++.
What I can do is only change all -1 index to a positive index?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='dashesy' date='2019-09-26T18:47:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/WilliamZhaoz&gt;@WilliamZhaoz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or wait for opset11 in ORT. I looked at each case and found the positive index that would have same results, and changed all -1 to positive index equivalent. -1 is more elegant, but this should work
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>