<bug id='300' author='LexXia' open_date='2019-01-09T08:09:14Z' closed_time='2019-03-13T19:23:42Z'>
	<summary>Build Test "failed", "bidirectional simple weights no bias" test from GRUTest takes too much time</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
I am building onnx runtime (master branch) in ubuntu 16.04 virtual machine. The build progress has finished, followed with test phases. However, the test phase stopped at GRUTest.BidirectionalDefaultActivationsSimpleWeightNoBiasTwoRows. I have waited for more than 4 hours in this step, so I think there is something wrong.
System information

OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): Linux Ubuntu 16.04
ONNX Runtime installed from (source or binary): building
ONNX Runtime version: master branch
Python version: 3.7.1
GCC/Compiler version (if compiling from source):  gcc 5.4.0
CUDA/cuDNN version: -
GPU model and memory: -

To Reproduce
Describe steps/code to reproduce the behavior:
git clone
./build.sh --config RelWithDebInfo --build_wheel
or
./build.sh --build_wheel
Expected behavior
A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
Build and test successful

If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42466682/50885516-dff2f600-1428-11e9-8448-2a56f9490c40.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='LexXia' date='2019-01-09T17:10:55Z'>
		How much memory does the VM have?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='LexXia' date='2019-01-10T03:22:54Z'>
		
How much memory does the VM have?

This VM has 2G memory and 30G disk. I have checked the usage of memory and disk. During the testing phase,  the machine has around 700M free memory and 9G disk available. Therefore, I think the memory and disk amount is not the limitation. Thank you for your response.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='LexXia' date='2019-02-20T21:53:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LexXia&gt;@LexXia&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Have you resolved this issue or do you still need help troubleshooting?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='LexXia' date='2019-03-13T19:23:41Z'>
		Marking the issue as closed. Please reopen if you still require assistance.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>