<bug id='3263' author='jinfagang' open_date='2020-03-19T06:29:33Z' closed_time='2020-09-14T12:20:30Z'>
	<summary>CPU and GPU different behaviour</summary>
	<description>
Hi I found same ONNX model CPU and GPU got different results.
is that int32 casued error?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jinfagang' date='2020-03-19T17:07:14Z'>
		Can you please share more details on the model and which versions of the runtime you are using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jinfagang' date='2020-03-20T03:41:31Z'>
		oh, yes, here is the model. we can feed it forward and compare the output, it's not same and actually some value is wrong (not all value)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://share.weiyun.com/56x0RnE&gt;https://share.weiyun.com/56x0RnE&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Pls my help me have look, it actually can forward using onnxruntime.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jinfagang' date='2020-04-26T20:12:11Z'>
		I have got the same error with the Conv operation. It appears that, after many operations, the value accumulates floating point errors. For example, using 3D convolutions 2 times caused the CPU and GPU outputs to differ little. Further convolutions resulted on a increase of the output error.  2D convolutions resulted on the same problem but only after many layers (50 operations on my test) resulted on the values to differ. Any developments?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jinfagang' date='2020-04-30T10:55:48Z'>
		I have got the same problem which same ONNX mode CPU and GPU got different results, my model is keras_retinanet (backbone is resnet50),  and cpu results are correct (same keras results.)
What causes the difference in results ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jinfagang' date='2020-07-03T02:58:54Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale due to inactivity and will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs. If further support is needed, please provide an update and/or more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jinfagang' date='2020-07-09T10:37:27Z'>
		I have got the same problem using GPU...(Inference with CPU seems to be same as Keras
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/faxu&gt;@faxu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Anything update ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='jinfagang' date='2020-09-07T11:48:22Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale due to inactivity and will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs. If further support is needed, please provide an update and/or more details.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='jinfagang' date='2020-09-14T12:20:29Z'>
		This issue has been automatically closed due to inactivity. Please reactivate if further support is needed.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>