<bug id='1087' author='lucaventurini' open_date='2019-09-11T13:22:42Z' closed_time='2019-09-17T09:04:16Z'>
	<summary>When restarting from checkpoint, the model is trained more than max_epochs</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
As in the title, when loading a model that was already trained for some epochs, setting max_epochs parameter trains for further max_epochs.
To Reproduce
I saved a checkpoint after 3 epochs. When I load this checkpoint and run with max_epochs=3, I see epoch 4, 5, 6 get executed.
Expected behavior
The above behavior could make sense, but I'd really like to set the total max epochs (or my jobs can potentially never end if they keep getting interrupted and restored).
So, in the example above, I would expect that no further epochs are trained.
Alternatively, how can I read how many epochs were already trained when I load the checkpoint?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lucaventurini' date='2019-09-17T09:14:57Z'>
		hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lucaventurini&gt;@lucaventurini&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this should be fixed in master branch. Can you check if it works for you?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lucaventurini' date='2019-09-18T08:22:51Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alanakbik&gt;@alanakbik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , the update seems to work as expected.
I'd only mention that it breaks the loading of a checkpoint made with old code:
/usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/torch/serialization.py:454: SourceChangeWarning: source code of class 'flair.embeddings.DocumentRNNEmbeddings' has changed. you can retrieve the original source code by accessing the object's source attribute or set torch.nn.Module.dump_patches = True and use the patch tool to revert the changes.
  warnings.warn(msg, SourceChangeWarning)
/usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/torch/serialization.py:454: SourceChangeWarning: source code of class 'flair.embeddings.StackedEmbeddings' has changed. you can retrieve the original source code by accessing the object's source attribute or set torch.nn.Module.dump_patches = True and use the patch tool to revert the changes.
  warnings.warn(msg, SourceChangeWarning)
/usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/torch/serialization.py:454: SourceChangeWarning: source code of class 'flair.embeddings.WordEmbeddings' has changed. you can retrieve the original source code by accessing the object's source attribute or set torch.nn.Module.dump_patches = True and use the patch tool to revert the changes.
  warnings.warn(msg, SourceChangeWarning)
Traceback (most recent call last):
  File "train_flair.py", line 163, in &lt;module&gt;
    sys.exit(main(sys.argv[1:]))
  File "train_flair.py", line 155, in main
    trainer = ModelTrainer.load_checkpoint(check_file, corpus)
  File "/usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/flair/trainers/trainer.py", line 489, in load_checkpoint
    model.corpus = corpus
AttributeError: 'dict' object has no attribute 'corpus'
I personally don't need to load old checkpoints though.
Thank you for the fix!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>