<bug id='1644' author='NielsRogge' open_date='2020-05-28T12:23:18Z' closed_time='2020-06-03T06:59:27Z'>
	<summary>ClassificationCorpus not using all data provided</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
ClassificationCorpus is not using all the data provided in 3 txt files (train.txt, dev.txt and test.txt). I suspect this to be an encoding issue, however Pandas is able to read in all the data with the same encoding type (utf-16) provided as parameter.

This &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/14tnyFZhnQHppb8fim8ZLgEwT5hLZx2TB&gt;colab notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Expected behavior
I expect the ClassificationCorpus object to use all data provided. The weird thing is, when I read the txt data as Pandas dataframes, all data is read. But when I read the txt data as ClassificationCorpus objects, some data is not used, as can be seen by the difference in total length (see notebook).
Environment (please complete the following information):

Google Colab
Flair: installed from source

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='NielsRogge' date='2020-05-28T16:46:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NielsRogge&gt;@NielsRogge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for reporting this and sharing the steps to reproduce! &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcelmmm&gt;@marcelmmm&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you take a look at this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='NielsRogge' date='2020-06-01T10:13:33Z'>
		The problem is that in the data file the label and the text is separated by a tab and not a blank.
E.g. one line looks like this:  __label__1\t100st Prunus padus 60/90\n
with a \t between __label__1 and 100st. Now if we have a line where the text consists of only one word the line is not processed since there is no blanks at all in the line. So all the lines with one word are omitted.
It should work if you replace the tabs with blank spaces.
Since this is not a sensible restriction I will add the case where tabs are used to the code.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>