<bug id='174' author='alanakbik' open_date='2018-10-27T16:01:26Z' closed_time='2018-11-07T16:29:35Z'>
	<summary>Sort out serialization of large models on MacOS and Windows</summary>
	<description>
We have been getting a number of reports that serialization of very large models does not work on Mac OS (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/flairNLP/flair/issues/171&gt;#171&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/flairNLP/flair/issues/23&gt;#23&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) and Windows (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/flairNLP/flair/issues/172&gt;#172&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) setups. It seems that this is a problem caused by the pickle module which we use for serialization.
To reproduce the error on Windows / Mac OS, do
from flair.models import SequenceTagger
tagger = SequenceTagger.load('ner-ontonotes-fast')
To fix this we need to either:

Figure out what we must do so that pickling of very large objects (&gt;1GB) works across platforms
Find an alternative to serialization with pickle

Fixing this issue is a priority for us - any help from the community with mac OS / Windows setups is appreciated!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='alanakbik' date='2018-10-30T05:38:35Z'>
		Hi Alan,
I would be glad to help with the testing of flair for Windows.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='alanakbik' date='2018-11-03T14:13:48Z'>
		Is there a tentative date by when this issue would get fixed. For testing on Mac, I can help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='alanakbik' date='2018-11-03T16:57:54Z'>
		Thanks - I'm hoping we'll have this fixed at the beginning of next week and then perhaps do another release (0.3.2) at the end of next week!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='alanakbik' date='2018-11-05T17:49:07Z'>
		I've checked in a workaround to address the problem. Positive side effects are that word embeddings and some trained models are now smaller, so faster to store / load. Also, I've added FastText embeddings for 9 languages in smaller size ('de', 'pl', 'fr', 'it', 'es', 'pt', 'nl', 'ar', 'sv').
This branch now lets me use the 'ner-ontonotes' model and can train large models on my MacOS setup.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/devmaha&gt;@devmaha&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rohitmujumdar&gt;@rohitmujumdar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - could you test this branch on your respective setups?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='alanakbik' date='2018-11-06T06:11:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alanakbik&gt;@alanakbik&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for quick turnaround. I am on it. Will let you know how it goes
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='alanakbik' date='2018-11-06T12:00:20Z'>
		Tested on windows - new model loads faster and works well. I was wondering what those 12 classes are that the model can identify. We could just see only a few.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>