<bug id='802' author='n-ibrahimov01' open_date='2019-06-14T08:43:47Z' closed_time='2019-06-25T12:26:24Z'>
	<summary>I am getting different embeddings every time I initialize CharacterEmbeddings</summary>
	<description>
This is a code that I am using:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;from flair.embeddings import CharacterEmbeddings
c_embeddings = CharacterEmbeddings ()

word_string_1 = "Example"
word_string_2 = "Example"

c_embeddings_1 = CharacterEmbeddings ()
c_embeddings_2 = CharacterEmbeddings ()




sentence_embed_it_1 = Sentence (word_string_1)
sentence_embed_it_2 = Sentence (word_string_2)

c_embeddings_1.embed(sentence_embed_it_1)
c_embeddings_1.embed (sentence_embed_it_2)

for token in sentence_embed_it_1:
    emb_1 =  (token.embedding.data)

for token in sentence_embed_it_2:
    emb_2 =  (token.embedding.data)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

emb_1 and emb_2 return different values.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='n-ibrahimov01' date='2019-06-20T13:48:53Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/n-ibrahimov01&gt;@n-ibrahimov01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes the reason for this is that the  are randomly initialized and only make sense if you train them on a downstream task first. So you can use them when &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zalandoresearch/flair/blob/master/resources/docs/TUTORIAL_7_TRAINING_A_MODEL.md&gt;training your own model&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. During model training, these embeddings will then get trained to make sense for that task.
If you're just interested in embedding text and not in training a downstream task model, you should use any of the pre-trained embeddings, such as WordEmbeddings, FlairEmbeddings and BertEmbeddings.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='n-ibrahimov01' date='2019-06-23T03:47:16Z'>
		Why don't large pretrained character embeddings models exist yet?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='n-ibrahimov01' date='2019-06-24T05:31:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hellisotherpeople&gt;@Hellisotherpeople&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the  are large pre-trained character embeddings.
They're different in that FlairEmbeddings are contextualized and pre-trained, whereas CharacterEmbeddings are uncontextualized and require to be trained on a task. We did some comparisons of the two in our COLING 2018 paper; At least on the tasks we looked at, flair embeddings were much better and when we used them, task-trained character features were no longer necessary.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='n-ibrahimov01' date='2019-06-24T16:20:06Z'>
		I should have read your paper more closely 😁.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='n-ibrahimov01' date='2019-06-25T12:26:24Z'>
		:D no worries - will close this issue, but feel free to reopen if you have more questions!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>