<bug id='197' author='InsciteAnalytics' open_date='2019-07-02T19:03:26Z' closed_time='2019-07-06T14:48:43Z'>
	<summary>Overflow error</summary>
	<description>

Python says its an Overflow error. Seems to be happening during correlation calculations:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/files/3351888/pandas.profiling.error.txt&gt;pandas profiling error.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

To Reproduce
df.info() is as follows:
&lt;class 'pandas.core.frame.DataFrame'&gt;
MultiIndex: 12966 entries, (Aruba, 2018) to (Taiwan, China, 2016)
Columns: 368 entries, Urban_population_(%of_total) to Energy_intensity_level_of_primary_energy(MJ/$2005_PPP)
dtypes: float64(368)
memory usage: 36.4+ MB

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/files/3351899/pip.freeze.txt&gt;pip freeze.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Additional context
In case you might be wondering, its not a multi index issue as the code runs fine on parts of the same dataframe.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='InsciteAnalytics' date='2019-07-04T17:46:52Z'>
		Before calculating the correlations, the package checks if we should even try. Some columns are problematic, for example with a high number of distinct values. My best guess would be that one or more columns in this DataFrame are problematic.
If we know the cause, we can try to detect this beforehand. You could really help us by either narrowing down the columns and/or providing more data on what the characteristics is/are of the problematic column(s).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='InsciteAnalytics' date='2019-07-05T01:04:13Z'>
		Should'nt a try and except solve the issue. It should just say that correlations cant be calculated for those columns and move on instead of the whole program crashing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='InsciteAnalytics' date='2019-07-06T14:48:43Z'>
		In these cases, we would still want diagnostic information. To prevent crashing but still encouraging users to report failing correlations, I've added a try-except clause with a warning.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='InsciteAnalytics' date='2019-07-06T16:37:24Z'>
		Thanks! &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sbrugman&gt;@sbrugman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . I have more than 370 columns so its hard to narrow down. But there are tons of missing values and almost perfect correlation columns. Would it help if i attach a csv of .describe()?
PS: Btw I am getting the same error still. It's happening when it calculates the kendall correlation. The solve in my case was to put OverflowError in the exception (rather than ValueError which is the current case).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>