<bug id='301' author='bufferboy' open_date='2020-01-01T04:06:12Z' closed_time='2020-01-07T00:37:44Z'>
	<summary>I have pandas-profiling installed, but running the task has no results</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
If the description consists of multiple non-related bugs, you are encouraged to create separate issues.
To Reproduce
We would need to reproduce your scenario before being able to resolve it.
Data:
Please share your dataframe.
If the data is confidential, for example when it contains company-sensitive information, provide us with a synthetic or open dataset that produces the same error.
You should provide the DataFrame structure, for example by reporting the output of df.info().
You can anonymize the column names if necessary.
Code: Preferably, use this code format:
"""
Test for issue XXX:
https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/issues/XXX
"""
import pandas as pd
import pandas_profiling


def test_issueXXX():
    df = pd.read_csv(r'&lt;file&gt;')

    # Minimal reproducible code
Version information:
Version information is essential in reproducing and resolving bugs. Please report:

Python version: Your exact Python version.
Environment: Where do you run the code? Command line, IDE (PyCharm, Spyder, IDLE etc.), Jupyter Notebook (Colab or local)
pip: If you are using pip, run pip freeze in your environment and report the results. The list of packages can be rather long, you can use the snippet below to collapse the output.

Click to expand Version information

&lt;&lt;&lt; Put your version information here &gt;&gt;&gt;



Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bufferboy' date='2020-01-01T04:06:59Z'>
		I have pandas-profiling installed, but running the task has no results
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bufferboy' date='2020-01-02T03:44:10Z'>
		Could you provide the minimal information to reproduce this error?

the minimal code you are using to generate the report
which environment you are using (jupyter notebook, console or IDE) and packages (pip freeze &gt; packages.txt)
a sample or description of the dataset (df.head(), df.info())

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bufferboy' date='2020-01-02T18:51:25Z'>
		I encountered the same issue. It turned out to be caused by the lower version of jupyter_core that misses secure_write module.
I fixed it by updating the jupyter version:
pip install --upgrade jupyter_client
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bufferboy' date='2020-01-06T01:23:26Z'>
		
I encountered the same issue. It turned out to be caused by the lower version of jupyter_core that misses secure_write module.
I fixed it by updating the jupyter version:
pip install --upgrade jupyter_client

thank you very much.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>