<bug id='315' author='neomatrix369' open_date='2020-01-11T12:33:34Z' closed_time='2020-01-14T21:34:43Z'>
	<summary>`get_rejected_variables` missing after release of v2.4.0</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
My old code which used to work on a version prior to v2.4.0 now does not work as it uses parameters and methods that have been removed/deprecated in this version.
One of them is access to the list of Rejected variables - this is invaluable for data-processing and other reasoning activities.
I didn't see it mentioned in the release notes or in the docs - that they are removed and if there are alternative ways to accomplish it
How would we do this in the new version? Process the report as a JSON file and then access the rejected variables from there? Any other methods?
The docs are good but would be great to see a format like this, &lt;denchmark-link:https://scikit-learn.org/stable/modules/generated/sklearn.linear_model.LinearRegression.html&gt;https://scikit-learn.org/stable/modules/generated/sklearn.linear_model.LinearRegression.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 where we see a list of all parameters and then potentially examples to follow.
To Reproduce
Version being used: v2.4.0 (worked in the previous version)
Try running the below with the new version of pandas-profiling:
    profile = dataset.profile_report(title=title,
                        # if 'bayesian_blocks_bins': True fails 
                        # to provide a valid number of bins use the below config:
                        #   {'bins': 8, 'bayesian_blocks_bins': False} 
                          plot={'histogram': {'bayesian_blocks_bins': True}}, 
                          style={'full_width': True}, 
                          minify_html=True)
and then also try this:
    filename, fileext = os.path.splitext(output_file)
    rejected_variables_filename = f'{filename}-rejected-variables.txt'
    rejected_variables = profile.get_rejected_variables(threshold=0.9)
    print("Rejected variables: ", rejected_variables)
both will fail to compile/run with errors!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='neomatrix369' date='2020-01-11T14:57:45Z'>
		Hi Mani,
There are three different observations in this one issue: rejected variables are missing, documentation could be more extensive and a bug in bayesian blocks. It would be good to split them into separate issues (a feature request for documentation, a bug report for the bayesian blocks, please make sure to include a dataset). We then can dedicate this issue to the rejected variables.
You have a good point that the removal of the get_rejected_variables was not mentioned. There were a few reasons to remove it (temporarily):

the function used to recalculate the rejections, rather than extract them from the report
the function was restricted to only one kind of correlation (#298 and #299)
negative correlations were not considered (#284)

The v2.4.0 release fixes these issues. The same functionality can now be obtained using:
profile.get_description()['messages']. In v2.4.1 I'll add an improved mapping from the description set to rejected variables (=get_rejected_variables).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='neomatrix369' date='2020-01-13T11:42:19Z'>
		Hi Simon, I'll try to split these but also will answer quickly to some of the points.

bayesian bug was already reported earlier I think, the note:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;                        # if 'bayesian_blocks_bins': True fails 
                        # to provide a valid number of bins use the below config:
                        #   {'bins': 8, 'bayesian_blocks_bins': False} 
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

comes either from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/blob/b55b023915429cf68138c8ce4758b87cad872b11/src/pandas_profiling/config_dark.yaml#L77&gt;your config&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or issues/discussions made previously, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/issues/222&gt;#222&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/issues/227&gt;#227&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/issues/245&gt;#245&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pandas-profiling/pandas-profiling/issues/293&gt;#293&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. So there might not be something to report, I just added that note for myself so I follow the right config.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='neomatrix369' date='2020-01-13T11:47:48Z'>
		I'll request docs for the get rejected variable aspect.
And also for removal of these parameters, that worked in the previous version:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;style={'full_width': True}, minify_html=True
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='neomatrix369' date='2020-01-13T11:51:07Z'>
		With regards to reinstating get rejected variables, it's better to keep the same name and internally make the above call as you suggested so +1 there:
def get_rejected_variables(threshold=0.5):
    return profile.get_description()['messages']
(a contrived example)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>