<bug id='448' author='sbrugman' open_date='2020-04-25T10:59:35Z' closed_time='2020-05-07T17:39:10Z'>
	<summary>Conda install defaults to v1.4.1</summary>
	<description>
This still seems to be an issue.  What I've found is it may depend on which other packages you have installed.  My solution was to specify the version of pandas-profiling when doing a conda install:
conda install -c conda-forge pandas-profiling=2.6.0
Substitute '2.6.0' with the latest version here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/pandas-profiling&gt;https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/pandas-profiling&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

When I didn't specify the version, it seemed to install an older version (1.4.1-0 for Linux).  When I did specify the most recent version, it also downloaded qt-5.9.7 which it hadn't done before.  I'm not sure what's going on, because in another conda env, I was able to simply do conda install -c conda-forge pandas-profiling and it worked, but I had installed some other packages first.
If you look at the conda page (&lt;denchmark-link:https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/pandas-profiling&gt;https://anaconda.org/conda-forge/pandas-profiling&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) it has multiple versions on there (1.4.1 and 2.6.0) for all OSs.  My guess is this is what's causing the problem.
Originally posted by @nateGeorge in #136 (comment)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sbrugman' date='2020-04-25T11:39:50Z'>
		Great catch &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nateGeorge&gt;@nateGeorge&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! I've opened issues at the conda feedstock. Could you provide some additional diagnostic information (e.g. Python version, conda version)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sbrugman' date='2020-04-25T12:57:53Z'>
		Note I closed the issue over at conda-forge as the link there referenced the anaconda channel but if the issue still appears with -c conda-forge then something else is happening. Python and conda version as well as the conda output are needed though to understand the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sbrugman' date='2020-04-25T13:11:01Z'>
		@nateGeroge Could you verify that &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xhochy&gt;@xhochy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's suggestion that the problem comes from not specifying a channel/specifying the  channel? If so, we can close this issue.
Your other observation that qt was installed was spot on, that issue has now been resolved.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sbrugman' date='2020-04-25T15:48:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sbrugman&gt;@sbrugman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I installed it like  and it installed the older version in one of my conda environments.

Conda version: 4.8.3
Python version: 3.7.7

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sbrugman' date='2020-04-25T16:04:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xhochy&gt;@xhochy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 What are your thoughts on where this could come from?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-07T17:40:23Z'>
		
@sbrugman I installed it like conda install -c conda-forge pandas-profiling and it installed the older version in one of my conda environments.

Conda version: 4.8.3
Python version: 3.7.7


It seems this problem occurs when the environment is corrupted, for instance when conda and pip installations are mixed. I'd recommend creating a new environment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-13T17:12:48Z'>
		I'm having the same issue. Installed conda install -c conda-forge pandas-profiling but it installed 1.4. Tried to reinstall the package over 1.4 and was unable.
Removed the pandas-profiling package and attempted an install of 2.8.0.
No go. Any insight?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-13T17:17:55Z'>
		Did the explicit install of 2.8 update any other packages?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-13T17:25:15Z'>
		It wouldn't let me install 2.8 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xhochy&gt;@xhochy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-13T17:25:49Z'>
		With what message?
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-13T17:44:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/xhochy&gt;@xhochy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Not sure what the problem was, but I...

Uninstalled pandas-profiling
Updated all conda files
Ran the install for 2.8.0

And I'm fine now. Thanks for the help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='sbrugman' date='2020-05-14T23:32:19Z'>
		thank you! It was the only thing that really solved the problem! 2h+ trying to fix
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>