<bug id='2946' author='morgangiraud' open_date='2020-08-13T12:23:36Z' closed_time='2020-08-15T12:36:02Z'>
	<summary>Neptune logger with a validation epoch end conflict due to the 'epoch' key added on the fly.</summary>
	<description>
Hi everybody! First thanks for this lib, it is very handy!
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When using pytorch lightning in conjunction with the neptune logger, one can see this kind of error popping every time an epoch ends:
neptune.api_exceptions.ChannelsValuesSendBatchError: Received batch errors sending channels' values to experiment SOC-114. Cause: Error(code=400, message='X-coordinates must be strictly increasing for channel: e4e2635d-b707-46fa-9a1b-996dd009790f. Invalid point: InputChannelValue(timestamp=2020-08-13T11:55:38.422Z, x=5.0, numericValue=2.0, textValue=null, image', type=None) (metricId: 'e4e2635d-b707-46fa-9a1b-996dd009790f', x: 5.0) Skipping 1 values.
the import part in this error is the following line: X-coordinates must be strictly increasing
This is because, in trainer/logging.py, the epoch key is added on the fly on line 69:
scalar_metrics['epoch'] = self.current_epoch
But why does Neptune complains?
If you log all the timesteps (using row_log_interval = 1), at the end of an epoch, 2 calls are emitted to the logger: One to log the training logs and one for the validation logs.
Both of those have the same step value which is the current training step value. Since the key epoch is duplicated in both those calls, Neptune receives the key epoch twice with the same step value leading to the exception.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

launch training with:

Neptune logger
training logs
validation logs
row_log_interval=1

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behaviour&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Don't add the epoch key on the fly which force the logger to log it.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='morgangiraud' date='2020-08-13T12:24:16Z'>
		Hi! thanks for your contribution!, great first issue!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='morgangiraud' date='2020-08-14T00:18:53Z'>
		thanks!
yeah, unfortunately, this might be a problem on their end since we have to track the epoch.
In the meantime, can you post a colab that replicates this issue?
thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='morgangiraud' date='2020-08-14T07:42:31Z'>
		Hi,
Thanks for answering.
I've been looking at the code and I'm not sure why you need that epoch at that moment.
When I look at the following code, I see that the epoch key is added on only one part of the "if statement". So the code used after this part can't rely on this key to exist. What am I missing?
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;if "step" in scalar_metrics and step is None:
    step = scalar_metrics.pop("step")
else:
    # added metrics by Lightning for convenience
    scalar_metrics['epoch'] = self.current_epoch
    step = step if step is not None else self.global_step
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='morgangiraud' date='2020-08-15T15:46:09Z'>
		Thanks for the quick fix 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>