<bug id='3545' author='ananthsub' open_date='2020-09-18T06:14:08Z' closed_time='2020-10-03T22:29:03Z'>
	<summary>on_save_checkpoint callbacks runs in rank zero only</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If any callback implements on_save_checkpoint, then that function runs only in the rank zero worker. I think this is suboptimal as you might want to do some communication across workers before saving state.
The lineage of calls here is:

model checkpoint callback's on_validation_end is decorated with rank_zero_only
this calls the checkpoint callback's _save_model
which calls it's save_function
the save_function is trainer.save_checkpoint
save_checkpoint in checkpoint_connector calls dump_checkpoint
dump_checkpoint calls trainer.on_save_checkpoint()
trainer on_save_checkpoint() calls any callback implementing on_save_checkpoint 

I think this could be avoided with more judicious usage of . the main benefit of  in the model checkpoint callback to avoid redundant file I/O. For saving the checkpoint, that is taken care of by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/blob/master/pytorch_lightning/trainer/connectors/checkpoint_connector.py#L338&gt;this check.&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Other file I/O in the model checkpoint callback could be similarly guarded, and we should remove the decorator from on_validation_end
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ananthsub' date='2020-09-18T07:34:17Z'>
		With this thread i wanted to raise awareness of a limitation in the callback API here and a proposed workaround. if the code complexity isn't palatable, then we should document the limitations of the API.
making the implementation in on_validation_end have some more checks for trainer.is_global_zero rather than relying on the catch-all decorator isn't so bad.  we're still able to apply the rank_zero_only decorator to functions that do only file I/O, like _del_model
Removing the decorator from on_validation_epoch_end means we must also remove the decorator from on_pretrain_routine_start because state is set in on_pretrain_routine_start that is later read in on_validation_end. if on_pretrain_routine_start runs on rank zero only, then there are uninitialized fields when on_validation_end runs in non-zero ranks.
It's also unclear what we need to do for the model checkpoint's own definitions of on_save_checkpoint. In general, do all callbacks implementing on_save_checkpoint now need to check for trainer.is_global_zero? is that a dealbreaker?
Note, this is really tricky because someone could define a different model checkpoint callback, and that callback might not have all these rank_zero_only decorators. This means that other callbacks which define on_save_checkpoint now have different behavior because their execution depends on the model checkpoint callback! Those functions could now be running on all ranks. This could lead to some really tough bugs. IMO, the assumption when writing callbacks should be that this function will run on all ranks, and folks should add explicit checks in their code (e.g. trainer.is_global_zero if they want to narrow it down further)
cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jeremyjordan&gt;@jeremyjordan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wdyt about this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ananthsub' date='2020-09-18T12:43:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/williamFalcon&gt;@williamFalcon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 PTAL
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ananthsub' date='2020-10-03T22:29:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/pull/3688&gt;#3688&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 finished this
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>