<bug id='4468' author='EliaCereda' open_date='2020-11-01T16:28:03Z' closed_time='2020-11-01T18:36:45Z'>
	<summary>ModelCheckpoint filenames and metric names containing / (slash)</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The current behaviour of ModelCheckpoint is problematic when the checkpoint's name includes a metric whose name contains a slash character.
Since the implementation always includes the name of the metric along with its value, a format specifier like {some/name} results in the checkpoint being stored in a subdirectory. Everything appears to work correctly apart from the inconvenience of having a subdirectory which is not deleted when deleting old checkpoints.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Reproducer&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1E4EKc2Ndt4XluRjpGC83hyohyF0BQESU?usp=sharing&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1E4EKc2Ndt4XluRjpGC83hyohyF0BQESU?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The two lines marked as # STEP 1: ... and # STEP 2: ... are sufficient to reproduce the issue, the checkpoints are stored in lightning_logs/version_0/checkpoints.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I haven't found a way to avoid this problem, because the substitution from {metric} to metric=value is hardcoded in PyTorch Lightning code.
I don't particularly care about the specific name of my checkpoints, so I'd propose for PL to automatically escape the slashes to some other character. Alternatively, PL should provide a way to manually specify a different name for the metric in the filename or a way to suppress the name altoghether.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


CUDA:

GPU:

Tesla T4


available:         True
version:           10.1


Packages:

numpy:             1.18.5
pyTorch_debug:     False
pyTorch_version:   1.6.0+cu101
pytorch-lightning: 1.0.4
tqdm:              4.41.1


System:

OS:                Linux
architecture:

64bit



processor:         x86_64
python:            3.6.9
version:           #1 SMP Thu Jul 23 08:00:38 PDT 2020



&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Supporting metrics with a slash in the name is desirable for me because wandb then automatically groups them in the dashboard.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='EliaCereda' date='2020-11-01T16:28:46Z'>
		Hi! thanks for your contribution!, great first issue!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='EliaCereda' date='2020-11-01T18:31:55Z'>
		duplicate &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/issues/4012&gt;#4012&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
??
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='EliaCereda' date='2020-11-01T18:36:42Z'>
		Yes, it is. Don't know how I could not find it in my search, sorry for the duplicate.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='EliaCereda' date='2020-11-01T18:38:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/EliaCereda&gt;@EliaCereda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 btw do you have any suggestions here on how to handle this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='EliaCereda' date='2020-11-01T19:01:20Z'>
		I left a comment in the original issue ;)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>