<bug id='62' author='jondot' open_date='2018-01-17T23:20:38Z' closed_time='2018-01-23T17:33:18Z'>
	<summary>memory leak in motion-detection sample</summary>
	<description>
Hi all,
Thanks for a great library, I find the API much simpler than any other Go open-cv library.
If you'd run the motion-detection sample, you'll see memory always grows. I came a full circle to this porting an open-cv 2.x project I have to gocv, and I knew I should be looking for leaks, from previous experience. I then validated the case with your sample, as an isolated example of the problem.
I think here the leak comes from FindContours, somehow.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jondot' date='2018-01-18T13:23:05Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jondot&gt;@jondot&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you for paying attention to memory usage.
I just committed this code to the  branch: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hybridgroup/gocv/commit/77bc4f33407e589b0d2a1802475d31e867df6661&gt;77bc4f3&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I think it should address the leaks you found, and a few more. Would you be able to try it out?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jondot' date='2018-01-18T13:36:02Z'>
		I actually patched it on my side, and include one more edge case than what you did I believe, I can submit a PR. I'm just busy with other things right now (will take a few hours till i get some time to submit).
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jondot' date='2018-01-18T13:44:44Z'>
		That sounds great, thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jondot' date='2018-01-18T17:08:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deadprogram&gt;@deadprogram&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Feel free to check out my pull request
Thanks for a great library, I've been looking for an opencv3 library for Go for ages.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jondot' date='2018-01-18T18:49:24Z'>
		This code is now in the dev branch I will leave this issue open until the next GoCV release. Thanks again!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jondot' date='2018-01-23T17:33:18Z'>
		This code was released as part of v0.8.0 so now closing. Thanks again!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>