<bug id='1178' author='sneiman' open_date='2020-03-18T01:10:19Z' closed_time='2020-04-07T09:42:17Z'>
	<summary>DeprecatedWarnings when loaded</summary>
	<description>
Ubuntu 19.10, Python 3.7.5, pytorch 1.4.0, venv, installed with pip3
Builds based on clones of master after ~3/14 may issue DeprecationWarnings when loaded. This occurs if built within venv environment with include-system-site-packages = true or built outside venv. It does not occur if include-system-site-packages = false, or if using earlier repo clone.
This is a fresh ubuntu install, and the only python packages installed are in support of ml work - pytorch, pytorch-lightning, numpy, sci-py, tensorflow, etc.
The errors:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;/home/seth/dev/pytorch_work/.venv.ptl.master/lib/python3.7/site-packages/graphql/type/directives.py:55: DeprecationWarning: Using or importing the ABCs from 'collections' instead of from 'collections.abc' is deprecated since Python 3.3,and in 3.9 it will stop working
  assert isinstance(locations, collections.Iterable), 'Must provide locations for directive.'
/home/seth/dev/pytorch_work/.venv.ptl.master/lib/python3.7/site-packages/graphql/type/typemap.py:1: DeprecationWarning: Using or importing the ABCs from 'collections' instead of from 'collections.abc' is deprecated since Python 3.3,and in 3.9 it will stop working
  from collections import OrderedDict, Sequence, defaultdict
/home/seth/dev/pytorch_work/.venv.ptl.master/lib/python3.7/site-packages/trains/backend_interface/metrics/events.py:27: DeprecationWarning: The usage of `cmp` is deprecated and will be removed on or after 2021-06-01.  Please use `eq` and `order` instead.
  @attr.attrs(cmp=False, slots=True)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Seems like this might be due to new code that depend on newer versions of installed packages, so here is pip3 freeze outside of venv:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;numpy==1.18.1
Pillow==6.1.0
torch==1.4.0
torchvision==0.5.0
tqdm==4.43.0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T21:33:22Z'>
		could you please give full error trace?
so far I see only  error which is third-party lib...
maybe &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bmartinn&gt;@bmartinn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could help...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T21:51:13Z'>
		That is the full  trace. Three warnings come up - 2 for graphql, 1 for trace. Both 3rd party libs. The reason I raised the question is that they did not start appearing until repo clones after ~march 14. I haven't changed the environment ...
Can you see all 3 - I can see them here.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T22:09:37Z'>
		that is about the time we have added Trains...
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T22:29:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , I can probably take care of the warning inside the Trains package, but as you mentioned those are 3rd party libraries...

Moreover  had no "eq" argument in previous versions, and I would hate to bump the minimum  version in the Trains requirements ...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T22:45:47Z'>
		If its not due to new ptl code making an error or using the wrong version of something, it seems like this is at most a release note - easy for users to mask with a filter. Shall we close?
FYI - just noticed that for some reason the whole freeze list does not show. Don't know why you would need it at this point, but ask if you do ...
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T23:04:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bmartinn&gt;@bmartinn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 kind of extreme case would be using some warning ignore?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-18T23:08:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Doable, but this is a Trains/GraphQL repository issue, don't you think?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='sneiman' date='2020-03-19T00:15:14Z'>
		fwiw - i think ptl should let the warnings stand if they are not due to some 'mis-behavior' in ptl.  they are easily screened by a warning filter in user code and if trains doesn't fix them before they become fatal at least user will know.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='sneiman' date='2020-04-07T09:42:17Z'>
		as it is Trains issue, I ll close it here... feel free reopen if needed 🐰
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>