<bug id='1727' author='kessido' open_date='2020-05-04T09:47:57Z' closed_time='2020-08-06T12:02:23Z'>
	<summary>Progress bar \ log dict items added to outputs in training_epoch_end</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When running with training_step returning something along this:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;return { 'loss':x,
            'some_value_for_epoch_end': y,
            'progress_bar':{'v1':z.mean()}}

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

you get 'v1' as part of the outputs in epoch end. This is unexpected imo.
Also in case it is:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;return { 'loss':x,
            'some_value_for_epoch_end': y,
            'progress_bar':{'some_value_for_epoch_end': z.mean()}}

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

you get 'some_value_for_epoch_end' = z.mean(), as the values get overwritten.
It originate from file trainer/logging.py
lines 172, 173, where you overwrite the values using progress_bar_outputs + log_outputs
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kessido' date='2020-05-04T09:48:40Z'>
		Hi! thanks for your contribution!, great first issue!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kessido' date='2020-05-04T17:21:15Z'>
		Isn't it a feature?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch-lightning.readthedocs.io/en/0.7.5/experiment_reporting.html#modify-progress-bar&gt;https://pytorch-lightning.readthedocs.io/en/0.7.5/experiment_reporting.html#modify-progress-bar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I would await to see 'v1': SomeValue at the progress bar output after what I see in the docs.
Or do you mean you wan't only to see the value without 'v1'?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kessido' date='2020-05-04T19:50:18Z'>
		Might be, but I looked at the progress bar, and log, as something that goes to the "back end".
The "overwriting" property is a but I believe.
Lets say someone is trying to aggregate "acc" for the training_epoch_end phases, but he also like to report "acc" in the progress bar.
"acc1" is of size [batch_size, 1], while "acc2" is of size [1], just a scalar.
When arriving to training_epoch_end, he well see all outputs have only the [1] shaped outputs, instead of the [batch_size, 1] ones.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kessido' date='2020-05-04T20:38:12Z'>
		Ah okay. Now I understand. Do you have runnable example code or notebook for that issue?
The logging class returning each dict but also a complete callback_metric dict. See:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/blob/master/pytorch_lightning/trainer/logging.py#L171-L179&gt;https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/blob/master/pytorch_lightning/trainer/logging.py#L171-L179&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So I think you could access all metric dicts by trainer.some_dict (progress_bar_metrics, callback_metrics). The question is I think if there is any value overwritten and gone forever. Currently I think it isn't.
EDIT:
I think that returning the following dict would overwrite it without getting it back:
{
    'loss': loss,
    'value': 1,
    'progress_bar': { 'value': 2}
}
where callback_metrics['value'] == 2. Same when passing 'value' to logs. Don't know if this case should be handled but I think it could lead to bugs. Some ideas how it could be solved:

Do not collect log and progress bar metrics in callback_metrics (but in the comments there is written it should...)
Leave the log and progress_bar logs in different sub dicts (like callback_metrics['progress_bar']['value']. Don't know if this would lead to other errors.
Give it priorities and add it to the docs. Like first prior would have the callback_metric, then logs, then progress_bar (like {'value': 1, 'progress_bar': {'value': 3}, 'logs': {'value': 2}})
?

Think this should be discussed more.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kessido' date='2020-05-04T21:25:47Z'>
		Hey here is an example:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1kYjEH2h5Ki9ygZ0XlA6hpbcxA1L1NNzb?usp=sharing&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1kYjEH2h5Ki9ygZ0XlA6hpbcxA1L1NNzb?usp=sharing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

IMO training output should contain only values that will be used at the epoch end step, and not contain progress_bar \ log values, so this is a valid solution. At least I expected it to be this way and was considerably surprised when it didn't.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kessido' date='2020-05-05T10:19:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kessido&gt;@kessido&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Good example! This could be normal usage. I would wait for other opinions and ideas. Maybe I try solution 2 above the next days and check which tests will fail or which classes will be affected. But I think this could be a little bit harder.
Another quick solution would be to append a prefix to log and progress_bar dict values. This wouldn't affect other classes I think but could lead also to collisions.
Let's see what others will say or what ideas they have.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='kessido' date='2020-05-06T03:08:49Z'>
		I agree, the log and progress bar dict should not end up in epoch_end. If one really wants to collect a metric from these subdicts in epoch end, then one should simply store a copy of it in the top-level dict.
Unrelated, but noticed in your colab: You have a acc key in training_step and an acc_key in epoch end for the logger. This is not good, since this will affect the global_step in the logger and increase it by 1 after every epoch. You should rename it to "epoch_acc" or something like that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='kessido' date='2020-05-06T18:13:48Z'>
		
I agree, the log and progress bar dict should not end up in epoch_end. If one really wants to collect a metric from these subdicts in epoch end, then one should simply store a copy of it in the top-level dict.
Unrelated, but noticed in your colab: You have a acc key in training_step and an acc_key in epoch end for the logger. This is not good, since this will affect the global_step in the logger and increase it by 1 after every epoch. You should rename it to "epoch_acc" or something like that.

Haha, nice catch! 😆
I usually call them with "train_x" or "val_x"~ but I just wrote it as an example :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='kessido' date='2020-05-12T14:30:18Z'>
		If no one else responding I'll add a PR for that. The simplest solution I tested was just remove adding log and progress bar dict to callback metric. I had to change the base model validation step in tests to pass.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='kessido' date='2020-05-12T14:37:31Z'>
		hey awesome, I will review PR as soon as I have time! Thanks for your effort
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='kessido' date='2020-05-12T21:12:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/awaelchli&gt;@awaelchli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 are you preparing another pr then the ref &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/pull/1800&gt;#1800&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='kessido' date='2020-05-13T04:00:03Z'>
		No, if &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/olineumann&gt;@olineumann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
's pr addresses the issue, it should not be necessary
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='kessido' date='2020-07-12T04:22:07Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='kessido' date='2020-08-03T21:59:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/williamFalcon&gt;@williamFalcon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this fixed with structured results?
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='kessido' date='2020-08-06T12:02:31Z'>
		yes! fixed with structured results
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>