<bug id='367' author='VismantasD' open_date='2019-10-14T05:21:19Z' closed_time='2019-10-23T10:27:16Z'>
	<summary>setting gpus=-1 and gpus='-1' in Trainer give different behaviours</summary>
	<description>
I discovered this while looking through the code. Trainer constructor does not mention that
gpus can be -1 or '-1'. However if such values are passed they are accepted and result in
different behaviour: -1 will result in no gpus used, '-1' will use all available gpus.
To Reproduce

Run any model first setting trainer gpus parameter to -1. No gpus will be used.
Run same model setting gpus to '-1'. All available gpus will be used.

Being able to set -1 to indicate that all gpus should be used is and I believe useful behaviour.
The issue is in function &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/williamFalcon/pytorch-lightning/blob/19c2b8fc9e73326c3e320c29e8f932893bd49460/pytorch_lightning/trainer/trainer.py#L340&gt;self.__parse_gpu_ids(gpus)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 where the handling of -1 when passed as int is not implemented.
Solution would be to implement equivalent logic for -1 as for '-1'.
Happy to submit a PR.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-14T10:57:18Z'>
		yeah, fair. would love a PR! (also docs update)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-16T21:22:50Z'>
		Question. What is the intended behaviour when setting gpus in the Trainer to an int? (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/commit/e2cabb03ba86c4dc0271a4531bce7bf2dff53e94&gt;e2cabb0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
).
Is it specifying number of gpus to use? Or is it specifying a specific gpu? Depending on the choice one of __set_root_gpu() or num_gpus() needs fixing:

If it is number of gpus, then __set_root_gpu  would be returning 0 but it should be returning None in this case.
If it is specific gpu (e.g. gpus=3 means running on 3rd gpu) then num_gpus would be returning 3 instead of 1.

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-16T21:32:59Z'>
		number is for how many gpus to use. i guess the docs need to be updated to make that clear?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-16T23:33:56Z'>
		Thanks, Yeah, I think they could be more specific and it is hard to read it from code. I'll update the documentation in the PR.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-17T06:17:23Z'>
		awesome!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='VismantasD' date='2019-10-23T10:27:16Z'>
		On master
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>