<bug id='4199' author='MohammedAljahdali' open_date='2020-10-16T23:14:08Z' closed_time='2020-10-17T11:06:19Z'>
	<summary>Metric is different in logger and progress bar</summary>
	<description>
Hey
I am recording a metric called Character Error Rate, I was monitoring it through tensorboard logger, I also record some outputs with their CER every 100 batch, and I noticed that the CER is low  on the recorded outputs, compared to the epoch CER I saw on tensorboard and I said this might be a lucky batches. Then when I looked on the epoch CER on my progress bar it was so different from the on in tensorboard, and the CER I saw on the examples started to make sense. I don't know how to re-produce this because it's happening during a very long experiment.
Progress bar val_cer_epoch =  0.291:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/24215630/96321334-b8798600-101d-11eb-9dd8-04ae96c5eea3.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Tensorboard val_cer_epoch = 0.687:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/24215630/96321400-eeb70580-101d-11eb-941e-02b7619b723d.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

note:
Opening an issue on a project is new for me, so excuse me if I am doing it wrong.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MohammedAljahdali' date='2020-10-16T23:14:50Z'>
		Hi! thanks for your contribution!, great first issue!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MohammedAljahdali' date='2020-10-17T00:00:07Z'>
		which version of Lightning are you using here?
maybe the same problem as  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/issues/4141&gt;#4141&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which was fixed in the latest version. If you are not on the latest version, try to install 1.0.2
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MohammedAljahdali' date='2020-10-17T10:28:35Z'>
		My version is 1.0.0 . The issue you mentioned is the same as mine, I will try to install 1.0.2, if this did not work I will post here to inform you. Thanks you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MohammedAljahdali' date='2020-10-17T11:06:18Z'>
		The issue is fixed with 1.0.2, I will close this issue
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>