<bug id='4312' author='masoncusack' open_date='2020-10-22T19:23:34Z' closed_time='2021-01-07T16:44:38Z'>
	<summary>Torchvision model state inconsistency in multi-gpu mode (distributed training)</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I noticed that, when trying to train on multiple GPUs using Lightning 0.10.0, the outputs of the torchvision model  were &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/torchvision/models.html#torchvision.models.detection.fasterrcnn_resnet50_fpn&gt;those described here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for inference (eval mode). However, when using a single GPU on lightning 0.10, or multi-gpu on lightning 0.9, this behaviour stopped, and the model was in training mode as expected, with outputs of a forward pass in my training loop reflecting those documented for this mode.
A manual additional call to .train() set things right, but I then started seeing errors in my eval process, which leads me to believe that something is interfering with model state under circumstances which haven't changed except for the number of GPUs in use, like eval mode is being activated by default.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Run a forward pass for the fasterrcnn_resnet50_fpn torchvision model (I'm not sure whether this extends to other torchvision or wider PyTorch models), using a single GPU, with lightning 0.10
Run a forward pass for the fasterrcnn_resnet50_fpn torchvision model, selecting multiple GPUs with lightning 0.10
Notice that model state appears to change between these circumstances, and in the case of this model, this causes the outputs of a forward pass to change in accordance with the torchvision documentation (linked above).

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

E.g. for fasterrcnn_resnet50_fpn:
Expected output from forward pass at train time (taken from use of single GPU, lightning 0.10.0):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;{
    'loss_classifier': tensor(0.5534, device='cuda:0', grad_fn=&lt;NllLossBackward&gt;),
    'loss_box_reg': tensor(0.1873, device='cuda:0', grad_fn=&lt;DivBackward0&gt;),
    'loss_objectness': tensor(0.1856, device='cuda:0', grad_fn=&lt;BinaryCrossEntropyWithLogitsBackward&gt;),
    'loss_rpn_box_reg': tensor(0.0244, device='cuda:0', grad_fn=&lt;DivBackward0&gt;)
}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Actual output from forward pass at train time (taken from use of multi-GPU, lightning 0.10.0):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;{
    'boxes': tensor([[176.8907, 198.9963, 252.4170, 248.9736],
    [392.0787, 185.2145, 426.4388, 229.0993],
    [178.8200, 207.2800, 213.0467, 251.0375],
    [421.2797, 180.9008, 523.6691, 237.5523],
    [...]], device='cuda:1'),
    'labels': tensor([1, 1, 1, ...], device='cuda:1'),
    'scores': tensor([0.7446, 0.7164, 0.6861, 0.6852, 0.6635, 0.6364, 0.6237, 0.6221, 0.6205,
    0.6201, 0.6193, 0.6137, 0.6082, 0.6064, 0.6020, 0.6018, 0.6008, 0.5992,
    0.5986, 0.5983, 0.5903, 0.5840, 0.5731, 0.5713, 0.5696, 0.5636, 0.5627,
    ...], device='cuda:1')
}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

These are the intended outputs from inference (eval mode) according to the documentation.
And when printing model.training I got the following:
For Lightning 0.10.0, single GPU:
Is the model in training mode?: True
For Lightning 0.10.0, multi-GPU:
Is the model in training mode?: False
🤔
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


CUDA:

GPU:

Tesla V100-PCIE-16GB
Tesla V100-PCIE-16GB


available:         True
version:           10.2


Packages:

numpy:             1.19.2
pyTorch_debug:     False
pyTorch_version:   1.6.0
pytorch-lightning: 0.10.0
tqdm:              4.50.2


System:

OS:                Linux
architecture:

64bit
ELF


processor:         x86_64
python:            3.8.5
version:           #32~18.04.1-Ubuntu SMP Tue Oct 6 10:03:22 UTC 2020



	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='masoncusack' date='2020-10-29T21:00:39Z'>
		Thanks for the issue! Mind updating to 1.0.3 to see if issue persists?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='masoncusack' date='2020-11-03T13:14:18Z'>
		Hi,
The issue seems to persist on upgrading to lightning 1.0.3, and 1.0.4.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='masoncusack' date='2020-11-16T16:32:29Z'>
		Hey! Sorry for the late reply. Can you try to see if issue persists on boring model? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/blob/master/pl_examples/bug_report_model.py&gt;https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/blob/master/pl_examples/bug_report_model.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='masoncusack' date='2020-12-02T22:06:06Z'>
		Hey, sorry for the wait.
I noticed the boring model as it stands today fails when using Lightning 0.9.0 anyway. It required return statements in the ,  and  functions to work, so I used  as a quick fix, as suggested &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/issues/84&gt;in a separate issue&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
When switching to 0.10.0,  I got the error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;pytorch_lightning.utilities.exceptions.MisconfigurationException: training_epoch_end expects a return of None. HINT: remove the return statement in training_epoch_end
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

So I reverted the changes.
I couldn't replicate the specific model state issue between 0.9.0 and 0.10.0 with the BoringModel. It seems to be in training mode throughout once the right modifications are made.
However, I notice the code I'm working with does return dicts from those functions.  It doesn't suffer the same error as the boring model, but clearly there were some fundamental changes between 0.9.0 and later versions which changes the expectation of whether the _epoch_end functions return anything.
Do you think this could be the cause? Of course I'm still confused that the outcome isn't a crash but inconsistent model state.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='masoncusack' date='2020-12-14T17:15:36Z'>
		Are you able to try using master or 1.1?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='masoncusack' date='2021-01-07T16:44:36Z'>
		Feel free to reopen if still persists!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>