<bug id='65' author='williamFalcon' open_date='2019-08-07T16:25:55Z' closed_time='2019-08-07T17:06:54Z'>
	<summary>codecov doesn't respect ignore</summary>
	<description>
need to add some ignore files to codecov... but it seems to not care about the ignore part:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;coverage:
  precision: 0  # 2 = xx.xx%, 0 = xx%
  round: nearest # how coverage is rounded: down/up/nearest
  range: 40...100 # custom range of coverage colors from red -&gt; yellow -&gt; green
  status:
    # https://codecov.readme.io/v1.0/docs/commit-status
    project:
      default:
        against: auto
        target: 99% # specify the target coverage for each commit status
        threshold: 20% # allow this little decrease on project
        # https://github.com/codecov/support/wiki/Filtering-Branches
        # branches: master
        if_ci_failed: error
    # https://github.com/codecov/support/wiki/Patch-Status
    patch:
      default:
        against: auto
        target: 40% # specify the target "X%" coverage to hit
        # threshold: 50% # allow this much decrease on patch
    changes: false
    ignore:
      - "pytorch_lightning/utilities/arg_parse.py"
      - "raise *"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='williamFalcon' date='2019-08-07T16:37:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ok. Unfortunately i'm on a really tight research agenda. I took a lot of time already to make sure the coverage was solid and up to 99%. I don't have time to figure out this codecov thing and it's a bit of engineering overhead right now which is detracting from research.
If this method doesn't work today, we'll roll back to standard coverage and the config file for that. But I don't want to add unnecessary engineering overhead that isn't 100% complete into the package.
Let me know what you think. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='williamFalcon' date='2019-08-07T17:06:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ok, it's stable now and the correct coverage shows (through the .svg badge). if you get the command-line submit working to codecov then great, we can use it as long as it's accurate.
otherwise, let's stick to the badge for now and move on to adding other cool features everyone's been asking about &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/issues/50&gt;#50&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PyTorchLightning/pytorch-lightning/issues/49&gt;#49&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='williamFalcon' date='2019-08-07T17:12:07Z'>
		Ignore files should be specified in codecove run not in the codecov config
Ok I don't mind to keep your svg badge for now since there are some complication with the Automatic one... My point was just that in future it would better to have automatic one and in the time I was proposing it I didn't know about the limitations with GPU...
Just I would move the svg badge to docs folder...
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='williamFalcon' date='2019-08-07T17:24:42Z'>
		agreed. moved and updated
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='williamFalcon' date='2019-08-19T08:02:59Z'>
		Also, it seems that you have a syntax error in your Codecov.yaml
curl --data-binary @.codecov.yml https://codecov.io/validate
see &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.codecov.io/docs/codecov-yaml&gt;https://docs.codecov.io/docs/codecov-yaml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>