<bug id='965' author='williamFalcon' open_date='2020-02-27T11:56:54Z' closed_time='2020-06-01T15:00:35Z'>
	<summary>Graceful keyboard doesn't work as expected</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jeremyjordan&gt;@jeremyjordan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Not sure the fix is what you were looking for? Make sure to also log the message only from proc_0.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3640001/75442880-5523d200-592e-11ea-9ee0-837bb8dd9ff4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-02-27T14:16:34Z'>
		Thanks I’ll look into this. To reproduce, is this running in a Colab notebook with a TPU enabled?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-03-02T04:26:59Z'>
		I spent some time looking into this but haven't yet figured out how to gracefully exit when using DDP. We know that the first KeyboardInterrupt was caught due to the logging.
Reading the docs for &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/multiprocessing.html#spawning-subprocesses&gt;torch.multiprocessing&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I see it says:

In the case an exception was caught in the child process, it is forwarded and its traceback is included in the exception raised in the parent process.

I'm wondering if the KeyboardInterrupt is being sent to all of the processes and the child processes are re-raising to the main process which can only handle the exception once.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-09T11:12:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jeremyjordan&gt;@jeremyjordan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 how is it going here?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-10T03:03:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Borda&gt;@Borda&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I could use some help figuring out how to fail gracefully in the case of DDP
when the user signals a KeyboardInterrupt for the first time, it should signal all of the nodes to finish their work, collect back onto the main process, and then run the teardown routine. if the user signals for a second KeyboardInterrupt, it should stop immediately.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-13T19:20:54Z'>
		Do you mean that first KeyboardInterrupt ends the teardown and the second KeyboardInterrupt ends even the teardown? Maybe we shall really implement the trainer status enum...
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-16T01:57:33Z'>
		yes i believe an exception is being thrown for each worker and raised back to the main process. the main process catches the first exception and begins running the training teardown but then the subsequent exceptions cause it to halt immediately. does that make sense? any ideas how to handle that?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-25T18:08:07Z'>
		I have not tried to solve this particular problem - but I have wrestled some similar problems - sharing what I learned in case it helps.
You can probably intercept the KeyboardInterrupt in each process by setting a signal handler like this in each ddp process:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;def signal_handler(sig, frame):
        # do something here - probably pass
        # I would try to re raise the error from None - to avoid sending all the history ...
        # might even translate it to your own exception ... ExitTraining?
        raise ExitTraining from None
signal.signal(signal.SIGINT, signal_handler)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To make these active in each ddp process, they have to be defined and signal.signal() called in ddp_train().
Catch ExitTraining in the main, cpu based process. At this point, you 'should' have control of the interrupt.
You can create a shared Value (see python/pytorch multiprocessing) in Trainer.__init__(). You then use this as a flag to signal time to teardown. So ... your handler for ExitTraining in the main process would set the flag to True. And somewhere AFTER a barrier call in the training loop you check it, and initiate teardown.
NOTE that for ddp, you MUST create the shared value with
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;mp.get_context('spawn').Value(...)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This should work on a single node. To work across nodes, I believe you will have to create a Manager() - see mp.
Hope this at leasts gives you a useful direction ...
I do something similar
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='williamFalcon' date='2020-04-29T00:24:22Z'>
		A short note, I also encountered this problem in DDP. I found that the KeyboardInterrupt is not caught sometimes, and even though it's caught, the self.interrupted is only set in child process, which means the value for the main process is not set. A workaround for me is to try-catch the mp.spawn() sentence and set the flags in the main process.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>