<bug id='30' author='MyMakibox' open_date='2020-02-10T23:26:05Z' closed_time='2020-02-11T15:56:53Z'>
	<summary>exited: nginx (terminated by SIGILL (core dumped); not expected)</summary>
	<description>
Awesome project that I am using to make ML available to students.
Picked up this issue:
After following docs, cannot access webservices, log shows
exited: nginx (terminated by SIGILL (core dumped); not expected)

Docker version 19.03.5
Host Machine OS Linux:
Command used to start the workspace : docker run -d 
-p 8080:8080 
--name "ml-workspace" -v "${PWD}:/workspace" 
--env AUTHENTICATE_VIA_JUPYTER="mytoken" 
--shm-size 512m 
--restart always 
mltooling/ml-workspace:latest

Possible Fix:
This is likely the same issue described here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/docksal/service-vhost-proxy/issues/35&gt;docksal/service-vhost-proxy#35&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/metwork-framework/mfext/issues/384&gt;metwork-framework/mfext#384&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Running on older hardware means no SSE4.2.
It would be great if this can be worked around so that older hardware can be used by students to access current tools. ML-Tooling already helps a lot when connecting to a remote server, which is great. This issue prevents running the container locally. Alternatively, SSE4.2 should be mentioned as a hardware requirement, or tested for in the container with appropriate logging.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MyMakibox' date='2020-02-11T00:03:26Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MyMakibox&gt;@MyMakibox&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for reporting this issue and your investigation! Indeed, this looks like a problem with the binaries of OpenResty, which do no support some older processors (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/openresty/openresty/issues/267#issuecomment-309296900&gt;openresty/openresty#267 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). Theoretically, we might solve this by building the workspace (and OpenResty) on a computer with an older CPU. But this will most likely be quite a challenge. Do you have more information on what kind of CPU you have in your hardware and how old it is?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MyMakibox' date='2020-02-11T03:55:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LukasMasuch&gt;@LukasMasuch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The specific laptop shows /proc/cpuinfo:
Intel(R) Core(TM)2 Duo CPU     T5450  @ 1.66GHz
While it was on its way to scrap, it works very well with ubuntu and a browser connected to a PC hosting ML-Workspace.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MyMakibox' date='2020-02-11T15:56:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MyMakibox&gt;@MyMakibox&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I added a short description about this issue to the Known Issues section (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ml-tooling/ml-workspace/tree/develop#known-issues&gt;develop branch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). Unfortunately, fixing this might be too much effort as of now. If more people encounter the problem, we will do some more evaluation on if and how to provide a fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MyMakibox' date='2020-06-16T00:19:46Z'>
		I have the same problem
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>