<bug id='44' author='dennischancs' open_date='2020-06-17T06:59:04Z' closed_time='2020-12-12T21:53:29Z'>
	<summary>Is there a backdoor to download xmrig miner?</summary>
	<description>
/bin/bash ./mainscript.sh script that sneakily download xmrig v5.11.1  in the background as root.
Did the same thing happen to you?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dennischancs' date='2020-06-18T17:27:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dennischancs&gt;@dennischancs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The  is definitely not from us. Do you have any additional information on this script and your deployment? How did you deploy the workspace? What is the content of the ? I checked multiple of our workspace deployments, but wasn't able to find any mention of xmrig or the mainscript.sh.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dennischancs' date='2020-06-20T08:22:59Z'>
		I encountered this script when I left my instance exposed to the Internet. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dennischancs&gt;@dennischancs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 i suggest you add in authentication to prevent such things from happening.
Edit: To see if you are infected, get to Terminal and issue the history command. This will show the history of commands the intruder executed in your environment. To resolve this, shutdown your docker container and recreate one with authentication turned on. Remember to put in a strong password.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dennischancs' date='2020-06-23T06:54:25Z'>
		
I encountered this script when I left my instance exposed to the Internet. @dennischancs i suggest you add in authentication to prevent such things from happening.
Edit: To see if you are infected, get to Terminal and issue the history command. This will show the history of commands the intruder executed in your environment. To resolve this, shutdown your docker container and recreate one with authentication turned on. Remember to put in a strong password.

Thank you very much. This never happened again.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dennischancs' date='2020-06-23T06:56:05Z'>
		
@dennischancs The mainscript.sh is definitely not from us. Do you have any additional information on this script and your deployment? How did you deploy the workspace? What is the content of the mainscript.sh? I checked multiple of our workspace deployments, but wasn't able to find any mention of xmrig or the mainscript.sh.

I deleted the container right then and there without bothering to read the contents.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>