<bug id='152' author='ZoranPandovski' open_date='2019-04-07T14:40:59Z' closed_time='2019-05-04T18:30:12Z'>
	<summary>ModuleNotFoundError: No module named '_tkinter'</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
Train new model with the latest mindsdb version throws an error. LudwigModel uses matplotlib that depends on tkinter backend.
With different OS tkinter is not shipped with Python, or if users install python from source.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7192539/55684985-a65f5780-5951-11e9-8c14-82c53ea64ff5.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Desktop (please complete the following information):

python 3.7.3 version


According to &lt;denchmark-link:https://wiki.python.org/moin/TkInter&gt;tkinter docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
:
If it fails with "No module named _tkinter", your Python configuration needs to be modified to include this module (which is an extension module implemented in C). Do not edit Modules/Setup (it is out of date). You may have to install Tcl and Tk (when using RPM, install the -devel RPMs as well) and/or edit the setup.py script to point to the right locations where Tcl/Tk is installed. If you install Tcl/Tk in the default locations, simply rerunning "make" should build the _tkinter extension.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-04-09T08:46:14Z'>
		Hmh... this is a rather tricky issues actually, since we can't exactly install binary libraries easily in setup.py since it's all OS dependent.
Bar making a change to ludwig for matplotlib to use a different backend, I'm not sure ow to go about this.
Even wireder according to this: &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/37459386/using-matplotlib-without-tcl&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/37459386/using-matplotlib-without-tcl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 matplotlib shouldn't even require tlc, it should try all possible backend.
Can you give me the values of the DISPLAY and MPLBACKEND as well as the OS version of the machine you are testing this on ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-04-11T14:13:22Z'>
		Adding an option to not use tkinter at all can resolve the issue. Matplotlib have an option for that as you provide on the link above matplotlib.use('agg'), but since we are using it through Ludwig I am not sure how we can provide that.
I am testing on Ubuntu 16.04 and Antegros Arch with Python 3.7.3 version.
For the MPLBACKEND matplotlib returns TkAgg.
I have tried to override it before the Predictor call, but I guess it is overwritten later.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-04-22T15:56:01Z'>
		Try running unset MPLBACKEND and then running the model.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-05-02T20:45:27Z'>
		On Fedora 30 this issue can be solved by installing python3-tkinter.
$ sudo dnf -y install python3-tkinter
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-05-04T18:28:09Z'>
		Installing Tk manually will solve the issue:
sudo apt-get install python3-tk tk
In my case, I was having different python3 versions so after installing the module I had to rebuild python version:
./configure
make
make install
Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/George3d6&gt;@George3d6&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paulfantom&gt;@paulfantom&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>