<bug id='204' author='yummuy' open_date='2019-05-13T10:28:54Z' closed_time='2019-06-12T15:17:49Z'>
	<summary>module mindsdb has no libs on Mac</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is. Error on importing mindsdb on python3 + MacOS
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Open ipython prompt with python3.6
Run import mindsdb
See error

Expected behavior
A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
Screenshots
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
Desktop (please complete the following information):

OS: MacOS Sierra 10.12.6
Additional info if applicable

Additional context
Logs:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;In [8]: import mindsdb
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
AttributeError                            Traceback (most recent call last)
&lt;ipython-input-8-0e567d645fe9&gt; in &lt;module&gt;()
----&gt; 1 import mindsdb

~/Library/Python/3.6/lib/python/site-packages/mindsdb/__init__.py in &lt;module&gt;()
      4
      5 from mindsdb.config import CONFIG
----&gt; 6 import mindsdb.libs.constants.mindsdb as CONST
      7
      8 from mindsdb.__about__ import __package_name__ as name, __version__

AttributeError: module 'mindsdb' has no attribute 'libs'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yummuy' date='2019-05-13T10:29:14Z'>
		Should I do reinstall and try whole thing again?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yummuy' date='2019-05-13T13:09:48Z'>
		Hi,
I'm able to install locally in a virtualenv with python3.6.8 and run mindsdb without any issues, but I can't emulate an OSX environemnt.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/torrmal&gt;@torrmal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  has macbook, so if there's aparticular issue installing on macbook he would probably be able to help
In the meanwhile, could you run:
pip3 uninstall mindsdb &amp; pip3 install mindsdb and tell me the output of that ? (Maybe there's an error when installing). If the command doesn't work like that use pip instead of pip3
Also, could you give me your python version (run python --version or python3 --version... depending on the alias you use to invoke python 3)
I'm suspecting either and install error or maybe a bad mindsdb version ( though I doubt anything we published on pip would result in that error... so install error is most likely).
Thank you for reporting this :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yummuy' date='2019-05-14T18:19:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yummuy&gt;@yummuy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did this help?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yummuy' date='2019-06-12T15:17:48Z'>
		Has been inactive for a long time, so I'll go ahead and close it. Feel free to make a comment here if the problem arises again and you can provide the additional debugging info required and I'll re-open it and look into it more.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yummuy' date='2019-06-14T10:20:12Z'>
		Myself currently has same issue on windows 10, python 3.6.4
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/19726972/59502693-9f604280-8ec8-11e9-8077-03ece8492371.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Any suggestion? Thanks
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>