<bug id='227' author='ZoranPandovski' open_date='2019-05-21T16:57:19Z' closed_time='2019-05-22T06:32:17Z'>
	<summary>SSLCertVerificationError</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When learning from the dataset that is hosted on S3 SSLCertVerificationError is thrown. The same issue  was reported previously with the datasets that were served from Github as raw files.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Learn from file hosted on S3 filestore. e.g https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/mindsdb-example-data/home_rentals.csv


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7192539/58115226-ec1e6980-7bf9-11e9-89b6-0668cedd7f79.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Desktop (please complete the following information):

OS: Ubuntu 19.04
Python 3.7.3
Mindsdb latest version 1.1.2

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-05-21T21:07:41Z'>
		Hmh, I remembered having a PR that changed urllib3 to request... maybe it didn't get merged from some reason.
Anyway, this is probably an error with the local machine, rather than urllib3, since I'm able to download the file just fine.
I would suggest:

Making the file in the standard example http
Switching to request instead of urllib3 (higher level, easier to not mess something up with it)
Not verifying the certificate (data is still downloaded via https, so better than using http, only issue if if someone is trying to do an MTM attack during the handshake)

We can do 1 of the above or all 3 and hope to fix it... I can't replicate this locally, so, kinda hard to figure out the root cause. Could actually be that the root certs on your local machine aren't up to date.
Anyway &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/torrmal&gt;@torrmal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  feel free to decide on a course of action and I'll take it, otherwise, I'll go ahead and:

Switching from urllib3 to request
If cert fail verifies, try to re download without verifying and issue a warning to the user that we couldn't verify the certificate from his local aturhortiy.

Which should get rid of the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ZoranPandovski' date='2019-05-22T06:32:17Z'>
		Should be fixed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/pull/228&gt;#228&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, hopefully.
if not, as mentioned above, it's probably an issue with the users machine in some way.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>