<bug id='405' author='George3d6' open_date='2020-03-09T19:09:41Z' closed_time='2020-06-25T11:46:59Z'>
	<summary>32 bit version of python</summary>
	<description>
Currently as per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/issues/403&gt;#403&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , lightwood (and by extension mindsdb) fails to install on 32bit python environments.
We should see if there's an easy way to make it work, since 32 bits might still be used for a long time on various embedded device.
If there isn't (or if there is, but it takes too long to implement support) we should add a notification to the docs that you need 64 bit python (where we mention the python version requirements).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ZoranPandovski&gt;@ZoranPandovski&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would you have time to look into this ?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='George3d6' date='2020-03-09T19:36:01Z'>
		Yes, I can update the docs for now and check which one of the dependencies(TensorFlow for sure) requires a 64bit version.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='George3d6' date='2020-03-09T19:38:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ZoranPandovski&gt;@ZoranPandovski&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tensorflow is not a dependency, Pytroch is the one that was likely causing issues in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mindsdb/mindsdb/issues/403&gt;#403&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , but yeah, feel free to update the docs for now :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='George3d6' date='2020-03-10T20:54:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/George3d6&gt;@George3d6&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Exactly Pytorch supports only 64 bit interpreter according to its documentation:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/windows.html&gt;https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/windows.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


PyTorch doesn’t work on 32-bit system. Please use Windows and Python 64-bit version.

The same goes for Tensorflow if You were going to use it in any of Your endeavours:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/install#install-tensorflow-2&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/install#install-tensorflow-2&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


TensorFlow is tested and supported on the following 64-bit systems

I am also having some problems with the GUI version of the software such as that columns in type(str) are not possible to use in "query". But I feel like this deserves another issue opened.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='George3d6' date='2020-04-16T17:06:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Kaszanas&gt;@Kaszanas&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you please run the GUI, it should automatically pull the latest version with a lot of new bugs fixed. Please,  provide info if you are still experiencing the same issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='George3d6' date='2020-04-30T08:40:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Kaszanas&gt;@Kaszanas&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any update on this ?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>