<bug id='539' author='George3d6' open_date='2020-06-25T22:26:35Z' closed_time='2020-07-06T14:48:51Z'>
	<summary>Remove hardcoded cert from code</summary>
	<description>
I am informed using a test SSL cert hardcoded inside public source code goes against certain best practices.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='George3d6' date='2020-06-26T07:10:57Z'>
		Yes, that surely must be done. I have already started make function to create new cert at mindsdb starts. But found issue with crossplatform work of such function. Will try to find some python lib to make certs what not depends of os libs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='George3d6' date='2020-06-26T09:49:54Z'>
		Certbot maybe?
It's amazing, although probably linux-only.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://certbot.eff.org/&gt;https://certbot.eff.org/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='George3d6' date='2020-06-26T12:27:43Z'>
		Certbot is for slightly different purpose. Easiest way to make cert on linux is use openssl command (or for python use OpenSSL module).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='George3d6' date='2020-07-06T02:09:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/btseytlin&gt;@btseytlin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/StpMax&gt;@StpMax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is saying cerbot is for public SSL certs, basically it does the job of registering your SSL certificate with the centralized authorities that run the website encryption racket around the internet.
As &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/StpMax&gt;@StpMax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is saying we can use OpenSSL, except that OpenSSL 100% does not come by default with every distro, at least not the command line utility (I don't think ??). Anyway, I'm fairly sure even if it does it's not present on windows.
So I'd rather use this: &lt;denchmark-link:https://pypi.org/project/certauth/&gt;https://pypi.org/project/certauth/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  ... but &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/StpMax&gt;@StpMax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if you think there's an issue with that approach do tell, we have plenty of time, no need to get this running until right at the very moment we do the 2.0.0 release.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>