<bug id='433' author='amolchanov86' open_date='2018-12-18T04:03:13Z' closed_time='2018-12-21T21:28:31Z'>
	<summary>garage/envs/base.py calls tests.quirks</summary>
	<description>
As the title says one of the garage modules calls tests.quirks which semantically should be part of the garage module, for example, garage.tests.quirks instead (or any other if you would like).
The problem arrives when I am trying to run something inside of my projects folder, obviously, since tests are somewhere up the folder hierarchy it can not find it.
At the same time, the name "tests" is too generic to just put it into PYTHONPATH.
Hence, I believe, some restructuring is appropriate.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-18T06:45:44Z'>
		good catch!
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jonashen&gt;@jonashen&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 @gonzaiva can one of you fix this? I think it would be sufficient to just copy  to .
This one will require a backport into release-2018.10
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-18T19:42:53Z'>
		Okay, I'll work on this today.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-18T23:17:49Z'>
		 was moved to  in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/pull/434&gt;#434&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, however, should we close this issue until we have decided how to repackage ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-19T20:28:33Z'>
		What do you mean by repackage tests?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-19T21:12:51Z'>
		I understood by Artem's issue that tests is too generic for the PYTHONPATH, so we should repackage it as garage.tests.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-19T22:29:07Z'>
		Yes. That would be one solution.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-20T22:27:57Z'>
		Oh I see, you mean about distributing the tests.
Putting tests in the same package as src can be a bad idea because of exactly this issue. You actually don't want the test package to be importable from the source, because then you could end up with code peeking to see if it's under test or not :P.
Right now we assume that if you are running tests, you are cloning from git. The test runner (now: nose2, future: pytest) should always be able to run the full suite when executed from the root directory.
It's unclear whether this repository could ever be distributed as a pip package because of its extensive native dependencies and complex installation (we will try but may not succeed). Right now we are focusing on separating out as many parts as possible into packages which can be distributed properly with pip. In the case that we do distribute with pip, it would be possible to package the tests under the namespace garagetests and provide them as an optional variant garage[tests]
For the new packages which we are spinning off of garage, we have been following &lt;denchmark-link:https://blog.ionelmc.ro/2014/05/25/python-packaging/#the-structure&gt;this guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 from a very well-respected Python package maintainer. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/akro&gt;https://github.com/rlworkgroup/akro&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for an example.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-21T01:34:10Z'>
		I guess after KNOWN_GYM_NOT_CLOSER_VIEWER moving to the base.py and excluding import of tests it should be fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='amolchanov86' date='2018-12-21T01:44:37Z'>
		Ok. We will close once Angel backports it to release-2018.10
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>