<bug id='755' author='ryanjulian' open_date='2019-06-26T15:42:47Z' closed_time='2019-07-17T18:30:57Z'>
	<summary>Docs builds are failing</summary>
	<description>
This is both on master and the fix_docs_gen branch. It appears to be a TensorFlow install error in the rtfd environment.
See:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://readthedocs.org/projects/garage/builds/9260419/&gt;https://readthedocs.org/projects/garage/builds/9260419/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://readthedocs.org/projects/garage/builds/9260420/&gt;https://readthedocs.org/projects/garage/builds/9260420/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ryanjulian' date='2019-06-26T22:11:43Z'>
		Looks like changing the python interpreter from 2.x to 3.x in rtfd advanced settings broke master.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/commit/44fb818d9dadbf85cb63c1a7ebcaae735e1fa8e4&gt;This commit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fixes it by forcing python 3.6 since tf doesn't support 3.7, but then rtfd tries to fetch dm_control from pypi instead of github and &lt;denchmark-link:https://readthedocs.org/projects/garage/builds/9284984/&gt;fails there&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ryanjulian' date='2019-06-27T20:32:11Z'>
		ReadTheDocs appears to be trying to use easy_install to attempt to install the package, which is a really old way of installing python packages.
easy_install fails to properly parse the &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0508/&gt;PEP508&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 string used to declare the git-based dependency for dm_control in setup.py
I attempted to force it to use pip to install with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/commit/e6119bd1e5235f970ef6dd3c75789c9feedc5f04&gt;this commit&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 -- we will see what the results are.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ryanjulian' date='2019-06-27T21:19:34Z'>
		Still the same :|
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ryanjulian' date='2019-06-27T21:23:12Z'>
		My attempt got a little farther, but is still hanging up on dm_control and mpi4py installs, because we can't get some C-based libraries (e.g. mujoco) on ReadTheDocs.
Is install required to generate the apidoc?
If so, I think we will have to create a special requirements file which omits the offending packages, then mock them out using autodoc_mock_imports. There is a guide &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/stable/faq.html#i-get-import-errors-on-libraries-that-depend-on-c-modules&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
TODO:

Determine if install is required to generate the API doc
Create docs/requirements.txt which lists the install dependencies only for documentation and omits the offending packages
Add appropriate autodoc_mock_imports config
File a bug to investigate pbr, pyproject.toml, and other ways of unifying requirements lists separate from setup.py

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>