<bug id='853' author='zhanpenghe' open_date='2019-08-29T20:39:51Z' closed_time='2019-09-04T21:56:56Z'>
	<summary>Make snapshot_config a required argument</summary>
	<description>
Currently, if we don't pass a snapshot_config to the runner like this (sorry, I am an old school garage user so I did not catch up with the snapshotter):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;def run_task(*_):
    with LocalTFRunner() as runner:
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

the snapshots and log data could locate at different locations SILENTLY when we specify a log directory or log prefix.
I suggest that we should make this argument (i.e. the snapshot_config of a local runner) required so doing this will at least raise an error. Or, alternatively, I think we should handle this by forcing the snapshotter to use the log directory of dowel and remove the snapshot_dir from snapshotter. What do you think?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/krzentner&gt;@krzentner&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/naeioi&gt;@naeioi&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ryanjulian&gt;@ryanjulian&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zequnyu&gt;@zequnyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zhanpenghe' date='2019-08-29T20:41:26Z'>
		This should either be required, or the default behavior should be sane. It should not locate the logs at different positions.
I slightly prefer just making the defaults sane, since writing a SnapshotConfig adds friction.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zhanpenghe' date='2019-08-29T20:42:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ryanjulian&gt;@ryanjulian&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I prefer this too.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zhanpenghe' date='2019-08-29T21:40:53Z'>
		I agree it is dangerous to have a silent bug: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/pull/699#issuecomment-507883750&gt;#699 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
It is interesting to force  to use  directory, since as I studied the source code, it's kind of hard to get  from . For this, we might need to refactor logger's API? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhanpenghe&gt;@zhanpenghe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Also I think this way we need to think more about 's default  when we are not using experiment API (when doing tests).
Alternatively as you pointed out, we can make config required for Runner, and add a temporary config to test fixtures for the use of every test.
It's hard to foresee which one is better, but I can try both to figure out.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='zhanpenghe' date='2019-09-04T21:56:56Z'>
		Close by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/pull/860&gt;#860&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>