<bug id='231' author='mohammedayub44' open_date='2018-10-16T15:20:06Z' closed_time='2018-10-26T07:59:55Z'>
	<summary>Running on CPU giving error after running local_init_op</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I'm running the quick start example from documentation on a CPU machine using the following -
Tensorflow: 1.8.0
OS: Windows
Python: 3.5.5
I get an error what seems to be a InvalidArgumentError while its trying to export the model. Attached is the cmd output log for more info. Also the config file. Not sure what I'm doing wrong.
Command : 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/files/2483746/error_opennmt_run_cpu.txt&gt;error_opennmt_run_cpu.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/files/2483752/params_yml.zip&gt;params_yml.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Appreciate any help.
Thanks !
Mohammed Ayub
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T15:32:26Z'>
		Hi,
This is a duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/issues/142&gt;#142&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
It was a TensorFlow issue that has been fixed in TensorFlow 1.10.0. If you can't update your TensorFlow version right now, you should replace train_and_eval by train to avoid the error.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T18:27:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/guillaumekln&gt;@guillaumekln&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I cannot upgrade the Tensorflow version because I need to use this model in another application that runs Tensorflow 1.8. I will probably use  command to run the training. Do I need a separate command for  part ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T18:46:09Z'>
		Yes, you can still run eval or infer separately.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T18:55:05Z'>
		great thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/guillaumekln&gt;@guillaumekln&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T19:29:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/guillaumekln&gt;@guillaumekln&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Running the eval step gives the same error, not sure if any changes are required to the  file.
Below are the commands I ran without chaging anything in yml file:

onmt-main train --model_type NMTSmall --auto_config --config data.yml
onmt-main eval --model_type NMTSmall --auto_config --config data.yml

Mohammed Ayub
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-16T19:50:53Z'>
		Per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/issues/142&gt;#142&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the issue happens during evaluation or inference (more specifically during beam search). Splitting training and evaluation only allows to run the training fully.
However, it only happens with small models or models that are not fully trained. I suggest letting the train run longer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-17T01:16:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/guillaumekln&gt;@guillaumekln&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 oh okay. I will try running it for longer time and update you. Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-24T13:42:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/guillaumekln&gt;@guillaumekln&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Sorry for the late response. I ran the model for about 12,000 steps and ran the eval its giving me the below error.

Attached is the complete Command line output file.:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/files/2510704/error_transformerbig.txt&gt;error_transformerbig.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Is this because of short sentences in the eval file. I could see some of them have just one or 2 words in each line.
Thanks !
Mohammed Ayub
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='mohammedayub44' date='2018-10-26T07:59:55Z'>
		You should post a new issue with this error if it is still happening. I did not manage to reproduce it.
Closing this issue as it is initially a duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/OpenNMT/OpenNMT-tf/issues/142&gt;#142&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>