<bug id='272' author='Pironus' open_date='2019-02-01T02:22:14Z' closed_time='2019-06-11T18:30:13Z'>
	<summary>ml5.pix2pix Issue : Grey Patch Overlay</summary>
	<description>
Hi! I am running the ml5.pix2pix script from many different computers, and I always get the same issue: a grey patch overlayed on top of the output image. The same issue is happening with the &lt;denchmark-link:https://ml5js.org/docs/pix2pix-example&gt;pikachu example on ml5's website&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/17068463/52098694-05919c00-259e-11e9-9854-d16dc30c8fbd.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  (circled here in yellow)
It does not seem to be a problem with my computer, but somehting in the code itself. Any idea what's  wrong?
Thanks in advance!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-01T18:33:05Z'>
		Oh, weird! I can't reproduce this, but I am running on a mac with Chrome Version 72.0.3626.81 (Official Build) (64-bit). What OS and browser are you using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-01T20:27:15Z'>
		Thanks for your answer...yes, on safari, and some version of firefox (for mac), it works. I am using a PC, with Chrome &amp; Firefox. I am opening the pikachu example from different PCs, with the same browsers (chrome or firefox), and I get the same issue. Any idea?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-02T17:29:25Z'>
		Thank you for reporting this, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Pironus&gt;@Pironus&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
!
I was wondering what's your PC's OS version(windows 8 or 10?), and your Chrome's version. It will help me to reproduce the error. Also is there any error or warning in your browser's console?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-02T18:00:27Z'>
		I am using Chrome 71 on Windows 8.1.
There is no errors in the console, just the following messages:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/17068463/52167545-7b0a8300-26ea-11e9-9b06-829f1bda3ac2.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-06T15:07:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yining1023&gt;@yining1023&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , did you have time to look into this bug? I have been trying to debug it myself, no luck so far :/
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-06T16:33:35Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Pironus&gt;@Pironus&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I tried to use Browserstack to test Chrome 71 in Windows 8.1 environment, but I cannot reproduce the error :/.
One way to debug it is to run the pix2pix examlple(&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ml5js/ml5-examples/tree/master/p5js/Pix2Pix/Pix2Pix_callback&gt;code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) locally, and console.log the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ml5js/ml5-examples/blob/1986d7a571572f17e926adc1603b6438414263b1/p5js/Pix2Pix/Pix2Pix_callback/sketch.js#L100&gt;results&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in the  function to see if the the transfer function is giving the whole output image. If you could send me the results, I can check it. Thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-11T13:29:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yining1023&gt;@yining1023&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I have the same problem in my implementation as well. I posted it in the tensorflowjs google group &lt;denchmark-link:https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!msg/tfjs/uV5sbRaXM_E/XcjppJsXBAAJ&gt;https://groups.google.com/a/tensorflow.org/forum/#!msg/tfjs/uV5sbRaXM_E/XcjppJsXBAAJ&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It seems not to work in some versions of windows. I have tested the output of the generator network and it seems that the output of the network is wrong (half-zeroed).
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Pironus' date='2019-02-11T13:48:18Z'>
		Thank you so much, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zaidalyafeai&gt;@zaidalyafeai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Pironus' date='2019-06-11T18:30:13Z'>
		Hi All! I will close this for now assuming this is either no longer an issue or is no longer of interest. Please feel free to reopen if you're still encountering this issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>