<bug id='383' author='johnnyKontec' open_date='2019-05-24T04:14:47Z' closed_time='2020-11-05T16:03:16Z'>
	<summary>some iOS devices not working properly</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;→ Description 📝&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

i tried different apple devices to test ml5.js (&lt;denchmark-link:https://ml5js.org/docs/image-classification-example&gt;https://ml5js.org/docs/image-classification-example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). And find that some of them can not working properly. There are no any related error messages found in console log.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;→ Screenshots 🖼&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

iPhone X
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/50976413/58302198-780fdb80-7e1c-11e9-9518-5e5b5a388967.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;→ Helpful Information 🦄&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

All using safari to open the example link
Working:
iPhone 6(iOS 12.3)
IPad 2018(iOS 12.2)
Not Working
IPhone X(iOS 12.2)
IPhone XR(iOS 12.3)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='johnnyKontec' date='2019-06-11T15:24:38Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/johnnyKontec&gt;@johnnyKontec&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - thanks for the notes here. Interesting that some of the demos do not work in iPhoneX. A few ideas on why the examples might not be running:

Sometimes the issue could also be that loading the large models might not be so suitable for mobile devices which could explain why those examples aren't loading.
Usually chrome and firefox work best when working with ml5 and p5js. This is something also in the back of our minds - making sure browser support on desktop and mobile are ok. Though generally speaking, the size of the models will affect the performance or the ability for the device to run the example.

Thanks for flagging this!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='johnnyKontec' date='2019-06-14T21:11:21Z'>
		Does it have to do with getUserMedia (on iOS firefox and chrome)? Thats my basic experience - and conclusion - so far on iOS - only Safari supports getUserMedia. See link: &lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/41619598/alternative-to-getusermedia-for-reading-live-camera-stream-on-ios&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/41619598/alternative-to-getusermedia-for-reading-live-camera-stream-on-ios&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='johnnyKontec' date='2020-11-05T16:03:16Z'>
		Tested the image classification examples on iPhoneXR and they seem to be working using Safari and Firefox (mobile)! Maybe additional support has been added over the last year to enable this: &lt;denchmark-link:https://caniuse.com/stream&gt;https://caniuse.com/stream&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Closing for now, but please reopen if you're still noticing this issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>