<bug id='927' author='joeyklee' open_date='2020-04-20T20:45:56Z' closed_time='2020-11-24T14:59:15Z'>
	<summary>[Teachable Machine] P5 Web Editor URL goes to different user's project</summary>
	<description>
Dear ml5 community,
I'm submitting a new issue. Please see the details below.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;→ Step 1: Describe the issue 📝&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Did you find a bug? Want to suggest an idea for feature?


Bug

When one navigates to &lt;denchmark-link:https://editor.p5js.org/ml5/sketches/ImageModel_TM&gt;https://editor.p5js.org/ml5/sketches/ImageModel_TM&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which is the URL that should open up the default teachable machine URL from the ml5 account, for some reason the URL opens up to another user's project 
I think this may have to do with the way that the URL handling occurs on the p5 web editor... my hunch is that if we run our batch update/upload script and another project in the web editor database has the same name, then that existing project takes that named URL and not the typical id string maybe?
We definitely should try to figure out why this is occurring so that people using teachable machine don't get confused as to why they are being sent to this existing project!
cc/ &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/catarak&gt;@catarak&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bomanimc&gt;@bomanimc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='joeyklee' date='2020-04-30T23:37:18Z'>
		Thanks for reporting! I noticed that the web editor is making an API request to https://editor.p5js.org/editor/projects/ImageModel_TM to fetch the sketch. So it would make sense that it would be finding the first sketch with the name ImageModel_TM.
I think the way to fix this would be to change the API request so that the username is in the request URL. This hadn't come up before since most sketches are resolved by ID, but by exposing some URL via slug this issue shows itself :). I think the URL should be changed to /&lt;username&gt;/projects/&lt;slug&gt;.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='joeyklee' date='2020-04-30T23:38:18Z'>
		I don't think it's possible to transfer this issue across to the p5.js web editor repository but I'll make a new ticket there.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>