<bug id='1148' author='Unlingius' open_date='2019-01-17T17:19:53Z' closed_time='2020-06-26T02:48:47Z'>
	<summary>different image.transforms with different cars</summary>
	<description>
Hi! I have a question about image.transform. I use modified manual_control.py example.
I set x,y,z roll, pitch, yaw of attached camera to [2.0, 0.0, 1.0, 0.0, 0.0, 0.0], relative to car.
My car is on the flat horizontal road, and i look, what image.transform is received. I expect, that image.transform.z will be 1.0 relative to road (my car is not moving), but it's false, image.transform.z is 1.143.
Moreover, then i push backspace to change the car. After it, when car has dropped on the road, i wait for receiving image.transform again. And these transforms are significantly different. Why? It looks like a bug.
i understand, that there are physics, suspension.... But difference of z 0.14 is too huge for that effects i think.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Unlingius' date='2019-01-17T17:45:53Z'>
		Oh, now i select car "Lincoln Mkz2017".  I observe, that when my car hardly brakes, its nose turn to up, not down.
UPD: I observe, that some car in rest on horizontal flat give not zero vehicle.transform.pitch and roll. Workaround for me is to check vehicle.transform before using car. But, generally, it is strange. What does Carla team think about it?
Below is cars with correct model (pitch=roll=0 on horiz plane):
shevrolet impala
seat leon
ford mustang
citroen c3
bmw grandtourer
toyota prius
mini cooperst
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Unlingius' date='2019-01-18T10:27:33Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Unlingius&gt;@Unlingius&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for reporting!
The pivot of the vehicles is at the bottom of the chassis, so that difference in Z is due to the height of the wheels and may be different between vehicles.
The issue with the pitch, roll seems like a bug indeed, we'll investigate this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Unlingius' date='2020-03-19T22:11:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcgpuig&gt;@marcgpuig&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do we know if this issue is solved?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>