<bug id='1207' author='anshulpaigwar' open_date='2019-02-01T17:16:13Z' closed_time='2020-06-26T02:49:27Z'>
	<summary>Carla 0.9.2 gets slower after every iteration of scenario_runner</summary>
	<description>
I am using Scenario_runner with Carla 0.9.2. I observed while doing multiple repetitions Carla gets slower and slower. I am running Carla in benchmark mode with fps = 10hz and after every repetition framerate drops (frame rate =  3 Hz after 50 reps). I am destroying all the actors after every rep but it seems memory is not completely released. When I restart the Carla server the frame rate goes back to normal.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Is there any way to refresh/reset Carla world using python API ??&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

world.destroy() doesn't solve the problem.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-02-08T11:59:03Z'>
		Yes, that looks like if some sensor is not properly destroyed.

Is there any way to refresh/reset Carla world using python API ??

Not yet, but soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-03-01T00:13:30Z'>
		Try launching the simulator and the Scenario runner using python sub-processes, to restart the server kill the process and relaunch. Steps to launch and kill a process can be found here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4789837/how-to-terminate-a-python-subprocess-launched-with-shell-true&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4789837/how-to-terminate-a-python-subprocess-launched-with-shell-true&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-03-06T09:12:58Z'>
		This the hack I also tried. I made a shell script to launch and kill the server in loop
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-03-06T14:33:51Z'>
		Since last week's 0.9.4, it is possible to reload the world. That should clean up every residual actor that gets lost in the world.
world = client.reload_world()
Have you tried this? seems easier than killing the simulator process each time. You can also start a different map with
world = client.load_world('Town01')
Nevertheless, I'm marking this as bug to investigate further and see if we're leaking actors.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>