<bug id='1270' author='anshulpaigwar' open_date='2019-02-19T09:57:25Z' closed_time='2020-03-19T22:29:17Z'>
	<summary>Python API for Carla 0.9.3 requires libpng16  incompatible with ROS</summary>
	<description>
Python API for Carla 0.9.3 requires libpng16 while ROS and Gazebo still work with libpng12. When I installed libpng16 using apt-get it auto removes some important Gazebo and ROS files. I think Carla should also stick to libpng12 for a while. Is there any way to install both libpng16 and libpng12 ??
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-02-19T10:02:09Z'>
		This is a known issue, unfortunately we don't know how to fix this except by removing PNG support &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/pull/924&gt;#924&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. The problem is that we use Boost GIL for handling images, and as it turns out is not compatible with libpng12.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-02-25T08:15:55Z'>
		I think you can reinstall ros-kinetic-gazebo* after installing Carla. I did this way and they both work well in my machine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-02-26T09:18:15Z'>
		Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jkewang&gt;@jkewang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this worked for me too.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-03-21T19:07:02Z'>
		Did you ever try FreeImage? Link to python wrapper: &lt;denchmark-link:http://freeimagepy.sourceforge.net/&gt;http://freeimagepy.sourceforge.net/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='anshulpaigwar' date='2019-10-28T22:32:10Z'>
		I actually found another solution that doesn't require reinstalling ROS. If you install the libpng16-16 package (which only has the libpng runtime library files) instead of libpng16-dev, none of the Gazebo/ROS files will be removed. And it seems that the CARLA Python API works fine with only the runtime library files: I tried the tutorial.py script and it saved the PNG files without a hitch.
Hopefully this works for others as well.
EDIT: I've only tried this with the 0.9.5 release version; not sure if it works in 0.9.6 or the latest dev version of CARLA.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>