<bug id='1325' author='Tauvic' open_date='2019-03-01T13:15:21Z' closed_time='2019-03-12T13:07:55Z'>
	<summary>BUG: Missing libcarla library</summary>
	<description>
CARLA 0.9.3 on Windows
Python Version: 3.5.6
In tried using the python client but when running spawn_npc.py I get a DLL load failure. I think a DLL libcarla is required but not included in the Windows distribution.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://drive.google.com/file/d/1YHTtYljaqv2kuvHYmqqtHSVMwdZaZAQe&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1YHTtYljaqv2kuvHYmqqtHSVMwdZaZAQe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-01T19:54:10Z'>
		Yes, this is known issue, but it's not missing libcarla but zlib. As a workaround you can compile (or download) a x64 zlib.dll, and paste it in the PythonAPI folder.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-03T17:01:14Z'>
		Thanx,
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;I tried your advise, downloaded zlib.dll x64 and put it into the PythonAPI folder. But still no success.
I got this error:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Traceback (most recent call last):
File spawn_npc.py, line 24, in 
import carla
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.6-win-amd64.egg\carla_init_.py", line 7, in 
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.6-win-amd64.egg\carla\libcarla.py", line 7, in 
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.6-win-amd64.egg\carla\libcarla.py", line 6, in bootstrap
File "C:\Users\tauvic.ritter\AppData\Local\Continuum\anaconda3\lib\imp.py", line 343, in load_dynamic
return _load(spec)
ImportError: DLL load failed: Kan opgegeven module niet vinden.
=======================================
Note that i renamed the egg because im using python 3.6.5 and not python 3.7
On line 7 in carla/PythonAPI/source/carla/init.py it says: from .libcarla import

This makes me still wondering what is libcarla?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-04T15:05:00Z'>
		I am having the same issue
CARLA 0.9.4
Windows
Python 3.5.6
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-06T14:51:30Z'>
		
Note that i renamed the egg because im using python 3.6.5 and not python 3.7

That won't necessarily work. Different versions are compiled with different "python.h" headers, they may not be compatible with each other.

This makes me still wondering what is libcarla?

The libcarla module contains all the native code (written in C++) of the carla module. At this point that's all there is, that's why in the __init__.py  there is only a line with from .libcarla import *. This library is included inside the .egg file, so I would be surprised if this is the DLL missing, most probably is some dependency of libcarla.
But it's nice that the error message only says a DLL is missing, not which DLL, isn't it? 😄
It may also be that the DLL needs to be added to the anaconda path somehow, I have never tried running the client with anaconda on Windows.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-07T13:35:44Z'>
		Try my branch marcgpuig/zlib_static_link
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-10T02:21:46Z'>
		Encountering the same error with python 3.7.2 using anaconda on Windows 10 with compiled version of CARLA 0.9.4
Edit: Created a new environment in Anaconda, and now it's working fine. Could it be related to Anaconda in some way?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-12T13:06:37Z'>
		Great &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SAmmarAbbas&gt;@SAmmarAbbas&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for sharing!
Edit: Closing the issue because this error was fixed in 0.9.4.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-28T10:54:58Z'>
		Hello,
i have the same Issue on Windows 10, Python 3.7.2 (64 Bit) and Carla 0.9.4.
Pasting the zlib.dll into the PythonAPI folder didn´t worked for me.
When there will be a compiled Version from Carla 0.9.4 for Windows which works?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-28T19:59:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DanielDrde&gt;@DanielDrde&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it works for me on Windows 10 with Carla 0.9.4, so I guess it's not a fault on their part. Are you using anaconda? In any case, I would suggest creating a new virtual environment with Python 3.7, and testing it there.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-29T08:46:26Z'>
		I´ve tried it with Visual Studio Code and the Idle Editor with no success. But i haven´t tried to create a virtual environment. Do you use the virtualenv Package for creating this new environment? I´m not that much experienced with Python, so thanks for your Help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Tauvic' date='2019-03-30T20:17:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/DanielDrde&gt;@DanielDrde&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I created a new environment with Anaconda for Python 3.7.2. I guess you could try with virtualenv as well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Tauvic' date='2019-04-02T09:19:44Z'>
		I´ve tried it with a new virtual environment and a new installation of python 3.7.2, Carla 0.9.3 and 0.9.4 but unfortunately it didn´t worked. Same error Message:
Traceback (most recent call last):
File "c:/Users/Server/Downloads/CARLA_0.9.3/dynamic_weather.py", line 28, in 
import carla
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.7-win-amd64.egg\carla_init_.py", line 7, in 
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.7-win-amd64.egg\carla\libcarla.py", line 7, in 
File "PythonAPI\carla-0.9.3-py3.7-win-amd64.egg\carla\libcarla.py", line 6, in bootstrap
File "C:\Users\Server\AppData\Local\Programs\Python\Python37\lib\imp.py", line 343, in load_dynamic
return _load(spec)
ImportError: DLL load failed: Das angegebene Modul wurde nicht gefunden.
So i think i have to work with the stable Version of carla (0.8.4) and unfortunately without the API.
Thanks for your help, Daniel.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='Tauvic' date='2019-04-09T16:51:11Z'>
		Same problem for me using Carla 0.9.4, Python 3.7.3 under Windows 10.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nsubiron&gt;@nsubiron&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it seems the "DLL" that failed to load is libcarla.cp37-win_amd64.pyd
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='Tauvic' date='2019-04-29T07:13:24Z'>
		I have the same problem &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/fbuchinger&gt;@fbuchinger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 but with windows 7. Did you fix it ?
Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='Tauvic' date='2019-08-16T05:32:35Z'>
		I have the same problem
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='Tauvic' date='2019-10-24T22:56:02Z'>
		same problem. But it only occurred to my own .py file. The same "No module named 'Carla'." didn't show when I run the built-in example .py files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='Tauvic' date='2020-01-11T22:15:56Z'>
		Same problem here w/ carla 0.9.5
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='Tauvic' date='2020-06-18T00:08:20Z'>
		... and the same here with Windows and 0.9.9.
Tried with python 3.8 (which isn't supposed to work, as I found out later) and Python 2.7.18 (which should work, but doesn't)
Traceback (most recent call last):
File "spawn_npc.py", line 24, in 
import carla
ImportError: No module named carla
Hey, carla-team, we all know that linux is far more sexy and all, but couldn't you make this just a little bit easier for us poor Windows-victims? Pleaaaase?
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='Tauvic' date='2020-07-03T14:56:24Z'>
		My suggestion is to use Python 3.7 along with a clean virtual environment.
In particular, I downgraded Python from 3.8.0. to 3.7.8 and tested everything in a clean virtualenv environment managed by PyCharm.  That's worked for me on CARLA 0.9.8 on Windows 10.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>