<bug id='2864' author='najibghadri' open_date='2020-05-18T10:20:57Z' closed_time='2020-09-07T11:58:54Z'>
	<summary>Recorder file info - can't get position data.</summary>
	<description>
0.9.8
I need the position of vehicles, lane and pedestrians aroung ego car, but can't get any from a recorder log. I have read through the API, used all arguments etc, and even the code leading to CarlaRecorderQuery.cpp.
I have a recording full of cars aroung the hero car and pedestrians and later I call client.show_recorder_file_info(recorder_filename, show_all) with the server on, and I get a header, listing all the Creates of the sensors and traffic lights and whatnot, but only one vehicle the hero vehicle, and then it lists the frames list of frames but still no data about any other vehicle or pedestrian.
Why do I need this is simple: I need ground truth data for testing and training NNs. That's mainly why I am using a simulator.
A snapshot so you see there are vehicles:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/11639734/82202036-93afa400-9901-11ea-94c7-41fb4bd87bdf.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The result:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/najibghadri/285edb21dc44343a141f8cccea45f440#file-show_recorder_file_info-py-a-output&gt;https://gist.github.com/najibghadri/285edb21dc44343a141f8cccea45f440#file-show_recorder_file_info-py-a-output&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

As I said I tried everything, tried show_recorder_actors_blocked min distance min time with very small, zero, -1. Hope I am missing something. Obviously tried opening the file too.
Supposedly show file info should show all the data.

(frames, times, events, state, positions...)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='najibghadri' date='2020-06-26T06:37:08Z'>
		This sounds weird. It may be a bug. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bernatx&gt;@bernatx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Axel1092&gt;@Axel1092&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you take a look?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='najibghadri' date='2020-07-02T11:00:06Z'>
		This is very strange. Did you use the recorder from the manual_control.py script, or you used separated scripts as start_recording.py?
We will try to reproduce that, but it is clear that the recorder only got the hero vehicle.
Can you specify the steps you follow to record that session?
Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='najibghadri' date='2020-08-31T11:39:41Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>