<bug id='2994' author='elandg' open_date='2020-06-25T18:01:51Z' closed_time='2020-09-06T23:58:55Z'>
	<summary>Unable to control vehicle in Carla with Logitech G29 steering wheel</summary>
	<description>
I've been trying to run Carla using the manual_control_steeringwheel.py file, but am repeatedly getting "NoSectionError: No section: 'G29 Racing Wheel'". I will attach the full terminal output below. I am using the 0.9.9.2 Windows version of Carla, starting CarlaUE4.exe first, and using the Logitech G29 steering wheel. After reading some other posts, I have included a wheel_config.ini file in the carla folder, installed Logitech G Hub, and have tried using self._parser.read(r"C:/Users/Eric Landgraf/Default/Umich/UMTRI/CARLA_0.9.9.2-W/PythonAPI/examples/wheel_config.ini"), which should be the absolute path (both will be attached as text files). If anyone has gotten their Logitech G29 steering wheel to work with Carla, please let me know what I should change.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/44939120/85770771-42a58380-b6e9-11ea-9d4f-a1f6aeb8aa7f.JPG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/files/4833045/wheel_config.txt&gt;wheel_config.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/files/4833041/manual_control_steeringwheel.txt&gt;manual_control_steeringwheel.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='elandg' date='2020-07-01T16:10:00Z'>
		I apologize for the simple mistake, I had moved the "wheel_config.ini" file to the main carla folder without changing the absolute path. However, I am now getting an out of bounds error.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/44939120/86266571-69553580-bb93-11ea-9aaf-1936f76d7da3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I have uncommented out the line  and that has lead to the [] you see printed above the error message. I am going to try reconfiguring my g29 steering wheel and see if that helps. Any other suggestions are also appreciated.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='elandg' date='2020-08-30T23:39:42Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='elandg' date='2020-09-19T16:23:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/elandg&gt;@elandg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Did you figure out the list index out of range?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='elandg' date='2020-10-21T20:47:38Z'>
		
@elandg Did you figure out the list index out of range?

This is because the number of axes is 0, making the value in jsInputs to be wrong. If you try self._joystick.get_numaxes(), you can see it.
To check if it is possible to do it in Win10, I have tried some workarounds but there seems to be no simple fix.

I tried to replace pygame by pygame_sdl2. This helps in detecting 4 axes.
Then there are more problems - as pygame_sdl2 does not implement everything, so many complaints were out.
I stopped pushing when I realized that I need to also rewrite pygame.surfarray.make_surface(), as this is not supported by pygame_sdl2.

It makes sense to have a note in the release saying that it is just problematic to make the G29 steering wheel also work for Win10.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='elandg' date='2020-10-22T14:42:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chengchihhong&gt;@chengchihhong&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Turns out pygame has a branch that has sdl2. Using that solved the problem.
Edit: this is what I did.
pip3 uninstall pygame
pip3 install pygame==2.0.0.dev6
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>