<bug id='3092' author='youngsend' open_date='2020-07-22T03:47:43Z' closed_time='2020-10-04T13:32:24Z'>
	<summary>0.9.8 - Cannot create navigation bin file if import by Create one Blueprint asset</summary>
	<description>
Hi, everyone.
I am new to carla. I am using 0.9.8 and I want to spawn walker on my own map.
What I have done:
When I import my test.fbx into carla Unreal Editor by Create one Blueprint asset, FbxScene blueprint is generated and all StaticMeshes are in it. I cannot generate the pedestrian navigation bin file.
When I import test.fbx into Editor by Create Level Actors, FbxScene is not generated (SceneNode is generated) and I succeed in generating bin file and spawning walkers on sidewalk (using the provided RecastBuilder).
However, I find that the latter import method loses RoadRunnerTrafficJunction information compared to the former method.
My question:
Can I generate pedestrian navigation bin file while importing by Create one Blueprint asset?
I think this should be possible, because all tutorials I found choose Create one Blueprint asset.
I'm confused because in those tutorials' screenshots, road static meshes appeared in World Outliner, while my static meshes are all in FbxScene blueprint class.
Thank you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='youngsend' date='2020-07-22T07:56:26Z'>
		I deleted the Sidewalk StaticMesh in FbxScene and added it (it is in Static folder) again into World Outliner.
After that I succeeded in creating pedestrian navigation file and spawning walker on sidewalk.
However, I still want to ask why navigation bin file cannot be created with FbxScene holding the Sidewalk StaticMesh.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='youngsend' date='2020-07-24T00:42:41Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bernatx&gt;@bernatx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you help with this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='youngsend' date='2020-07-24T13:53:25Z'>
		Hi,
Have you any file to share so we can test it?
I suppose the FBX has something that has problems when it is imported to Unreal (we use the FBX importer from Unreal).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='youngsend' date='2020-09-27T12:51:33Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>