<bug id='310' author='felipecode' open_date='2018-03-26T12:51:34Z' closed_time='2018-07-30T15:52:48Z'>
	<summary>Start Positions are different before the first reset.</summary>
	<description>
The CARLA simulator periodically resets itself while waiting for
the python client to connect.
However, If the python client system connects to the
CARLA simulator before the server resets a first time, it receives
a set of start position in different order.
Tested:
Carla 0.7.1
Carla 0.8
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='felipecode' date='2018-04-17T09:55:41Z'>
		
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4332953/38862776-1ccf45e4-4236-11e8-82dd-d238611c9e94.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4332953/38862789-28b66f0e-4236-11e8-9837-2077a229efaa.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='felipecode' date='2018-04-17T09:56:10Z'>
		We can sort the positions before sending them by object name, this way the positions would always arrive in the same order.
diff --git a/Unreal/CarlaUE4/Plugins/Carla/Source/Carla/Game/CarlaGameModeBase.cpp b/Unreal/CarlaUE4/Plugins/Carla/Source/Carla/Game/CarlaGameModeBase.cpp
index 1e0049d..f191b21 100644
--- a/Unreal/CarlaUE4/Plugins/Carla/Source/Carla/Game/CarlaGameModeBase.cpp
+++ b/Unreal/CarlaUE4/Plugins/Carla/Source/Carla/Game/CarlaGameModeBase.cpp
@@ -287,5 +287,8 @@ APlayerStart *ACarlaGameModeBase::FindUnOccupiedStartPoints(
 #endif // WITH_EDITOR
     }
   }
+  UnOccupiedStartPoints.Sort([](const APlayerStart &amp;Lhs, const APlayerStart &amp;Rhs){
+    return Lhs.GetName() &lt; Rhs.GetName();
+  });
   return FoundPlayerStart;
 }
However, this order would be the one of the first reset, i.e., precisely the one that we don't want. I don't see any other property of the actors persistent among runs and episodes.
Changing the order of the positions would mean to change all the code that relies on that, on benchmark and other client code, where this order is hard-coded.
Since the client-server communication is going to change soon, allowing arbitrary positions and other improvements, it is better not to change this and live with this bug for now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-30T15:34:36Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-30T15:52:47Z'>
		As from version 0.9.0 we no longer have start positions listed, we'll add at some point a system for recommending start locations.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>