<bug id='3280' author='SchDevel' open_date='2020-09-10T13:30:13Z' closed_time='2020-09-24T07:45:27Z'>
	<summary>0.9.10: LiDAR point clouds not displaying NPC cars</summary>
	<description>
Hello together,
I am currently experiencing a problem regarding the LiDAR point clouds with CARLA, running on Ubuntu 18.04.
As shown in the attached screenshot, cars (red bounding box) are not reflecting any points. However, pedestrians work fine. This can be seen at the blue bounding box slightly behind the green one. The model / car with the LiDAR attached on has the green bounding box.
Non-NPC cars, just standing at the side of the road, work fine.
Is this some configuration problem?
Looking forward hearing from you.
Best Regards
SchDevel
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/71081085/92735645-dcd8a780-f379-11ea-9c34-e2ebea7eb1eb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SchDevel' date='2020-09-17T08:46:01Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SchDevel&gt;@SchDevel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This is not a configurable parameter and it should work fine.

Are you using the packaged version?
In case you don't: did you modify the editor with custom or new cars?
Do you know if it's a signle car model that is causing this? Which model it is?

I'm not able to reproduce your error on our current dev branch:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15848712/93447412-ab5c6080-f8d2-11ea-89d2-5eaf9e76eaa7.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So if this was an issue in your current version, it will be fixed in 0.9.10.
Cheers!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SchDevel' date='2020-09-24T02:01:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/SchDevel&gt;@SchDevel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 could you give us an update? Is this feature still not working for you?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SchDevel' date='2020-09-24T07:45:27Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/germanros1987&gt;@germanros1987&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/marcgpuig&gt;@marcgpuig&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
sorry for my late response.
I actually did a clean install of the CARLA server to make sure that I did not mess up anything in the editor.
Indeed, when importing my own blueprint car, I somehow messed up and replaced other car-files, too.
The problem is now solved.
Thank you so much!
Best regards
SchDevel
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>