<bug id='33' author='Tak-Au' open_date='2017-11-17T15:56:41Z' closed_time='2017-11-18T14:19:04Z'>
	<summary>Get images from the game</summary>
	<description>
I am able to get the server and client to run.  I loook though the python example.py.  I am trying to have the image and user action save so I can try out behavior cloning.  However I can’t seem to get image save although I set save image to true in the python example file.  I
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Tak-Au' date='2017-11-17T17:18:33Z'>
		Yes, you are right, there is a bug in the current Python implementation. We will fix it asap. Sorry about this
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Tak-Au' date='2017-11-17T17:39:40Z'>
		Is there anything i can help to solve this problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Tak-Au' date='2017-11-18T14:30:59Z'>
		Hey, thanks for offering! At the moment we are discussing how to fix this, so not much you can help, but it's appreciated :) we'll come with a solution soon
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Tak-Au' date='2017-11-18T17:11:42Z'>
		I edited the carla_manual_control.py to allow for image and data recording.  I am currently after imitation learning.  My goal is for be able to interface with Keras model to allow for the model to drive the car.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Tak-Au' date='2018-03-26T10:43:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nsubiron&gt;@nsubiron&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
   I am unable to save the images too... what is the work-around to get the images ...
Thank you
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Tak-Au' date='2018-03-26T10:55:49Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/naveen7v&gt;@naveen7v&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
You can check the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/blob/master/PythonClient/client_example.py&gt;client_example.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to see how is done. You can save the images there by running with the  switch
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ ./client_example.py -i
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Internally, the images received from the simulator have a member function to save the image as png
measurements, sensor_data = client.read_data()

for name, measurement in sensor_data.items():
    measurement.save_to_disk('filename.png')
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Tak-Au' date='2018-03-26T13:34:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nsubiron&gt;@nsubiron&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Dear sir...the client_example.py is as you say and i ran it with the -i switch,
but the client.read_data() returns a empty sensor_data dict... but measurements are there
I just have rgb camera sensor enabled...is it a problem in my side?
Edit:
When i ran the carla server using the build from source method ...the sensor data are saved to disk
Thank you
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>