<bug id='513' author='nsubiron' open_date='2018-06-18T15:42:26Z' closed_time='2020-03-19T21:55:57Z'>
	<summary>0.8.4 (Linux) - Random crashes when using two-wheeled vehicles</summary>
	<description>
Random crashes occur in PhysX related code concerning the vehicle's wheels. This crash seems to happen only when running the simulation with bikes and motorbikes. The exact place of the crash varies but it's usually due to some NaN value. Possibly some uninitialized memory in the shader that computes the wheel's physics.
Here an extract of the log of one of the crashes: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/files/2111938/log.txt&gt;log.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

As a workaround, for now you can disable all the two-wheeled vehicles with
CarlaSettings.ini
[CARLA/LevelSettings]
; Disable bikes and motorbikes, if true only four-wheeled
; vehicles will be spawned.
DisableTwoWheeledVehicles=true
Python
settings = CarlaSettings()
settings.set(DisableTwoWheeledVehicles=True)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nsubiron' date='2018-06-19T09:04:13Z'>
		is it possible to set bikes or motorbike as player vehicle? i tried using the init file, it cannot load...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nsubiron' date='2018-06-19T10:24:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MRAWAY77&gt;@MRAWAY77&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Please, open a separate issue for that
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nsubiron' date='2018-07-16T16:43:25Z'>
		I observed the same issue also when setting the number of vehicles to 0
but without setting the DisableTwoWheeledVehicles=true.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='nsubiron' date='2018-11-30T15:20:37Z'>
		In 0.9.1, if you are using the spawn_npc.py script you can use the --safe argument to spawn only vehicles that do not cause accidents. At this point all the bikes are left out, also the Isetta.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;./spawn_npc.py --safe
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='nsubiron' date='2020-03-19T21:55:57Z'>
		This should now be solved by the Traffic Manager.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>