<bug id='576' author='XGodina' open_date='2018-07-12T10:51:11Z' closed_time='2018-10-26T19:26:28Z'>
	<summary>Adjust Pedestrian Animations</summary>
	<description>

 Tweak Pedestrian scale
 Fix the scale difference between Idle and walk animations
 Improve Walkcicle animations

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='XGodina' date='2018-10-20T11:34:58Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-21T06:32:08Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/XGodina&gt;@XGodina&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - How to add animation to pedestrian like making them walk.


Can it be done in Unreal itself or we need any other modeling tool to achieve the same and then import it in unreal?


I want to move the pedestrian hands up and down , is there any tutorial or link I can refer to achieve the same.


Please guide as its really urgent.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-21T13:11:48Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/YDSh510&gt;@YDSh510&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Here &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/bing-search?keyword=animations&gt;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/bing-search?keyword=animations&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. There is a lot of documentation and Tutorial about animations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-23T05:35:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/XGodina&gt;@XGodina&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Thanks for the link. Also wanted to know if there is any documentation w.r.t to pedestrian blueprint BP_Walker as I need to add logic for adding hand movement. So wanted to understand how Carla team have done for legs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-24T09:12:41Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/XGodina&gt;@XGodina&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Any update w.r.t how to add hand movements in walker . ( Moving hands up and down)
As I don't see any option via CharacterMovement component.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-27T05:15:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/XGodina&gt;@XGodina&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Need some urgent pointers to proceed further. Please support.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='XGodina' date='2019-05-27T09:12:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/YDSh510&gt;@YDSh510&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't know what do you refer a w.r.t.  If you want to add new animation in pedestrian you have three ways.
1- Edit animation in Unreal - You can find a lot of tutorial on the internet
2- Edit in Maya and export to Unreal
3- We are working to control pedestrian by API. Will be available the next release.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>