<bug id='590' author='felipecode' open_date='2018-07-16T17:08:43Z' closed_time='2018-07-19T17:39:02Z'>
	<summary>Crash on 0.8.4</summary>
	<description>
related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/issues/513&gt;#513&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Specs:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I ran CARLA 0.8.4
Connected a client with python3
It crashed in less than 72 hours.
The number of pedestrians is 200.
Number of vehicles 0
The Bikes were not disabled but there were no vehicles
I am attaching the logs
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/carla-simulator/carla/files/2198645/CarlaUE4.log&gt;CarlaUE4.log&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-17T08:33:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-code&gt;[2018.07.14-02.07.23:428][162]LogSpawn: Warning: SpawnActor failed because of collision at the spawn location [X=-368.000 Y=25136.000 Z=127.000] for [YamahaBp_C]
[2018.07.14-02.07.23:464][162]LogCarla: Starting the timer to spawn the other -1 vehicles, one per 3.000000 seconds
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Nice, so it first spawns 1 vehicle then spawns -1 vehicle, seems optimal to me 😄
This seems like an issue of the vehicle spawner that it actually tried to spawn a motorbike. I'll take a look.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-17T09:42:16Z'>
		I'm not able to reproduce. I also noticed that in the last episode you actually requested 20 vehicles.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-17T16:18:44Z'>
		I don't know how that would happen. I don't change the configuration file.
I  noticed that the last episode was run with something like a default configuration.
20 vehicles, 30 pedestrians, weather 1
Anyway
I tried again also disabling the bikes. I haven't seen the crash in 24 hours.
I am still having some weird connection problems. But this could be on my side.
I will retry with version 0.8.2
Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-19T17:39:02Z'>
		So, conclusion.
You should set the flag:
conditions.set(DisableTwoWheeledVehicles=True)
Without this flag, it seems CARLA can crash even without vehicles..
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='felipecode' date='2018-07-19T19:38:22Z'>
		Still worth noticing that there is a bug in the current vehicle spawner. We are not fixing it for now as the vehicle spawner is most probably going to disappear in the 0.9.0 release.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>