<bug id='815' author='CarterLilley' open_date='2019-07-27T23:23:18Z' closed_time='2019-07-29T16:55:23Z'>
	<summary>CRITICAL An unexpected crash has occurred during conversion</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deepfakes/faceswap/files/3438692/crash_report.2019.07.27.191805371170.log&gt;crash_report.2019.07.27.191805371170.log&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Attached is my crash report. Extracted about 100 photos from both parties, trained for about 2hrs. 40 mins. Applying photo face to a video of me talking.
Not sure what's going on. I'm using a Microsoft Surface Book II, with a GTX 1060, i7, 16GB ram.
Need help ASAP please! Working on a time sensitive project! Thanks for everyone's hard work on this very impressive and cool program. Thought I would have way more issues up until now. Thanks.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-27T23:25:43Z'>
		This looks like a bug in face filter. Don't use the face filter and it should run through fine.
Also. 100 photos? 2 hours 40 mins? Your swap is going to be bad!
See here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://faceswap.dev/forum/app.php/faqpage&gt;https://faceswap.dev/forum/app.php/faqpage&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-27T23:33:02Z'>
		No, totally, I get that! This was just a preliminary test to see if I understand the workflow and process. Once I get this whole thing start to finish I'll be able to make a more complex one later this week.
Thanks for the help, by the way! I'm unsure how to not use the face filter - using the GUI version of faceswap. Is it a box or something? Sorry!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-27T23:33:59Z'>
		You should follow the FAQ because it will take you to a guide for extraction etc.
Basically don't use the filter/nfilter box. I will look to fix it at some point, but it won't be immediate.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-27T23:48:06Z'>
		I relied on the FAQ and the documentation pretty heavily to get me to this point! Im just trying to make a shitty preliminary test so that, should I not be able to do this for one reason or another, I don't waste too much time haha.
So, clearing both of those fields let it run without error, and gave me a converted clip as output. Which is nice...but there appears to be no discernible difference between the before/after. No edit at all.
I knew it wouldn't be good, but I was kind of expecting at least a garbled face-mess to confirm the process is working. Should it remain completely unchanged?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-28T14:56:28Z'>
		Usage issues are best raised in the Forum or in the Discord Server.
I am leaving this open as the initial issue is a bug.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='CarterLilley' date='2019-07-29T16:55:23Z'>
		The filter/nfilter bug in convert should be fixed in latest commit
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>