<bug id='575' author='aslicedbread' open_date='2019-03-01T01:28:14Z' closed_time='2020-06-10T09:50:27Z'>
	<summary>About the ValueError: Token indices sequence length is longer than the specified maximum sequence length</summary>
	<description>
Hi~
I recently used Flair to tag the electronic chinese medical records. And every record is a long text but less than 1000 characters. I found that Flair based on BERT has a limit on the length of the input sequence:

ValueError: Token indices sequence length is longer than the specified maximum  sequence length for this BERT model (613 &gt; 512). Running this sequence through BERT will result in indexing errors.

Is there a solution?
Hope to get your reply, Thanks.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='aslicedbread' date='2019-03-01T09:24:12Z'>
		Are you using bert-base-multilingual-cased or bert-base-chinese? Monolingual models give better tokenization wtih longer subwords segments due to the limited WordPiece vocabulary size.
Other than that, up to 1000 Chinese characters is pretty long. Can you split the text into smaller units like sentences or paragraphs?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='aslicedbread' date='2019-03-03T02:44:03Z'>
		
Are you using bert-base-multilingual-cased or bert-base-chinese? Monolingual models give better tokenization wtih longer subwords segments due to the limited WordPiece vocabulary size.
Other than that, up to 1000 Chinese characters is pretty long. Can you split the text into smaller units like sentences or paragraphs?

Hi~
Yes, I'm using bert-base-chinese.  Do you mean that 'bert-base-chinese' give better tokenization wtih longer subwords segments than 'bert-base-multilingual-cased' ? I‘m a bit confused about the Monolingual models, is it like BiLSTM-CRF model without bert ?
Yes, I split the text into smaller units later and it works.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='aslicedbread' date='2020-02-05T08:05:54Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aslicedbread&gt;@aslicedbread&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I am also facing the same issue. Could you please show me how you have split the text and feeding to the model?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='aslicedbread' date='2020-06-04T08:25:23Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>