<bug id='393' author='lucgiffon' open_date='2020-05-16T07:34:19Z' closed_time='2020-05-17T21:28:58Z'>
	<summary>Magnitude-based weight pruning with Keras doesn't work with actual Keras models</summary>
	<description>
Hello
The magnitude weight pruning procedure doesn't work with keras layers but only with tf.keras layers. I think it should be stated more clearly in the documentation.
On this page: &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/model_optimization/guide/pruning/pruning_with_keras#build_a_pruned_model_layer_by_layer&gt;https://www.tensorflow.org/model_optimization/guide/pruning/pruning_with_keras#build_a_pruned_model_layer_by_layer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I don't think it is specified a single time. I mean in the text. The code actually uses tf.keras but it is unclear why it couldn't work with keras alone. The title should at least be
Magnitude-based weight pruning with tf.keras
And I believe adding a bulletpoint in the "worth clarifying" section would be useful.
Bye
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lucgiffon' date='2020-05-17T21:25:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lucgiffon&gt;@lucgiffon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: thanks for the feedback and welcome followup on my response below.
I knew about this potential confusion and had something to partially improve it, now submitted &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/model-optimization/blob/master/tensorflow_model_optimization/g3doc/guide/pruning/pruning_with_keras.ipynb&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, where tf.keras is explicitly mentioned at the start. The API docs &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.tensorflow.org/model_optimization/api_docs/python/tfmot/sparsity/keras/prune_low_magnitude&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 take a similar approach.
It does not go as far as you said though, with mentioning tf.keras in the title and having a "worth clarifying" note, partially because the implicit idea behind anything under tensorflow.org is that it's specific to the TensorFlow version. I agree it's not perfect for everyone, but keeping it as is keeps things concise.
Past the Keras 2.3.0 release, TF will be the only backend in the official release. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/keras-team/keras/releases/tag/2.3.0&gt;https://github.com/keras-team/keras/releases/tag/2.3.0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and the general documentation updates on keras.io.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lucgiffon' date='2020-05-17T21:28:58Z'>
		Closing but feel free to reopen.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>