<bug id='150' author='picheny-nyu' open_date='2020-08-25T03:21:07Z' closed_time='2020-08-27T23:59:31Z'>
	<summary>Cannot compile flashlight with Conan</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Bug Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I get this error when trying to compile flashlight per the documentation:
cereal/1.3.0: Retrieving from server 'flashlight'
cereal/1.3.0: Trying with 'flashlight'...
ERROR: Failed requirement 'cereal/1.3.0' from 'conanfile.py (flashlight/0.1@conan/stable)'
ERROR: cereal/1.3.0 was not found in remote 'flashlight'
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Reproduction Steps&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I issued the following command per the documentation:
conan install flashlight 0.1@conan/stable -r=flashlight --build flashlight
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Platform and Hardware&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

GNU Linux 3.10.0-1127.18.2.el7.x86_64
Thanks
Michael
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Additional Context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

[Add any additional information here]
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T03:40:58Z'>
		cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jacobkahn&gt;@jacobkahn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T15:25:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/picheny-nyu&gt;@picheny-nyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 — since our recent consolidation, the Conan build is a bit broken - I'll get around to fixing it in the next week or so. Sorry about this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T15:59:22Z'>
		Any workarounds? I tried the manual build instructions and also ran into problems. Otherwise I guess I just have to wait :-(
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T16:04:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/picheny-nyu&gt;@picheny-nyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 — you can give more details on the problems you ran into with the manual build?
We're still getting things in order over the next few days.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T17:23:10Z'>
		In response to
cmake .. -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=Release -DFLASHLIGHT_BACKEND=CUDA
I get
-- Could NOT find GTest (missing: GTEST_LIBRARY GTEST_INCLUDE_DIR GTEST_MAIN_LIBRARY) (Required is at least version "1.10.0")
-- googletest not found - will download and build from source
-- Configuring incomplete, errors occurred!
This is for v0.2 which is per the documentation. Also even though I specify backend as CUDA I do not have NCCL and it tried to look for some distributed stuff anyway. I commented that out and then this error came up. It seemed to have done a partial copy of googletest but never successful compiled it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T23:42:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/picheny-nyu&gt;@picheny-nyu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 -- what do you want to build? The flashlight core? The ASR components? flashlight libraries? That'll help us figure out what's going on here.

cmake .. -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=Release -DFLASHLIGHT_BACKEND=CUDA

FLASHLIGHT_BACKEND has been changed to FL_BACKEND. This will be reflected in the build documentation soon.

It seemed to have done a partial copy of googletest but never successful compiled it

You don't need to install GoogleTest yourself - if you don't, the build will download it automatically.

do not have NCCL and it tried to look for some distributed stuff anyway

For now, even if you're not doing distributed training, you'll still need to install NCCL to build everything.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-25T23:46:49Z'>
		I did not try to install googletest, the build did not properly download it.
Is that change (to FL_BACKEND) valid on v0.2 ?
Regarding nccl I have a 10.2 CUDA version with nccl. How do I point to that (it is in a different directory, not sure how it finds CUDA stuff now).
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-26T18:10:14Z'>
		Please use for now v0.2 and installation from source, conan will be fixed only during several weeks.
Could you send the full log of your CMake command (without any your changes)? W2l can be built only with distributed mode, so please install NCCL and follow all installation instruction. Another option is to use docker image or follow installation steps in the docker file.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-26T19:17:15Z'>
		OK, luckily I found out that someone has a 10.2 CUDA nccl. How do I tell the build process where to find it?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-27T19:38:22Z'>
		Please set env variable NCCL_ROOT_DIR (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/facebookresearch/flashlight/blob/master/cmake/FindNCCL.cmake#L17&gt;https://github.com/facebookresearch/flashlight/blob/master/cmake/FindNCCL.cmake#L17&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-27T21:31:04Z'>
		Thanks. Done. Worked!!
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='picheny-nyu' date='2020-08-27T23:59:31Z'>
		Closing then for now, because Conan will be supported a bit later (and due to restructuring we need to fix it anyway).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>