<bug id='377' author='loomlike' open_date='2018-12-18T04:05:54Z' closed_time='2018-12-20T12:40:46Z'>
	<summary>python evaluation "KeyError: 'rating'" when a result DataFrame includes a col_rating column</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is affected by this bug?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Python evaluation module
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;How do we replicate the issue?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If col_rating != col_prediction and the result dataframe has both col_rating and col_prediction columns, _merge_rating_true_pred module's merge operation will change col_rating name as col_rating"_x" and col_rating"_y" automatically, which causes "KeyError: 'rating'" error.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Expected behavior (i.e. solution)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Since I explicitly pass the rating column name and prediction column name when I call the evaluation functions, I expect the functions to work with a result DataFrame that has col_prediction column and a ground-truth DataFrame that has col_rating column. Even if the result DataFrame has col_rating in addition to the col_prediction, the functions should ignore that and work as expected.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='loomlike' date='2018-12-18T08:59:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/loomlike&gt;@loomlike&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in designing the interface, the input dataframes should contain one of the two columns, either col_rating or col_prediction. The assumption is that the result DataFrame does not have both rating and prediction columns, otherwise it may not be necessary to have ground-truth and result DataFrames separated because the result DataFrame already contains both...
Probably some early-failing check is needed in the function to make sure inputs satisfy the requirements. What do you think?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='loomlike' date='2018-12-18T14:39:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yueguoguo&gt;@yueguoguo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Like the idea of early-failing. Probably check the input DataFrames and raise error at the beginning.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='loomlike' date='2018-12-20T12:40:46Z'>
		Fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/recommenders/pull/383&gt;#383&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>