<bug id='23' author='jwmueller' open_date='2019-10-11T19:08:36Z' closed_time='2019-11-20T01:20:01Z'>
	<summary>should have try-except block when fetching model files</summary>
	<description>
When running the basic image classification tutorial, I get log statements like:
[ worker local ] : FileNotFoundError: [Errno 2] No such file or directory: '/home/ubuntu/.mxnet/models/resnet50_v1b-0ecdba34.zip'
presumably because the file hasn't yet been downloaded.  However, we should enclose the file access in a try-except block to prevent such errors from printing, since the user may otherwise think autogluon is broken.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-11T19:31:02Z'>
		Yes, this is the downloading issue from gluoncv probably due to multiple process are trying downloading the same model, my temporary solution is to prefetch all the models from the gluoncv model zoo.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-11T19:41:22Z'>
		Why can't we just enclose that part in a try-except block?
Because the multi-process nature of the model-fetching causes problems?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-11T19:48:44Z'>
		Yes, I am not sure whether try-except would resolve the issue...
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-11T20:22:01Z'>
		The problem is because multiple parallel access of the same file. Try exception won't fix this.
One solution is adding a lock to gluoncv get_model function.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-11T20:50:43Z'>
		I will address this by adding a lock to AutoGluon built-in-network.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jwmueller' date='2019-10-12T00:04:06Z'>
		As mentioned during standup, we will probably require a general solution which allows threads to access and create files which potentially have overlapping names. Especially if we save the model parameters every epoch as is commonly done for early-stopping
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>