<bug id='377' author='CoinCheung' open_date='2020-03-25T06:25:55Z' closed_time='2020-04-06T20:31:31Z'>
	<summary>How could I save fitted model and reload in in another script ?</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I am new to autogluon, and I find the basic usage in the &lt;denchmark-link:https://autogluon.mxnet.io/tutorials/object_detection/beginner.html&gt;page&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which shows how could I train a yolov3 model. After the training is done, I need to save the trained best model, and use the saved model for prediction in the future tasks. I have found no explicit save/reload example in the docs, would you please tell me how could I save and reuse the best trained model ?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CoinCheung' date='2020-03-26T21:36:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jerryzcn&gt;@Jerryzcn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhreshold&gt;@zhreshold&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , can you please respond to this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CoinCheung' date='2020-03-26T21:51:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhanghang1989&gt;@zhanghang1989&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chongruo&gt;@chongruo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

By checking the existing detector implementation, I found there's no implemented  and  function, do you guys have discussion about this before?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CoinCheung&gt;@CoinCheung&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The easiest solution for you is to use  to dump and load the detector object. We will update once we have concrete solution for serialization and de-serialization.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CoinCheung' date='2020-03-26T22:44:31Z'>
		It was discussed before, but I don't think action was taken to implement it: (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/awslabs/autogluon/issues/183&gt;#183&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/awslabs/autogluon/issues/282&gt;#282&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ).
I think this should be high priority to enable ease of use for users.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CoinCheung' date='2020-03-26T23:30:45Z'>
		Sorry that I am not familiar with object detection code.
detector.model.save_parameters('net.params') should save the mxnet model params.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='CoinCheung' date='2020-03-27T02:10:16Z'>
		Thanks for replying !!!  if this problem is solved, please add a few lines to the doc so that we could figure this out faster.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>