<bug id='2821' author='Korijn' open_date='2020-06-11T11:26:08Z' closed_time='2020-08-12T05:33:31Z'>
	<summary>Installing package on Windows fails on too long filenames</summary>
	<description>
Installing onnx fails on my Windows 10 machine due to filepaths being too long ("De bestandsnaam of -extensie is te lang" is dutch for "The filename or -extension is too long"):
ERROR: Could not install packages due to an EnvironmentError: [WinError 206] De bestandsnaam of -extensie is te lang: 'c:\\users\\korij_000\\appdata\\local\\pypoetry\\cache\\virtualenvs\\zb-hps-algo-bkp0o5gs-py3.6\\Lib\\site-packages\\onnx\\backend\\test\\data\\node\\test_negative_log_likelihood_loss_input_shape_is_NCd1d2d3_none_no_weight_negative_ignore_index_expanded\\test_data_set_0'
I am able to work around this issue by installing to a folder higher up in my filesystem, but this filename looks a bit excessive.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Korijn' date='2020-06-18T05:20:48Z'>
		@jacky82226 : Let's fix this
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Korijn' date='2020-06-18T15:18:56Z'>
		***The links to the file and PR have been updated.
Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Korijn&gt;@Korijn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Thank you for reporting this bug! I was wondering that did you encounter other files also encounter this error? (Although it is the longest one...)
I suspect the problem is &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/blob/925b3657924c0c16cd20b54595f41e76159b03ab/onnx/backend/test/case/node/softmaxcrossentropy.py#L829&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and it has been update in a recent &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/pull/2725&gt;PR&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. It surprisingly passed Windows-CI somehow, maybe it's because the maximum length of filename varies on different Windows machines. (or different languages)
I will propose a PR to fix this. Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Korijn' date='2020-06-18T16:28:01Z'>
		If I may make a suggestion: don't include your tests and especially your test data in your wheels. It's not needed at runtime and makes the package much bigger.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Korijn' date='2020-06-19T17:12:27Z'>
		
If I may make a suggestion: don't include your tests and especially your test data in your wheels. It's not needed at runtime and makes the package much bigger.

Good point. Did you use pip install onnx? It should be unnecessary to include them while installing the library...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Korijn' date='2020-06-19T17:34:27Z'>
		

If I may make a suggestion: don't include your tests and especially your test data in your wheels. It's not needed at runtime and makes the package much bigger.

Good point. Did you use pip install onnx? It should be unnecessary to include them while installing the library...

Yes I did. You can either use the filter keyword arguments to find_packages in setup.py or filter the returned list manually to exclude all the test packages.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Korijn' date='2020-07-21T23:13:28Z'>
		To get away from such issue:


When you install python, the install should have asked you if you want to apply a fix for this:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/51624449/python-setup-disabling-path-length-limit-pros-and-cons


If you rejected the fix, and you're not using Windows 10, I suggest you upgrade it to. Starting with Windows 10 version 1607, if the filename is in Unicode, then you won't hit this limit.


Otherwise, use UNC path. "\?".


Make the test data file names shorter can  be a temporary solution, but it would be better if the underlying code could be fixed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Korijn' date='2020-07-22T07:25:01Z'>
		Thanks for the advice.
I read that you ended up not removing the test data because people are apparently using it? Just keep in mind that more and more people will start using the test data in the package and it will become harder and harder to remove it the longer you wait.
Just like there are alternative methods to deal with long paths as you explained, there are alternative ways to distribute test data too :) for example, they could use git clone and use command line options to shallowly retrieve just your test data folders.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Korijn' date='2020-07-22T22:28:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Korijn&gt;@Korijn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 please add your feedback about test data in the package in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/issues/2917&gt;#2917&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Korijn' date='2020-08-12T05:32:45Z'>
		Closing this issue as the long testnames have been changed. Rest of the discussion whether the test dta should be part of onnx package itself will be tracked under issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/onnx/onnx/issues/2917&gt;#2917&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>