<bug id='143' author='andrisan' open_date='2016-06-16T04:44:33Z' closed_time='2016-06-18T13:56:00Z'>
	<summary>Using tflearn in conda virtual environment</summary>
	<description>
I tried to use tflearn in conda virtual environment.
source activate &lt;environment_name&gt;
python
&gt;&gt;&gt;import tflearn
And it gave me the error of Segmentation fault, after tensorflow library is loaded:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I tensorflow/stream_executor/dso_loader.cc:108] successfully opened CUDA library libcublas.so locally
I tensorflow/stream_executor/dso_loader.cc:108] successfully opened CUDA library libcudnn.so locally
I tensorflow/stream_executor/dso_loader.cc:108] successfully opened CUDA library libcufft.so locally
I tensorflow/stream_executor/dso_loader.cc:108] successfully opened CUDA library libcuda.so locally
I tensorflow/stream_executor/dso_loader.cc:108] successfully opened CUDA library libcurand.so locally
Segmentation fault (core dumped)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

and then python exits
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='andrisan' date='2016-06-17T05:40:07Z'>
		Arf, these kind of errors are difficult to track. I will try to reproduce it.
Is it working when you are not using a virtual environment?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='andrisan' date='2016-06-17T07:05:46Z'>
		I haven't tried to install tflearn in system environment, as I installed tensorflow in the virtual environment. I think it defeats the purpose of isolated system that I want to achieve in the first place, if I install tflearn and tensorflow in the system environment.
Another articles I found suggest to install h5py and hdf5, and I tried to install those twos using:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;conda install h5py
conda install hdf5
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

And the problem still exists
Note:
I cannot import skimage.io in virtual environment too. It gave me the same error of Segmentation fault, however I can import skimage.io in system environment
Update:
It turns out that the problem is related to skimage. Even though scikit-image is listed in the installed package in my virtual environment (conda list), I do install it again (conda install scikit-image), and this solved the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='andrisan' date='2016-11-29T07:13:18Z'>
		I have this issue too,when I use tensorflow it works ,but when import tflearn ,it show Segmentation fault and break
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='andrisan' date='2017-04-07T04:50:02Z'>
		hi all, have you fixed this issue. i also have this issue when i finish training and testing, not  when import
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>