<bug id='154' author='rohanpooniwala' open_date='2016-06-24T08:02:01Z' closed_time='2016-06-28T05:16:01Z'>
	<summary>A little help with SequenceGenrator and lstm</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I am new to deep learning and have only decent knowledge of neural network and theano. I am starting to develop a lstm network with my own dictionary (which have three words as of now), and the input and output is totally based on trail and error. The program is working if I only use char in dictionary, but I want to use strings. Here is the code:
`
import tflearn
X = [[[1,0,0]],[[0,1,0]],[[0,0,1]]]
Y = [[0,1,0],[0,0,1],[1,0,0]]
dict = {'test ':0,'python ':1,'love ':2}
g = tflearn.input_data([None,  1,3])
g = tflearn.lstm(g, 10, return_seq=True)
g = tflearn.lstm(g, 10)
g = tflearn.fully_connected(g, 3, activation='softmax')
g = tflearn.regression(g, optimizer='adam', loss='categorical_crossentropy',                                     learning_rate=0.001)
m = tflearn.SequenceGenerator(g , dictionary=dict,seq_maxlen=1,  clip_gradients=5.0,                             checkpoint_path='model_shakespeare')
m.fit(X, Y, validation_set=0.1, batch_size=128,
n_epoch=1, run_id='shakespeare')
seed = ['love ']
print("-- TESTING...")
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;print ("predict :")&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;print (m.predict(seed))&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

print("-- Test with temperature of 1.0 --")
print(m.generate(6, temperature=1.0, seq_seed=seed))
print("-- Test with temperature of 0.5 --")
print(m.generate(6, temperature=0.5, seq_seed=seed))
`
This gives me the following error:
Traceback (most recent call last): File "lstm.py", line 28, in &lt;module&gt; print(m.generate(6, temperature=1.0, seq_seed=seed)) File "/usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/tflearn/models/generator.py", line 221, in generate sequence = sequence[1:] + next_char TypeError: can only concatenate list (not "str") to list 
Replacing the string (test,python,love) with (a,b,c) and changing seed to a string gives me no error. What I think is either the generate() doesn't support a string dictionary  OR I am doing something wrong.
I have tried many trial-error modification to try to fix this , nothing worked out.
Thanx in advance :)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-06-25T12:24:57Z'>
		I think the error is due to the fact that seed should be a string and not a list.
you can try:
seed = 'love '
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-06-25T12:27:46Z'>
		I tried that, in that case it tries to iterate each character and ends up with error
'L' not found in dictionary.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-06-25T12:37:14Z'>
		Arf yes, generator was created to handle char, and seem that it is not compatible with list.
Can you try to change: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tflearn/tflearn/blob/master/tflearn/models/generator.py#L218&gt;https://github.com/tflearn/tflearn/blob/master/tflearn/models/generator.py#L218&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 into:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;next_char = [self.rev_dic[next_index]]
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Basically, the error says that you try to concatenate the seed (a list) with a string ('next_char', the predicted next id)
I can try to debug that as soon as I get a computer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-06-26T07:03:30Z'>
		hi, thanx for the suggestion.
next_char = [self.rev_dic[next_index]]
worked, but I had to change
generated = seq_seed sequence = seq_seed whole_sequence = seq_seed
to
generated = list(seq_seed) sequence = list(seq_seed) whole_sequence = list(seq_seed)
since list in python works as a pointer, so I have to make a new list. Rest all code is fine. Right now trying with a larger dataset to see if it really works. Thanx for the help 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-07-29T20:58:03Z'>
		What if we want to predict the next word given a sequence of words? like when
seed = ['love ', 'test ']
I get this error:
File "tflearn/models/generator.py", line 217, in generate x[0, t, self.dic[char]] = 1. IndexError: index 1 is out of bounds for axis 1 with size 1
Do you have a sample code in tflearn for when we want to predict the next word given different sequences of words?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-07-29T21:02:54Z'>
		Hi, even I was getting the same error, so I had to change the for loop (which is right above the place where you make changes. Due to some reason, I can access the tflearn file right now, but if you manual trace it (i made a table for every variable) you will know the error. It wasnt a big change, but I can't exactly remember it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-07-29T22:13:54Z'>
		I changed the generator.py and by modifying the x entry after this line:
x = np.zeros((1, self.seq_maxlen, len(self.dic)))
so x values can have multiple 1 now. The code is not returning errors anymore, but I doubt the results of the LSTM method are accurate anymore. Maybe we need to change the structure of the network as well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='rohanpooniwala' date='2016-08-01T21:54:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aymericdamien&gt;@aymericdamien&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 do you have any example of  the Sequence Genrator that works with lists? More specifically given a list of strings, it uses LSTM to predict the next string. It seems SequenceGenrator only works with char, and I've been trying to change generator.py but so far has not achieved much success.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>