<bug id='10' author='Steviey' open_date='2019-01-13T10:43:45Z' closed_time='2019-01-15T09:38:31Z'>
	<summary>[RESOLVED] Implicit Conversion Warnings</summary>
	<description>
DWX_ZeroMQ_Server_v2.0.1_RC8
I get a bunch of warnings...actually can't been overseen...
implicit conversion from 'number' to 'string'	(multiple lines)
declaration of 'data' hides global declaration in file [...] Z85.mqh (multiple lines)
expression not boolean	GlobalVariable.mqh (multiple lines)
By the way, is this server version for Python only?
I can't find any information, on how to handle the versions in regard to R.
And is it OK to use the old version because of its simple, easy to extend structur?
Thank you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Steviey' date='2019-01-14T05:23:52Z'>
		Hello Steviey,
The "implicit conversion from 'number' to 'string'" is brought about in mql4 when you convert a number variable to a string variable in your code without explicitly coding it to do that. For example:
int number = 10;
Alert(number);
The above code will throw that warning. Instead, you should convert the the variable 'number' of type integer to type string. Like this:
int number = 10;
Alert(string(number));
Use the function string(); to remove those errors.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Steviey' date='2019-01-14T05:33:04Z'>
		ZeroMQ works with both Python and R. If you scroll through this webpage: &lt;denchmark-link:https://blog.darwinex.com/zeromq-interface-python-r-metatrader4/&gt;https://blog.darwinex.com/zeromq-interface-python-r-metatrader4/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 at the very end is the sub topic 'Sample Code' where you can find a link to ZeroMQ implemented in R. This is the actual link: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/darwinex/DarwinexLabs/blob/master/tools/R/ZeroMQ_MT4_R_Template.R&gt;https://github.com/darwinex/DarwinexLabs/blob/master/tools/R/ZeroMQ_MT4_R_Template.R&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Steviey' date='2019-01-14T17:53:52Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Steviey&gt;@Steviey&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,
Thank you for raising this - could you please do the following:


paste a text log of the warnings generated? need to ascertain which files are generating them, the MQL4 script for the EA itself, the dependencies, and/or both.


confirm which version / which file you are referencing here in this issue?


The latest MQL4 EA in v2.0.1_RC8 is language-neutral in the sense that you can implement the sequence of commands and send to the EA via any programming language of choice.
As long as the message is structured as the EA is expecting it in, the sending application could be any ZeroMQ supported language capable of digesting JSON responses.
We have not yet released a version for v2.0.1_RC8 in R, only Python.
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Steviey' date='2019-01-15T08:51:04Z'>
		[UPDATE] Implicit conversion warnings resolved in an updated DWX_ZeroMQ_Server_v2.0.1_RC8.mq4.
Changes will be committed shortly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Steviey' date='2019-01-15T09:23:38Z'>
		Done!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>