<bug_data>
<bug id='332' author='pelillian' open_date='2018-10-08T20:12:51Z' closed_time='2018-10-17T17:46:26Z'>
 	<summary>Express Installation does not work as described in the docs</summary>
 	<description>
 Express installation does not work. This is very important if we want other groups to start using garage!
 The scripts should just work without any user intervention.
 Mujoco installation (&amp; others?) should be disabled by default.
 	</description>
 	<comments>
 		<comment id='1' author='pelillian' date='2018-10-08T20:37:09Z'>
 		Can you please provide the error message on installation? Also is it for linux or mac?
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='2' author='pelillian' date='2018-10-08T20:38:35Z'>
 		I look forward to a short PR updating the docs.
 AFAIK setup_linux.sh and setup_osx.sh already work unattended if given the write command line args.
 IMO MuJoCo should be included by default because it is required for many examples. Not requiring MuJoCo doubles the number of system configurations we need to support and test, unnecessarily.
 Half-initialized systems are incredibly difficult to write and test code for. That's why all dependencies are required, even if some people don't necessarily need them. I'll trade a couple GB of hard disk space for stability and predictability any day.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='3' author='pelillian' date='2018-10-08T20:48:09Z'>
 		
 Can you please provide the error message on installation? Also is it for linux or mac?
 
 I talked to Angel and the issue was that I had to comment out the line in the script importing mujoco:
 &lt;denchmark-code&gt;# Build mujoco-py and check it's correctly installed
 python -c 'import mujoco_py
 &lt;/denchmark-code&gt;
 
 It works now. Do you want me to update the docs explaining how to install without mujoco? Or should it just say how to use the command line args?
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='4' author='pelillian' date='2018-10-08T20:53:38Z'>
 		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ryanjulian&gt;@ryanjulian&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I understand! I was thinking that because mujoco is not freeware that not everyone can just install it. I think Keren mentioned that in the future there was going to be a lighter weight "mini-garage"??
 Anyway thanks for explaining :)
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='5' author='pelillian' date='2018-10-12T22:22:40Z'>
 		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rlworkgroup/garage/pull/336&gt;#336&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  will close
 		</comment>
 	</comments>
 </bug>
<commit id='a3c336b095fe6cb41d1d6c79dcf3e76245df13ba' author='Peter Lillian' date='2018-10-15 14:18:34-07:00'>
 	<dmm_unit complexity='None' interfacing='None' size='None'></dmm_unit>
 	<modification change_type='MODIFY' old_name='docs\user\installation.rst' new_name='docs\user\installation.rst'>
 		<file_info nloc='None' complexity='None' token_count='None'></file_info>
 		<modified_lines>
 			<added_lines>13,14,15,16,17,18,23,29,30</added_lines>
 			<deleted_lines>17,23</deleted_lines>
 		</modified_lines>
 	</modification>
 </commit>
</bug_data>
