<bug id='623' author='Davidovic' open_date='2018-01-23T18:52:46Z' closed_time='2018-01-24T01:13:06Z'>
	<summary>NullPointerException in evaluation of the AnimalsClassification example</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I posted this question on the Gitter channel and was asked to create an issue because it might be a bug.
When trying out the AnimalsClassification example I ran into a NullPointerException during evaluation of the network:
Exception in thread "main" java.lang.IndexOutOfBoundsException: Index: 1, Size: 1
at java.util.ArrayList.rangeCheck(ArrayList.java:653)
at java.util.ArrayList.get(ArrayList.java:429)
at org.deeplearning4j.examples.convolution.AnimalsClassification.run(AnimalsClassification.java:195)
at org.deeplearning4j.examples.convolution.AnimalsClassification.main(AnimalsClassification.java:320)
Somehow the number of labels expected in the evaluation didn't match the number provided by the image pipeline. Instead of the 4 directories with animals from the example, I am using 2 directories with shapes ("ellipse" and "rectangle"). I changed "numLabels" from 4 to 2 accordingly:
protected static int numLabels = 2;
I set a breakpoint at line 195:
String expectedResult = allClassLabels.get(labelIndex);
When the error occurs the "allClassLabels" ArrayList size is 1, although it should be 2. It only contains "ellipse".
Then I noticed that line 72 was still roughly matching the total number of images in the "animals" directory:
protected static int numExamples = 80;
My two "shapes" directories contain 500 images each. When "numExamples" remains at 80, it seems the pipeline only takes 80 images from one directory, which means they all have the same label. I would expect the pipeline to take 80 images spread out over both directories, like 50/50?
BalancedPathFilter pathFilter = new BalancedPathFilter(rng, labelMaker, numExamples, numLabels, batchSize);
Or is it the following line:
FileSplit fileSplit = new FileSplit(mainPath, NativeImageLoader.ALLOWED_FORMATS, rng);
which only takes images from one directory and not the other, because of the low numExamples that's already satisfied by the first directory?
When I change "numExamples" to something like 600, then I don't get the error, because then 500 images are taken from the first directory and another 100 from the second, covering the 2 labels. I'm not sure if I am right, but it seems like that's what's happening.
Gist:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/Davidovic/6856b678919bddfea135332995202493&gt;https://gist.github.com/Davidovic/6856b678919bddfea135332995202493&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Version Information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

DL4J 0.9.1
Mac OS 10.13.2
IntelliJ
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Davidovic' date='2018-01-24T01:13:06Z'>
		Thank you for pointing this out. Please let us know if the refactored example (once it gets merged) still causes problems.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Davidovic' date='2018-01-24T03:08:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Davidovic&gt;@Davidovic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 And for issues related to DataVec, please post your issues over there.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>