<bug id='45' author='shashi-netra' open_date='2016-01-09T18:22:46Z' closed_time='2016-01-10T22:16:47Z'>
	<summary>Deepdetect crashes often without any warning</summary>
	<description>
I get an aborted (core dumped) message every so often and Deepdetect stops. I am using it to tag images with the imagenet model
Sometimes the issue is obvious such as a very large image or a dead link, but often it is just a normal image for no discernible reason.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='shashi-netra' date='2016-01-09T18:46:11Z'>
		Can you post the typical server log that leads to such a crash, along with the predict POST single or batch call ?
Also, if you are not running the currrent master branch, it would be useful if you could specify which commit you're on.
EDIT: also needed: whether you are using a GPU and what memory it has (or machine RAM is running on CPU)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='shashi-netra' date='2016-01-10T20:48:45Z'>
		Thanks for your reply.
I pulled from the master about 1 month ago for my current install (commit: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jolibrain/deepdetect/commit/bda863348dac73c60ef279b09ca1b321587025df&gt;bda8633&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
After looking into the issue some more, it seems the issue is with throwing errors leading to unhandled exceptions and causing the OS to call terminate()
This happens with image formats not supported by OpenCV (such as .gif):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;curl -X POST "http://xxx.com:8080/predict" -d "{\"service\":\"imgnet\",\"parameters\":{\"input\":{\"width\":224,\"height\":224},\"output\":{\"best\":5}},\"data\":[\"http://i.ytimg.com/vi/0vxOhd4qlnA/maxresdefault.jpg\"]}"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

works fine, but:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;curl -X POST "http://xxx.com:8080/predict" -d "{\"service\":\"imgnet\",\"parameters\":{\"input\":{\"width\":224,\"height\":224},\"output\":{\"best\":5}},\"data\":[\"https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/39/Specialist_Science_Logo.gif\"]}"
terminate called after throwing an instance of 'dd::InputConnectorBadParamException'
what():  no data for image https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/39/Specialist_Science_Logo.gif
curl: (52) Empty reply from server
[1]+  Aborted                 (core dumped) ./deepdetect/build/main/dede -stderrthreshold 0 --host xxx.com &gt; dede.txt
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Similarly, broken links cause a crash:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;terminate called after throwing an instance of 'dd::InputConnectorBadParamException'
what():  no data for image http://i.ytimg.com/not_a_real_link.jpg
curl: (52) Empty reply from server
[1]+  Aborted                 (core dumped) ./deepdetect/build/main/dede -stderrthreshold 0 --host xxx.com &gt; dede.txt
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Thanks in advance for your help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='shashi-netra' date='2016-01-10T21:19:08Z'>
		Thanks for the thorough report. The crash with .gif can be reproduced so I'll clear this asap.
Note that the .gif are not handled at the moment (nor for training or prediction) since they are made of multiple frames. What do you expect from classifying a .gif, getting a prediction over the first frame or a prediction of each of the frame ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='shashi-netra' date='2016-01-10T22:16:47Z'>
		Commit above fixes the regression following parallelized image reading. Thanks for reporting this one.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>