<bug id='176' author='chestnut3108' open_date='2020-05-25T16:05:10Z' closed_time='2020-05-28T18:05:54Z'>
	<summary>The website hangs when opening a previously saved file</summary>
	<description>
While importing the data I have encountered that page become unresponsive. Steps I have followed:-

Edited a NER task, saved the labelled file.
Opened the file in UDT to modify some labels.

The tab in chrome becomes totally unresponsive I have to kill the process. In the dev tools I am getting the following error hope it helps.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;index.js:1 Warning: Maximum update depth exceeded. This can happen when a component calls setState inside useEffect, but useEffect either doesn't have a dependency array, or one of the dependencies changes on every render.
    in Unknown (at App.js:20)
    in ToastProvider (at App.js:19)
    in LabelHelpProvider (at App.js:18)
    in AuthProvider (at App.js:17)
    in AppConfigProvider (at App.js:16)
    in ThemeProvider (at Theme/index.js:21)
    in Unknown (at App.js:15)
    in App (at src/index.js:5) 
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='chestnut3108' date='2020-05-27T18:36:19Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chestnut3108&gt;@chestnut3108&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, was this desktop or web? How many samples were in the dataset?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='chestnut3108' date='2020-05-28T06:29:52Z'>
		Hi,

It was web version, I had annotated a small text file of about 250 words
for NER task. I reopened the file after downloading it in JSON format
because I wanted to modify some annotations, that's when I encountered this
issue.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Thu, May 28, 2020, 12:06 AM Severin Ibarluzea ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Hey @chestnut3108 &lt;https://github.com/chestnut3108&gt;, was this desktop or
 web? How many samples were in the dataset?

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#176 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AEAJ4U7JRIDZ7WP35IYMDLTRTVMTDANCNFSM4NJUFMNQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='chestnut3108' date='2020-05-28T18:17:48Z'>
		🎉 This issue has been resolved in version 0.10.16 🎉
The release is available on:

GitHub release
npm package (@latest dist-tag)

Your semantic-release bot 📦🚀
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>