<bug id='10545' author='edoakes' open_date='2020-09-03T19:02:26Z' closed_time='2020-09-04T00:48:32Z'>
	<summary>Can't clean up named actor (non-detached)</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Non-detached actor names don't seem to be reclaimed when the actor exits.
Discovered while refactoring Serve to support clusters scoped to the driver program.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import time
import ray

ray.init()

@ray.remote
class A:
    pass

a = A.options(name="hello").remote()
ray.kill(a, no_restart=True)
del a

# This loop never exits.
while True:
    try:
        ray.get_actor("hello")
        print("Actor still alive")
    except:
        print("Actor was deleted")
        break
    time.sleep(1)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

If we cannot run your script, we cannot fix your issue.

 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='edoakes' date='2020-09-03T19:04:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ericl&gt;@ericl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Making this P0 because it is a pretty fundamental issue for the named actor API and it's a blocker for the serve change we want to get in for 1.0. LMK if you disagree.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='edoakes' date='2020-09-03T19:14:30Z'>
		Little outside topic, but Why don't we make actors detached if name is provided but lifetime is not? It will secretly breaks lots of people's codebase otherwise.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='edoakes' date='2020-09-03T19:40:36Z'>
		re: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rkooo567&gt;@rkooo567&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that would prevent users from creating non detached actors that are named, which is a key requirement from Ant and also used in RLlib (this was broken by the recent change to couple named with detached).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='edoakes' date='2020-09-03T19:42:17Z'>
		Ok I see, it's just an issue with removing the name label, only read the last comment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='edoakes' date='2020-09-03T20:26:55Z'>
		This seems like it's probably the culprit:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/src/ray/gcs/gcs_server/gcs_actor_manager.h#L95&gt;https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/src/ray/gcs/gcs_server/gcs_actor_manager.h#L95&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>