<bug id='12153' author='TomaAlexandru' open_date='2020-11-19T07:46:49Z' closed_time='2020-11-21T06:15:16Z'>
	<summary>Ray node connects to random redis port</summary>
	<description>
Hello.
Python version: 3.6.8
Ray version: 1.0.1
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Node can't provide workers even successfully connects to head.
I have two Centos machines, first is head and the second connects to head.
redis runs on head machine on port 6379
First machine :  ray start --head --port=6380 --dashboard-host=0.0.0.0
Second machine: ray start --address='161.97.xx.xxx:6380' --redis-password='5241590000000000'
The first node successfully starts with all workers.
The second node connects successfully but displays in timeline, and in dashboard on PID column: "0 workers / 4 cores":
...
W1119 08:22:22.445783 1513663 1513663 redis_context.cc:303] Failed to connect to Redis, retrying.
F1119 08:22:23.602082 1513663 1513663 redis_context.cc:298] Could not establish connection to redis 161.97.xx.xxx:12662 (context.err = 1)
I have no idea why the node tries to connect on redis port 12662 (seeme to be randoom), I also need to mention that remote redis connection works fine and i can successfully connect to the node from the second node to first node.
Can you please help me?
Thank you very much for your support.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='TomaAlexandru' date='2020-11-19T07:50:48Z'>
		Did you make sure to open all ports specified here? &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/configure.html#ports-configurations&gt;https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/configure.html#ports-configurations&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='TomaAlexandru' date='2020-11-19T13:22:05Z'>
		
Did you make sure to open all ports specified here? https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/configure.html#ports-configurations

Very usefull hint!
I've closed firewall on both machines and everithing works fine!
however there are something that i can't understand if want to start firewalld service.
--min-worker-port: Minimum port number worker can be bound to. Default: 10000.
--max-worker-port: Maximum port number worker can be bound to. Default: 10999.
those ports need to be opened in firewall across the machines because ray use those for worker nodes?
what is the difference between --node-manager-port and --port on head node?
thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='TomaAlexandru' date='2020-11-20T04:55:52Z'>
		Thank you very much guys, you've helped me a lot!
(&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/dHannasch&gt;@dHannasch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 very good explanation in your commit)
Regards,
Alex.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>