<bug id='12363' author='mfitton' open_date='2020-11-24T20:00:39Z' closed_time='2020-12-02T22:08:14Z'>
	<summary>[Dashboard] Duplicate IPs/Machine View Rows in dashboard</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3156716/100145087-a70d7000-2e4c-11eb-9458-5cd3bc9d91fe.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please provide a script that can be run to reproduce the issue. The script should have no external library dependencies (i.e., use fake or mock data / environments):
If we cannot run your script, we cannot fix your issue.

 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:34:34Z'>
		Simon sent me a message indicating that this issue is still present. PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/12410&gt;#12410&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 did not actually fix it 
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:35:16Z'>
		We are distinguishing them based on the node id right? Isn't it kind of expected?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:43:13Z'>
		Yeah, but I would expect the nodes with the same IP would all have the same node ID, so I would expect them to have the same react key and thus not have duplicate renders.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:47:10Z'>
		I noticed that there are actually duplicate nodes in the payload with different node IDs, where one of the node's raylet is marked DEAD and the other is not. I'll continue investigating. Seems like a backend issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:48:01Z'>
		When raylet restarts, they will have the different node id although the ip is the same
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:48:38Z'>
		It is like each raylet runtime is a new node in the perspective of gcs. We can probably just filter dead nodes from rendering?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T21:58:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/simon-mo&gt;@simon-mo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this is the issue I mentioned in slack.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-01T22:00:18Z'>
		Yeah, filtering dead nodes from rendering does sound like the simplest fix. I'm going to read the code a little more, but will probably go with filtering dead nodes as a hot fix.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>