<bug id='12895' author='mfitton' open_date='2020-12-15T22:21:25Z' closed_time='2020-12-15T22:58:07Z'>
	<summary>[Docker] Microbenchmark client put gb/s perf regression</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When running the release tests in Docker via the product, two aspects of the microbenchmark show a regression in speed, namely in  and 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3156716/102279237-ea08b380-3edf-11eb-9e77-068aa35453e4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3156716/102279240-eb39e080-3edf-11eb-8ec0-9dffb35ff2c4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Here is the analysis difference from the previous version:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3156716/102279389-26d4aa80-3ee0-11eb-9a87-1b70d79dcb0f.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Run using the ray-project/releaser tool on the 1.1.0 release in the Anyscale product latest ray docker image.  is what I'm using to trigger the build. The only difference with the release branch is a line:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/3156716/102279709-b4b09580-3ee0-11eb-9690-d1e0327a4d9d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please provide a short code snippet (less than 50 lines if possible) that can be copy-pasted to reproduce the issue. The snippet should have no external library dependencies (i.e., use fake or mock data / environments):
If the code snippet cannot be run by itself, the issue will be closed with "needs-repro-script".

 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='mfitton' date='2020-12-15T22:58:07Z'>
		Verified that this was caused by passing too little memory to --shm-size. Relevant warning for Ray:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;2020-12-15 22:51:11,578	WARNING services.py:1640 -- WARNING: The object store is using /tmp instead of /dev/shm because /dev/shm has only 2147483648 bytes available. This may slow down performance! You may be able to free up space by deleting files in /dev/shm or terminating any running plasma_store_server processes. If you are inside a Docker container, you may need to pass an argument with the flag '--shm-size' to 'docker run'.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This error message was a little confusing, so improving it here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/12896&gt;#12896&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>