<bug id='13231' author='micahtyong' open_date='2021-01-06T09:28:23Z' closed_time='2021-01-14T23:20:04Z'>
	<summary>[dashboard][core] Running ray memory yields reference types inconsistent with master/memory-management.html</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Upon running  in the command line while a Ray application is running, yielded reference types are inconsistent with what is described in &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/memory-management.html#debugging-using-ray-memory&gt;the docs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. In multiple instances, the reference type is incorrectly denoted as .
Ray version and other system information (Python version, TensorFlow version, OS):

Ray 1.2.0
Python 3.6.8
TensorFlow 2.4.0
macOS 10.14.6

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Create a mock Ray application using an example from the docs.
For example,

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import ray
import time
ray.init()

@ray.remote
def f(arg):
    return arg

a = ray.put(None)
b = f.remote(None)

time.sleep(100)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Run the application, then run ray memory
At this point, you should see results that are inconsistent with what is in the documentation as described above.


 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='micahtyong' date='2021-01-06T09:32:10Z'>
		cc: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rkooo567&gt;@rkooo567&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='micahtyong' date='2021-01-06T18:54:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-code&gt;At this point, you should see results that are inconsistent with what is in the documentation as described above. (EDIT: The beta introduction of object spilling has created an issue where ray memory will break entirely and yield AttributeError: store_stats).
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This might be because you didn't rebuild the core after you pull the latest master. Is it reproducible when you use ray by downloading the master wheel?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='micahtyong' date='2021-01-06T19:06:36Z'>
		You're right, just edited the PR!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>