<bug id='254' author='robertnishihara' open_date='2017-02-07T21:14:51Z' closed_time='2017-02-16T19:32:27Z'>
	<summary>Errors arising from lack of isolation between drivers on the same cluster.</summary>
	<description>
Some test failures, for example &lt;denchmark-link:https://travis-ci.org/ray-project/ray/jobs/195442413&gt;https://travis-ci.org/ray-project/ray/jobs/195442413&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 are caused by this. In this test, two drivers both define a remote function . When the second driver calls its copy of , the task gets assigned to a worker and the worker executes the first driver's copy of . There are a couple of problems here.


When two drivers both define a remote function with the same name, one of them will override the other. This happens because remote functions are currently identified by their module name plus function name. This could be fixed by incorporating the driver ID in the remote function ID (e.g., hashing them together).


Drivers currently have an "import counter" which counts how many things the driver has imported (e.g., remote functions, environment variables, etc). Drivers also keep track of how many things they have exported (e.g., how many remote functions they have defined). When a remote function is defined on the driver, it makes a note of how many exports were exported before it, and it will not run on a worker until that worker has imported at least that many things. However, this counter is currently shared between drivers and so exports from both drivers are incrementing a counter on the workers. This is the problem that we're running into in the link above. We need a separate counter for each driver (or we need to rethink how we're doing exports).


This is somewhat driver-centric (it won't probably handle situations where remote functions are defined on workers). Should we support that? We probably do need to support the creation of actors from tasks run on workers, so we may need to handle that a little differently.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='robertnishihara' date='2017-02-16T19:32:27Z'>
		This should be addressed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/288&gt;#288&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which makes each worker maintain a separate dictionary of remote functions for each driver. It also removes the import counter concept.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>