<bug id='2648' author='whikwon' open_date='2018-08-14T05:33:06Z' closed_time='2018-08-21T05:19:36Z'>
	<summary>[rllib] DDPG opensim env issue</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;System information&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OS Platform and Distribution (e.g., Linux Ubuntu 16.04): ubuntu 16.04
Ray installed from (source or binary): source
Ray version: 0.5.0
Python version: 3.6.1
Exact command to reproduce:

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Describe the problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Executing DDPG in  Pendulum-v0 environment has no problem.
However, when i execute DDPG in  Prosthetics environment, error occurs during gradient calculation.
Do I have to add some additional code in custom environment to solve this problem?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/30768596/44073432-d325c11a-9fce-11e8-839b-66ade9fb9d02.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Source code / logs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

import ray 
import ray.tune.registry import register_env
from ray.rllib.agents import ddpg
from osim.env import ProstheticsEnv

def env_creator(env_config):
    return ProstheticsEnv(False)

register_env("prosthetics", env_creator)
ray.init("&lt;head-ip:port&gt;")

agent = ddpg.DDPGAgent(env="prosthetics", config={"num_workers": 140, "gpu": True})

for i in range(1000):
    result = agent.train()
    print(result)
    if i % 10 == 0:
        agent.save()
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-14T22:22:14Z'>
		This is odd, you shouldn't be getting MultiAgentBatch types there. Could you print the types (or even better the full contents) of each s on this line?: 


ray/python/ray/rllib/evaluation/sample_batch.py


         Line 224
      in
      d01dc9e






 out[k] = np.concatenate([s[k] for s in samples]) 





		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-15T05:25:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ericl&gt;@ericl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I tried  and got all the  stuff.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-15T07:13:52Z'>
		That's weird, and it definitely crashes on the next line with the type of s being MultiAgentBatch?
It would be great to get a smaller reproduction case that doesn't require osim, I tried running the above and could not reproduce the crash on python 3.6 (though I didn't fully install osim, just used a similar env).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-15T08:25:57Z'>
		Yeah, I've also tried Pendulum-v0 and it worked. I think it doesn't work well only for the osim environment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-15T17:24:33Z'>
		Do you know what's special about osim that causes this to happen? Is it possible to make an env with the same action and observation space to reproduce?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='whikwon' date='2018-08-17T03:20:34Z'>
		I've ran local desktop and it runs. I think one of my VM has environment problem something like that. I'll find out and let you know if it belongs to ray. Please close this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>