<bug id='4029' author='robertnishihara' open_date='2019-02-12T22:30:03Z' closed_time='2020-06-25T18:05:54Z'>
	<summary>Stdout/stderr from all drivers are streamed to all other drivers.</summary>
	<description>
As of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/3892&gt;#3892&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the stdout/stderr of all drivers is streamed to all other drivers. An individual driver can opt out by calling .
To reproduce this, do the following.


Start Ray.
ray start --head --redis-port=6379



Start a driver that prints stuff.
import ray
import sys
import time

ray.init(redis_address='localhost:6379')

@ray.remote
def f():
    while True:
        print('hi')
        sys.stdout.flush()
        time.sleep(0.1)

f.remote()


Start another driver, and see that it receives the stdout from the first driver.
import ray

ray.init(redis_address='localhost:6379')


&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Some options to address this.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Workers can belong to specific drivers (this means logs will be complicated for cross driver applications, e.g., named actors).
Workers can redirect there stdout/stderr on a per-task basis.
Workers can print extra annotations in their stdout/stderr which the log monitor can parse and use to choose which drivers to publish to.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='robertnishihara' date='2019-02-13T03:46:21Z'>
		I like option 3.
For option 2 what kind of api were you thinking about?  Like an additional keyword in ray.remote decoration?
I am already making use of this feature a little and find it handy to include timestamp and function name to each stdout.  Not saying these should be added by default but giving that as an example.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='robertnishihara' date='2019-02-13T07:15:22Z'>
		Option 2 would not require the user to do anything. Instead, there would one log file per worker/driver combination, and whenever a worker executes a task for a given driver, it logs to the file for that worker/driver combination. This would all be done under the hood.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='robertnishihara' date='2019-02-13T17:48:27Z'>
		2 or 3 sound fine to me then.  I am not doing cross driver work yet so that isn't an issue for me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='robertnishihara' date='2019-03-24T01:08:52Z'>
		If this isn't going to be fixed soon, can we at least document it somewhere prominently? This was very confusing to me for a while: now I know what's causing it, it's largely a non-issue, as I can look at output from my other logging methods.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='robertnishihara' date='2019-03-25T06:01:47Z'>
		Thanks &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AdamGleave&gt;@AdamGleave&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for bringing this up. I'll take a look at fixing it this week.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-05-18T21:13:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/edoakes&gt;@edoakes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/simon-mo&gt;@simon-mo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 isn't this kind of a deal breaker for serve?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-05-18T21:16:46Z'>
		In deployment, Serve's drivers are short-running script so this doesn't matter too much. However, I agree P1 is the correct priority
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-05-31T18:50:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ijrsvt&gt;@ijrsvt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'm stealing this issue for now, you don't need to worry about it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-05-31T19:06:08Z'>
		Thanks Eric!
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Sun, May 31, 2020 at 11:50 AM Eric Liang ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 @ijrsvt &lt;https://github.com/ijrsvt&gt; I'm stealing this issue for now, you
 don't need to worry about it.

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#4029 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AFC5KQQJ436ETVC2VX6LAD3RUKRGNANCNFSM4GXAYDJA&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-08-28T11:45:38Z'>
		Is this problem solved? I am still getting output from all drivers at version 0.8.6
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='robertnishihara' date='2020-08-28T15:26:05Z'>
		This should be solved. If you still see all logs then it's a bug. Can you post a new issue with a reproducible example? Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>