<bug id='6627' author='AmeerHajAli' open_date='2019-12-29T11:46:04Z' closed_time='2020-11-28T08:19:51Z'>
	<summary>RLlib: stop condition not met</summary>
	<description>
rllib
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

if you give "stop":{"episodes_total":X} and X is smaller than train_batch_size then it terminates after train_batch_size without any warning that something is wrong with the parameters. This is problematic when debugging and the train_batch_size and other parameters are implicit.
Ray version and other system information (Python version, TensorFlow version, OS):
Does the problem occur on the latest wheels?
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please provide a script that can be run to reproduce the issue. The script should have no external library dependencies (i.e., use fake or mock data / environments):
If we cannot run your script, we cannot fix your issue.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AmeerHajAli' date='2020-02-06T22:53:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AmeerHajAli&gt;@AmeerHajAli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 please provide a reproducible script (or fix this in rllib)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AmeerHajAli' date='2020-02-07T02:46:30Z'>
		here is a simple example:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import ray
from ray import tune
ray.init()
tune.run(
    "PPO",
    stop={"timesteps_total": 10},
    config={
        "env": "CartPole-v0",
        "lr": tune.grid_search([1e-3,1e-4])
    })
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

this will run for 4000 steps rather than 10 steps (because the default number of training steps in PPO is 4000).
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AmeerHajAli' date='2020-11-14T07:37:44Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='AmeerHajAli' date='2020-11-28T08:19:47Z'>
		Hi again! The issue will be closed because there has been no more activity in the 14 days since the last message.
Please feel free to reopen or open a new issue if you'd still like it to be addressed.
Again, you can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks again for opening the issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>