<bug id='7182' author='pmacalpine' open_date='2020-02-16T07:29:48Z' closed_time='2020-02-19T17:32:14Z'>
	<summary>[rllib] GPU memory leak until out of memory when using local_mode with ray in pytorch PPO</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When running pytorch PPO with  rllib steadily uses up all the GPU memory due to what appears to be a memory leak (the attached log shows a constant linear increase in vram usage until it nears 100% and eventually runs out of memory) when training on atari (breakout).  The CPU memory leak in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/issues/6962&gt;#6962&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is also still present, but in this case is much slower than the GPU memory leak.  Note that I don't see the GPU memory leak if I don't run ray with local_mode=True in which case GPU memory usage is constant.  I also don't see this GPU memory leak with tensorflow when I run ray with local_mode=True.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7802157/74600766-e780c780-504a-11ea-8a96-8a9fe83c5ec4.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Ray version and other system information (Python version, TensorFlow version, OS):
python: 3.7.6
ray: 0.9.0.dev0
OS: Ubuntu 18.04.03 LTS
torch: 1.3.0
tensorflow: 2.0.0
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please provide a script that can be run to reproduce the issue. The script should have no external library dependencies (i.e., use fake or mock data / environments):
In the attached files I added a command line argument for local mode to train.py which is needed when running the following command to recreate the problem:
python train.py --ray-local-mode true -v -f atari-ppo-pt.yaml
If we cannot run your script, we cannot fix your issue.

 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.
attachments.tar.gz

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='pmacalpine' date='2020-02-19T17:32:14Z'>
		Thanks for opening this! This is the same issue as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/issues/6962&gt;#6962&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . We are currently working on a fix. I will close this one.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>