<bug id='7677' author='brechtmann' open_date='2020-03-20T15:40:11Z' closed_time='2020-11-27T08:18:08Z'>
	<summary>[tune] Mlflow example does not track loss to mlflow.</summary>
	<description>
OSX
Ray installed from pip
Ray version: 0.7.5
Python version: 3.7.3
Exact command to reproduce:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/python/ray/tune/examples/mlflow_example.py&gt;https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/python/ray/tune/examples/mlflow_example.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The problem can be solved by making the loss a float by adding a dot.
 mean_loss=(config["height"] - 14.)**2 - abs(config["width"] - 3))
This issue occurs due to the fact, that only floats, but no integers are passed to mlflow:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/python/ray/tune/logger.py#L90&gt;https://github.com/ray-project/ray/blob/master/python/ray/tune/logger.py#L90&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Below one can see the data generated by mlflow. Run 1 is with the original example notebook
and run 2 with the float modification. As one can see run 2 has files tracking the mean_loss but run 1 does not.
Maybe this could be changed, so that integers can be tracked.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/37140213/77179320-9c822600-6ac8-11ea-89d7-12b3a2247b9e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


[ x ] I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='brechtmann' date='2020-03-20T19:20:30Z'>
		Ah; would you be open to pushing a fix?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='brechtmann' date='2020-03-20T19:40:38Z'>
		I will give it a try.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='brechtmann' date='2020-03-25T16:35:40Z'>
		Sorry but I have a bunch of other things to do and don't know your code base at all, so I will leave this to you. Sorry
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='brechtmann' date='2020-03-25T21:13:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/brechtmann&gt;@brechtmann&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 No problem! Appreciate you letting me know. I'll get your PR merged in a couple days.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='brechtmann' date='2020-11-13T07:41:09Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='brechtmann' date='2020-11-27T08:18:01Z'>
		Hi again! The issue will be closed because there has been no more activity in the 14 days since the last message.
Please feel free to reopen or open a new issue if you'd still like it to be addressed.
Again, you can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks again for opening the issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>