<bug id='7755' author='kyang922' open_date='2020-03-26T12:55:14Z' closed_time='2020-11-27T07:18:06Z'>
	<summary>non-ascii characters in remote function crash ray</summary>
	<description>
I am using ray 0.8.2 and encountered a problem when using non-ascii characters in my remote function. this problem seems have been solved once but in 0.8.2 and 0.8.3 it appear again.
for detail, please see the following link.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/4047#issuecomment-604373744&gt;Support non ascii characters in the source code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

this post was posted 1 year ago so I open a new issue to remind you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kyang922' date='2020-03-26T13:18:52Z'>
		What version of python are you using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kyang922' date='2020-03-26T13:22:29Z'>
		I am using Python 3.7, thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kyang922' date='2020-11-13T06:41:13Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kyang922' date='2020-11-27T07:18:02Z'>
		Hi again! The issue will be closed because there has been no more activity in the 14 days since the last message.
Please feel free to reopen or open a new issue if you'd still like it to be addressed.
Again, you can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks again for opening the issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>