<bug id='7803' author='xlnwel' open_date='2020-03-30T01:50:20Z' closed_time='2020-11-27T07:18:08Z'>
	<summary>Ray class does not support `__getattr__`</summary>
	<description>
The following code works fine in general
class A:
    def __init__(self):
        self.a = 1
    
    def retrieve(self):
        return self.a
    
class B:
    def __init__(self):
        self.a = A()
    def __getattr__(self, name):
        return getattr(self.a, name)
    
b = B()
b.retrieve()
However, if I decorate class B with ray.remote as below, it sends an error says there is no attribute retrieve.
if ray.is_initialized:
    ray.shutdown()
ray.init()
RayB = ray.remote(B).   # B is from the previous code block
b = RayB.remote()
print(ray.get(b.retrieve.remote())).   # AttributeError: 'ActorHandle' object has no attribute 'retrieve'
ray.shutdown()
I know that manually redefining retrieve in class B could make it work. But it will be more desirable to support __getattr__ in ray if possible.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='xlnwel' date='2020-11-13T06:41:09Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='xlnwel' date='2020-11-27T07:18:04Z'>
		Hi again! The issue will be closed because there has been no more activity in the 14 days since the last message.
Please feel free to reopen or open a new issue if you'd still like it to be addressed.
Again, you can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks again for opening the issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>