<bug id='7907' author='jonmorton' open_date='2020-04-06T02:54:20Z' closed_time='2020-11-13T04:43:05Z'>
	<summary>[tune][docs] Search Algorithm Example w/ HyperOpt isn't better than random search</summary>
	<description>
The example at &lt;denchmark-link:https://ray.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tune-tutorial.html#search-algorithms-in-tune&gt;https://ray.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tune-tutorial.html#search-algorithms-in-tune&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for using HyperOpt is not better than random search, according to my understanding.
The default n_inital_points for the HyperOpt searcher is 20, which I think means the first 20 trials are drawn randomly. Since the example in the docs uses num_samples=10, this isn't really illustrating search with HyperOpt -- or am I missing somethig?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jonmorton' date='2020-04-06T02:58:06Z'>
		Ah yeah the doc was written to illustrate usage, but I didn't carefully check all the parameters. Do you want to push a fix? happy to merge.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jonmorton' date='2020-11-13T03:42:55Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jonmorton' date='2020-11-13T04:43:05Z'>
		We actually updated the example recently, so this shouldn't be the case anymore.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>