<bug id='8007' author='josjo80' open_date='2020-04-13T20:28:27Z' closed_time='2020-11-13T02:35:51Z'>
	<summary>[RLlib] &amp; [Tune] Tensorboard No Longer Works in Ray 0.8.4</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Tensorboard no longer works in Ray 0.8.4&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Linux 18.04
Python 3.6.9
Tensorflow 2.1.0
Tensorflow-gpu 2.1.0
Ray 0.8.4
Tensorboard 2.1.0
I updated my packages to reflect the latest builds but I can no longer see training run results in Tensorboard.  I am not using Tune to perform the training routine.  I'm iterating through the trainer as below (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/issues/6669&gt;#6669&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;for i in range(args.num_iters):
    print(pretty_print(ppo_trainer.train()))
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I followed the release notes from release 0.8.2, issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/6836&gt;#6836&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , however, after installing  I still could not see training results.  I then uninstalled , thinking that there was a namespace clash.  I again entered:  however I got the following error:

I then uninstalled tensorboardX and reinstalled tensorboard 2.1.0 and am back to the original problem that I can't see the training results.
I noticed that when I look at an older training run (using Ray0.8.0) in ~/ray_results/experiment_xxx it includes a file like the following: events.out.tfevents.1586553975.cassini.  Whereas with the updated packages I no long see such a file in the experiment folder.
I have also flipped the flag "monitor" to True in the config settings per the new release.  That does not appear to help either.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='josjo80' date='2020-04-20T17:35:22Z'>
		Hm, so you definitely need TensorboardX. Can you try uninstalling everything (you should have a tensorboard: No such file... error), and only  installing tensorboardX?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='josjo80' date='2020-11-12T23:45:44Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>