<bug id='9187' author='SanjiAp' open_date='2020-06-29T07:47:17Z' closed_time='2020-11-28T22:36:30Z'>
	<summary>[raysgd][TFTrainer] Error while starting grpc server</summary>
	<description>
I am running the simple tensorflow example given in the document.
So raysgd uses distributed tensorflow and distributed tensorflow uses GRPC server to communicate between the servers.
For doing this ray finds the free ports on the server but somehow problem is with list of ports that it finds.
Right now for simplification I solved this problem by giving static list of ports.
          ports = range(12345,(12345 + len(ips)))
Ray version : 0.8.5 and getting this error in 0.8.6
python version : 3.6.10
tensorflow version : 2.2.0
OS : centos 7
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='SanjiAp' date='2020-06-29T07:50:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22998616/85987429-3f710700-ba0b-11ea-9514-7290da059306.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='SanjiAp' date='2020-11-14T22:03:38Z'>
		Hi, I'm a bot from the Ray team :)
To help human contributors to focus on more relevant issues, I will automatically add the stale label to issues that have had no activity for more than 4 months.
If there is no further activity in the 14 days, the issue will be closed!

If you'd like to keep the issue open, just leave any comment, and the stale label will be removed!
If you'd like to get more attention to the issue, please tag one of Ray's contributors.

You can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io/&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='SanjiAp' date='2020-11-28T22:36:25Z'>
		Hi again! The issue will be closed because there has been no more activity in the 14 days since the last message.
Please feel free to reopen or open a new issue if you'd still like it to be addressed.
Again, you can always ask for help on our &lt;denchmark-link:https://discuss.ray.io&gt;discussion forum&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray#getting-involved&gt;Ray's public slack channel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks again for opening the issue!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>