<bug id='9474' author='kocic11' open_date='2020-07-14T18:30:38Z' closed_time='2020-07-19T00:24:53Z'>
	<summary>'ray memory' fails with invalid password error when cluster is started with redis-password option</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When ray cluster is started using redis-password option ray memory always fails with invalid password error.
Ray version and other system information (Python version, TensorFlow version, OS):
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Please provide a script that can be run to reproduce the issue. The script should have no external library dependencies (i.e., use fake or mock data / environments):
Start a cluster:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ray start --head --webui-host=0.0.0.0 --redis-port=55555 --redis-password="password"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Run a command:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ray memory
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;redis.exceptions.AuthenticationError: invalid password
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

If we cannot run your script, we cannot fix your issue.

 I have verified my script runs in a clean environment and reproduces the issue.
 I have verified the issue also occurs with the latest wheels.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kocic11' date='2020-07-17T21:27:08Z'>
		You should be able to resolve this after this PR is merged. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ray-project/ray/pull/9492&gt;#9492&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kocic11' date='2020-07-19T00:24:53Z'>
		Thanks. I noticed the PR was merged but it's not part of any release. I guess I could build ray or wait for the next release.
Do you have any timeline for the next release? When will it be available?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kocic11' date='2020-07-19T00:28:10Z'>
		We are planning to have the next release in the beginning of August!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kocic11' date='2020-07-19T01:01:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kocic11&gt;@kocic11&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 you could also try using the latest nightly snapshot of master (&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/installation.html&gt;https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/installation.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kocic11' date='2020-10-20T01:58:33Z'>
		This issue is still not resolved in the latest version of the code..
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='kocic11' date='2020-10-20T02:01:14Z'>
		Did you try ray memory --redis-password=""? Can you explain more about how it is not resolved and how to reproduce the issue?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>