<bug id='9685' author='renatobellotti' open_date='2020-07-24T16:04:01Z' closed_time='2020-07-24T18:20:53Z'>
	<summary>[tune] Cannot access logdir in functional API</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;What is the problem?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I am trying to save something at the end of the training. To achieve this, I'm trying to get the save directory for the trial. The code from the &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/tune/api_docs/logging.html#custom-loggers&gt;documentation&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ("Trainable Logging" --&gt; "Functional API") is as follows:
def trainable(config):
    library.init(
        name=trial_id,
        id=trial_id,
        resume=trial_id,
        reinit=True,
        allow_val_change=True)
    library.set_log_path(tune.track.logdir)

    for step in range(100):
        library.log_model(...)
        library.log(results, step=step)
        tune.track.log(results)
To me, it is not clear where the name library comes from. So I was assuming  this had nothing to do with my problem, and thought the relevant part was the tune.track.logdir variable. However, that variable does not exist.
When I run the example code, I get the following error message:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;AttributeError: module 'ray.tune' has no attribute 'track'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I'm new to ray and tune, so perhaps there is another way to get the log directory for the trial. I found the documentation a bit sparse about this issue if the functional API is used.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Reproduction (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Ray version: 0.8.6 (from PyPI)
import ray
from ray import tune

def training_function(config):
    # see:
    # https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/tune/api_docs/logging.html
    # (section "Trainable Logging")
    tune.report(logdir=tune.track.logdir)

ray.init()

analysis = tune.run(training_function,
                    config={
                        'dummy': [1],
                    },
                    local_dir='test_local_dir',
                    num_samples=1,
                    resources_per_trial={'cpu': 1},
                    queue_trials=False)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='renatobellotti' date='2020-07-24T16:26:53Z'>
		Hi, thanks for raising this issue. Yes I agree the documentation is pretty confusing here; we'll make sure to clear it up for the next release.  has actually been deprecated in place of . In your example, there's actually no need to pass in a  to - it will automatically log to the trial directory. You simply need pass in a dictionary of the values you want to log &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/tune/api_docs/trainable.html#function-based-api&gt;https://docs.ray.io/en/latest/tune/api_docs/trainable.html#function-based-api&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. If you do want to get the logdir you can do so with  inside your training function.
The name library in the documentation is supposed to refer to any 3rd party library you would like to use for logging, it's not a variable name on its own.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='renatobellotti' date='2020-07-24T19:00:35Z'>
		Thank you very much, now it is working well! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>