<bug id='101' author='johnmellor' open_date='2015-05-10T16:57:53Z' closed_time='2015-05-12T01:15:16Z'>
	<summary>WebInstall one_time.sh uninstalls CUDA (&amp; NVIDIA driver)!</summary>
	<description>
The &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v1.0/docs/WebInstall.md&gt;WebInstall instructions&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tell you to run a script called  which runs the following command:
sudo apt-get install libatlas-base-dev libatlas-dev libboost-all-dev libopencv-dev libprotobuf-dev libgoogle-glog-dev libgflags-dev libhdf5-dev libleveldb-dev liblmdb-dev libsnappy-dev  -y -q
But running this uninstalled CUDA (without prompting, due to the -y -q)!
This is because libboost-all-dev lists libhwloc-plugins as a recommended package (and Ubuntu installs recommended packages by default). But libhwloc-plugins in turn requires ocl-icd-libopencl1, which conflicts with nvidia-libopencl1-343, which is required by various CUDA packages.
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/ocl-icd/+bug/1247736&gt;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/ocl-icd/+bug/1247736&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/nvidia-cuda-toolkit/+bug/1311975&gt;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/nvidia-cuda-toolkit/+bug/1311975&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Hence running ./one_time.sh caused the following packages to be removed: cuda cuda-6-5 cuda-drivers cuda-runtime-6-5 nvidia-libopencl1-343.
And the next time I ran sudo apt-get autoremove --purge, since cuda had been removed to resolve the conflict, it also removed my NVIDIA driver, amongst other packages:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;The following packages will be REMOVED
  cuda-command-line-tools-6-5* cuda-core-6-5* cuda-cublas-6-5*
  cuda-cublas-dev-6-5* cuda-cudart-6-5* cuda-cudart-dev-6-5* cuda-cufft-6-5*
  cuda-cufft-dev-6-5* cuda-curand-6-5* cuda-curand-dev-6-5* cuda-cusparse-6-5*
  cuda-cusparse-dev-6-5* cuda-documentation-6-5* cuda-driver-dev-6-5*
  cuda-license-6-5* cuda-misc-headers-6-5* cuda-npp-6-5* cuda-npp-dev-6-5*
  cuda-samples-6-5* cuda-toolkit-6-5* cuda-visual-tools-6-5* freeglut3*
  freeglut3-dev* libxmu-dev* libxmu-headers* linux-headers-3.13.0-44*
  linux-headers-3.13.0-44-generic* linux-image-3.13.0-44-generic*
  linux-image-extra-3.13.0-44-generic* linux-signed-image-3.13.0-44-generic*
  nvidia-343-dev* nvidia-modprobe*
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Proposed solution&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Changing run_once.sh to install libboost-all-dev with --no-install-recommends solves the conflict (since libhwloc-plugins and hence ocl-icd-libopencl1 will not be installed). Specifically, run_once.sh should run the following commands:
sudo apt-get install --no-install-recommends libboost-all-dev  -y -q
sudo apt-get install libatlas-base-dev libatlas-dev libopencv-dev libprotobuf-dev libgoogle-glog-dev libgflags-dev libhdf5-dev libleveldb-dev liblmdb-dev libsnappy-dev  -y -q
DIGITS seems to work fine without libhwloc-plugins and ocl-icd-libopencl1.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional info&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I noticed later on that the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v1.0/docs/WebInstall.md&gt;WebInstall instructions&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 say that "CUDA driver of version 346 or later" is required, and I only have 343. But 343 is the latest version available when you download &lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-downloads-geforce-gtx9xx&gt;https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda-downloads-geforce-gtx9xx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (I have a GTX 970) and install it &lt;denchmark-link:http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/6_5/rel/docs2/CUDA_Getting_Started_Linux.pdf&gt;as instructed&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
:
$ sudo dpkg -i cuda-repo-ubuntu1404-6-5-prod_6.5-19_amd64.deb
$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install cuda
$ echo 'export PATH=/usr/local/cuda-6.5/bin:$PATH' &gt;&gt; ~/.profile
$ echo 'export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/usr/local/cuda-6.5/lib64:$LD_LIBRARY_PATH' &gt;&gt; ~/.profile
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='johnmellor' date='2015-05-11T18:01:23Z'>
		Thanks for the great bug report, and sorry for the trouble! I'll test this and get the issue fixed for the next release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='johnmellor' date='2015-05-12T01:15:16Z'>
		That seems to work, thanks again!

the WebInstall instructions say that "CUDA driver of version 346 or later" is required

You're right, 343 should be sufficient for the 1.0 installer since it comes with CUDA 6.5. That's a documentation bug. The next version of the installer will come with CUDA 7.0 and you will need to have 346 or higher installed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='johnmellor' date='2017-08-23T11:38:00Z'>
		I am trying to install caffe on 16.04 Ubuntu (with cuda 8.0 and cudnn 6.0 installed) for setting up NVIDIA DIGITS but when is run the command:
sudo apt-get install --no-install-recommends libboost-all-dev  -y -q
It gives me this error:
The following packages have unmet dependencies:
libboost-all-dev : Depends: libboost-date-time-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-filesystem-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-graph-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-graph-parallel-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-iostreams-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-log-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-mpi-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-mpi-python-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-program-options-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-regex-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-serialization-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-system-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-thread-dev but it is not going to be installed
Depends: libboost-wave-dev but it is not going to be installed
E: Unable to correct problems, you have held broken packages.
Please can you tell me a fix for this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>