<bug id='1102' author='sherifshehata' open_date='2016-09-21T09:31:53Z' closed_time='2016-09-21T16:32:27Z'>
	<summary>Feature request: no validation datasets, sharing validation set</summary>
	<description>
Hello,
I would suggest that you redesign the handling of training and validation sets. In some cases a user may need to do training only without validation (maybe because the user merged validation and training sets for generating a final model, or to do faster training). Additionally sometimes the user could use a shared validation set across different versions of training sets, which would lead to data duplication in the current setup.
Thanks you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sherifshehata' date='2016-09-21T09:41:03Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sherifshehata&gt;@sherifshehata&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 are you referring to the Object Detection workflow?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sherifshehata' date='2016-09-21T11:18:44Z'>
		Yes. Sorry i didn't specify that in the original description.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='sherifshehata' date='2016-09-21T12:10:27Z'>
		The original intention was to make the validation set optional in the object detection work-flow. Obviously now if you leave the corresponding fields blank in the form you get an error. Digging into this a bit more it looks like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v4.0.0/digits/utils/forms.py#L51&gt;validate_required_if_set&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is not behaving as intended because of this test:
if other_field_value is not None and other_field_value is not "":
In our case if we leave the field blank the value of the field is u'' and:
&gt;&gt;&gt; u'' is not ''
True
I don't know if it's a regression (I think I tested it!) but it looks to me like we could replace the condition with:
if other_field_value:
As it seems to do what we want:
&gt;&gt;&gt; bool(None)
False
&gt;&gt;&gt; bool(u'')
False
&gt;&gt;&gt; bool('')
False
I have tentatively pushed &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/pull/1105&gt;#1105&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if you wish to try. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lukeyeager&gt;@lukeyeager&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 any idea on this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='sherifshehata' date='2016-09-21T12:30:46Z'>
		I think this will solve it. Thank you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>