<bug id='1545' author='S4WRXTTCS' open_date='2017-03-29T22:16:35Z' closed_time='2017-03-30T00:29:49Z'>
	<summary>Configuration Issues with Digits 5.0 on Ubuntu 16.04</summary>
	<description>
I installed Digits 5.0 using the deb based network installer for CUDA 8, and Ubuntu 16.04
It runs correctly, but I'm having issues starting/stopping the service. I'm also having issues reconfiguring it to put the Jobs somewhere else other than the default.
When I try to stop the nvidia-digits-server it comes back with this error message
"stop: Unable to connect to Upstart: Failed to connect to socket /com/ubuntu/upstart: Connection refused"
When I try to make configuration changes according to the UbuntuInstall.md documentation I get this error message when running the sudo python -m digits.config.edit command
/usr/bin/python: No module named digits.config.edit
I did try setting up an environmental variable at startup, and that didn't work either. I believe that's only valid if it's manually installed. Or maybe I didn't put it early enough in the start up.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='S4WRXTTCS' date='2017-03-29T23:03:32Z'>
		Aha, so our DIGITS 5.0 deb packages finally made it on the public repo! Time to update our docs. These are outdated (still intended for the 4.0 debs): &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v5.0.0/docs/UbuntuInstall.md&gt;https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v5.0.0/docs/UbuntuInstall.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
In the meantime, please refer to these files to solve your problems:

https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/releases/tag/v5.0.0-rc.1
https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/digits-5.0/docs/Configuration.md (don't try to use python -m digits.config.edit anymore because of #1091)
https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/digits-5.0/packaging/deb/extras/custom_http_errors/502.html (you have SystemD on 16.04, not upstart)

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='S4WRXTTCS' date='2017-03-30T00:15:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/S4WRXTTCS&gt;@S4WRXTTCS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 will you take a look at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/pull/1546&gt;#1546&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
? Please let me know if it doesn't give you enough information to fix your problem.
Temporary link: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lukeyeager/DIGITS/blob/updated-5.0-debs/docs/UbuntuInstall.md#troubleshooting&gt;https://github.com/lukeyeager/DIGITS/blob/updated-5.0-debs/docs/UbuntuInstall.md#troubleshooting&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='S4WRXTTCS' date='2017-03-30T00:28:46Z'>
		These instructions work great.
Thanks for your help.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>