<bug id='337' author='yangj1e' open_date='2015-10-02T08:07:44Z' closed_time='2015-10-02T22:12:24Z'>
	<summary>No response after starting the server</summary>
	<description>
I got the following RuntimeWarning after starting the server by ./digits-devserver, and then there is no response. The thread is in uninterruptible sleep state.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;/home/ubuntu/anaconda/lib/python2.7/site-packages/setuptools-18.3.2-py2.7.egg/pkg_resources/__init__.py:203: RuntimeWarning: You have iterated over the result of pkg_resources.parse_version. This is a legacy behavior which is inconsistent with the new version class introduced in setuptools 8.0. In most cases, conversion to a tuple is unnecessary. For comparison of versions, sort the Version instances directly. If you have another use case requiring the tuple, please file a bug with the setuptools project describing that need.

Saved config to /home/ubuntu/DIGITS/digits/digits.cfg
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-02T16:28:40Z'>
		Whoops, I'm sure that has to do with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/pull/336&gt;#336&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I'm investigating now.
What version of setuptools do you have, exactly?
$ pip list | grep setuptools
setuptools (7.0)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-02T16:52:41Z'>
		When I upgrade to the latest version of setuptools, I get that same warning, but the server and testsuite both still work just fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-02T22:13:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yangj1e&gt;@yangj1e&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the warning should be gone. If you still have an issue, that's something else. Let me know.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-03T12:31:24Z'>
		Thanks, the warning has gone. But unfortunately, I am still having trouble with the server.
I am using aws g2.2xlarge Ubuntu 14.04 and I use anaconda instead of system python. It used to work fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-03T13:30:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lukeyeager&gt;@lukeyeager&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It seems that if I manually create the  file, the server can start normally, otherwise, it would get stuck.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='yangj1e' date='2015-10-06T16:41:54Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yangj1e&gt;@yangj1e&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,  won't work without a valid configuration file. But  should prompt you to provide any missing information. Let me know if that's not the behavior that you're seeing.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>