<bug id='625' author='ssilphf' open_date='2016-03-10T05:10:07Z' closed_time='2016-08-09T16:15:37Z'>
	<summary>Accuracy show the wrong result on graph</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I have a problem when I use digits3.3dev.
I train a mode using GoogLeNet.
The graph show that accuracy go to 100% ,but when I use the "Test a list of images" on the same job's val.txt file. Result is all class in one category (my mode have 4 categories ,so the accuracy must be about 25%).
And I also use the same dataset and same parameters on digits2.3dev ,it go well. I don't know what is the different of digits2.3dev and digits3.3dev.
Can anyone help me ,please?



I have used "classification" under ~/digits/example/ to test, the result is different with  "Test a list of images".
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ssilphf' date='2016-03-10T19:06:56Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ssilphf&gt;@ssilphf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I can't reproduce your problem yet.
I just merged &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/pull/608&gt;#608&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which should give you some more information when you classify a list of images. Try it out and see if you can get any more information.
Also, if you can give me some standard information about your machine I may be able to spot something fishy:

DIGITS version (use git describe)
Caffe version
cuDNN version
CUDA version
NVIDIA driver version
Operating system

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ssilphf' date='2016-03-10T23:38:26Z'>
		Thank you for speedy re-comment.
That is my information:
Digits version = 3.3 (downloaded yesterday)
Caffe version = 0.14 (download 2016.02.03)
cuDNN version = 4.0
CUDA version = 7.5
NVIDIA driver version = 352.79
OS version = ubuntu14.04.4
This is my training graph, that shows accuracy go to about 100%.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/17756903/13688374/d334c8e2-e764-11e5-955e-b6652982918b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

and this is my result when using "Test a list of images"
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/17756903/13688381/e465ba86-e764-11e5-9987-4aefb5088af1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

then, this is my result when using "/digits/example/classfication/use_archive.py"
I use the same picture in "val.txt", but result is not same as "Test a list of images"
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/17756903/13688284/3118f90c-e764-11e5-9882-1db607f3dd86.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ssilphf' date='2016-03-14T20:21:19Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ssilphf&gt;@ssilphf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you be more specific on the versions you are using:

DIGITS: go to your DIGITS directory and do git describe
Caffe: go to your Caffe directory and do git describe
CuDNN: did you install from deb package? If so, do dpkg -s libcudnn4. Otherwise let us know the file name of your libcudnn.so.4.0.x library.

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ssilphf' date='2016-03-14T21:20:24Z'>
		I'm sorry, but maybe because I didn't use the comment git clone to get the file from github (I just use download ZIP), when I use git describe, that told my this:

fatal: Not a git repository (or any of the parent directories): .git

CuCNN: the file name is libcudnn.so.4.0.7
I find that the problem maybe not from DIGITS, and maybe from caffe or torch or itorch.
so I decide to reinstall all of my PC.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ssilphf' date='2016-03-18T01:45:30Z'>
		I had reinstall my all system and my new version is:
DIGITS:v3.2.0-55-ga13fdf8
Caffe:v0.14.3
CuDNN:libcudnn.so.4.0.7
but the problem still here.
And I use DIGITS2.3dev(other all is same as DIGITS3) on the same dataset,
then I got a different result.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ssilphf' date='2016-05-03T11:11:04Z'>
		DIGITS: v3.1.0-49-g17668e3
Caffe: v0.14.2
CuDNN: libcudnn.so.4.0.4
I have encountered similar issue where one of my model trained using GoogLeNet (I modified the network to optimize the top 2 categories instead of top 5) with higher epochs shows high top2 and top1 accuracy(96.25,91.67). However, when I test a list of images, it shows results similar to posted above; top 1 prediction(and rest of them too) are same for all images(Image 1).
One other bug that i just noticed that was not all the images were picked up from the list, rather the results contained same image being predicted again and again in the results. This was the case even in other model where the prediction output was good(Image 2).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/11766583/14981581/af7f1c0a-114d-11e6-9e24-7c0ed022aa69.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/11766583/14981596/cfdbc412-114d-11e6-90d6-f6e12120c88e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='ssilphf' date='2016-05-03T11:32:01Z'>
		Hello, can you try to upgrade to more recent software? There is a bug in
CuDNN 4.0.4 that causes issues when doing batched inference (
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/issues/536#issuecomment-187452074&gt;#536 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) so you
should upgrade to version 4.0.7.
On Tue, May 3, 2016 at 1:11 PM, rajulanand &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

DIGITS: v3.1.0-49-g17668e3
Caffe: v0.14.2
CuDNN: libcudnn.so.4.0.4
I have encountered similar issue where one of my model trained using
GoogLeNet (I modified the network to optimize the top 2 categories instead
of top 5) with higher epochs shows high top2 and top1
accuracy(96.25,91.67). However, when I test a list of images, it shows
results similar to posted above; top 1 prediction(and rest of them too) are
same for all images. One other bug that i just noticed that was not all the
images were picked up from the list, rather the results contained same
image being predicted again and again in the results. This was the case
even in other model where the prediction output was good.
[image: image]
https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/11766583/14981581/af7f1c0a-114d-11e6-9e24-7c0ed022aa69.png
[image: image]
https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/11766583/14981596/cfdbc412-114d-11e6-90d6-f6e12120c88e.png
—
You are receiving this because you commented.
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
#625 (comment)

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='ssilphf' date='2016-05-06T07:26:36Z'>
		Can you please suggest me how to upgrade cudnn to 4.0.7? I broke my existing digits, nv-caffe installation while trying to do that? I am on 15.04 so I have to build everything from source (I can't get to install 14.04 on my machine for reasons unknown to me). The cuda-7.5 installation contains default 4.0.4 and even after install 4.0.7 from deb file, the lib64 only contains files from 4.0.4. cmake of nv-caffe installations doesn't seem to find cudnn and variables CUDA_cublas_LIBRARY, CUDA_curand_LIBRARY are also set to not found. Any suggestions?
Update: I was able to resolve cudnn to latest version, however now I can't compile nv-caffe despite satisfying all the dependencies mentioned on github for compling nv-caffe.
Update II: I was able to compile nv-caffe but now digits fail with Intel MKL FATAL ERROR: Cannot load libmkl_avx2.so or libmkl_def.so
Update III: I was able to resolve all the issues and having working version of digits, nv-caffe with latest cudnn.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='ssilphf' date='2016-05-09T08:29:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gheinrich&gt;@gheinrich&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Caffe: v0.14.4-4-ge67ce3a
DIGITS: v3.3.0-14-gb989c7b
CuDNN: 4.0.7
After upgrading and everything, I am still getting the wrong prediction result on that particular model.
Note that, wrong prediction result happened in only one of the models so far which I trained very heavily on GoogLeNet ( few images, large epochs).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/11766583/15107553/0ae2bc2e-15ee-11e6-845b-da84d0e9dd21.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='ssilphf' date='2016-05-09T08:49:45Z'>
		Can you tell us what the validation accuracy was for this model and what the confusion matrix looks like when you are doing "classify many"? To get a confusion matrix you may use the val.txt file from your dataset job folder. The Top-1 accuracy you get when doing "classify many" should be exactly the same as the validation accuracy you get during training. Also let us know if you are using batch normalization in your model. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='ssilphf' date='2016-08-09T16:15:36Z'>
		Closing due to inactivity.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='ssilphf' date='2016-11-08T04:41:33Z'>
		Dear Greg, I am getting a significant difference between the accuracy shown on the plot / in the final log file and the one from Classify Many module. Specially, this discrepancy happens in the GoogleNet trained models.  I see this issue in the LeNet models as well but can be tolerated. If you have found the solution , please advise as I really need to get this job done.
FYI: I installed the latest version of DIGITS via this instruction &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/master/docs/UbuntuInstall.md&gt;https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/master/docs/UbuntuInstall.md&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and please let's assume I'm not a beginner.
To solve the above issue, I even resized my samples before using Classify Many but it still the results don't match. I also resized all my samples and retrained a new model from scratch and then used Classify Many module but didn't work neither. I am pretty sure there is something wrong in the feedforward network or the parameters sent to the feedforward network by DIGITS.
Your prompt help is much appreciated!
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='ssilphf' date='2016-11-08T08:32:43Z'>
		Does "classify one" show the expected result? Can you give numbers (accuracy on validation set v.s. accuracy during inference)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='ssilphf' date='2016-11-08T17:41:42Z'>
		Greg - regarding the "classify one" and "classify many" , I have too many samples so that I tested a few of them randomly and the results are identical. It seems both produce the same accuracy.
I attached the accuracy I have on the plot and what I get from classify many. There is a huge difference. I believe what is on the plot is correct because I have trained the model with the original Caffe and pretty much the same number.  During training, the accuracy is 98.49% but in the classify many results that is 83.14%.
(for some reason I remove the class and sample names)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/14916745/20109996/6e1896d6-a597-11e6-86d3-d5bc7fe02dcd.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/14916745/20110003/749a8348-a597-11e6-8f0d-9e4aa8718c94.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='ssilphf' date='2016-11-16T01:18:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gheinrich&gt;@gheinrich&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Any update to your end ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='ssilphf' date='2016-11-30T22:31:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gheinrich&gt;@gheinrich&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rajulanand&gt;@rajulanand&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 The issue came from cropping images by Caffe or Digits. For GoogleNet model, when you use 256x256 images, Caffe can implicitly handle cropping during training and validation somehow. But when you use the same samples for testing / predicition , it doesn't work. There are a few sources of the issue, in addition to the potential problem of cropping, the mean of training samples of 256x256 is different with the cropped images at 224 or cropping and it might not be fully correct. Because the mean is calculated for samples of 256 but is used for samples of 224.
I tested several combinations of training and testing samples and the only way works perfectly fine was to train the GoogleNet by already cropped / resized images at 224x224 and to test by simliar images (cropped or resized at 224x224).
This is the only approach that ensures you to have a correct mean of traning data and identical image preprocessing (sample dimension: 224x224). At least worked for me hope it helps. I suggest to DIGITS folks to update their documentation or double check the codes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='ssilphf' date='2016-12-01T14:12:09Z'>
		I am surprised that this has such a dramatic impact. That indicates that your network might not generalize well to new examples. Don't you have too much correlation between your training and validation sets? Either way, you might want to use mean pixel subtraction instead of mean image subtraction.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>