<bug id='934' author='Nernas' open_date='2016-07-27T08:06:05Z' closed_time='2016-08-01T07:00:13Z'>
	<summary>Can't select adam solver</summary>
	<description>
Hi, Guys.
I use digits 4.0 and nvcaffe 0.15 version on windows.
I can't object detection example. because I can't select adam solver.
also RMSPROP and ADADELTA too.
Thoes three solvers support only Torch?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Nernas' date='2016-07-27T08:40:35Z'>
		Hello,
SGD, NESTEROV, ADAGRAD, RMSPROP, ADADELTA and ADAM solvers are only enabled if DIGITS correctly recognizes (NVIDIA) Caffe as being version at least version 0.14, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/blob/v4.0.0/digits/frameworks/caffe_framework.py#L37-L40&gt;see code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Can you let us know which version/flavour of Caffe are reported in the Info menu (top right corner of the main page)? As a workaround you might want to edit the code to forcibly enable the missing solvers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Nernas' date='2016-07-27T09:44:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gheinrich&gt;@gheinrich&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Oh, sorry. nvcaffe is nvidia caffe 0.15 version. All build is complete and no errors.
nvidia caffe 0.15 version is not stable?
can't understand that version.
Now, (nvidia) caffe version now 0.16 (or rc) then 0.15 is already stable yet?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Nernas' date='2016-07-27T16:30:18Z'>
		
Can you let us know which version/flavour of Caffe are reported in the Info menu (top right corner of the main page)?

Please just give us this info. It's possibly a bug with version-parsing on Windows (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/pull/769&gt;#769&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Nernas' date='2016-07-29T14:50:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Nernas&gt;@Nernas&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , can you try caffe -version in your command prompt?  Also, on the upper right corner of the web page, there is a 'info' menu.  Can you tell us what you see in that menu?  We would like to see if your caffe reports correct version so DIGITS can enable those solvers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Nernas' date='2016-08-01T07:00:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lukeyeager&gt;@lukeyeager&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/IsaacYangSLA&gt;@IsaacYangSLA&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Sorry for late comment.
I was solve this problem yet.
Windows caffe and nvidia caffe have save problem that caffe -version make wrong message.
'caffe say caffe version CAFFE_VERSION'
then, I need to fix that problem. ( if we dont use digits, that's no problem. )
because digits say 'Your Caffe does not have version info. Please upgrade it'
I can find that problem solved to this page.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NVIDIA/DIGITS/issues/47&gt;#47&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I was changed root/digits/config/caffe_option.py ln 169
version_string = line[line.find(pattern) + len(pattern)+1:].rstrip()
to version_string = '0.12.0'
my caffe build version is 0.15.3, but digits know that my caffe version is 0.12.
then, I can't select that 3 solver type.
finally, caffe_option.py ln 169
version_string changed my nvidia caffe's version 0.15.3, then I can select all solver.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>