<bug id='297' author='rodriguesfas' open_date='2020-05-08T03:36:51Z' closed_time='2020-05-13T00:36:10Z'>
	<summary>WARNING: Can not find mwt: default from official model list. Ignoring it.</summary>
	<description>
Hello, I'm running a pipeline with stanza and I get an error for the MWT analysis.
WARNING: Can not find mwt: default from official model list. Ignoring it.
Do you know what it is? For some reason this model is not low in stanza_resources.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rodriguesfas' date='2020-05-08T05:46:52Z'>
		Can you provide more details on how you initialize the pipeline? A code snippet will help us reproduce the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rodriguesfas' date='2020-05-13T00:27:07Z'>
		I am getting the same warnings for both en and zh models.
The code and logs are as follows:
stanza.download('zh-hans')
nlp = stanza.Pipeline(lang='zh-hans', processors='tokenize,mwt,pos', use_gpu=False)
Downloading https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stanfordnlp/stanza-resources/master/resources_1.0.0.json: 116kB [00:00, 1.25MB/s]                     2020-05-13 08:25:16 INFO: Downloading default packages for language: zh-hans (Simplified_Chinese)... 2020-05-13 08:25:18 INFO: File exists: C:\Users\WT.YX\stanza_resources\zh-hans\default.zip. 2020-05-13 08:25:25 INFO: Finished downloading models and saved to C:\Users\WT.YX\stanza_resources. 2020-05-13 08:25:25 WARNING: Can not find mwt: default from official model list. Ignoring it. 2020-05-13 08:25:25 INFO: Loading these models for language: zh-hans (Simplified_Chinese):
2020-05-13 08:25:25 INFO: Use device: cpu 2020-05-13 08:25:25 INFO: Loading: tokenize 2020-05-13 08:25:25 INFO: Loading: pos 2020-05-13 08:25:28 INFO: Done loading processors!
stanza.download('en')
nlp = stanza.Pipeline(lang='en', processors='tokenize,mwt,pos', use_gpu=False)
Downloading https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stanfordnlp/stanza-resources/master/resources_1.0.0.json: 116kB [00:00, 1.28MB/s]                     2020-05-13 08:23:02 INFO: Downloading default packages for language: en (English)... 2020-05-13 08:23:02 INFO: File exists: C:\Users\WT.YX\stanza_resources\en\default.zip. 2020-05-13 08:23:07 INFO: Finished downloading models and saved to C:\Users\WT.YX\stanza_resources. 2020-05-13 08:23:07 WARNING: Can not find mwt: default from official model list. Ignoring it. 2020-05-13 08:23:07 INFO: Loading these models for language: en (English):
Are there any tricks I am missing here? And based on the tutorials, mwtprocessor is required for pos, so will the absence of mwtprocessor affect the subsequent pos performance? Thanks for any enlightenment!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rodriguesfas' date='2020-05-13T00:36:10Z'>
		According to the &lt;denchmark-link:https://universaldependencies.org/u/overview/tokenization.html&gt;Universal Dependencies tokenization guideline&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, many languages do not have multi-word token (MWT) expansions. These languages include English and Chinese. So we do not have MWT models for English and Chinese and you do not need the MWT processors to produce accurate UD parsing for these languages.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rodriguesfas' date='2020-05-13T00:37:50Z'>
		To add on the above answer, since this is a warning message, you can simply ignore it and it should not affect the actual running of the pipeline at all. But removing mwt from the processors list should help you get rid of the warning message.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>