<bug id='300' author='TahaMunir1' open_date='2020-05-11T12:36:49Z' closed_time='2020-05-11T21:35:03Z'>
	<summary>Unknown morphological feature: 'ConjType'</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
When I run nlp(comment) for Urdu language, I got error:
[E167] Unknown morphological feature: 'ConjType' (9141427322507498425). This can happen if the tagger was trained with a different set of morphological features. If you're using a pretrained model, make sure that your models are up to date: python -m spacy validate
some of the docs work while some don't.
To Reproduce
Following code to get tokens and pos tags:
snlp = stanza.Pipeline(lang='ur') nlp = StanzaLanguage(snlp) doc = nlp('یہ سرد اور تلخ تھا')
Expected behavior
No error and a list of pos tags, tokens should have been received but instead got an error for conjunction.
Environment (please complete the following information):

Windows and CentOs
Python3.8
Stanza version: 1.0.0

Additional context
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='TahaMunir1' date='2020-05-11T20:54:17Z'>
		Are you using the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/explosion/spacy-stanza&gt;spacy-stanza library&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
? It looks like that this error was thrown by spaCy instead of Stanza, likely due to spaCy failing to recognize one of Stanza's output tags, so maybe this issue should be posted there?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='TahaMunir1' date='2020-05-11T21:31:59Z'>
		Yes, actually I realized that it was due to spacy-stanza and posted same question there as well. Conjunctions are working fine with other languages but strangely faced the error in one of them.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='TahaMunir1' date='2020-05-11T21:35:02Z'>
		Great. It is likely that spaCy has some special lexicon for morphological features and for Urdu it fails to match the ConjType onto a lexicon item. I am closing this issue for Stanza for now, but feel free to comment/reopen if this ends up being a Stanza issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>