<bug id='2069' author='lcy-seso' open_date='2017-05-09T06:24:39Z' closed_time='2018-01-29T02:28:49Z'>
	<summary>When is_static=True and no pre-training parameters provided, no error occurs.</summary>
	<description>
Please use this PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/models/pull/34/files&gt;https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/models/pull/34/files&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 as an example, in which, some parameters are set  and no pre-training parameters are provided, but it still can run. This is not reasonable and some bugs may happen.
I suspect whether is_static=True is enable, and whether these static parameters are updated during training？
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-05-09T06:36:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qingqing01&gt;@qingqing01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 has told me, once a parameter is set , it will not be updated during the training, but if this is the case, why there casts no error?  how is the static parameter initialized?  What is the training process computing?
This behavior is dangerous.
I find the parameter init_model_path is invalid and useless for V2 API. Should this be documented?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-05-09T09:13:43Z'>
		At first, if the parameter attribute of initialization method is not set, the parameter's value will be set to zero by default.
Second, if is_static=True is set, the gradient buffer of the parameter will not be allocated, and the backward of the layer will skip.  The parameter value will not be updated.
So, the training process still can run, just some parameter are not updated.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-05-09T09:15:34Z'>
		But, if a parameter is set to static, it should be explicitly initialized, otherwise cast an error.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-05-09T09:20:37Z'>
		Usually, we will set static attribute to some parameter if we want to do some fine-tuning.
You are right, maybe we should  ensure that the static parameter must be explicitly initialized.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-08-21T18:33:29Z'>
		Close this issue due to inactivity. please feel free to reopen it if more information is available.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-10-23T10:15:15Z'>
		This is a bug that should be fixed, so I reopen it.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>