<bug id='3232' author='reyoung' open_date='2017-08-04T05:28:08Z' closed_time='2017-08-07T01:54:01Z'>
	<summary>MKLDNN changes global linker flags with shared library.</summary>
	<description>
When WITH_MKLDNN is true, configure.cmake changes linker flags to link -liomp for all executors and shared libraries. But some of Paddle executors and libraries (especially executors and shared libraries when refactoring) do not need MKLDNN and do not depend on it.
So we should change the configure.cmake to make targets who use iomp to link it.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to reproduce this issue.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

In Linux system, add cmake flag WITH_MKLDNN=ON, and make any binary or shared library which does not depends on MKLDNN will trigger this error.
Like
cmake .. -DWITH_MKLDNN=ON
make paddle_pybind
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Error line of code&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/Paddle/blob/develop/cmake/configure.cmake#L77

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T07:28:02Z'>
		I can not reproduce this issue follow your steps.
It will link iomp5 only if WITH_MKLDNN=ON and WITH_MKLML=ON.
But I do can find the issue with cmake .. -DWITH_MKLDNN=ON -DWITH_MKLML=ON.
Then I found that no mklml package installed, when  make paddle_pybind.
Then cause the issue.
Anyway, will follow up.
Thx.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T07:32:17Z'>
		I got another question, please help me clarify. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/reyoung&gt;@reyoung&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/luotao1&gt;@luotao1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Does paddle_pybind need cblas?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T07:40:08Z'>
		
Then I found that no mklml package installed, when make paddle_pybind.

As downloading mklml package need several minutes, if make paddle_pybind before downloading sucessfully, the issue will be caused.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T07:44:51Z'>
		Actually it may not download mklml at all, since I did not depend on it.
Then I should ensure that if cblas is needed, so I can depends it on mklml.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T08:04:25Z'>
		
Does paddle_pybind need cblas?

No, paddle_pybind does not need cblas.

I can not reproduce this issue follow your steps.

A clean environment could reproduce this issue. Screen record video is &lt;denchmark-link:https://asciinema.org/a/WZ6uNJJ9EaTqMiX1ujN6H3Uij&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='reyoung' date='2017-08-04T08:20:04Z'>
		First of all, thanks for your kindly video.

A clean environment could reproduce this issue. Screen record video is here.

I think I know why that I can not reproduce. I pull the latest code and you disable MKLML and MKLDNN by default.

No,  paddle_pybind does not need cblas.

I will try to find a better way to link to specific executors which requires mkldnn.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>