<bug id='3710' author='lcy-seso' open_date='2017-08-28T01:15:43Z' closed_time='2018-07-10T05:22:40Z'>
	<summary>the infer interface in V2 API has some problems.</summary>
	<description>
the infer interface in V2 API has some problems which are VERY UNREASONABLE in use:


One problem as reported in this issue: #2170.

the infer interface always flattens the prediction results given by one or multiple layer (if multiple layers are specified as outputs of the network) by concatenating them: https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/Paddle/blob/develop/python/paddle/v2/inference.py#L86
Such a concatenation will fail if multiple output layers have a different height which is a very common situation, for example, If I want to output both a sequence layer and a non-sequence layer. The former one has a variable length, then the concatenation will fail.



by using the infer interface, users have to choose a field to output, the available choices are value, field, ids.

this line https://github.com/PaddlePaddle/Paddle/blob/develop/python/paddle/v2/inference.py#L70 iterate over the specified fields for all the chosen output layers.
for one layer user may want multiple fields as outputs, such as in NMT.
but if multiple layers are specified as outputs of the network, a user may want different fields for different layers.
This will cause a bug in the infer interface because the current implementation of infer interface constraints different output layers must output the same fields.



&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/reyoung&gt;@reyoung&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  I will fix this because I find I cannot bypass it, but I just want you to know the problem!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-09-27T02:23:13Z'>
		Is there any updates on this issue? I find that when I use a layer with sequence output as the output of the model, the infer interface will concat all sequence output of the whole batch to one long sequence, which is also unreasonable.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lcy-seso' date='2017-09-27T02:40:13Z'>
		please check this &lt;denchmark-link:http://doc.paddlepaddle.org/develop/doc_cn/faq/index_cn.html#infer-layer&gt;http://doc.paddlepaddle.org/develop/doc_cn/faq/index_cn.html#infer-layer&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>