<bug id='466' author='wangkuiyi' open_date='2016-11-15T01:01:22Z' closed_time='2016-12-01T20:42:27Z'>
	<summary>Build Docker images for release tags.</summary>
	<description>
From this &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/paddledev/paddle/builds/&gt;build history&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it seems that we have only  Docker images build automatically by DockerHub.com, right? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/reyoung&gt;@reyoung&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Given that we are now having releasing models and release tags, we can build Docker images for each release tag.  I noticed an example setup &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.docker.com/docker-hub/builds/&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 in DockerHub.com's help pages.  An illustrative figure is as follows:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://camo.githubusercontent.com/5b576580c4b6ee01f2a5e10fa41a5fe04726e72a90bc508d543d58427da9764c/68747470733a2f2f646f63732e646f636b65722e636f6d2f646f636b65722d6875622f696d616765732f72656765782d68656c702e706e67&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='wangkuiyi' date='2016-11-16T00:31:09Z'>
		I noticed that the Dockerfiles we current have s &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/baidu/Paddle/blob/develop/paddle/scripts/docker/build.sh#L24&gt;build.sh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which invokes  and .  This would prevents dockerhub.com from building Docker images from the wanted tags.  The key is that the Dockerfiles have to be placed at the root directory of the the source tree, so that we can use  in the Dockerfile to copy the whole source tree into the Docker image at build time, but cannot use  to retrieve the source from anywhere out of the Docker context.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='wangkuiyi' date='2016-11-26T07:19:49Z'>
		I reviewed the current way that we build Docker images.  This real problem is that we cannot build from any Git commit, e.g., the current work on a developer's notebook.
The key is that Dockerfile shouldn't run git clone and switch to a certain tag/branch, but should build from the current local repo.
Another challenge is that the version should not be specified in CMakeLists.txt, but should be derived from Git tag or Git commit ID.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>