<bug id='1514' author='atulim' open_date='2018-09-24T12:14:56Z' closed_time='2018-10-20T18:02:48Z'>
	<summary>On account of running MLPACK in WINDOWS 10</summary>
	<description>
Sir ,
When building in Visual Studio 2017  as stated under Windows Build Instructions in &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&gt;http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , when we enter the given project location and type of project , it is showing an 
Hence further instructions cannot be followed.
(Kindly help as I am inclined towards contributing in mlpack)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22341556/45951567-86092480-c021-11e8-8792-5883ac4f640c.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='atulim' date='2018-09-24T13:08:51Z'>
		As stated by-  Keon &lt;denchmark-link:https://keon.io/mlpack-on-windows/&gt;https://keon.io/mlpack-on-windows/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 This also doesn't work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='atulim' date='2018-09-24T13:22:58Z'>
		Can you give a detailed report of what you've done?  Have you unpacked mlpack into the directory C:\mlpack\mlpack-3.0.3\?  (I am not a Windows expert so I can try my best to help but I may be unable to due to unfamiliarity with Visual Studio.)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='atulim' date='2018-09-24T14:17:10Z'>
		Yes sir I have done everything as prescribed to me. Unpacked for the same
location as given in the first url mentioned, but it won't help.
Kindly help.
Thanks for your concern.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Mon, 24 Sep 2018, 18:53 Ryan Curtin, ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 Can you give a detailed report of what you've done? Have you unpacked
 mlpack into the directory C:\mlpack\mlpack-3.0.3\? (I am not a Windows
 expert so I can try my best to help but I may be unable to due to
 unfamiliarity with Visual Studio.)

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#1514 (comment)&gt;, or mute
 the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AVTntEAHl_0yaHP9GuGK0syH7qzPMUc2ks5ueNy9gaJpZM4W2id6&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='atulim' date='2018-09-24T14:49:44Z'>
		can you open a command prompt (cmd) and run:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;devenv.exe /installvstemplates
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

let's see if that solves the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='atulim' date='2018-09-25T02:33:06Z'>
		Sir,
After entering the code in prompt it shows error
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22341556/45989439-55fd6800-c099-11e8-940b-678239a366e7.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Kindly check if I have installed correct software or not in the image below
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22341556/45989450-67df0b00-c099-11e8-9477-724dfb91c918.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='atulim' date='2018-09-25T04:10:29Z'>
		Followed as prescribed but not working
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Mon, 24 Sep 2018, 20:21 Marcus Edel, ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 can you open a command prompt (cmd) and run:

 devenv.exe /installvstemplates

 let's see if that solves the issue.

 —
 You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#1514 (comment)&gt;, or mute
 the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AVTntJDo9AZRzcCs0agDz5of_8qfEwUhks5uePFtgaJpZM4W2id6&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='atulim' date='2018-09-25T21:56:51Z'>
		Can you click the modify button in the installer and post the image? My guess is you haven't installed the C++ desktop development module.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='atulim' date='2018-09-26T13:18:44Z'>
		Maybe I can help. First of all you have to start a Developer Command Prompt for VS and not a standard Windows command prompt for the above command Marcus (zoq) was referring to!
Secondly the description you are following seems far too complicated to me. I never followed any description just used CMake (reads the CMakeLists.txt in the root folder of the mlpack install) and generated automatically the VS project files which worked without any problem immediately.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='atulim' date='2018-09-26T19:46:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zsogitbe&gt;@zsogitbe&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Kindly give me the link you want me to follow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='atulim' date='2018-09-26T19:51:56Z'>
		Atul, please learn to use CMake &lt;denchmark-link:https://cmake.org&gt;https://cmake.org&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . This is really necessary if you want to be able to easily create VS project files automatically. It is very easy to use but you will have to invest a little bit of time in it to learn it. With CMake it takes 5 minutes to make the mlpack VS project files. I can not provide you an easier solution.
I hope this helps. -Z
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='atulim' date='2018-09-26T22:13:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zoq&gt;@zoq&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for your help. It solved the issue.
However can you guide me to build mlpack &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&gt;http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 from here as I am facing unable to build it as it contains no mlpack.sin file even after running the command in the command prompt.
It would be grateful.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22341556/46112200-6b90a000-c207-11e8-9217-f80d83b86aca.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='atulim' date='2018-09-27T06:23:57Z'>
		Atul, learn to read the CMake messages on the screen and think about it! People often ask a question first and then think or even do not think. You should learn to do the opposite. First think and then ask a question if needed. -Z
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='atulim' date='2018-09-27T16:59:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/atulim&gt;@atulim&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it looks like cmake can't find the necessary boost packages; if you can provide some more information (like what's inside the C:/boost/boost_1_66_0/boost_1_66_0 folder) I can see if I can help you fix the issue, what cmake command did you use.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='atulim' date='2018-10-10T14:34:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/atulim&gt;@atulim&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I had the very same problem a couple of days ago: I followed the guided procedure step by step, but mlpack refused to build for several reasons. At last I succeded using boost_1_64_0 instead of 1_66_0.
Same OpenBlas, same Armadillo version, same everything as stated in the tutorial except from the boost library version (therefore if you wanna try you will have to change the command line arguments to
-DBOOST_INCLUDEDIR:PATH="C:/boost/boost_1_64_0/"
-DBOOST_LIBRARYDIR:PATH="C:/boost/boost_1_64_0/lib64-msvc-14.1"
)
Then a solution appeared and trying to build mlpack gave a last "Compiler out of heap space" error, which I solved by updating Visual Studio.
I used MSVS 2017 Professional, version 15.8.6
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='atulim' date='2018-10-10T14:39:11Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/GLmontanari&gt;@GLmontanari&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: strange that Boost 1.66 didn't work, CMake should be able to find it just fine, especially with  and  set in the  CMake option inside of .  Do you have any more information on why using Boost 1.66 failed?
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='atulim' date='2018-10-10T15:02:39Z'>
		Ok, so here is the whole story: I initially tried the procedure as explained here  &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&gt;http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.3/doxygen/build_windows.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 using boost_1_66_0 and I got the problem stated in this closed issue: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/563&gt;#563&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Fundamentally, or so I guess..., CMake couldn't find some libraries called boost_... .lib and libboost_....lib.
I checked under the corresponding folder and they where there.
Then I checked the CMakeLists.txt file and added Boost 1.66 in the Boost_ADDITIONAL_VERSIONS as you said.
Here is a copy of the file:
set(Boost_ADDITIONAL_VERSIONS
"1.66.0" "1.66"
"1.65.1" "1.65.0" "1.65"
"1.64.1" "1.64.0" "1.64"
"1.63.1" "1.63.0" "1.63"
"1.62.1" "1.62.0" "1.62"
"1.61.1" "1.61.0" "1.61"
"1.60.1" "1.60.0" "1.60"
"1.59.1" "1.59.0" "1.59"
"1.58.1" "1.58.0" "1.58"
"1.57.1" "1.57.0" "1.57"
"1.56.1" "1.56.0" "1.56"
"1.55.1" "1.55.0" "1.55"
"1.54.1" "1.54.0" "1.54"
"1.53.1" "1.53.0" "1.53"
"1.52.1" "1.52.0" "1.52"
"1.51.1" "1.51.0" "1.51"
"1.50.1" "1.50.0" "1.50"
"1.49.1" "1.49.0" "1.49")
find_package(Boost 1.66.0
COMPONENTS
program_options
unit_test_framework
serialization
REQUIRED
)
But still didn't work. At last I decided to try using an older boost release and with version 1_64_0 it worked.
What is weird is that the folder tree is the same for boost 1_64_0 and 1_66_0 and they contain the very same files, with a slightly different name, but somehow Cmake likes the former more than the latter.
I am no expert, but I'll try to help if you have further questions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='atulim' date='2018-10-11T10:07:57Z'>
		By the way this seems to be a generalized problem, since another issue reports the same for boost 1_68_0:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1524&gt;#1524&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='atulim' date='2018-10-20T18:02:48Z'>
		Thanks for the update.  In &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1524&gt;#1524&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the idea of using  was suggested, so once I find out some more information about that, perhaps I can work up a fix that will make finding Boost a lot more robust on Windows in general and solve both of these issues.
So I'll close this now since I think at this point it'll be solved the same way as that other issue.  If I'm wrong about that please feel free to reopen. :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>