<bug id='1516' author='marcespie' open_date='2018-10-08T13:05:24Z' closed_time='2018-10-20T15:36:58Z'>
	<summary>-lrt is not needed on OpenBSD either</summary>
	<description>
Seems to me someone should really write a test for the location of clock_gettime().
Or maybe just reverse the test.
Because NetBSD and FreeBSD have clock_gettime as part of libc either. They won't error out because they have a stub -lrt.
AFAIK, only Linux requires -lrt to get clock_gettime...
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T02:28:11Z'>
		Thanks for the input!
Where are you seeing that -lrt is being used?  As far as I know we're not explicitly linking against it.  Also the timers use stuff from chrono, not clock_gettime() (unless chrono internally uses clock_gettime(), but that shouldn't make a huge difference in our case anyway).
Are you by chance using a really old version of mlpack (like mlpack 1.x or 2.x)?  I seem to remember those explicitly linking against -lrt in places.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T06:37:59Z'>
		On Mon, Oct 08, 2018 at 07:28:25PM -0700, Ryan Curtin wrote:

    Thanks for the input!

    Where are you seeing that -lrt is being used? As far as I know we're
    not explicitly linking against it. Also the timers use stuff from
    chrono, not clock_gettime() (unless chrono internally uses
    clock_gettime(), but that shouldn't make a huge difference in our case
    anyway).

    Are you by chance using a really old version of mlpack (like mlpack 1.x
    or 2.x)? I seem to remember those explicitly linking against -lrt in
    places.
On libmlpack itself,  version 3.0.3

see the main CMakeLists.txt. Line 155 or so.

# For clock_gettime().
if (UNIX AND NOT APPLE AND NOT HAIKU)
  set(MLPACK_LIBRARIES ${MLPACK_LIBRARIES} "rt")
endif ()
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T12:42:32Z'>
		Oh, you're right, there it is.  Seems like my grepping around didn't find it.  I think we can just remove that block entirely since clock_gettime() isn't used anymore, so I'll do that.  👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-20T15:36:58Z'>
		Fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1523&gt;#1523&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Thanks again for the report 
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>