<bug id='1522' author='marcespie' open_date='2018-10-09T12:33:05Z' closed_time='2018-10-20T15:39:20Z'>
	<summary>packaging of python extensions fail</summary>
	<description>
The build system mistakenly assumes you can install stuff directly. This breaks havoc with any modern packaging system.
At the very least, support setting DESTDIR during configuration. It would be better to do that during the install stage, but it allows things to proceed correctly.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/2460366/patch.txt&gt;patch.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T12:35:28Z'>
		You can get the same effect by just configuring CMake with -DCMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX=/your/preferred/install/root/. :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T12:58:17Z'>
		This is a common misconception about DESTDIR.
DESTDIR is still needed.
Most modern packaging systems support a staging area.
You configure your software so that it can be run from a specific path, that's what CMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX is for (say /usr/local), but you don't install it directly: you install it in a staging area (say /path/to/staging/area) by using DESTDIR=/path/to/staging/area.
This installs files under /path/to/staging/area/usr/local   that are intended to be run from /usr/local.
Then you package them using your packaging tools, and then you've got a binary package you can install...
So there is the very important distinction that /path/to/staging/area never appears inside any of the installed files (config files and whatnot) and this is the reason why some kind of DESTDIR support is needed :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-09T13:06:18Z'>
		(I already responded to this via a personal email, but probably better to respond here publicly just so all the discussion is in one place.)
Thanks for the clarification---I understand the difference now.  Are you sure that DESTDIR doesn't already work?  i.e.
make DESTDIR=/path/to_staging_area/ install?
The CMake documentation suggests this already should work on UNIX-like CMake systems:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cmake.org/cmake/help/latest/envvar/DESTDIR.html&gt;https://cmake.org/cmake/help/latest/envvar/DESTDIR.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-20T15:39:20Z'>
		Fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1523&gt;#1523&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>