<bug id='1526' author='alexxucui' open_date='2018-10-11T20:22:32Z' closed_time='2018-10-25T23:07:31Z'>
	<summary>Mean shift isolated single point issue;</summary>
	<description>

No description provided.

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-11T20:57:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ShangtongZhang&gt;@ShangtongZhang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for implementing mean-shift.
I have a question about one of my use case:
I have three input points of:
(-8.03939 -24.0719)
(-8.03939 -24.0719)
(-5.54168 -16.5931)
I set the radius to 0.3. Obviously there should be 2 clusters but the lib gives only 1 cluster. The centroid are at (-8.039389, -24.071899) which makes sense. Even I removed the last point the centroid is still the same. I have tried turn on and off the force convergence but the results is the same. It seems the algorithm will always force one single points to some centroid.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-11T21:02:40Z'>
		Hey there &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alexxucui&gt;@alexxucui&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, what is  set to?  Is the third point being labeled as 'noise' instead of a cluster?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-11T21:19:05Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I cannot find  you mentioned. Do you mean  in the ? And I cannot find 'noise'? I only get  and  as output.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-11T21:24:23Z'>
		Oh, sorry! For some reason I mistakenly thought you were using dbscan. I'm traveling right now but I will try to reproduce and understand the issue later today or tomorrow.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-11T21:31:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks a lot.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-18T01:42:53Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alexxucui&gt;@alexxucui&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, sorry my response took so long.  It took until today to find a few minutes to look into this one.  I found that the existing mean shfit implementation disallows clusters that hold only a single point, but I don't know any reason for this.  (Perhaps it could be a parameter or something.)
In any case, I opened PR &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1536&gt;#1536&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 which should fix the issue.  I can't think of any easy workaround with the existing codebase, so you'll either have to copy the patch into your code manually, wait until the PR is merged, or wait until the next release that incorporates the patch.  (I have been meaning to release 3.0.4 for quite a while now, so I will have to actually find the time to do that in the next few weeks.)
Hope this helps!  Let me know if I overlooked anything.  And thanks for the bug report. 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='alexxucui' date='2018-10-25T23:07:31Z'>
		This should be fixed now that &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1536&gt;#1536&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is merged.  Thanks again for pointing out the bug and feel free to open more issues if you encounter more problems. :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>