<bug id='1544' author='marcespie' open_date='2018-10-22T14:00:03Z' closed_time='2018-11-09T21:47:29Z'>
	<summary>More dependency issues in CMakelists</summary>
	<description>
found by a co-developer on OpenBSD...  custom commands should have BYPRODUCTS when required so that dependencies actually work.
(2 patches attached)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/2501647/patch2.txt&gt;patch2.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/2501648/patch1.txt&gt;patch1.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This makes ninja build break half-randomly again.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-23T18:49:41Z'>
		Thanks for the fixes!  The patches look good to me, but before I prepare to merge them I have to figure out what to do about CMake reverse compatibility.  Our minimum version is 2.8 but BYPRODUCTS appears in something like 3.3 or so.  So I just need to test that there's not a failure on 2.8---or bump the minimum version.  I'll open a PR shortly, but it may be a little bit until I am able to find the right reverse compatibility fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-23T19:02:27Z'>
		On Tue, Oct 23, 2018 at 11:50:22AM -0700, Ryan Curtin wrote:

    Thanks for the fixes! The patches look good to me, but before I prepare
    to merge them I have to figure out what to do about CMake reverse
    compatibility. Our minimum version is 2.8 but BYPRODUCTS appears in
    something like 3.3 or so. So I just need to test that there's not a
    failure on 2.8---or bump the minimum version. I'll open a PR shortly,
    but it may be a little bit until I am able to find the right reverse
    compatibility fix.
Err, cmake 3.3 is over 3 years old by this point.

I surmise about everyone has updated already ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-23T19:07:48Z'>
		It's true, but I want to make sure the software can still be built on RHEL6 and Ubuntu 14.04, since a lot of people especially at universities with slow-moving IT processes can be stuck on that.  When I checked yesterday, I saw that the cmake package in the trusty repositories was 2.8.12.2... but what I did not see until I double-checked just now is that there is a cmake3 package that is sufficiently new, and this is also the situation for EPEL6.
So, I'll just update the minimum required CMake version in the PR.  :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='marcespie' date='2018-10-25T21:10:14Z'>
		Thanks again, PR opened as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1550&gt;#1550&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='marcespie' date='2018-11-09T21:47:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1550&gt;#1550&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 was merged a little while ago, so I'll go ahead and close this now.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>