<bug id='1694' author='bhavya01' open_date='2019-01-30T09:13:38Z' closed_time='2019-10-05T17:13:20Z'>
	<summary>Segmentation Fault: preprocess_split</summary>
	<description>
I am getting a segmentation fault when I run this in python3.5
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;df = pd.read_csv('covertype-small.csv')
labels = df['label']
dataset = df.drop('label', 1)
output = mlpack.preprocess_split(input=dataset, input_labels=labels, test_ratio=0.1)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

but on removing input_labels, it works fine.
output = mlpack.preprocess_split(input=dataset, test_ratio=0.1)
I built mlpack-3.0.4 from source on Ubuntu 16.04
Armadillo version: 6.5
Please suggest how to find out the issue.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bhavya01' date='2019-01-30T13:37:17Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bhavya01&gt;@bhavya01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 .
I think it will work.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;df = pd.read_csv('covertype-small.csv')
labels = pd.DataFrame(data=df['label'])
dataset = df.drop('label', 1)
output = mlpack.preprocess_split(input=dataset, input_labels=labels, test_ratio=0.1)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bhavya01' date='2019-01-30T14:43:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/KimSangYeon-DGU&gt;@KimSangYeon-DGU&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: nice workaround, thanks! 
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bhavya01&gt;@bhavya01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: I can reproduce this also, and I agree that it is a bug.  But can I ask why you did not use the 'bug report' issue template?  It makes it a lot easier for us...
If anyone wants to look into this (it may be a while until I can get to it), I am willing to bet that the issue will be in the to_matrix() function found in src/mlpack/bindings/python/mlpack/matrix_utils.py.  In the code snippet, labels is of type pandas.core.series.Series, so I guess that we are not handling this case correctly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bhavya01' date='2019-01-30T14:47:56Z'>
		Sorry, I wasn't sure if this was a bug or a problem in my installation. I would like to look into it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bhavya01' date='2019-01-30T15:00:23Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bhavya01&gt;@bhavya01&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sounds good.  Maybe we can update the issue template to use the word "problem" instead. 
If you want to look into it, feel free---my suggestion would be to take a look through the file matrix_utils.py that I mentioned, and maybe add some print() lines to see which paths are being taken through the code, to see what is being passed to mlpack.
You can also try to debug from the C++ side, by compiling mlpack with debug options (cmake -DDEBUG=ON ...), and then using gdb python and entering the code that fails, and figuring out what has happened at the site of the segfault.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bhavya01' date='2019-03-05T17:44:04Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='bhavya01' date='2019-03-20T02:46:02Z'>
		While I was testing out the &lt;denchmark-link:http://mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.4/doxygen/python_quickstart.html&gt;simple quickstart example&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I got a segmentation fault. Moreover, neither the given workaround nor the removal of  worked for me.
I am on Ubuntu 18.04 and I installed mlpack using pip install mlpack3.
I will check the to_matrix() function as soon as I can to solve the problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='bhavya01' date='2019-03-24T18:00:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mrkeremyilmaz&gt;@mrkeremyilmaz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 refer &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1772#issuecomment-475972722&gt;#1772&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='bhavya01' date='2019-10-05T17:13:20Z'>
		I tried to reproduce this with the current master branch and I am unable to.  I think the issue has been solved.  If anyone's still encountering it, feel free to reopen (or file a new issue). 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>