<bug id='1795' author='janek' open_date='2019-03-19T10:48:31Z' closed_time='2019-06-30T16:47:08Z'>
	<summary>pip installation not working on macOS + instructions a bit unclear</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Problem location&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.4/doxygen/python_quickstart.html&gt;http://www.mlpack.org/docs/mlpack-3.0.4/doxygen/python_quickstart.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Description of problem&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Installing the mlpack bindings for Python is straightforward. It's easy to use conda or pip to do this:
pip install mlpack/mlpack3

I'm not familiar with the path-like/syntax for pip packages, so I wasn't sure if it's a mistake or just a way of expressing that it should be either mlpack or mlpack3.
Anyway, I tried all three possibilities. Two of them do nothing and pip install mlpack actually installs something called mlpack 0.1.4 that looks like a very early version of this library. It contains only linear regression and logistic regression.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2146927/54600344-d98e8500-4a3c-11e9-9816-a3bd3a495e93.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If that is indeed a super old version of this library, it should definitely be removed, that's very confusing.
It would be wonderful if mlpack was possible to easily install with pip. So far I've spend an hour trying to install it (in any way, including source) - and I've been unsuccessful. I will try to open more issues for the docs later.
Thank you for your work, hope this can get fixed.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='janek' date='2019-03-21T13:52:53Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/janek&gt;@janek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, why don't you use ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='janek' date='2019-03-21T14:57:03Z'>
		hey, thanks for writing. I have tried it, and it doesn't work (the error message is in the screnshot).
I collected some info in the IRC chat, and if I understand correctly pip install mlpack3 is actually the correct command. It just doesn't work on macOS at the moment.
So what I would strongly suggest to do immediately is to change pip install mlpack/mlpack3 to pip install mlpack3 to avoid the confusion that I went through.
And of course, whenever possible, fix the pip installation for mac - but I understand that might be a larger issue/take longer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='janek' date='2019-03-21T15:25:18Z'>
		I see, can you try it in Python 3.6? It seems to be related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1670&gt;#1670&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Sorry, if it doesn't work in macOS.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='janek' date='2019-03-21T15:29:55Z'>
		Yeah, we only provide  packages which work on Linux, but not OS X.  So it won't work there.  In any case though, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/janek&gt;@janek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is right that the documentation is wrong and should be changed.
I'd like to dig into this a bit more and see what's needed for the OS X packages, but it'll be a little while until I have the time, I think.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='janek' date='2019-03-21T16:36:59Z'>
		Understandable. Thanks for responding and for your approach!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='janek' date='2019-06-30T16:47:07Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/janek&gt;@janek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, it took a while to get everything set up.  But now, we have the mlpack/mlpack-wheels repository, which we can use with Travis to build pip packages for mlpack for both OS X and manylinux.  Take a look, now mlpack 3.1.1 is uploaded and available: &lt;denchmark-link:https://pypi.org/project/mlpack3/&gt;https://pypi.org/project/mlpack3/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It's very easy to trigger these builds and make it part of the release pipeline, so you can expect these to remain up-to-date.  In addition, it's possible to use the mlpack-wheels repository to provide Windows packages.  But for now we are still debugging the Windows Python bindings in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1872&gt;#1872&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, so once we get that working then we can automate the release of Windows packages via PyPI.
Anyway, thanks for the report!  I'll go ahead and close this now because I believe the issue is fixed.  Let me know if there are any problems.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='janek' date='2019-07-01T11:04:09Z'>
		Looks good! Thanks a lot &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>