<bug id='1834' author='kolbma' open_date='2019-04-03T16:38:50Z' closed_time='2019-05-14T11:53:23Z'>
	<summary>Build problem $ENV{DESTDIR} got expanded on cmake call</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I think you have a mistake in your cmake scripts.
You use $ENV{DESTDIR}.
This gets expanded during cmake generating the files for Unix make.
So it gets set to the value the env-var has when calling cmake.
But this should be set to the DESTDIR variable when calling DESTDIR=... make install!
I need this escaped in the form \$ENV{DESTDIR}.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kolbma' date='2019-04-05T06:23:14Z'>
		I would like to work on this issue. Where did you find that $ENV{DESTDIR} in the source code.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kolbma' date='2019-04-05T08:25:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/3046943/01-fix-lib-path.patch.txt&gt;01-fix-lib-path.patch.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/chandramoulirajagopalan&gt;@chandramoulirajagopalan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
this is my current patch against 3.0.4 tag to support 64-bit arch targets and to make it install in DESTDIR for bundling.
Although up-to-now the python bindings doesn't work on import. But there is another issue for this at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1760#issuecomment-479570820&gt;#1760 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The $ENV{DESTDIR} is in src/mlpack/bindings/python/CMakeLists.txt. You can find in patch-file.
br
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kolbma' date='2019-04-05T21:11:32Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kolbma&gt;@kolbma&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for the report.  Have you tried against the git master branch?  There were some fixes for this in the time past.  I understand the report and you are right that at least in 3.0.4 the problem exists exactly as you describe it.  However, newer versions use  as a script that's called directly at install time, and I think this may not have the problem you described.  Can you give it a shot and let us know if the problem is still there?  Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='kolbma' date='2019-04-07T10:02:04Z'>
		
Can you give it a shot and let us know if the problem is still there? Thanks!

Ok. I'll have a look in the next days...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='kolbma' date='2019-05-07T10:53:20Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>