<bug id='1863' author='gmanlan' open_date='2019-04-15T22:28:45Z' closed_time='2019-09-17T16:05:37Z'>
	<summary>mlpack_test.exe fails for some tests when running on Windows [3.1.1 release]</summary>
	<description>
When building mlpack x64 from source, some tests fail when executed in a local Windows 10 system. These errors are diverse so if required, we can split them into different submissions.
Build configuration:

mlpack 3.1.1 release or master branch
Boost 1_65_1 (lib64-msvc-14.1)
armadillo-9.300.2
OpenBLAS built using msvc - branch develop (April 2019)
Visual Studio 15 2017 Win64
x64

Tests Errors:


unknown location(0): fatal error: in "ConvolutionalNetworkTest/VanillaNetworkTest": memory access violation
Possible workaround: manually unzip the .arm dataset from mnist_first250_training_4s_and_9s.tar, then the test will pass


unknown location(0): fatal error: in "LoadSaveTest/CaseTest": class std::runtime_error: Parse error at line 13 token 0: "TA".
Context: this is trying to parse the file casecheck.arff


parallel_sgd_test.cpp(100): fatal error: in "ParallelSGDTest/GeneralizedRosenbrockTest": absolute value of result{-nan(ind)} exceeds 1e-08


unknown location(0): fatal error: in "SdpPrimalDualTest/SmallLovaszThetaSdp": memory access violation occurred at address 0xfcfc4000, while attempting to  write to an inaccessible (or protected) address. sdp_primal_dual_test.cpp(278): last checkpoint: "SmallLovaszThetaSdp" test entry


input stream error tests/serialization.hpp(235): fatal error: in "SerializationTest/LayerNormSerializationTest": critical check success == true has failed [false != true]


main_tests/decision_tree_test.cpp(103): fatal error: in "DecisionTreeMainTest/DecisionTreeCategoricalOutputDimensionTest": Cannot load train dataset braziltourism.arff!


I made an effort to go over open/closed issues and although I found some references, I couldn't find exact matches with these errors. If somebody has seen some of this issues before, please link them here.
I have also checked one of the last AppVeyor builds and the tests seem to be passing fine, so I'm trying to understand if these failures are because:

Something is wrong with my local system?
Boost version? (AppVeyor build script is using 1.60)
Armadillo version? (AppVeyor build script is using 7.800.2)
Visual Studio version? (for some reason AppVeyor build script is using Visual Studio 14 2015 Win64 for both the Jobs? If so, the VS2017 job is useless?)

Thanks
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gmanlan' date='2019-05-09T03:51:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gmanlan&gt;@gmanlan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , did u reproduce the issue with 3.1.0 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gmanlan' date='2019-05-16T01:25:42Z'>
		I have tried again using the master-branch and I got the "VanillaNetworkTest: memory access violation" error again - which I can workaround by unzipping the dataset (although the error description doesn't make sense). Then I get the following errors:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Running 1607 test cases...
[FATAL] Cannot open file 'nonexistentfile.arff'.

unknown location(0): fatal error: in "RBMNetworkTest/BinaryRBMClassificationTest": integer divide by zero
C:\mlpack\src\mlpack\tests\rbm_network_test.cpp(42): last checkpoint: "BinaryRBMClassificationTest" test entry
unknown location(0): fatal error: in "RBMNetworkTest/ssRBMClassificationTest": integer divide by zero
C:\mlpack\src\mlpack\tests\rbm_network_test.cpp(127): last checkpoint: "ssRBMClassificationTest" test entry

*** 2 failures are detected in the test module "mlpackTest"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gmanlan' date='2019-08-01T23:25:46Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gmanlan' date='2019-08-07T03:02:29Z'>
		Sorry for the slow response---I know that [FATAL] Cannot open file 'nonexistentfile.arff'. is actually not a problem: the tests check that that file doesn't exist.
But the RBM tests are a bit more problematic.  However, I haven't seen this problem.  On my Windows VM (which ended up being Windows 7 just because that happened to get set up ok...) I have the following versions of packages:

Armadillo 9.600-RC3
Boost 1.70.0
OpenBLAS 0.2.14.1
Visual Studio Community 2019, version 16.1.6

Of those I would expect the only two to make a difference would be Armadillo and possibly the Visual Studio version.  The output I get for the RBM tests when I build the "RUN_TESTS" target is that they pass in ~15 seconds; no integer divide by zero issue or anything.
If AppVeyor is not successfully building on Visual Studio 2017, we should definitely get that fixed for sure.  I think I see the issue: the build_script section uses Visual Studio 14 2015 Win64 hardcoded, but it should actually be using the VSVER variable.  I'm not sure exactly how that works in the AppVeyor config, but I'll see if I can find a minute to put into it in the near-term future.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='gmanlan' date='2019-08-11T15:03:17Z'>
		I opened &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/1971&gt;#1971&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to handle the Visual Studio version issues, so now AppVeyor will build mlpack on VS2015, VS2017, and VS2019.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='gmanlan' date='2019-09-10T15:05:33Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>