<bug id='1967' author='AjitDingankar' open_date='2019-08-02T23:32:06Z' closed_time='2019-09-09T04:05:34Z'>
	<summary>Can't run mlpack executables on CentOS 7</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Get error "undefined symbol" when I try to run any mlpack executable
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Your environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


version of mlpack: 3.1.1
operating system: CentOS 7.6
compiler: gcc 4.8.5
version of dependencies (Boost/Armadillo): Boost 1.53.0 Armadillo 8.300.0
any other environment information you think is relevant:
export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/usr/local/lib/

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Build 3.1.1 and sudo make install
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Executable runs
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Actual behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


(base) ~$ mlpack_knn --version
mlpack_knn: symbol lookup error: mlpack_knn: undefined symbol: _ZN6mlpack4util10ProgramDocC1ERKSsS3_RKSt8functionIFSsvEERKSt6vectorISt4pairISsSsESaISB_EE
(base) ~$ which mlpack_knn
/usr/local/bin/mlpack_knn

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Related issues&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1966#issue-476315270&gt;#1966 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AjitDingankar' date='2019-08-03T00:08:52Z'>
		Tried the work-around/debug step suggested in:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/1760#issuecomment-469839621&gt;#1760 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

by pointing LD_LIBRARY_PATH to the lib subdirectory under the build directory.
Now the executable works!
How do I debug why sudo make install did not put the libmlpack* files under /usr/local/lib since I closed terminal where I built it?

Note: I also had the same error for importing in Python, but that was fixed with the above and
setting PYTHONPATH to /usr/local/lib/python3.7/site-packages as suggested in:
#1760 (comment)

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AjitDingankar' date='2019-08-03T01:49:51Z'>
		Wow, very odd that sudo make install did not put it in /usr/local/lib.  Is it possible that it put it in /usr/local/lib64 by any chance?  I've not used to RHEL conventions (I am a Debian user primarily) but I know that some things end up in lib64 and some in lib.
Otherwise, we can figure out a bit more if you can run sudo make install again and share the output.  I've never observed CMake failing to install libmlpack.so, so my guess is that it just put it somewhere weird for some weird CMake+RHEL reason.  I am sure we can get it figured out, just need to figure out what actually happened. :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AjitDingankar' date='2019-08-03T02:10:17Z'>
		Thanks for the prompt response on Friday evening, Ryan! 😉 
Will try to find the so in some unusual suspects, but if that doesn't work, should I just install it again or remove the build and start from scratch? 
Thanks,Ajit==== 
Sent from Yahoo Mail on Android

  On Fri, Aug 2, 2019 at 6:50 PM, Ryan Curtin&lt;notifications@github.com&gt; wrote:
Wow, very odd that sudo make install did not put it in /usr/local/lib. Is it possible that it put it in /usr/local/lib64 by any chance? I've not used to RHEL conventions (I am a Debian user primarily) but I know that some things end up in lib64 and some in lib.

Otherwise, we can figure out a bit more if you can run sudo make install again and share the output. I've never observed CMake failing to install libmlpack.so, so my guess is that it just put it somewhere weird for some weird CMake+RHEL reason. I am sure we can get it figured out, just need to figure out what actually happened. :)

—
You are receiving this because you authored the thread.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub, or mute the thread.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='AjitDingankar' date='2019-08-03T02:12:55Z'>
		Installing again is just fine---it'll just install all the files to the same place, so nothing on the system except the modification times of the mlpack files should change. :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='AjitDingankar' date='2019-09-02T03:05:31Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>