<bug id='2161' author='zsogitbe' open_date='2020-01-27T09:27:09Z' closed_time='2020-03-20T00:09:17Z'>
	<summary>LayerTypes design problem</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Issue description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The default BOOST mpl list size is 20! LayerTypes is much longer already! Even the introduction of MoreTypes is not sufficient for solving this issue! Furthermore CustomLayers (template argument) adds to this list even more items. This could cause compiler errors and crashes.
Perhaps this part of the code needs to be redesigned.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Your environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

MSVC
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zsogitbe' date='2020-01-27T21:05:36Z'>
		I guess you already use the latest compiler? When I try to reproduce the issue, I try to use the same compiler as you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zsogitbe' date='2020-01-28T07:42:41Z'>
		I use the latest version of MVS 2017. There is already a MVS 2019 which is newer. I do think however that this problem is only effected by the compiler in how the compilation ends. I guess that there will be some compilers which show an error and some which crash with e.g. a heap is full message. Strangely BOOST is using more list items than there are in LayerTypes, therefore if you decide to cut this in peaces then I think that you need to cut it in smaller peaces than the set BOOST mpl list size. I think that this is the problem.
Maybe you can wait with investing time in this until other people also have the same issue. I have solved the problem by increasing the BOOST mpl list size manually (compiler parameter + new files in boost) which is not an option for you since you do not want that everybody has to change the BOOST installation manually.
The only thing I do not understand is why I did not have this problem before MoreTypes is introduced.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zsogitbe' date='2020-03-01T16:44:09Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>