<bug id='230' author='rcurtin' open_date='2014-12-29T12:02:56Z' closed_time='2019-02-25T20:26:22Z'>
	<summary>Use log-space for DTree::ComputeVariableImportance()</summary>
	<description>
Reported by rcurtin on 20 Aug 42587487 19:11 UTC
It used to be that the density estimation tree would use long doubles, because a lot of the calculations depended on the volume of hypercubes, which in very high dimensions become very, very large.  The solution to this is to use the logarithm of the volume, but then we end up with situations where we need
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;log(a + b)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

but we only have log(a) and log(b).  Fortunately algebraic tricks can be used for the actual tree construction algorithms by exploiting the definitions of a and b (or as they actually are in the code, the definition of the error function R(t)).  So the tree construction is done nearly entirely in log-space (with one exception; the volume of one node divided by a leaf (V_t / V_i) can't be done in log-space (or I could not figure out how), but in that case it is not a huge problem because the quantity V_t / V_i turns out to be dependent mostly on the depth of the tree, and will probably only overflow for very, very deep trees (and other things will probably fail before that).
However there is still one function which needs to be addressed, which is DTree::ComputeVariableImportance().
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;// The way to do this entirely in log-space is (at this time) somewhat
// unclear.  So this risks overflow.
importances[curNode.SplitDim()] += (-std::exp(curNode.LogNegError()) -
    (-std::exp(curNode.Left()-&gt;LogNegError()) +
     -std::exp(curNode.Right()-&gt;LogNegError())));
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

There should be a way to exploit the definition of the variable importance as described in Pari's paper such that we can calculate the quantity (R(t) - R(t_l) - R(t_r)) in log-space.
Migrated-From: &lt;denchmark-link:http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/237&gt;http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/237&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rcurtin' date='2019-02-18T19:58:18Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>