<bug id='2393' author='bisakhmondal' open_date='2020-05-03T07:46:03Z' closed_time='2020-05-05T00:25:23Z'>
	<summary>Possible bug for GMMTest</summary>
	<description>
I am facing a strange issue every time while running the  executable (complete module), an error from GMMTest (test for the Gaussian Mixture Model) suite is getting popped up.
But this is not the case when I am running the test cases for GMMTest suite only. The test case  involves dealing with random numbers. This may be the cause, but not sure why it's working in solo execution.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/41498427/80908232-e99a1e80-8d3b-11ea-9cc8-2bc277968866.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

**Not sure if the problem is specifically happening only to my system after the latest build. But it's happening each and every time.
As a solution maybe we can increase the percentage tolerance from 10% to say 12 or 13%, or maybe that's not required at all as the tests for the PRs are passing.



mlpack/src/mlpack/tests/gmm_test.cpp


        Lines 1034 to 1038
      in
      c3fb2eb






 



 for (size_t i = 0; i &lt; 3; i++) 



 BOOST_REQUIRE_CLOSE(g.Component(sortedIndices[0]).Mean()[i], 



       d1.Mean()[i], 10.0); 



 





	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T07:51:37Z'>
		Hey, Does this occur on master branch?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T07:56:37Z'>
		Let me check. This is the build, before the final push of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/2268&gt;#2268&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T07:59:43Z'>
		
Let me check. This is the build, before the final push of #2268.

My master is the same as the one you mentioned. I ran the test a couple of hours back, No test failed. The branch is the same as the branch in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/2387&gt;#2387&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T08:59:01Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bisakhmondal&gt;@bisakhmondal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kartikdutt18&gt;@kartikdutt18&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the reporting and checks, and it's understandable as the test is stochastic. I remember each  test went through about more than 3,000 trials and passed with the random seed (). Despite those efforts, it seems to be failed sometimes.
I think your solution works and would it be better to make the 3 diagonal distributions far more distinguishable each other than now including your solution?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T09:14:00Z'>
		Hey &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/KimSangYeon-DGU&gt;@KimSangYeon-DGU&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for the input. I'll try one thing, I will run the  like a 1000 times and see if it fails. Mainly because I haven't gotten it to fail on my machine yet in a couple of runs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T09:17:32Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kartikdutt18&gt;@kartikdutt18&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for letting me know and I appreciate your checks. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bisakhmondal&gt;@bisakhmondal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 After increasing the tolerance by the value you mentioned ( or %), was the test passed on your machine?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T11:44:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kartikdutt18&gt;@kartikdutt18&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yep I have run the build on the master branch. Still it's failing. As a reference
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/41498427/80913255-e9f8e080-8d60-11ea-9ccd-96746afd8679.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/KimSangYeon-DGU&gt;@KimSangYeon-DGU&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 after increasing the tolerance to  it's working fine now.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/41498427/80913325-74414480-8d61-11ea-9ffd-5fe18bf63d58.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Thanks guys.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T11:50:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bisakhmondal&gt;@bisakhmondal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Can you open a PR?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T11:51:49Z'>
		Ya Sure.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:11:15Z'>
		So I ran this :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;for i in {1..1000}
do sudo ./bin/mlpack_test -t GMMTest;
done;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I didn't get any error in 1000 iterations. I am using OSX. As far as I can tell azure pipeline also isn't showing any failure. I don't mind increasing the tolerance but I am unable to reproduce this issue.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bisakhmondal&gt;@bisakhmondal&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you mind sharing your OS details. Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:18:07Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kartikdutt18&gt;@kartikdutt18&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, magically  this works fine in my system too :)) as I said in the issue description. The issue arises while running the complete test modules.
Sure, I am using Ubuntu 19.10 eoan release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:19:25Z'>
		Hmm, Let me change that. If that's the case that's definitely strange. Let do 5 iterations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:20:20Z'>
		


Exactly. Very strange.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:26:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kartikdutt18&gt;@kartikdutt18&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 When running tests, did you  put the code  on the top of the test by any chance? I mean right under .
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:30:50Z'>
		
did you put the code mlpack::math::RandomSeed(std::time(NULL)) on the top of the test by any chance?

Ahh, I didn't, I just rebased my master and ran the above command. Currently I am running this :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;for i in {1..5}
do sudo ./bin/mlpack_test;
done;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Did I miss something?
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:32:41Z'>
		In a 5 runs, the test still doesn't fail on OSX, maybe it's only associated with linux?
// Will update with the rest of the iterations in roughly an hour.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:38:40Z'>
		Ok, if we run one test many times and don't set the seed to random, the test will use the same seed in stochatic test, so it resulted in duplication of value. You're correct to use loop as a shell command, but in this case, we should add the random seed as well.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='bisakhmondal' date='2020-05-03T12:40:34Z'>
		
Ok, if we run one test many times and don't set the seed to random, the test will use the same seed in stochatic test, so it resulted in duplication

Ahh, sorry I missed that. That makes sense. Let me make the changes.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>