<bug id='2749' author='gscarella' open_date='2020-12-03T13:56:34Z' closed_time='2021-01-21T17:12:59Z'>
	<summary>Problem with LARS when successive calls</summary>
	<description>
Hello,
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Issue description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I have a problem with LARS when I make several successive solutions with it, in Lasso computations (for an Active Set method).
One solution never ends and causes a memory leak (which is annoying) while the problem doesn't seem to be degenerated.
It seems there happens a problem of numerical precision in LARS::Train, it gets stuck in the main loop.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;My environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


mlpack version: 3.4.2
armadillo  version:  9.900.4
boost   version: 1.74.0
The problem was encountered on Linux (Ubuntu 20 and CentOS 7).

I join an example with a data file.
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

In the example, code should terminate and print "Computation completed"
&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Actual behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

In the example, execution gets stuck and raises a memory leak at Neuron 7, iteration 3
Do you  know a way to solve the problem ?
Thanks
G. Scarella
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/5636443/test_lars.cpp.txt&gt;test_lars.cpp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/files/5636435/data_field.bin.txt&gt;data_field.bin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gscarella' date='2020-12-06T01:41:57Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gscarella&gt;@gscarella&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you so much for the clear, easy-to-reproduce example.  I can indeed see that for some reason LARS is not converging in this case, but the reason is not trivially obvious to me yet.  As I find time I will try to dig to the bottom of what is wrong.   As a workaround, I am not sure if it will work, but you could try changing the  parameter, or changing the value of , for instance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gscarella' date='2020-12-07T13:53:00Z'>
		Hello,
I tried with useCholesky set to false but the problem remains.
To be more clear: at line 22 in test_lars.cpp, when the loop goes from Neuron 4 to 9 (= the last Neuron), computation completes but when the loop goes from neuron 0 to 9 as in the attachment, it doesn't work and gets stuck at Neuron 7.
Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gscarella' date='2020-12-13T22:33:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gscarella&gt;@gscarella&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this was a very strange edge case that took a while to dig to the bottom of, but I think that I have solved it.  Can you try the fix in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/2767&gt;#2767&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and see if this solves your problem completely?  The test case you gave now does complete successfully, but I haven't verified the results in any other way (the change still passes all the other LARS tests we have). 
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='gscarella' date='2020-12-15T15:17:54Z'>
		Thanks a lot &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rcurtin&gt;@rcurtin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  for the fix!
So the example in the bug report works for me too now.
But I have a large number of other examples to test with Lars solver, it may take me several days to check that everything is ok.
I will report it if a problem is found.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='gscarella' date='2020-12-15T15:28:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gscarella&gt;@gscarella&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sounds good.  I'll merge the LARS fix shortly, and then we can keep this issue open in case you find some other issue. 
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='gscarella' date='2021-01-14T16:12:56Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had any recent activity.  It will be closed in 7 days if no further activity occurs.  Thank you for your contributions! 👍
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>