<bug id='351' author='rcurtin' open_date='2014-12-29T15:45:50Z' closed_time='2016-06-05T19:20:51Z'>
	<summary>visual studio compilation failure in x_tree_split.hpp</summary>
	<description>
Reported by rcurtin on 1 Feb 44732972 09:46 UTC
Reported in IRC:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;15:47 &lt; SinisterMJ&gt; Funny enough, the latest trunk has another compilation error with VS. Error 23:error C2864: 'mlpack::tree::XTreeSplit&lt;DescentType,StatisticType,MatType&gt;::MAX_OVERLAP' : only static const integral data members can be initialized within a                   class:\mlpack\src\mlpack\core\tree\rectangle_tree\x_tree_split.hpp:33
15:49 &lt; SinisterMJ&gt; This error doesn't touch me, and I fixed it for me by making it non-static, but still fyi
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Making the variable non-static does not work with gcc (and presumably clang), though.  I don't have a chance to look into this right now, but I think the solution may simply be a bit of refactoring or some other simple change.
Migrated-From: &lt;denchmark-link:http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/369&gt;http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/369&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rcurtin' date='2014-12-30T08:34:10Z'>
		Commented by rcurtin on 29 Jul 44733417 14:32 UTC
r17188 is a temporary workaround for the issue.  I think that allowing the user to specify the maximum overlap is good, but maybe it is better accomplished by holding a non-static member in the XTreeSplit and making the splitting methods non-static.  This will require the RectangleTree to be able to work with non-static splitting techniques though, which may take a decent amount of refactoring.  Another solution may be to add a template parameter to XTreeSplit that specifies the maximum overlap, but this will be a little difficult because floating-point values are not allowed a template parameters.  So it would be necessary to come up with some other integer-based encoding for the maximum overlap, or something like that.  Once a better solution is in place, this ticket can be resolved.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rcurtin' date='2016-06-05T19:20:51Z'>
		No longer occurs since Mikhail rewrote the X tree and fixed it.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>