<bug id='357' author='rcurtin' open_date='2014-12-29T15:52:52Z' closed_time='2016-09-15T15:25:28Z'>
	<summary>CoverTreeAlternateMetricTest occasionally fails</summary>
	<description>
Reported by rcurtin on 3 Jul 44936970 22:22 UTC
Now and then, TreeTest/CoverTreeAlternateMetricTest fails.  I doubt that this bug will be easy or fun.  To reproduce:

Modify CoverTreeAlternateMetricTest in src/mlpack/tests/tree_test.cpp, adding the following lines to the beginning of the test:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;size_t seed = std::time(NULL);
math::RandomSeed(seed);
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


Compile and run the test until you get a failure:

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ while(true); do bin/mlpack_test -t TreeTest/CoverTreeAlternateMetricTest; sleep 1; done
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;


When it fails, the random seed will have been printed.  So then you can modify your code and hardcode the seed.

The failure is that two points at the same level in the tree do not satisfy the separation invariant.  It will be difficult to track down the exact reasons that allowed those two points to be nodes in the tree with the same scale.  It may be worth trying to reduce the random dataset to only include the points that cause the failure (which will be difficult), using a much much smaller random dataset (which will be easy but may take much longer to generate a failure, if at all), or seeing if the same dataset causes the same error in John Langford's original code.
Since this will be particularly complex and it doesn't seem to be a problem that arises in most situations (and also that it doesn't actually affect the runtime results), I'm going to release 1.0.11 with this bug present and it can be fixed later.
Migrated-From: &lt;denchmark-link:http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/375&gt;http://trac.research.cc.gatech.edu/fastlab/ticket/375&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rcurtin' date='2016-09-15T15:25:28Z'>
		It turns out there is no need to check the separation invariant.  In the long version of the cover tree paper (&lt;denchmark-link:https://hunch.net/~jl/projects/cover_tree/paper/paper.pdf&gt;https://hunch.net/~jl/projects/cover_tree/paper/paper.pdf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), they write that for implementation they take a few shortcuts, including:

We relax the separation invariant in batch construction.

So, since the mlpack cover tree code is based heavily on the original cover tree code, the separation invariant is also relaxed in mlpack, and there is no need to test for it.  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/3f5503bfe71dbbda4b4551c9cdfaba8b819565ad&gt;3f5503b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 removes the test and fixes the issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>