<bug id='482' author='theSundayProgrammer' open_date='2015-11-22T23:52:31Z' closed_time='2015-11-23T13:29:39Z'>
	<summary>Serialization Test Fails on Windows</summary>
	<description>
This issue is similar to the load-save-test issue I raised earlier. But this time the error is in the test routine. Consider the following code from serial_test.cpp:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;template&lt;typename MatType,
         typename IArchiveType,
         typename OArchiveType&gt;
void TestArmadilloSerialization(MatType&amp; x)
{
  // First save it.
  ofstream ofs("test");
  OArchiveType o(ofs);
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

If the (I/0)ArchiveType is binary then the test fails due to the two character CR-LF eol marker. There are two options: one is to open the file as binary always; the other is partial function template specialization or something like that. I tried some tests using ios::binary and they seem to pass. But I am not sure about the general repercussions of opening a text file as binary.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='theSundayProgrammer' date='2015-11-23T13:29:39Z'>
		This is definitely related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/468&gt;#468&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
; I think it's actually the same issue, so I'll close this and comment there.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='theSundayProgrammer' date='2015-11-23T21:23:17Z'>
		This is not a duplicate. In &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/issues/468&gt;#468&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 there was nothing to do in mlpack. Here you know you are opening a binary file and yet you are not providing the ios::binary flag. Hence boost::serialization fails. My suggestion is to always provide the binary flag. If I do that in serial_test.cpp then all tests pass except DET Test.  Does that test pass on Linux/Unix?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='theSundayProgrammer' date='2015-11-24T00:12:51Z'>
		I did a full rebuild and the test now passes
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='theSundayProgrammer' date='2015-11-24T18:55:54Z'>
		You're right, this isn't a duplicate.  Sorry about that.  I tested your commit and merged it in (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/c265e575099a7c1231c380c9de0f3320a892f1f4&gt;c265e57&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
).  I also made it so that when  loads models on Windows that are binary ( / ), binary mode is used (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/4ce2fc6557b8f05b871826d5aaf34013af6f2f8c&gt;4ce2fc6&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
).  All the tests pass on Linux, with the exception of DETTest, which is another bug I haven't managed to completely reproduce and fix (but that's outside the scope of this, and I'm hoping to devote a bit of time to that later today).
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='theSundayProgrammer' date='2015-11-25T18:56:40Z'>
		I ran  the test on Visual Studio with Boost Test Plugin. The DET test now
passes on my box. Even earlier if I create a separate test project with
only DET Test then it succeeds.
It could be because multiple tests are being run concurrently.
On Wed, Nov 25, 2015 at 5:55 AM, Ryan Curtin &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

wrote:

You're right, this isn't a duplicate. Sorry about that. I tested your
commit and merged it in (c265e57
c265e57).
I also made it so that when data::Load() loads models on Windows that are
binary (boost::archive::binary_iarchive / boost::archive::binary_oarchive),
binary mode is used (4ce2fc6
4ce2fc6).
All the tests pass on Linux, with the exception of DETTest, which is
another bug I haven't managed to completely reproduce and fix (but that's
outside the scope of this, and I'm hoping to devote a bit of time to that
later today).
—
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
#482 (comment).

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Joseph Chakravarti Mariadassou
&lt;denchmark-link:http://thesundayprogrammer.com&gt;http://thesundayprogrammer.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>