<bug id='507' author='Fractally' open_date='2016-01-27T11:42:29Z' closed_time='2016-01-27T17:10:29Z'>
	<summary>CMake issue with mlpack on Ubuntu</summary>
	<description>
Hey guys,
I am using the cmake gui to configure cmake. I have compiled Armadillo to use with mlpack. Armadillo found the following (cmake output):

MKL_FOUND = YES
ACMLMP_FOUND = NO
ACML_FOUND = NO
OpenBLAS_FOUND = YES
ATLAS_FOUND = NO
BLAS_FOUND = YES
LAPACK_FOUND = YES

When I ran cmake in my mlpack build directory, I get the following error:

ARMA_USE_WRAPPER is not defined, so all dependencies of Armadillo must be manually linked.
Using MKL for LAPACK/BLAS: /usr/lib/liblapack.so;/opt/intel/mkl/lib/intel64/libmkl_intel_thread.so;/opt/intel/mkl/lib/intel64/libmkl_core.so;/opt/intel/mkl/lib/intel64/libmkl_rt.so;/opt/intel/lib/intel64/libiomp5.so;/opt/intel/mkl/lib/intel64/libmkl_intel_lp64.so
CMake Error at CMake/FindArmadillo.cmake:196 (message):
Cannot find LAPACK library, but ARMA_USE_LAPACK is set.  Try specifying
LAPACK libraries manually by setting the LAPACK_LIBRARY variable.
Call Stack (most recent call first):
CMakeLists.txt:113 (find_package)

I have tried to add the following entry to the mlpack cmake (with no luck):

LAPACK_LIBRARY = /usr/lib/liblapack.so

I have noticed that the field mkl_lapack_LIBRARY is empty in cmake. I also tried adding the path /usr/lib/liblapack.so to it with no luck. Any ideas?
Thanks!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Fractally' date='2016-01-27T15:35:45Z'>
		Hi there,
I think that I have fixed this in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/a7a05d8fe4f5dcf6c98e80582689e0f645941c95&gt;a7a05d8&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
; the issue was, essentially, a typo in the CMake configuration scripts.  But I don't have a system with working MKL to test on; can you update to the latest git master and see if that fixes your issue?
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Fractally' date='2016-01-27T17:10:29Z'>
		Thanks for the reply. I downloaded the latest version from github and the issue seems to have been resolved. I could configure and generate using cmake. I have tried compiling, but now have a load of undefined references to mkl_lapack_xxx, mkl_blas_xxx and mkl_iss_xxx. I guess the linking with MKL is incorrect. Will have to investigate. Closing this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>