<bug id='508' author='planetmarshall' open_date='2016-01-27T12:51:14Z' closed_time='2016-06-05T19:20:01Z'>
	<summary>CMake Generated Visual Studio 2013 project fails to build</summary>
	<description>
CMake generated Visual Studio 2013 project requires support for 'constexpr', which is not supported by the Visual Studio 2013 C++ compiler (VC12). See
&lt;denchmark-link:https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh567368.aspx&gt;https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/hh567368.aspx&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-01-27T15:28:26Z'>
		This is true.  Visual Studio compilers have been... difficult to work with, and have been slower than gcc or clang in implementing C++11 support.  So unfortunately you'll need to use VS2015 or newer.
Did CMake issue an error while configuring, or did this happen when you tried to compile?  It sounds like I should modify CXX11.cmake to only detect a working compiler when VC14 or newer is being used.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-02-07T22:14:21Z'>
		Please update your vc2013 with &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=41151&gt;vc2013 ctp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, maybe you would be able to compile mlpack after you install this package(atleast it support constexpr)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-02-19T10:53:30Z'>
		Bad news, even with &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=41151&gt;vc2013 ctp&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, vc2013 still can not compile mlpack
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-03-02T22:36:42Z'>
		It looks like the right thing to do here is disable support for any Visual Studio version older than 2015; this is a straightforward task for someone who wants to start contributing.  See the file CMake/CXX11.cmake.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-03-03T02:30:51Z'>
		It looked pretty straightforward so I went ahead and made the changes and opened a pull-request !
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/pull/543&gt;#543&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='planetmarshall' date='2016-06-05T19:20:01Z'>
		Two changes should fix this for good: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/935e76dd53ca6a4b905ad241b45cd8e12a3ef796&gt;935e76d&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which causes configuration to fail for Visual Studio 2013 since VS2013 will not compile mlpack, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/20f8bc08afb6f4a445d07dc95896625fde552507&gt;20f8bc0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, which, when available, uses the newer  command from CMake to check if a compiler supports the C++11 features we need, which is a better solution in the end.  So now CMake will tell you if the compiler you are using cannot build mlpack.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>