<bug id='598' author='ghost(ghost)' open_date='2016-03-29T09:51:47Z' closed_time='2016-04-13T01:36:31Z'>
	<summary>a strange warnning when running cf</summary>
	<description>
./mlpack_cf -t train.csv --output_file model.csv
[WARN ] Number of random columns (columnsToAverage) is more than the number of columns available in the V matrix; weird results may ensue!
the train.csv is:
0,1,4
1,0,5
1,1,1
2,0,2
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2016-04-04T17:40:55Z'>
		This warning will be issued whenever the data matrix has fewer than five points, because the matrix decomposition is (by default) initialized using 5 random columns of the training data.  With any larger data matrix this will not be a problem.  In your case I am guessing that you are just testing the program, so I would not worry about the warning.  If you are getting weird results like the warning suggests, maybe adding a couple more points to your dataset would be useful.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2016-04-06T10:07:20Z'>
		thx， I‘ve found the reason made this warn, and another little stuff:
./mlpack_det
terminate called after throwing an instance of 'std::runtime_error'
what():  fatal error; see Log::Fatal output
Aborted (core dumped)
If No arguments applied, I think help info should be show, boost::program_options support this util
, cause Aborted is not very friendly :)
In mlpack 1.0.x , no aborted info ：）， but in 2.x,  src/mlpack/core/util/cli.cpp has changed in
void CLI::ParseCommandLine(int argc, char** line)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2016-04-12T15:10:54Z'>
		Are you sure it's displaying nothing at all?  It should be displaying an error too, not just the exception.  Here is what I get on my system (compiled without debugging symbols):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ bin/mlpack_det
[FATAL] Neither --training_file (-t) nor --input_model_file (-m) are specified!

terminate called after throwing an instance of 'std::runtime_error'
  what():  fatal error; see Log::Fatal output
Aborted
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

There was an issue with this output when compiled with debugging symbols, which I fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/78f53daf5a91e221432c93ea43fbdc9de2ec2f15&gt;78f53da&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.  Do you want to update to the latest git master revision and see what you get as output?  Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2016-04-13T01:37:01Z'>
		thanks, fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/78f53daf5a91e221432c93ea43fbdc9de2ec2f15&gt;78f53da&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>