<bug id='911' author='dongli' open_date='2017-03-03T23:33:48Z' closed_time='2017-03-06T02:14:04Z'>
	<summary>DistributionTest/GammaDistributionFittingTest failed</summary>
	<description>
I built mlpack 2.1.1 on macOS 10.12.3 with clang-800.0.42.1. mlpack is built successfully, but when test it failed:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;mlpack-2.1.1/src/mlpack/tests/distribution_test.cpp:481: fatal error: in "DistributionTest/GammaDistributionFittingTest": difference{0.11739} between gDist.Beta(0){1.6760847564140695} and betaReal{1.5} exceeds 10%
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dongli' date='2017-03-04T11:08:19Z'>
		Hi Dong,
This is probably a random error. Some times the fitting does not converge to the right number.
Can you try running the test again? We might need to loosen the tolerance a little more...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dongli' date='2017-03-04T12:39:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mentekid&gt;@mentekid&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have tried several times with no luck.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dongli' date='2017-03-04T20:04:15Z'>
		Can you confirm that you rebuild the test every time or used another seed for every run something by using something like:
math::RandomSeed((size_t) std::time(NULL));
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dongli' date='2017-03-06T02:14:04Z'>
		Hey Li,
Sorry about this.  I actually ended up fixing this 5 days after 2.1.1 was released but since there has not been a new version released yet, there is not a new version for you to update to.  Like &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mentekid&gt;@mentekid&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 said, this was a random failure caused by variance in the tests.  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mlpack/mlpack/commit/0b5d5f1c945c2ddecce7eec0d0453de543cfe34e&gt;0b5d5f1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 was the commit that reduced the variance in the tests.
2.2.0 will be released soon (I hope this week, or really, I hope tomorrow, since it doesn't look like it'll happen today...) and this will take care of the issue.  Random test failures are hard to keep down with probabilistic tests...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='dongli' date='2017-03-06T02:14:53Z'>
		I should also add, there is nothing wrong with the Gamma distribution code in 2.1.1, this was just an issue where the test had too much variance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='dongli' date='2017-03-09T06:26:23Z'>
		Thanks, I will wait for the new version!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>