<bug id='102' author='qixuxiang' open_date='2018-07-26T04:20:52Z' closed_time='2018-07-27T01:30:15Z'>
	<summary>issue about docker</summary>
	<description>
Thanks for your awesome codeshare!
I am new to docker and I do not know how to use dockerfile.
When I run the command
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;docker image build .
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I check docker images and find a image whose container id and image id is none, maybe it is the docker images I need. But I can not docker run the images.
So what should do to use it? Thanks a lot!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='qixuxiang' date='2018-07-26T22:21:32Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/qixuxiang&gt;@qixuxiang&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. If the  is  then something likely went wrong although I've never seen that before. Just to check: Are you referring to  and  as being  after you ran the command: ? If this is what it looks like
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291311-f890f5de-90fe-11e8-88b7-dd0a53e22615.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

then it's an easy fix. You can rename images that you've created by running the command: docker tag &lt;IMAGE ID&gt; &lt;NAME_THAT_YOU_WANT&gt;. To run a container from that image and get a terminal inside, simply do docker run -it &lt;IMAGE_NAME&gt; bash.
If that wasn't the case, it'd be useful to see a screenshot of what you're saying to further help with this. There is something weird going on with docker pull hqkhan/bindsnet therefore unless you weren't doing so already, I'd suggest you clone the repo and work from there. I will provide a step by step way of working with bindsnet through a docker container below:

Clone repo using git clone https://github.com/Hananel-Hazan/bindsnet

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291085-311ca368-90fe-11e8-9dab-f0836c54b99e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Go into newly cloned directory by cd bindsnet and run docker image build .

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291148-7944f186-90fe-11e8-92fd-73f559d06e92.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It should be downloading relevant packages. Once its done it should look like this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291302-f09354bc-90fe-11e8-9197-7f3ca467e83a.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Rename the image by issuing
docker tag 0bc51f9781d0 bindsnet
Note: Your IMAGE ID will be different than mine. bindsnet can be whatever you want it to be.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291454-8681aeba-90ff-11e8-8cea-0ad9267dd802.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Create a container off of bindsnet image and obtain a bash terminal inside by issuing
docker run -it bindsnet bash
Note: if your image name was not bindsnet, use your own image name there.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/22674069/43291565-e7234bb6-90ff-11e8-8911-047e06795d1d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

After that, simply run python and test if bindsnet is working.
I hope this helps. Let me know if there's anything else that I can help with.
P.s : docker-compose capabilities coming later to allow for mounting volumes and running jupyter notebooks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='qixuxiang' date='2018-07-27T01:30:11Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hqkhan&gt;@hqkhan&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Thanks for your elaborative answer! This is the most careful answer I have ever seen in github, you are a true life saver!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='qixuxiang' date='2018-07-27T02:05:58Z'>
		Happy to help!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>