<bug id='1343' author='JulienMaille' open_date='2020-07-15T18:28:15Z' closed_time='2020-08-17T12:50:27Z'>
	<summary>Files that need to be redistributed (Windows)</summary>
	<description>
I'm using OpenVino through OpenCV and was wondering what these files are for and if they need to be redistributed on Windows platform:

cache.json
pcie-ma248x.elf
usb-ma2x8x.mvcmd
usb-ma2450.mvcmd

Thanks a lot
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-07-15T21:41:48Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/JulienMaille&gt;@JulienMaille&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The pcie-ma248x.elf, usb-ma2x8x.mvcmd and usb-ma2450.mvcmd files are the firmware for Myriad devices. You shouldn't need to redistribute these files if you are not using the MYRIAD Plugin.
Have you taken a look at the &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.openvinotoolkit.org/latest/openvino_docs_install_guides_deployment_manager_tool.html&gt;OpenVINO Deployment Manager&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
? It's avaiable for Windows and Linux to help create a deployment package.
Regards,
Jesus
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-07-16T07:30:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jgespino&gt;@jgespino&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the link. BTW the images showing the interactive mode python script are missing (404)
I have an Intel Compute Stick 2 and can't find this option in the interactive script.
Finally the archive created by that script is a mix of release and debug with both .dll and .lib files, so this is not what I call a redistributable.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-07-16T21:25:23Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/JulienMaille&gt;@JulienMaille&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

You are correct, the Intel Neural Compute Stick 2 (VPU) is not currently available for the Windows version of the Deployment Manager. I will provide your feedback to update the documentation and create a feature request to add the VPU target as an option for Windows as well.
Regards,
Jesus
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-08-14T15:06:07Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/JulienMaille&gt;@JulienMaille&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Looks like VPU is actually implemented in the Deployment Manager for Windows as well. There is a bug in the configuration file that pointing to the wrong location which hides the VPU target as an option.
As a quick workaround, modify the C:\Program Files (x86)\IntelSWTools\openvino\deployment_tools\tools\deployment_manager\configs\main.json file.
Change Line 57, 58, and 59 from:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/lib/intel64/Release/usb-ma2450.mvcmd",
        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/lib/intel64/Release/usb-ma2x8x.mvcmd",
        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/lib/intel64/Release/pcie-ma248x.elf",
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

To:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/bin/intel64/Release/usb-ma2450.mvcmd",
        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/bin/intel64/Release/usb-ma2x8x.mvcmd",
        "deployment_tools/inference_engine/bin/intel64/Release/pcie-ma248x.elf",
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Please give that a try and let me know if this works for you.
Regards,
Jesus
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-08-16T09:05:38Z'>
		Yes it seems to work, thank you!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-08-17T12:50:27Z'>
		Great! I will close this issue, feel free to re-open or start a new one if you have additional questions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='JulienMaille' date='2020-10-24T08:56:40Z'>
		Fixed in 2021.1
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>