<bug id='197' author='Wehrdo' open_date='2019-06-25T17:19:41Z' closed_time='2020-05-27T10:43:31Z'>
	<summary>Intel Inference Engine cpu_extension_avx2.dll Debug and Release</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; 3.4.6
Operating System / Platform =&gt; Windows 10 Pro 1809 build 17763.437 64 Bit
Compiler =&gt; Visual Studio 2017 15.8.7

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The Openvino toolkit comes with DLLs that need to be in the path for runtime loading. They are located in Program Files\IntelSWTools\openvino\inference_engine\bin\intel64\(Release/Debug), for both debug and release versions. In release 2019.1.148, the DLL cpu_extension_avx2.dll is different between the Debug and Release folders, but has the same name. Therefore if you add both the Debug and Release folders to your PATH, the wrong one might be loaded. This causes memory access violations when running.
This seems like an issue that Intel needs to fix, but I wanted to record it here so it's known.
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Build OpenCV with Intel Inference engine.
Add to path:

C:\Program Files (x86)\IntelSWTools\openvino\inference_engine\bin\intel64\Debug
C:\Program Files (x86)\IntelSWTools\openvino\inference_engine\bin\intel64\Release


Run application using DNN module in both Debug and Release mode. One of these should crash. (Whichever appears second in PATH)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Wehrdo' date='2019-07-07T08:43:31Z'>
		Avoid using of Debug/Release binaries in the same process. This is MSVC limitation (due different runtimes).

if you add both the Debug and Release folders to your PATH, the wrong one might be loaded

Don't add both. Add path corresponding to your app configuration only.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV

OpenCV uses the same paths (for installation) on Win32 with adding of d suffixes for Debug binaries.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Wehrdo' date='2019-12-17T17:02:54Z'>
		I second that request, all dlls have a different filename in debug, except for cpu_extension_avx2.dll and plugins.xml
It would be convenient to rename it to cpu_extension_avx2d.dll or cpu_extension_avx2_debug.dll
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Wehrdo' date='2020-05-27T10:43:31Z'>
		Hi,
OpenVINO doesn't contain extension libraries more. All kernels from extension libraries were moved to the CPU plugin.
I will close the ticket. Please reopen it, in case of any questions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>