<bug id='2' author='vickyhexr' open_date='2019-07-08T11:01:11Z' closed_time='2019-10-10T13:37:18Z'>
	<summary>I couldn't import Deepposekit</summary>
	<description>
Hey. I've installed all dependencies and cloned complete things. when i open the project in jupyter-lab i couldn't import deepposekit. Please help me out
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-08T19:16:38Z'>
		Can you provide more details such as the error message and what OS (Ubuntu, Windows, etc.) and python environment (Anaconda, pip, python3, etc.) you're using?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-09T12:45:36Z'>
		Hey, I am using Windows 10.
Python environment is pip.
I've  installed Keras and Tensorflow GPU as well.
Cloned deepposekit from git.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/51114027/60888935-7d62a180-a275-11e9-8f29-6fd987fec8b8.JPG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This is the error when i try to import deepposekit.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-09T13:10:18Z'>
		Hi, thanks for the details. ModuleNotFoundError means you have not installed the deepposekit package or python cannot find it in the site-packages directory. You say you "Cloned deepposekit from git", but did you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jgraving/deepposekit/blob/master/README.md#installation&gt;follow the installation instructions&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
? Alternatively you can install directly in jupyter by running:
import sys
!{sys.executable} -m pip install git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit.git git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit-annotator.git
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-09T13:15:19Z'>
		Hi, thanks for the quick reply. I think i followed the instructions completely and it didn't throw any error.  Anyways i tried it by using jupyter by using
import sys
!{sys.executable} -m pip install git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit.git git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit-annotator.git these lines. Still it has error itseems.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/51114027/60890817-b0a72f80-a279-11e9-8f7b-3071d26ce43a.JPG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-09T13:31:14Z'>
		Looks like you're using anaconda on Windows, which we don't fully support yet. It seems the Shapely dependency for imgaug cannot be installed on windows with pip. Can you try installing imgaug using conda?
conda config --add channels conda-forge
conda install imgaug
Alternatively you can try installing Shapely with pip using a pre-compiled wheel found here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/#shapely&gt;https://www.lfd.uci.edu/~gohlke/pythonlibs/#shapely&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 then run:
pip install /path/to/wheel/file.whl
and replace the path with where your wheel file is stored
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-10T05:26:17Z'>
		After installing imgaug i couldn't import deepposekit. Is there any issues with Windows?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-10T14:57:55Z'>
		We are working on a better solution for windows and anaconda. Once imgaug is installed then you should be able to install deepposekit from jupyter without any errors:

import sys
!{sys.executable} -m pip install git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit.git git+https://www.github.com/jgraving/deepposekit-annotator.git

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-11T08:18:34Z'>
		Hey buddy. I think i have a problem with shapely and imgaug. Can i use Python 3.6? I got this doubt suddenly. Do you have any requirements.txt for deepposekit?? If yes can you post it here?? Thanks in advance.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-07-11T09:28:17Z'>
		I've re-installed everything and its working now. I am able to import deepposekit now. My next question is,Can i use this library for human pose estimation?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-08-05T09:57:21Z'>
		Hi, Glad you got it working. You can use deepposekit for human pose estimation, but we do not provide any pretrained models, so you'll need to provide your own training data. I'll leave this issue open for now until we implement a better solution for your original problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-08-05T10:00:00Z'>
		Thanks for the reply, Jake.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='vickyhexr' date='2019-10-10T13:37:18Z'>
		After further research it seems this issue is specific to Anaconda on Windows. It appears the  dependency for  must be manually installed. I've updated the readme here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jgraving/DeepPoseKit#installing-with-anaconda-on-windows&gt;https://github.com/jgraving/DeepPoseKit#installing-with-anaconda-on-windows&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

So, I'll go ahead and close this.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>