<bug id='649' author='EnricoBeltramo' open_date='2018-05-26T00:07:59Z' closed_time='2018-09-30T09:57:35Z'>
	<summary>tutorial_bipedalwalker_a3c_continuous_action.py not convergence</summary>
	<description>
I tryed to launch the demo tutorial_bipedalwalker_a3c_continuous_action.py, but I have a very low convergence (best result: reward: -5.1 | running_reward: -5.6 either after 40000 iteration). In simulation it fall almost immediately. There is some parameters to tune?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-26T00:10:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zsdonghao&gt;@zsdonghao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 who can be relevant for RL? I can't be of any help on this topic
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-26T21:09:42Z'>
		I tried the original implementation of the author (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MorvanZhou/Reinforcement-learning-with-tensorflow/blob/master/experiments/Solve_BipedalWalker/A3C.py&gt;https://github.com/MorvanZhou/Reinforcement-learning-with-tensorflow/blob/master/experiments/Solve_BipedalWalker/A3C.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) and it looks to work. May be the issue is the porting on tensorlayer
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-28T17:13:44Z'>
		
@zsdonghao who can be relevant for RL? I can't be of any help on this topic

I supposed that if a porting on tensorlayer of a working example don't work, may be there is some issue related to library. If is not considered relevant, should be closed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-28T20:08:38Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/EnricoBeltramo&gt;@EnricoBeltramo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sorry for the late reply, actually, I tested it today, but I found that both TL code and the original implementation cannot converge ...  (under the lastest TL and TF 1.7)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-28T20:44:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zsdonghao&gt;@zsdonghao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you try with an old TL + TF version?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-29T18:31:42Z'>
		I tested on tf 1.6.0, I have a low convergence, but acceptable. If I overtraining (i.e. &gt; 40000 iterations) it looks after convergence, diverge again
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-29T23:49:42Z'>
		previously it works very well, that should be a problem, and I guess the problem is related to the sampling part.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-05-30T00:00:59Z'>
		What about TL 1.7.4 and TF 1.8.0 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-01T17:14:00Z'>
		What is the last working version tested on?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-01T18:33:33Z'>
		According to the release &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorlayer/tensorlayer/releases?after=1.6.6&gt;https://github.com/tensorlayer/tensorlayer/releases?after=1.6.6&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

it was working on TL 1.6.0
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-01T19:46:05Z'>
		We can easily try and see what changed. Who designed this tutorial ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-10T10:48:16Z'>
		Hi, just wondering if there has been any development with this issue?  I've reverted back to TF 1.0 with no TL for my research now (i.e. the original authors A3C implementation), but of course would much rather be using up to date versions of TF and TL!
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-10T17:09:37Z'>
		We are investigating it. The error may come from TF not TL.
If you have any idea, we would be glad to receive any PR
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-12T11:21:11Z'>
		I observed (using a few different model) that if I introduce mechanism like semaphores in order to synchronize the update of weights between threads and common network, the convergence improve. Should be an issue of multithreading?
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-06-13T11:03:41Z'>
		The original author of A3C update his code to TF1.8
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MorvanZhou/Reinforcement-learning-with-tensorflow/commit/682e89bd7f00b7c2b3598a7bb5975598def9e4cf#diff-2202f4dab91d61358d9ac9058a499562&gt;MorvanZhou/Reinforcement-learning-with-tensorflow@682e89b#diff-2202f4dab91d61358d9ac9058a499562&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='EnricoBeltramo' date='2018-09-30T09:57:35Z'>
		fixed.
I close this issue, feel free to reopen it if you want to discuss.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>