<bug id='535' author='edgarriba' open_date='2020-04-25T12:26:25Z' closed_time='2020-04-29T16:21:07Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] spatial_softargmax2d tests broken</summary>
	<description>
In the current version the tests for spatial_softargmax2d tests are broken.
After checking the code I believe that there's a mismatch in the normalization parameter.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kornia/kornia/blob/master/test/geometry/test_spatial_softargmax.py#L77&gt;https://github.com/kornia/kornia/blob/master/test/geometry/test_spatial_softargmax.py#L77&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-25T12:26:33Z'>
		/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/anibali&gt;@anibali&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-28T00:04:12Z'>
		The tests themselves are indeed quite broken, but the code being tested is correct as far as I can see.
The main problem is that the author of these tests confused the similarly named  and  functions (see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kornia/kornia/issues/353#issuecomment-587165931&gt;#353 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). To recap the difference,  applies spatial softmax before calling . Is the naming terrible? Yes, I made a mistake there for sure.
My suggestion would be to rename one of these functions for clarity, or to simply merge the functions and introduce a boolean argument for whether softmax should be applied.
Anyway, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kornia/kornia/pull/544&gt;#544&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fixes the tests.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-28T07:38:52Z'>
		indeed, probably it's worth renaming. In order to make it consistent with &lt;denchmark-link:https://kornia.readthedocs.io/en/latest/geometry.html?highlight=conv_softargmax#kornia.geometry.conv_soft_argmax2d&gt;convolutional&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 versions, what about  and  ?
Besides, what about grouping under a same submodule  ? (or other related  name) /cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ducha-aiki&gt;@ducha-aiki&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-28T08:08:08Z'>
		The name spatial_argmax2d is not good since argmax is the non-differentiable operation that takes the location of the highest-value pixel (ie the "arguments" x, y that give the maximum value). That's how I would expect a function called spatial_argmax2d to behave. The operation that we are doing is more like an expectation or weighted mean. How about spatial_expectation2d?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-29T16:28:37Z'>
		definitely this is confusing, I would go for one single functionality. Why did you split both ? just curious.
For consistency I would have:

spatial_softmax2d
--&gt; does only softmax over 2d, actually this could be a generic thing by specifying a tuple of consecutive axis, right ?
spatial_soft_argmax2d
conv_soft_argmax2d

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-29T22:57:42Z'>
		Let's draw a comparison to a similar situation in PyTorch itself. In PyTorch they have both &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/nn.functional.html#nll-loss&gt;nll_loss&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/nn.functional.html#cross-entropy&gt;cross_entropy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. The first is a meaningful individual operation which expects a log probability input, the second is a convenience which combines &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/nn.functional.html#log-softmax&gt;log_softmax&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and  since they are often used together. We have a very similar situation here.
Our "expectation" operation is analogous to the nll_loss function. It is commonly used immediately after a softmax, but does not have to be. It simply requires a probability map (pixels are non-negative and sum to 1), which could be obtained through means other than softmax.
So to have a good API for everything (let's leave the convolutional function out of the discussion for now), we should have 3 operations:

spatial_soft_argmax2d (analogy: cross_entropy, simply combines the other two)
spatial_softmax2d (analogy: log_softmax)
spatial_expectation2d? (analogy: nll_loss)

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='edgarriba' date='2020-04-30T06:08:09Z'>
		Perfect, I buy your history and go ahead with the renaming. What about also the module thing?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>