<bug id='569' author='Rachana-Baldania' open_date='2019-07-10T12:03:24Z' closed_time='2020-03-11T11:18:56Z'>
	<summary>DateMatcher() : Date Identification Issues</summary>
	<description>
Hello,
I am using Johnsnowlabs Spark NLP for implementing question answering system and we are unable to detect dates correctly while using datematcher() function:
Two consecutive date formats in one string then cannot detect two dates
For example, "who sold the most beer in 1/02/2014 and 1/05/2016"
Johnsnowlabs NLP DateMatcher: [2014/01/02]
Getting a wrong result when I am trying to extract data
For example, "sold the most cake during April 2015 5:30 a.m"
Johnsnowlabs NLP DateMatcher: [2015/04/05]
I want to identify dates only not amount
For example, "items which have above 23372.8 $ sales value"
Johnsnowlabs NLP DateMatcher: [2017/12/08]
When date and value are in one string should be identified date and value separately and correctly
For example, "I need to know how many sales of less than 8,000 were made in March of 2015"
Johnsnowlabs NLP DateMatcher: [2015/03/08]
So, Can you please enhance/solve these bugs of DateMatcher() as soon as possible? please share your suggestions.
Thank you.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Rachana-Baldania&gt;@Rachana-Baldania&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Rachana-Baldania' date='2019-07-24T09:33:29Z'>
		I see two issues:

Only the first matched date is being extracted
Values are ignored or mistaken as dates

Am I right? By the way, how do you extract the values like 8,000? I don't think DateMather is the annotator for that. Maybe RegexTokenizer?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Rachana-Baldania' date='2019-07-28T14:06:44Z'>
		Yes both two points are correct.

DateMatcher not showing POS for numbers for ex. , any date or value. So
some times 8,000 value is ignored by Datematcher or sometimes its merged
with date output for ex. what are the sales which is greater than 8000 in
march,15.

I dont know there is problem with regex or annotator but i think values
should be treated differently from date.

Thank you.

*Regards,*
*Rachana Baldania.*
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Wed, Jul 24, 2019 at 3:03 PM Maziyar Panahi ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 I see two issues:

    1. Only the first matched date is being extracted
    2. Values are ignored or mistaken as dates

 Am I right? By the way, how do you extract the values like 8,000? I don't
 think DateMather is the annotator for that. Maybe RegexTokenizer?

 —
 You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#569?email_source=notifications&amp;email_token=AJZ4ISY5VT37UZIHK73O33TQBAOW5A5CNFSM4H7OTJD2YY3PNVWWK3TUL52HS4DFVREXG43VMVBW63LNMVXHJKTDN5WW2ZLOORPWSZGOD2VYJZQ#issuecomment-514557158&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AJZ4IS57XMS2FKWBCUJONV3QBAOW5ANCNFSM4H7OTJDQ&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Rachana-Baldania' date='2020-03-11T11:18:56Z'>
		There is a new annotator called MultiDateMatcher that allows the extraction of multiple dates in a document and sentence. The behavior is the same as DateMatcher so it can be replaced easily with MultiDateMatcher in the pipeline.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>