<bug id='58' author='clayms' open_date='2017-12-10T21:05:57Z' closed_time='2017-12-18T05:03:31Z'>
	<summary>using setRequiredAnnotatorTypes() with many of the annotators throws error.</summary>
	<description>
Many of the annotators in annotator.py list requiredAnnotatorTypes() as a parameter when using either &lt;annotatorName&gt;().explainParams(), or dir(&lt;annotatorName&gt;).
However, when using &lt;annotatorName&gt;().setRequiredAnnotatorTypes on most of these annotators, the following error is thrown.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Py4JJavaError: An error occurred while calling o830.getParam.
: java.util.NoSuchElementException: Param requiredAnnotatorTypes does not exist.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The only place where the requiredAnnotatorTypes parameter is shown is in the class AnnotatorProperties of annotator.py starting on line 29.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='clayms' date='2017-12-15T14:02:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/clayms&gt;@clayms&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  What annotator you use?
I tried with different annotators and it works for me:
print(PerceptronApproach().explainParams())
print(EntityExtractor().explainParams())
print(ViveknSentimentApproach().explainParams())
print(NorvigSweetingApproach().explainParams())
print(NerCrfApproach().explainParams())
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='clayms' date='2017-12-17T19:56:10Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/aleksei-ai&gt;@aleksei-ai&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have tried it with RegexTokenizer, Normalizer, Stemmer, Lemmatizer, RegexMatcher, EntityExtractor, DateMatcher, SentenceDetectorModel, PerceptronApproach, SentimentDetectorModel, NERRegexApproach, and NorvigSweetingApproach.
the .explainParams() method works on all of them, but when I try and use the .setRequiredAnnotatorTypes when building the annotator to use in a pipeline, that is when the error I referenced above is thrown.
Thanks,
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='clayms' date='2017-12-18T04:53:41Z'>
		Hi, setRequiredAnnotatorTypes() is a deprecated method and should not be used. This function in python code is just a mistake of a lingering code. Shall be deleted. Thank you &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/clayms&gt;@clayms&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Required annotators are a fixed property of annotators, and cannot be modified per annotators inherent functionality.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='clayms' date='2017-12-18T05:03:31Z'>
		Merged Fix
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>