<bug id='1133' author='jaqub-manuel' open_date='2020-05-05T12:18:51Z' closed_time='2020-06-11T00:15:09Z'>
	<summary>Evolve parameters</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
Thanks for this great work.
I have trained my model for one class (includes 700 images) and gec mAP 60.
To increase mAP, I used evolve and got evolve.tx, but it has lotf of parameters. I cant not figure out what are the first 7 parameters, other starts with giou. My evolve txt looks like this:
0.96      0.833      0.911      0.892       1.47      0.247          0       3.57    0.00573       0.99       65.7      0.983      0.198       0.01     0.0005      0.935   0.000492          0     0.0132      0.702      0.361          0          0          0          0.
giou starts 3.57 and so on, but what is ( 0.96      0.833      0.911      0.892       1.47      0.247          0) ?
Thanks for advance
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T12:19:31Z'>
		Hello @jaqub7676, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T17:32:11Z'>
		@jaqub7676 your best result will be the first row. First 7 values are metrics, the rest are your hyps.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:24:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  many thanks.
To justify (sorry),  the order of metrics ? , prec, rec, map, f1, val/giou loss, val/obj loss and val/cls loss.. If so, I updated hyps in train.py, but I did not got higher results, got  map 0.86 with 0.06 increase, P: 0.96, R:0.68 AND F1: 0.80. According to these hyps, I had to get (0.96 0.833 0.911 0.892 1.47 0.247 0) that map is 0.91... ? Am I right ? (It looks like only F1 is same compared to evolve params).
Another quesiton, I wonder what do you suggest for my medical data (700 images and 200 for test) with single class ?
Do I need to do augmententation before training or train.py is enough ? I am waiting for your suggest ? ( yolo.weights and yolov3.cfg worked best for me).
Many thanks again.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:40:44Z'>
		@jaqub7676 the first 7 are P, R, mAP, F1, and then the 3 losses: GIoU, obj, class
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:43:44Z'>
		Thanks again. Do you have any suggestion for my other questions ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:44:10Z'>
		@jaqub7676 reproducibility of results will depend on many factors, but in general seperate trainings may not be deterministic, so you can expect variations from one training run to another.
This is quite unfortunate obviously, especially in the case of hyperparameter evolution, where we'd ideally like all of the mAP change to be caused by the hyperparameters rather than nondeterministic factors, but it is the current state of affairs in the industry. See &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/randomness.html&gt;https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/notes/randomness.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Augmentation during training is all you need (there's no point creating additional copies of your dataset before training). I would suggest using yolov3-spp, as it should produce better results.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:46:44Z'>
		last thing, Only if we use darknet, then we can update anchors. For others like yolov3-spp etc, do I need to use k-means anchor to get new anchor for my datasets. Or evolve is doing everything includes anchors ?  Thnaks again.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:49:10Z'>
		@jaqub7676 --evolve will not modify your anchors. You can use this function to get optimal anchors for your dataset:



yolov3/utils/utils.py


        Lines 693 to 698
      in
      d405959






 def kmean_anchors(path='./data/coco64.txt', n=9, img_size=(320, 1024), thr=0.20, gen=1000): 



 # Creates kmeans anchors for use in *.cfg files: from utils.utils import *; _ = kmean_anchors() 



 # n: number of anchors 



 # img_size: (min, max) image size used for multi-scale training (can be same values) 



 # thr: IoU threshold hyperparameter used for training (0.0 - 1.0) 



 # gen: generations to evolve anchors using genetic algorithm 





		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T20:51:11Z'>
		Thanks...
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-05T21:04:13Z'>
		@jaqub7676 you're welcome, good luck!
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-06T13:45:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Hi, Thank you for your amazing work!
I have a question about hyperparameters. If I use image augmentation, is that right I change the 0 in the following code to 1? And does the value 1.98 represent the rotation degree, the 0.05 represent that the translation is 5%?

And if I trained at multi-scale, do I need to uncomment the following code? Because the default hyp "obj loss gain"is evolved at 320.

Thank you in advance for your reply!
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-06T20:27:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tyb197&gt;@tyb197&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes that is correct, units are degrees rotation and fractional translation. No, you do not need to comment that line (we should probably remove it to avoid confusion). It simply scales the obj loss accordingly, which may help certain datasets, but the current hyps are defined at 416 rather than 320 FYI.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-05-06T20:28:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tyb197&gt;@tyb197&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 also yes, if you remove the zeros then augmentation will proceed acording to these values. You can observe the result in train*.jpg after you start training.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='jaqub-manuel' date='2020-06-06T00:15:06Z'>
		This issue is stale because it has been open 30 days with no activity. Remove Stale label or comment or this will be closed in 5 days.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>