<bug id='1153' author='Hidayat722' open_date='2020-05-09T22:59:32Z' closed_time='2020-06-23T00:15:50Z'>
	<summary>MAP is high using multi-scale train but detection results are not good</summary>
	<description>
I have trained a single class modul using img-size of 1280 multi-scale is True my MAP is .97 but detection results are not good my test image size is 2560X520 any help would be appreciated.
Thanks in Advance.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-09T23:00:09Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hidayat722&gt;@Hidayat722&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-09T23:03:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hidayat722&gt;@Hidayat722&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 test at your train size.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-09T23:51:54Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 i did the same but since its multi-scale and detection is at single-scale so that's the issue for some images the rest are fine. Maybe i could do hard-mining or something like that
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-10T00:00:58Z'>
		Don't really understand the problem. The original image resolution is irrelevant. If you train at 640, then test at 640. If you train multisclae 320-640, then test at 640. That's all there is to it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-10T00:03:37Z'>
		I trained at resolution of 1280 multi-scale, the training is fine i have MAP of .92 but when i do detection at the same size the results are not good, for both training and testing i am using image size of 2560X520.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-10T00:06:16Z'>
		1280 multiscale will train at 1280/1.5 to 1280 * 1.5, therefore you should test at no more than 1280*1.5.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-10T00:08:54Z'>
		Thanks for your help and quick response i really appreciate that i will try at different scales
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-10T00:19:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Hidayat722&gt;@Hidayat722&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 sure. Basically you want to train at the same sizes that you plan on running inference on. So for example if you want to run inference or test at 640, you should plan ahead and train around that size, i.e. train.py --img 640 --multi. This allows you to test/infer at sizes a 50% larger or smaller than 640. If you stray outside that zone mAP will suffer.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-05-18T07:31:35Z'>
		
@Hidayat722 sure. Basically you want to train at the same sizes that you plan on running inference on. So for example if you want to run inference or test at 640, you should plan ahead and train around that size, i.e. train.py --img 640 --multi. This allows you to test/infer at sizes a 50% larger or smaller than 640. If you stray outside that zone mAP will suffer.

will the F1 decrease much when using --multi ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Hidayat722' date='2020-06-18T00:15:33Z'>
		This issue is stale because it has been open 30 days with no activity. Remove Stale label or comment or this will be closed in 5 days.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>