<bug id='1184' author='zzfpython' open_date='2020-05-16T01:17:36Z' closed_time='2020-05-18T15:41:34Z'>
	<summary>Some Qustions About the code</summary>
	<description>
Before submitting a bug report, please ensure that you are using the latest versions of:

Python
PyTorch
This repository (run git fetch &amp;&amp; git status -uno to check and git pull to update)

Your issue must be reproducible on a public dataset (i.e COCO) using the latest version of the repository, and you must supply code to reproduce, or we can not help you.
If this is a custom training question we suggest you include your train*.jpg, test*.jpg and results.png figures.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

REQUIRED: Code to reproduce your issue below
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;python train.py ...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.

OS: [e.g. Ubuntu]
GPU [e.g. 2080 Ti]

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Add any other context about the problem here.
Hi, I am watching your code these days and I found it is very beautiful and I have some questions.
Such as:(The code in datasets.py)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/39543924/82106763-a08f9480-9755-11ea-93a9-23d4a6916f62.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I want to know is here a function to do data augment.  'augment=False' Does it mean the aygment is closed as default?
And If I try 'python train.py' or 'python test.py'  How could I know whether I open the data augmentation?
Thank you for reply. Sorry to disturb you and maybe this is a simple question but I don't know the answer. Thank you for your advice.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zzfpython' date='2020-05-16T02:51:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zzfpython&gt;@zzfpython&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you, these are python default values that are used in the function in the absence of specifying an argument. So if you create an instance of LoadImagesAndLabels() without specifying a value for , it will be False.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zzfpython' date='2020-05-16T05:41:56Z'>
		
@zzfpython thank you, these are python default values that are used in the function in the absence of specifying an argument. So if you create an instance of LoadImagesAndLabels() without specifying a value for augment, it will be False.

Is that mean If clone the ropo and train the network ,the picture in the COCO will be enhanced as default .
Why I have this question, since I change the 'False' here to 'True' The training fails to start .
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zzfpython' date='2020-05-16T16:35:17Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zzfpython&gt;@zzfpython&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 don't alter these values. To get started see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>