<bug id='1282' author='M-S-KHAN' open_date='2020-06-05T22:50:57Z' closed_time='2020-06-10T18:47:34Z'>
	<summary>Yolov4-relu inference giving displaced bboxes</summary>
	<description>
I have trained yolov4-relu on custom dataset with 17 classes. I have made following changes:

No. of classes to 17 in each yolo layer
No. of filters to 66 ([5 + 17] * 3)
Altered the GIoU hyperparameter value to 1.00 due to "WARNING: non-finite loss, ending training tensor([nan, nan, 0., nan], device='cuda:0')" issue
Batch size = 6

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/51326962/83928297-b4ed0d00-a7a8-11ea-8c79-2c42540698e1.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Note: I have also tried to scale it down using model output in order to see if there is any issue in the drawing code but the issue persists.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='M-S-KHAN' date='2020-06-05T22:51:34Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/M-S-KHAN&gt;@M-S-KHAN&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI surveillance systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='M-S-KHAN' date='2020-06-05T23:47:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/M-S-KHAN&gt;@M-S-KHAN&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the labels you trained with are incorrect. See your train*.jpg for label overlays. Your centerpoints are offset. For label formatting and training guidelines see
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='M-S-KHAN' date='2020-06-10T18:47:34Z'>
		Yes I have had coco formatted annotation files and the coco-to-darknet conversion script was adding an offset in the new annotations. Thank you for the help though.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>