<bug id='1349' author='alex96295' open_date='2020-06-27T10:33:48Z' closed_time='2020-08-22T00:26:13Z'>
	<summary>Train on custom dataset - anchors</summary>
	<description>
Hello, I have a question since it is not specified in the Custom dataset training tutorial. If I want to train on a custom dataset, should I compute my own anchors or can I use those from the official yolo? As far as I know, anchors are bounded to dataset
Thank you
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='alex96295' date='2020-06-27T10:34:28Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alex96295&gt;@alex96295&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Ultralytics has open-sourced YOLOv5 at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, featuring faster, lighter and more accurate object detection. YOLOv5 is recommended for all new projects.


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/85340570-30360a80-b49b-11ea-87cf-bdf33d53ae15.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

To continue with this repo, please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='alex96295' date='2020-06-27T16:22:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alex96295&gt;@alex96295&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I would train both ways, with default and custom anchors.
You might want to try yolov5, since it automatically analyzes your anchors against your data before training starts, and then evolves new anchors and integrates them into your model if necessary. You don't have to do anything there, it's the default behavior.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='alex96295' date='2020-07-16T11:57:09Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Hello,This Repo's Yolov3 have autoAnchor?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='alex96295' date='2020-07-16T16:50:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/summeryumyee&gt;@summeryumyee&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 no
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='alex96295' date='2020-08-16T00:26:26Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>