<bug id='1554' author='nuqz' open_date='2020-11-13T09:41:24Z' closed_time='2020-12-19T00:35:04Z'>
	<summary>Remove cached labels before training</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

My custom dataset is too large to fit into RAM with --cache-images option enabled. So, I decided to split it into multiple parts and run training procedure sequentially with each part. On the second pass, I found that mAP and F1 dropped significantly (mAP ~ 0.9 -&gt; 0.008). When I started to figure out what was going on, I discovered that the labels are not cached again and I need to delete them like this:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;!rm -f data/my_custom_dataset/training/labels.npy
!rm -f data/my_custom_dataset/validation/labels.npy
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Create a small custom dataset and split it into multiple parts, then train model sequentially with each part.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;$ python train.py ... --data data/my_custom_dataset/part1.data --epochs 75 ...
$ python train.py ... --data data/my_custom_dataset/part2.data --epochs 150 --weights weights/best.pt ...
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Invalidate labels cache for subsequent runs.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Google Colab free tier.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='nuqz' date='2020-11-13T09:42:10Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nuqz&gt;@nuqz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Ultralytics has open-sourced YOLOv5 at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, featuring faster, lighter and more accurate object detection. YOLOv5 is recommended for all new projects.




&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/90187293-6773ba00-dd6e-11ea-8f90-cd94afc0427f.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

To continue with this repo, please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='nuqz' date='2020-11-13T12:26:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/nuqz&gt;@nuqz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the bug report! This has been fixed in YOLOv5, and updates will be pushed from there to here later this month.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='nuqz' date='2020-12-14T00:34:21Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>