<bug id='216' author='foocker' open_date='2019-04-17T01:52:29Z' closed_time='2019-04-17T09:55:07Z'>
	<summary>build_targets has something wrong? b, c = t[:, :2].long().t()  # target image, class, index error or some other wrong report.</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Go to '...'
Click on '....'
Scroll down to '....'
See error

Expected behavior
A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
Screenshots
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.
Desktop (please complete the following information):

OS: [e.g. iOS]
Version [e.g. 22]

Smartphone (please complete the following information):

Device: [e.g. iPhoneXS]
OS: [e.g. iOS8.1]
Version [e.g. 22]

Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='foocker' date='2019-04-17T02:28:19Z'>
		reject = True
if reject:
j = iou &gt; 0.10
t, a, gwh = targets[j], a[j], gwh[j]
this will lead your t empty.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='foocker' date='2019-04-17T09:55:07Z'>
		Hello, thank you for your interest in our work! This is an automated response. In the section of code you highlight, yes t can become empty. This does not cause any problems however, the code operates correctly with empty target vectors.
Please note that most technical problems are due to:

Your changes to the default repository. If your issue is not reproducible in a fresh git clone version of this repository we can not debug it. Before going further run this code and ensure your issue persists:

sudo rm -rf yolov3  # remove exising repo
git clone https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3 &amp;&amp; cd yolov3 # git clone latest
python3 detect.py  # verify detection
python3 train.py  # verify training (a few batches only)
# CODE TO REPRODUCE YOUR ISSUE HERE

Your custom data. If your issue is not reproducible with COCO data we can not debug it. Visit our Custom Training Tutorial for exact details on how to format your custom data. Examine train_batch0.jpg and test_batch0.jpg for a sanity check of training and testing data.
Your environment. If your issue is not reproducible in a GCP Quickstart Guide VM we can not debug it. Ensure you meet the requirements specified in the README: Unix, MacOS, or Windows with Python &gt;= 3.7, Pytorch &gt;= 1.0, etc.

If none of these apply to you, we suggest you close this issue and raise a new one using the Bug Report template, providing screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue. Thank you!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>