<bug id='471' author='ShawnCheung123' open_date='2019-08-25T07:36:49Z' closed_time='2019-08-26T12:22:09Z'>
	<summary>Problems when using opencv to read network</summary>
	<description>
Hello! Nice of you to share this great work.
I currently have some proplems using cv2 to reproduce the work.
I have already trained a weight on my custom dataset and works well on your code.
I am trying to use opencv to read the network, by using cv2.dnn.readNetFromDarknet.
However, nothing is detected. The network is loaded successfully.
Do you have any idea on this issue.
Looking forward to your kind reply.
My opencv job basically follows&lt;denchmark-link:url&gt;https://github.com/PySimpleGUI/PySimpleGUI/blob/master/YoloObjectDetection/yolo.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ShawnCheung123' date='2019-08-25T11:42:17Z'>
		That's beyond the scope of this repo. You can convert trained pt weights to darknet format that is compatible with AlexeyAB/darknet, but we do not support the original darknet repository.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ShawnCheung123' date='2019-08-25T11:49:16Z'>
		
That's beyond the scope of this repo. You can convert trained pt weights to darknet format that is compatible with AlexeyAB/darknet, but we do not support the original darknet repository.

Thanks so much for your quick reply!
I have already converted to darknet format(*.weights). Weights can be loaded successfully but cannot detect anything. You mean maybe that's because opencv only supports the original darknet format?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ShawnCheung123' date='2019-08-25T15:18:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ShawnCheung123&gt;@ShawnCheung123&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't know. I think the header information has diverged a bit between the two darknets.
Maybe you could try lowering your confidence threshold for detections.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ShawnCheung123' date='2019-08-26T12:22:05Z'>
		
@ShawnCheung123 I don't know. I think the header information has diverged a bit between the two darknets.
Maybe you could try lowering your confidence threshold for detections.

Thank you! So nice of you.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>