<bug id='728' author='FranciscoReveriano' open_date='2019-12-18T20:53:21Z' closed_time='2020-03-16T00:10:17Z'>
	<summary>Assertion Failed Error</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A clear and concise description of what the bug is.
I am trying to reproduce the results and I am getting an : -215 Assertion Failed) Error. top &gt;= 0 &amp;&amp; bottom &gt;=0 &amp;&amp; left &gt;=0
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/48685139/71122260-2959d280-21ae-11ea-955e-83a14f6367fe.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I have not altered the code or images at all. I am running it directly from the .sh
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Cloned Github
ran the ./sh command to get COCO
Rewrote all the paths and ran the code as instructed

This happens right when it finishes the first epoch and does the testing on it.
Command used to start training:
python train.py --weights '' --cfg yolov3-spp.cfg --epochs 10 --batch 30 --accum 4 --multi --pre
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2019-12-20T22:12:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/FranciscoReveriano&gt;@FranciscoReveriano&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 there's been a lot of updates lately in train.py and test.py. One of them inadvertently caused an error similar to this, but it's been fixed in the last few days, could you git pull and try again?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2019-12-23T06:44:15Z'>
		modify about test: rect=False
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2020-01-09T16:57:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we are getting this bug too. It seems to be comming from the .shapes files created by the kmeans function! When deleting the .shapes files and starting the training so it makes its own .shapes files, everything is good. If we keep the .shapes file created with the kmeans function, we get this error at test!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2020-01-09T17:25:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Ownmarc&gt;@Ownmarc&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 oh that's odd. I suppose the quick and dirty solution is to remove the shapes file then before exiting the kmeans function. I'll take a look at it today.
BTW, I updated the kmeans function to add a second step after the kmeans. The second step runs a genetic algorithm which directly minimizes the IOUs of the anchor boxes (the kmeans only minimizes the w-h distances). This improves the metrics a bit more, though I still struggle to get great results with custom anchors from the function unfortunately, as often times the default anchors work better.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2020-01-09T19:05:58Z'>
		Its the training.shapes that get created by the kmeans function that causes problem for the training! Or maybe the lack of the validation.shapes.
The training will crash at the "test" after first epoch. Checked the LoadImagesAndLabels function that creates the .shapes and I couldn't find the problem. There is a try and except that should create the .shape file for validation properly.. When we delete all .shapes files before starting the training, everything goes well and both files get created.
Hope this helps
FYI, I've seen improvements in our custom training using kmeans calculated anchors, but our bndbox are also alot different in shape than those of coco..
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2020-02-09T16:48:12Z'>
		I personally got better results using custom anchors. Aside from metrics though the original measurements made more sense when visualizing inspecting the images.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='FranciscoReveriano' date='2020-03-11T00:09:46Z'>
		This issue is stale because it has been open 30 days with no activity. Remove Stale label or comment or this will be closed in 5 days.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>