<bug id='781' author='luan1412167' open_date='2020-01-15T06:46:32Z' closed_time='2020-01-18T02:03:43Z'>
	<summary>low confidence when train one class.</summary>
	<description>
Hi, thanks for your repo. It is very useful.
My proplem is that I have my custom dataset. It is extracted from COCO dataset with 1 cell phone class. I think that I have done rightly as train single class guide. I got about 50 mAP after 200 epoch. Then I run detect.py for inference, my model is not good as darknet original model. I notice that my model return low confidence(about ~0.7). Any suggest for me? Thanks
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='luan1412167' date='2020-01-15T17:23:19Z'>
		You can use the --classes flag to return inference results for a single category only.
We do not supply advice on custom training, however Ultralytics offers professional consulting in this area, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production AI solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based YOLOv3 surveillance systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime
iOS-device YOLOv3 integrated into custom apps for realtime 30 FPS inference
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination

If you'd like to discuss your requirements in greater detail, please contact Glenn Jocher at &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:glenn.jocher@ultralytics.com&gt;glenn.jocher@ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or visit us at &lt;denchmark-link:https://contact.ultralytics.com&gt;https://contact.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Alternatively, we will leave this issue open, and you are free to seek any available community support here.
$ python3 detect.py --source maxresdefault.jpg --classes 67
Namespace(agnostic_nms=False, cfg='cfg/yolov3-spp.cfg', classes=[67], conf_thres=0.5, device='', fourcc='mp4v', half=False, img_size=416, iou_thres=0.5, names='data/coco.names', output='output', save_txt=False, source='maxresdefault.jpg', view_img=False, weights='weights/ultralytics68.pt')
Using CPU

image 1/1 maxresdefault.jpg: 256x416 2 cell phones, Done. (0.616s)
Results saved to /Users/glennjocher/PycharmProjects/yolov3/output
Done. (0.732s)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/72455858-6cd93980-3778-11ea-827a-609f3b618b0a.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='luan1412167' date='2020-01-16T08:11:02Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  thanks for your reply.
I wonder that why my model alway return confidence score lower than 0.7. my pull code is latest.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/37315746/72507005-a0e65480-3875-11ea-9cfc-97992317b711.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

result from my model
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/37315746/72507081-c7a48b00-3875-11ea-88cb-3662db0b27a6.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

result from original model
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='luan1412167' date='2020-01-18T01:47:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/luan1412167&gt;@luan1412167&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we discovered a bug related to this issue. The bug only affected single class inference,  and multiplied all confidences by sigmoid(1) = 0.73, hence the lower confidence scores. We've fixed the issue in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/commit/cdb4680390e4140810518432dab0d8c4d37fb8d1&gt;cdb4680&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Please  and try again to see if this fixes the issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='luan1412167' date='2020-01-18T02:03:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  My issue have fixed by latest commit. Thanks for discovering out this issue. I highly appreciate your repo and support.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='luan1412167' date='2020-01-18T02:09:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/luan1412167&gt;@luan1412167&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 great, glad to hear it! Let us know if you suspect any other bugs :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>