<bug id='978' author='logic03' open_date='2020-03-29T09:55:08Z' closed_time='2020-06-18T00:15:35Z'>
	<summary>Question about mosaic</summary>
	<description>
I want to ask about "Mosaic", what is the principle and advantage of this data enhancement method? Do you have any relevant articles or materials?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='logic03' date='2020-03-29T09:55:42Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/logic03&gt;@logic03&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1G8T-VFxQkjDe4idzN8F-hbIBqkkkQnxw&gt;Google Colab Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov3&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;GCP Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='logic03' date='2020-03-29T20:40:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/logic03&gt;@logic03&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it's an augmentation technique we invented which results in improved AP on COCO.
You can train without it by doing python3 train.py --rect
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='logic03' date='2020-04-16T23:10:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 isn't it will cause false detection because It is mixing the images? can u elaborate it, please
Like this one, How actually we solve it, please
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov3/issues/940&gt;#940&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='logic03' date='2020-04-16T23:48:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NaeemKhan333&gt;@NaeemKhan333&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if you want to train without the mosaic loader simply run

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='logic03' date='2020-04-19T19:18:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NaeemKhan333&gt;@NaeemKhan333&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes this correct, this helps improve mAP in COCO and on most datasets. You can try training without the mosaic loader also to compare:

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='logic03' date='2020-04-19T20:59:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have trained model without mosaic loader using following command
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;python3 train.py --rect
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

But Training with Mosaic Loader has given much better accuracy than training without mosaic, but It causing few false detections. I have a single class and have 5000 training images and 500 testing images, but it causing a few false detections. I have used yolov3-spp-ultralytics, with predefined parameters and other settings  What could be the reason for false detection?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='logic03' date='2020-04-19T22:14:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/NaeemKhan333&gt;@NaeemKhan333&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 you choose your own rate of FPs by varying the  threshold:
python3 detect.py --conf 0.9
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='logic03' date='2020-04-19T22:41:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I cannot understand " choose your own rate of FPs" and mostly the score for detection, I get is in between 0.4--&gt;0.8 range, But some time false detection also gets a higher score like 0.6,0.65,0.7, which is strange for me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='logic03' date='2020-04-20T00:29:58Z'>
		You choose how many false positives you want by varying the confidence threshold.
The higher you increase —conf the less FPs you’ll see.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='logic03' date='2020-06-12T00:15:52Z'>
		This issue is stale because it has been open 30 days with no activity. Remove Stale label or comment or this will be closed in 5 days.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>