<bug id='986' author='yeshwanthmaringanti' open_date='2020-03-30T18:45:46Z' closed_time='2020-04-30T11:55:50Z'>
	<summary>Labels not found error</summary>
	<description>
Hi glenn , I followed each and every step of custom training  document as given. But still it is throwing the error. I am 100% sure that the path mentioned is correct and text files are also present in the same directory where images are present with .txt extension instead of .png.
Please look at the screenshot.  I don't know whats wrong with the data. because it worked with different train data previously , now when i re run it on new train data it's not working. Please help me out
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/49546514/77949401-86ecd780-72e4-11ea-9e89-6fa66090c440.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yeshwanthmaringanti' date='2020-03-31T00:13:58Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yeshwanthmaringanti&gt;@yeshwanthmaringanti&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 your label paths are incorrect. Follow the tutorial and mimic the label paths and structure presented there.

Your custom data. If your issue is not reproducible with COCO data we can not debug it. Visit our Custom Training Tutorial for exact details on how to format your custom data. Examine train_batch0.jpg and test_batch0.jpg for a sanity check of training and testing data.

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yeshwanthmaringanti' date='2020-03-31T13:44:07Z'>
		I have examined the label paths and they don't seem to be incorrect and all we have done is we  just included some more images to improve model performance , kindly advice us on what we can do and also  give us detailed note on cases when this assertion error reflected on the system.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yeshwanthmaringanti' date='2020-03-31T18:35:40Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yeshwanthmaringanti&gt;@yeshwanthmaringanti&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 your paths are incorrect as the error states, you need to fix. There is no bug. This is your responsibility.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>