<bug id='249' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' open_date='2019-11-09T01:51:06Z' closed_time='2020-01-20T19:35:54Z'>
	<summary>Replace Dropbox shared links with a different mechanism for distributing model weights.</summary>
	<description>
I have deleted Dropbox shared links used for distributing models, as a result this repo will stop working. I will update once I have decided on a new solution.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2019-12-10T14:16:44Z'>
		Hi, any update on this?
regards.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2019-12-24T00:09:00Z'>
		A docker registry over IPFS? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/miguelmota/ipdr&gt;https://github.com/miguelmota/ipdr&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Then a few of us can host IPFS nodes. I can help set this up. Or just IPFS nodes. If mutable links are required we could use: &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.ipfs.io/guides/concepts/ipns/&gt;https://docs.ipfs.io/guides/concepts/ipns/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2019-12-24T17:58:17Z'>
		I will share a gzip file containing all model weights etc. essentially everything that was previously distributed over Dropbox. Along with a change to codebase that allows specifying a source for download. Hopefully should have it by end of the 2019.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2019-12-30T17:51:08Z'>
		Hi, any updates for the weights files? I'm wondering if there is a separate docker service for OCR?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-11T16:00:59Z'>
		Any updates on this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-11T23:14:44Z'>
		hey sorry still working on this
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-13T14:45:58Z'>
		What about just put the gzip file containing all models (without code changes for downloading etc.) as a stop-gap solution? Without model files, the repo is not usable, really eager to try the repo out now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-13T18:29:50Z'>
		Sure let me post link to all sources.
All models are taken from other projects so this should be pretty easy
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-15T06:44:45Z'>
		That's great, I supposed you have not posted it yet?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-01-20T19:35:54Z'>
		Please email me if you would like to get the zip file with the model.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-04-01T00:55:26Z'>
		Hi. I'd like to have the models to get the project work please. Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='AKSHAYUBHAT' date='2020-05-25T07:12:08Z'>
		hey, mind sening me the zip file of the models, thanks ~
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>