<bug id='42' author='AdamBrownLab' open_date='2020-01-01T13:44:35Z' closed_time='2020-01-14T20:04:47Z'>
	<summary>Unable to use fit_onecycle on a model I compiled due to optimizer</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying experiment with the onecycle policy of the (AMAZING) ktrain library.
I took the old cats vs dogs via augmentation from keras &lt;denchmark-link:https://blog.keras.io/building-powerful-image-classification-models-using-very-little-data.html&gt;blog &lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/fchollet/0830affa1f7f19fd47b06d4cf89ed44d&gt;https://gist.github.com/fchollet/0830affa1f7f19fd47b06d4cf89ed44d&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and I want to see how the training policy changes the results.
However, the learner.fit_onecycle return the error 'RMSprop' object has no attribute 'beta_1'.
How should I compile my model, to allow onecycle to do its magic?
Is there a way to allow it to override the preexisting optimizer compiled into the model?
It is not possible to compile without an optimizer or to use the ktrain fit_onecycle without first compiling the model.
Many thanks :)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AdamBrownLab' date='2020-01-01T13:55:52Z'>
		Oh, is this because I did not compile the model with the adam optimizer?
It does run when I try it - but are the advantages of the policy are still in effect?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AdamBrownLab' date='2020-01-01T15:11:09Z'>
		By default, fit_onecycle (and autofit) will cycle the momentum along with learning rate for any Adam-like optimizer with beta_1 parameter.  You can use rmsprop if you set cycle_momentum=False in the call to learner.fit_onecycle.  When using RMSProp with cycle_momentum=False, the learning rate will still follow a 1cycle policy, but the momentum won't be cycled.
However, the docstring for fit_oneycyle needs to be corrected and there should probably be a check and perhaps graceful warning instead of a hard error if someone uses an optimizer other than Adam with cycle_momentum=True.  So, I'm marking this as a Bug to be fixed in next release.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AdamBrownLab' date='2020-01-01T15:49:40Z'>
		Glad to be of service, and thank you.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='AdamBrownLab' date='2020-01-14T20:04:47Z'>
		Fixed in 0.8.0 - thanks
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>