<bug id='43' author='Soharic' open_date='2019-01-04T00:36:57Z' closed_time='2019-03-07T18:52:12Z'>
	<summary>Cannot enlarge photos that have spaces in the filename</summary>
	<description>
I've installed Photo Manager to my localhost:8888 and have the thumbnail images with all the current filters working to narrow down the images shown. If I click an image though, it takes me to a random url (different for each photo) which is just a plain black page, so I cannot view my photos enlarged.
For example, a photo labelled "2018-03-13 01 Bournemouth Station Sponsored Sign by Bournemouth University.JPG" takes me to a black screen "&lt;denchmark-link:http://localhost:8888/photo/3259e783-f286-4c36-ae0f-f754f6a4df89&gt;http://localhost:8888/photo/3259e783-f286-4c36-ae0f-f754f6a4df89&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
"
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Soharic' date='2019-01-04T07:19:21Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Soharic&gt;@Soharic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Thanks for the report.
The URI you are getting linked to with a random ID is to be expected - photos get assigned a UUID when they are first imported. This is a React router page that you get to but your image should be displaying scaled and centred on it.
When you get to this page could you right-click and "inpect element" to see if there are any clues? There should be an &lt;denchmark-link:&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tag with a src including the file name. Could possibly be something to do with spaces in the filename or the JPEG not being decodable by the browser. Would be interesting to know if the download is 404ing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Soharic' date='2019-01-04T07:26:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/damianmoore&gt;@damianmoore&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 it would appear to be due to the spaces in the file name. I've since added 3 photos without spaces "20181108_200511.jpg" etc and they all load perfectly well.
From the 'Elements inspection on Chrome' working images have &lt;div class="PhotoDetail" style="background-image: url(&amp;quot;/photos/20181108_200511.jpg&amp;quot;);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; however for images with spaces in the name, this is simply &lt;div class="PhotoDetail"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Soharic' date='2019-01-04T08:20:24Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/damianmoore/photonix/issues/28&gt;#28&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 will eventually alter what image downloads here so should be a bit more robust then.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Soharic' date='2019-01-04T08:22:05Z'>
		Thanks for the update &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Soharic&gt;@Soharic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I'll work on fixing the filename spaces issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Soharic' date='2019-01-04T13:40:44Z'>
		
Thanks for the update @Soharic. I'll work on fixing the filename spaces issue.

Sounds great, thank you! The way I label my photos, they've all got spaces in...
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Soharic' date='2019-03-07T18:52:12Z'>
		Pretty sure this is solved now that all images shown go through the thumbnailer &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Soharic&gt;@Soharic&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>