<bug id='101' author='ngphuoc' open_date='2017-03-23T00:20:38Z' closed_time='2017-10-19T16:03:32Z'>
	<summary>In backpropagation step, the lossgradient dictionary of my model has 1 item missing.</summary>
	<description>
I got this error
update!(model, grads, opts) gives LoadError: weight, gradient, and optimization parameters not the same length
while trying to modify s2s.jl example for a classification problem. There is no error in the forward step but in the backpropagation step, 1 item of the lossgradient dictionary of my model was missing, causing the mentioned error. I will try to post an example causing the error later.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ngphuoc' date='2017-03-23T07:27:29Z'>
		One possible reason is that one of your keys is not used in the computational graph. Therefore, your grads dictionary does not have that key and update! complains about it. If you don't use some of your keys for some instances, you may want to iterate over the keys of grads:
for k in keys(grads)
    update!(model[k], grads[k], opts[k])
end
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ngphuoc' date='2017-03-23T12:39:05Z'>
		We should do this automatically as well.  Let's keep this issue open and
add to the requirements for next release.
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


On Thu, Mar 23, 2017 at 10:27 AM Ozan Arkan Can ***@***.***&gt; wrote:
 One possible reason is that one of your keys is not used in the
 computational graph. Therefore, your grads dictionary does not have that
 key and update! complains about it. If you don't use some of your keys for
 some instances, you may want to iterate over the keys of grads:

 for k in keys(grads)
     update!(model[k], grads[k], opts[k])end

 —
 You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#101 (comment)&gt;,
 or mute the thread
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/ABvNppomDhHWO6kbR3DWRRzbhqdU73aRks5roh7hgaJpZM4Ml_VE&gt;
 .



		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ngphuoc' date='2017-04-18T06:35:47Z'>
		Same problem in KUparser commit: 2a918d5 2017-04-18
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ngphuoc' date='2017-05-17T11:56:06Z'>
		This should be fixed with commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/denizyuret/Knet.jl/commit/f8baef54cc21e579cd6941832fabbffaa65accc0&gt;f8baef5&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 2017-04-18, which will be included in 0.8.3.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>