<bug id='138' author='0xfeedface1993' open_date='2017-12-26T07:37:15Z' closed_time='2018-02-14T17:10:45Z'>
	<summary>Import image data Error: Unsupported PNG color type: 3</summary>
	<description>
This is my image file: &lt;denchmark-link:url&gt;http://oqedp1ccg.bkt.clouddn.com/1xru.png&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

when I try import image data using  api,
console show error:

google not helpful, is that mean need translate PNG to JPEG format?
but API document say support PNG, what PNG format support ?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='0xfeedface1993' date='2017-12-26T10:04:08Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/0xfeedface1993&gt;@0xfeedface1993&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, Thank you for trying out the image analysis toolkit!
The link to your image seems to be broken (or not public). Yet I suspect it might be in RGBA format, which is currently not supported.
Please try the workaround suggested in: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/turicreate/issues/114#issuecomment-352497812&gt;#114 (comment)&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, or if you fail to even load the image try converting it to RGB format first with an external tool.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='0xfeedface1993' date='2017-12-27T01:57:15Z'>
		Sorry about image link, here is right one  &lt;denchmark-link:http://oqedp1ccg.bkt.clouddn.com/1xru.png&gt;image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Thanks to your advice, I'm try external tool like PIL:




&lt;PIL.PngImagePlugin.PngImageFile image mode=P size=300x80 at 0x111A70790&gt;

The image is using sRGB color space (konw by Finder), it is mode P, that will trigger error like

Unsupported PNG color type: 3

But, try this code to generate new image with mode RGBA:
&gt;&gt;&gt; Image.open('1xru.png').convert('RGBA').save('1xru.png')
&gt;&gt;&gt; img = Image.open('1xru.png')
&gt;&gt;&gt; img

&lt;PIL.PngImagePlugin.PngImageFile image mode=RGBA size=300x80 at 0x111A708D0&gt;

After that, turicreate.image_analysis.load_images() work just fine.
is RGBA format not support?
Am I in the right path?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='0xfeedface1993' date='2018-01-02T18:19:10Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/0xfeedface1993&gt;@0xfeedface1993&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
! Thanks for the image, that is really helpful since I am able to reproduce this issue. It looks like we are unable to load PNG images that are saved with an 8-bit palette (that is, a table of 256 colors). Images without color palettes are supported in both RGB and RGBA (RGB + opacity channel), but with RGBA images you can run into issues later (as in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/turicreate/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 with the object detector). Your proposed work-around of using  is a great idea and should work. I would convert it to  though, to make sure you don't trigger &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/turicreate/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I'm really sorry for the inconvenience this is causing!
I will leave this issue open until we have a more permanent fix in place.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='0xfeedface1993' date='2018-01-03T09:43:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gustavla&gt;@gustavla&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - I think that in the current state this will be simply a duplication of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/turicreate/issues/114&gt;#114&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, won't it?
Unless we plan to support also Palette mode in the future.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='0xfeedface1993' date='2018-01-03T20:18:52Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/igiloh&gt;@igiloh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I don't think they are duplicates. It's useful to be able to track the different modes in two separate issues:

#114: RGBA support
#138: P support

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>