<bug id='1914' author='srikris' open_date='2019-05-22T14:57:34Z' closed_time='2019-05-28T17:12:25Z'>
	<summary>API docs missing for image similarity annotations</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Signature: tc.image_classifier.annotate(data, image_column=None, annotation_column='annotations', image_similarity=True)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

No doc strings for image_similarity in the annotation tool.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Docstring:
Annotate your images loaded in either an SFrame or SArray Format

The annotate util is a GUI assisted application used to create labels in
SArray Image data. Specifying a column, with dtype Image, in an SFrame
works as well since SFrames are composed of multiple SArrays.

When the GUI is terminated an SFrame is returned with the representative,
images and annotations.

The returned SFrame includes the newly created annotations.

Parameters
--------------
data : SArray | SFrame
    The data containing the images. If the data type is 'SArray'
    the 'image_column', and 'annotation_column' variables are used to construct
    a new 'SFrame' containing the 'SArray' data for annotation.
    If the data type is 'SFrame' the 'image_column', and 'annotation_column'
    variables are used to annotate the images.

image_column: string, optional
    If the data type is SFrame and the 'image_column' parameter is specified
    then the column name is used as the image column used in the annotation. If
    the data type is 'SFrame' and the 'image_column' variable is left empty. A
    default column value of 'image' is used in the annotation. If the data type is
    'SArray', the 'image_column' is used to construct the 'SFrame' data for
    the annotation

annotation_column : string, optional
    If the data type is SFrame and the 'annotation_column' parameter is specified
    then the column name is used as the annotation column used in the annotation. If
    the data type is 'SFrame' and the 'annotation_column' variable is left empty. A
    default column value of 'annotation' is used in the annotation. If the data type is
    'SArray', the 'annotation_column' is used to construct the 'SFrame' data for
    the annotation
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='srikris' date='2019-05-23T01:28:12Z'>
		I think we should consider changing the parameter name as well. image_similarity=True doesn't really capture the intent of this parameter -- maybe we want something like prioritize_by_similar_images=True.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='srikris' date='2019-05-23T22:09:14Z'>
		Triage: let's err on the side of not exposing API if it doesn't really help the user. What's the use case for disabling image similarity, and how do users know when to disable it? (If we can't answer these questions, perhaps we shouldn't have this parameter at all.)
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='srikris' date='2019-05-28T17:12:25Z'>
		Fixed with &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/apple/turicreate/commit/c76bd40e2ce5ccf18414d5ec79c3befa55f0255f&gt;c76bd40&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>