<bug id='2244' author='MaximBazarov' open_date='2019-08-15T11:54:12Z' closed_time='2020-09-07T18:11:18Z'>
	<summary>OSOD logging output don't appear during process (5.7)</summary>
	<description>
Hi there, trying to use version 5.7, and want to thank y'all for all that fixes, now it works in Google Colab as well on CUDA 100.
Only one concern I found so far it that's the logs I have during the model creation process from the augmented images
Setting 'batch_size' to 32
Using GPU to create model (Tesla T4)
Setting 'max_iterations' to 5000
+--------------+--------------+--------------+
| Iteration    | Loss         | Elapsed Time |
+--------------+--------------+--------------+
| 1            | 5.738        | 17.7         |
| 13           | 5.218        | 28.2         |
and it's working, I can see that, but there's no output for quite some minutes.
For me, it's important learning, what's the capacity of this approach.
Could you please take a look at it?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1GaJLOhdrN-OG8zsL4vgo-wBcqJh6CPYv#scrollTo=6Q6YYscrpqmw&amp;line=6&amp;uniqifier=1&gt;Here's the code&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MaximBazarov' date='2019-08-15T14:19:15Z'>
		Still no logs btw, using only one image as a source
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MaximBazarov' date='2019-08-15T18:14:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MaximBazarov&gt;@MaximBazarov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - I'm glad to hear you are liking 5.7. I'm not understand the issue. Is the problem that you are not seeing any output for several minutes once you call ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MaximBazarov' date='2019-08-15T18:28:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/TobyRoseman&gt;@TobyRoseman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes, for several hours, the notepad is busy, GPU is working, but no output at all. Basically, the last output I saw is that in the first message.
It might be an issue with Google Collab though, not sure tbh, sorry can't provide more information.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MaximBazarov' date='2020-08-31T22:16:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MaximBazarov&gt;@MaximBazarov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - Is this still an issue with the most recent version TuriCreate?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='MaximBazarov' date='2020-09-07T07:16:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/TobyRoseman&gt;@TobyRoseman&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes, it works! Thank you very much!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>