<bug id='1072' author='robin-maillot' open_date='2020-10-01T12:30:57Z' closed_time='2020-11-12T00:31:00Z'>
	<summary>Error with pytorch requirement</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

When trying to install locally by running pip install -r requirements.txt the following error can occur depending on the CUDA version installed:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ERROR: Could not find a version that satisfies the requirement torch&gt;=1.6.0 (from -r requirements.txt (line 12)) (from versions: 0.1.2, 0.1.2.post1, 0.1.2.post2)
ERROR: No matching distribution found for torch&gt;=1.6.0 (from -r requirements.txt (line 12))
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Running  then  (as specified by pytorch &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&gt;here&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) solved this for me.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Trying to install in a fresh environment in Windows with CUDA 10.1
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Update readme to remove previous CUDA versions or give info on this error.
I think this is an issue with pytorch which requires specifique commands to install depending on environment so I'm not sure there is much you can do.
It would be nice to be able to run pip install -r requirements.txt without having preinstalled pytorch if possible.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OS: Windows
GPU RTX 2060
CUDA: 10.1

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-01T12:31:45Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/robin-maillot&gt;@robin-maillot&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-01T12:55:04Z'>
		For me adding --find-links https://download.pytorch.org/whl/torch_stable.html to the requirements file also worked but I am not sure o the unexpected consequences...
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-04T17:30:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/robin-maillot&gt;@robin-maillot&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes, torch installation specifics may vary depending on your OS and cuda version. For exact instructions see &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&gt;https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-05T09:36:03Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I think adding the following to the top of the requirements.txt would solve this issue and make it easier for people to install the requirements for yolov5?

Right now the error is kind of confusing and there is nothing in the readme about pytorch installation. Maybe adding the pytorch installation link to the readme would be good for people who have never installed pytorch, I know I wasted an hour or so researching the error.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-05T09:46:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/robin-maillot&gt;@robin-maillot&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 torch installations may always need a bit of finetuning to specific scenarios. In our CI tests for example, which run on a CPU-only instance, we specify a CPU-only installation of torch:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/actions/runs/288465315/workflow#L44-L51&gt;https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/actions/runs/288465315/workflow#L44-L51&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

      - name: Install dependencies
        run: |
          python -m pip install --upgrade pip
          pip install -qr requirements.txt -f https://download.pytorch.org/whl/cpu/torch_stable.html
          pip install -q onnx
          python --version
          pip --version
          pip list
Also if you have legacy CUDA installations those need to be specified as shown in linux install commands, i.e.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&gt;https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


Windows commands will also differ, so there's really no one size fits all solution. The presented solutions are mainly directed to linux users with the latest version of cuda, which can simply use the default pip install torch commands.
We could consider adding this link if it was robust to installations across all operating systems (linux, macos, windows) and all hardware configurations (CUDA, CPU only). Would it be possible for you to test these cases and and then submit a PR with what you find to work best?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-10-06T12:49:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I will have a look this week but can you give me a bit more information about the installation conditions:

Do you need the user to be able to install a CPU version when running on a machine with a gpu available? Or is the CPU only needed when no GPU is available?

For me (with outdated CUDA versions due to tensorflow requirements) I did not have to run the command recommended by pytorch simply running pip install torch -f https://download.pytorch.org/whl/torch_stable.html worked. I have not tested this with CUDA&lt;10.1 but I can try this weekend.
A quick fix could be just to add the pytorch link (&lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&gt;https://pytorch.org/get-started/locally/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) in the readme and warn the user that there might can be issues with previous cuda versions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='robin-maillot' date='2020-11-06T00:32:41Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>