<bug id='1372' author='glenn-jocher' open_date='2020-11-12T11:18:11Z' closed_time='2020-12-08T15:32:22Z'>
	<summary>W&amp;B Bug in Kaggle Notebook</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

It is impossible to select a W&amp;B option in the Kaggle notebook when training (on Chrome at least, other browsers not tested). This problem is compounded by the fact that wandb appears to be a default package in the kaggle notebook environment, meaning the issue is impossible to avoid by default. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AyushExel&gt;@AyushExel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you take a look at this please?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/98933416-e0ef8580-24e0-11eb-8ae8-a20e9f950715.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Run Setup cell
Run Train cell here and try to select a W&amp;B option

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/98933367-d1703c80-24e0-11eb-9981-fbf0b1043e9b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.kaggle.com/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;https://www.kaggle.com/ultralytics/yolov5&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-11-12T11:27:21Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 seems like a kaggle kernel specific problem. This doesn't happen on colab. There's a simple workaround that I just tested. Calling  manually solves this problem.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15766192/98934437-18bdf380-2508-11eb-8c17-9d791ccd9af3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-11-22T11:23:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AyushExel&gt;@AyushExel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 what do you think the best way to handle this is uniformly between the Colab and Kaggle notebooks? We need to maintain a single base notebook for reduced maintenance.
I was thinking maybe a seperate code block before train, that would install and init with a single click?
In any case you probably want to pass this failure mode up to the maintainers of the login code to see if they can get this working natively in kaggle also.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-11-22T12:10:53Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes a separate init block before training would be the way to go for now. I'll pass this on to the maintainers. Right now the team is busy launching this &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.wandb.com/datasets-and-predictions&gt;awesome dataset visualization feature&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that I told you about. But this will be fixed as soon as they're done with the launch.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-11-22T19:39:23Z'>
		Saving this here, can be inlined after existing # Start tensorboard (optional) cell.
# Start Weights &amp; Biases (optional)
%pip install -q wandb  #  use 'wandb disable'/'wandb enable' to turn off/on
!wandb login  
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-12-08T15:32:22Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AyushExel&gt;@AyushExel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I tested the Kaggle notebook again and this bug is resolved now :)
It appears that wandb is no longer a default installed package in their notebook environment, so the model trains without asking for a wandb login now. When I try to install wandb though I'm not able to paste in my key still. This happens to me in Chrome, I have not tested other browsers. The same op works fine in the Colab notebook, but Kaggle in particular seems to have issues with their UI when it comes to inserting values at prompts. Have you been able to complete this login in a kaggle notebook?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26833433/101503923-7e46a980-3927-11eb-9616-ed3be1214ecb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-12-08T15:39:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/glenn-jocher&gt;@glenn-jocher&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'll file a ticket today to get this fixed. I filed them for media panel viewing error and Recursion depth error but this error slipped out of my mind.
Also, I needed help with a  code snippet from yolo repo. Can you please check your slack?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='glenn-jocher' date='2020-12-08T18:20:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AyushExel&gt;@AyushExel&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 great, thanks! I just arrived in California, I have to take care of a few things, but I will get back on Slack later today.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>