<bug id='231' author='kidhasmoxy' open_date='2020-06-29T14:50:04Z' closed_time='2020-06-30T23:21:22Z'>
	<summary>Docker Images Require Unreleased Linux Drivers</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

CUDA acceleration is not available when using the Docker images as the Dockerfile was updated to use 20.06-py3, which relies on Nvidia Drivers that not past release candidate/ beta stage.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Attempt to start Docker image and you will see errors on platform support and how only CPU will be supported
Output:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ERROR: This container was built for NVIDIA Driver Release 450.36 or later, but
       version 440.100 was detected and compatibility mode is UNAVAILABLE.
       [[CUDA Driver UNAVAILABLE (cuInit(0) returned 804)]]
NOTE: MOFED driver for multi-node communication was not detected.
      Multi-node communication performance may be reduced.
Using CPU
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

GPU Acceleration is available on a stable channel released driver.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.

OS: Ubuntu 18.04 host
GPU Quadro P2000

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Additional context&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Do we need any of the capabilities provided in the latest image or can we revert to the previous one, which depends on the latest stable driver release?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='kidhasmoxy' date='2020-06-29T14:50:42Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kidhasmoxy&gt;@kidhasmoxy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='kidhasmoxy' date='2020-06-29T17:14:56Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kidhasmoxy&gt;@kidhasmoxy&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the feedback! The 20.06 image was tested on a GCP VM without issue. Just in case though we've reverted the yolov5:latest image to 20.03. You should be able to pull this image now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='kidhasmoxy' date='2020-09-02T15:14:48Z'>
		I also have this problem with Nvidia driver release 440.100 which is the default driver provided by ubuntu-desktop-20.04.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>