<bug id='252' author='LVROBOT' open_date='2020-07-01T03:18:45Z' closed_time='2020-07-01T04:44:01Z'>
	<summary>What is the difference between --resume and --weights ？</summary>
	<description>
I want to load a trained model，Should I use  --resume or --weights ？
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;parser.add_argument('--resume', action='store_true', help='resume training from last.pt')
parser.add_argument('--weights', type=str, default='', help='initial weights path）
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='LVROBOT' date='2020-07-01T03:19:26Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LVROBOT&gt;@LVROBOT&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='LVROBOT' date='2020-07-01T04:44:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LVROBOT&gt;@LVROBOT&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 --resume will resume from last.pt automatically, unless --weights are specified, in which case it will resume from the specified weights.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='LVROBOT' date='2020-11-04T12:46:24Z'>
		I am a newbie I want to know if I have trained a model say for 100 epochs and I want to restart the training from the 100th epoch will the --resume argument help?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='LVROBOT' date='2020-11-04T13:00:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/h0oni&gt;@h0oni&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 --resume is  intended for interrupted trainings. Use case is you train with default settings. Your machine restarts after 100 epochs. You use this command to continue training with your original settings:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;python train.py --resume
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>