<bug id='274' author='karanjakhar' open_date='2020-07-03T05:35:17Z' closed_time='2020-08-22T00:33:28Z'>
	<summary>Can't convert to CoreML</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;TypeError: Error while converting op of type: Slice. Error message: Input shape not available 
 Please try converting with higher minimum_ios_deployment_target.
You can also provide custom function/layer to convert the model.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Conversion from yolov5s to onnx is smooth. But when I try to convert onnx to CoreML then above error occurs. Please help. Any guide how to use these models on ios.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='karanjakhar' date='2020-07-03T05:35:54Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karanjakhar&gt;@karanjakhar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='karanjakhar' date='2020-07-07T18:28:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/karanjakhar&gt;@karanjakhar&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 we have updated  a bit to better support the 3 export channels (ONNX, TorchScript and CoreML).  See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/issues/251&gt;#251&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for a tutorial on how to use export.py. Note that export.py is mainly a guide that provides simple first steps for users like yourself to begin creating your own export pipelines though, it does not provide end-to-end export functionality.
We do offer paid end-to-end export services however, as well as providing reference apps for iOS and Android to use your exported models in. If you have a business idea for YOLOv5 at the edge, we'd be happy to help you get started! You can email &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:glenn.jocher@ultralytics.com&gt;glenn.jocher@ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for details if interested.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='karanjakhar' date='2020-07-17T14:49:54Z'>
		
TypeError: Error while converting op of type: Slice. Error message: Input shape not available 
 Please try converting with higher minimum_ios_deployment_target.
You can also provide custom function/layer to convert the model.

Conversion from yolov5s to onnx is smooth. But when I try to convert onnx to CoreML then above error occurs. Please help. Any guide how to use these models on ios.

help me if you figured out the problem!!
Thanks in advance!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='karanjakhar' date='2020-08-17T00:33:14Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>