<bug id='356' author='craine' open_date='2020-07-10T21:51:39Z' closed_time='2020-07-11T22:35:44Z'>
	<summary>Train and Test Batch images not being produced today?</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I was running custom data and notebook and my batch images stopped running and was giving me errors. I figured it was something I did, but then I opened your colabs tutorial and tried to run that and I'm seeing the same thing happen. Maybe this is all me but I cannot get train* jpgs to work for any test.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

This is what I'm running after training in my custom notebooks which have been running for weeks and in tutorial that you created.
Image(filename='./train_batch1.jpg', width=900)  # view augmented training mosaics
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;
Output:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
FileNotFoundError                         Traceback (most recent call last)
&lt;ipython-input-10-bf672b25fc38&gt; in &lt;module&gt;()
----&gt; 1 Image(filename='./train_batch1.jpg', width=900)  # view augmented training mosaics

3 frames
/usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/IPython/core/display.py in reload(self)
    629         """Reload the raw data from file or URL."""
    630         if self.filename is not None:
--&gt; 631             with open(self.filename, self._read_flags) as f:
    632                 self.data = f.read()
    633         elif self.url is not None:

FileNotFoundError: [Errno 2] No such file or directory: './train_batch1.jpg'


## Expected behavior
Expecting to see images or files in my directory but they are not there. 

## Environment
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.

Colabs Pro
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='craine' date='2020-07-10T21:52:26Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/craine&gt;@craine&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='craine' date='2020-07-11T03:49:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/craine&gt;@craine&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you, yes we have a current bug in the notebooks due to a recent PR. The good news is things are a bit more organized now, so your train*.jpg and all associated training images, weights, results etc are grouped into their own runs/experiment folder.
TLDR, will fix notebook tutorials soon, your training images etc are all now located in runs/exp0, runs/exp1, etc.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='craine' date='2020-07-11T03:50:07Z'>
		TODO: update notebooks to conform to new runs/exp structure.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='craine' date='2020-07-11T22:35:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/craine&gt;@craine&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 colab and kaggle notebooks are now updated and correct. Will close as resolved now. Please let me know if there are any further issues.

Google Colab Notebook with free GPU: 
Kaggle Notebook with free GPU: https://www.kaggle.com/ultralytics/yolov5

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>