<bug id='47' author='ggyybb' open_date='2020-06-13T02:36:21Z' closed_time='2020-08-10T00:32:27Z'>
	<summary>train.py error</summary>
	<description>
when i run train.py, i get this error:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/61568153/84557931-8f8c7000-ad61-11ea-869b-00293edbf140.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

datasets have been loaded
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ggyybb' date='2020-06-13T02:36:56Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ggyybb&gt;@ggyybb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ggyybb' date='2020-06-13T02:44:29Z'>
		i have solve it, i add a row in utils.py after 470 line, convert gij to float type, i want to know am i right?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/61568153/84558104-d9298a80-ad62-11ea-97ad-0e0b3ff37197.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ggyybb' date='2020-06-13T02:45:06Z'>
		
i have solve it, i add a row in utils.py after 470 line, convert gij to float type, i want to know am i right?


it worked.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ggyybb' date='2020-06-13T04:10:14Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ggyybb&gt;@ggyybb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that's odd, you should not need to modify any code to train. If your issue is reproducible in a common environment like colab or our docker image, we can take a look. Otherwise it may simply be your environment.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ggyybb' date='2020-06-13T04:11:07Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ggyybb&gt;@ggyybb&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I'll paste you links to working environments here just in case.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Reproduce Our Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

To access an up-to-date working environment (with all dependencies including CUDA/CUDNN, Python and PyTorch preinstalled), consider a:

GCP Deep Learning VM with $300 free credit offer: See our GCP Quickstart Guide
Google Colab Notebook with 12 hours of free GPU time. 
Docker Image https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5. See Docker Quickstart Guide

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ggyybb' date='2020-08-01T05:24:33Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>