<bug id='483' author='willa2016' open_date='2020-07-23T07:27:14Z' closed_time='2020-09-05T01:06:37Z'>
	<summary>libtorch import error</summary>
	<description>
I export the torchscript successfully throw export.py .but find that it cannot be loaded correctlly by libtorch(cpp)，I am sure that I used the libtorch(cpp) correctly because I had loaded other detection  models correctly.
the bug shows when :
module = torch:jit:load(“xxx.torchscript”)
torch::jit::script::ErrorReport at memory location 0x000000FED9AF0190
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='willa2016' date='2020-07-23T07:27:57Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/willa2016&gt;@willa2016&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note that Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='willa2016' date='2020-07-30T19:50:28Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/willa2016&gt;@willa2016&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I am able to load the torchscript model in my c++ application without any issue, just FYI my env is PyTorch 1.5.1, libtorch 1.5.1 and CUDA 10.2.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='willa2016' date='2020-08-31T00:19:12Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>