<bug id='542' author='AlexWang1900' open_date='2020-07-28T14:07:58Z' closed_time='2020-07-29T01:56:02Z'>
	<summary>best.pt not saved when it is from the last epoch</summary>
	<description>
Before submitting a bug report, please be aware that your issue must be reproducible with all of the following, otherwise it is non-actionable, and we can not help you:

Current repo: run git fetch &amp;&amp; git status -uno to check and git pull to update repo
Common dataset: coco.yaml or coco128.yaml
Common environment: Colab, Google Cloud, or Docker image. See https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5#reproduce-our-environment

If this is a custom dataset/training question you must include your train*.jpg, test*.jpg and results.png figures, or we can not help you. You can generate these with utils.plot_results().
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

in train.py line: 390
```
if (best_fitness == fi) and not final_epoch:  ###
torch.save(ckpt, best)
del ckpt
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;when the last epoch happens to have a best fitness,  it wouldn't save a best.pt,
the code outside the train.py cannot judge which .pt  is the best.  


## To Reproduce (REQUIRED)

train one epoch from an interrupted traning's  last.pt , or the best result happens to be in the last epoch.

Output:
"couldn't find best.pt" or load a wrong best.pt. (should be last.pt in this situation)

## Expected behavior
A clear and concise description of what you expected to happen.
when training compeletes, one can load best.pt as it is the best result.


## Environment
If applicable, add screenshots to help explain your problem.

 - OS: [e.g. Ubuntu]
 - GPU [e.g. 2080 Ti]


## Additional context
Add any other context about the problem here.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='AlexWang1900' date='2020-07-28T18:20:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/AlexWang1900&gt;@AlexWang1900&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes, good point! I do believe you've found a bug. Would you like to submit a PR or should I include this in the next push?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='AlexWang1900' date='2020-07-29T00:35:33Z'>
		I'd Like to summit a PR!
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


---Original---
From: "Glenn Jocher"&lt;notifications@github.com&amp;gt;
Date: Wed, Jul 29, 2020 02:21 AM
To: "ultralytics/yolov5"&lt;yolov5@noreply.github.com&amp;gt;;
Cc: "Mention"&lt;mention@noreply.github.com&amp;gt;;"AlexWang1900"&lt;41888506@qq.com&amp;gt;;
Subject: Re: [ultralytics/yolov5] best.pt not saved when it is from the last epoch (#542)





@AlexWang1900 yes, good point! I do believe you've found a bug. Would you like to submit a PR or should I include this in the next push?

—
You are receiving this because you were mentioned.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub, or unsubscribe.

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='AlexWang1900' date='2020-08-05T19:50:32Z'>
		Issue resolved, removing TODO.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>