<bug id='566' author='gizemtanriver' open_date='2020-07-30T11:29:06Z' closed_time='2020-08-01T22:10:05Z'>
	<summary>TypeError: must be real number, not str with evolve</summary>
	<description>
Hi, thanks for this amazing repo first of all!
I am working with the v2.0 release of the repo and so far I got quite promising results on my custom dataset. I tried to use --evolve today but I am getting a TypeError from the print_mutation function in utils.py at the end of the first run. It seems to be related to 'SGD' in hyp dictionary - which is a string. I see that the optimizer parameter was added to the dict in v2.0 so I guess this wasn't an issue in the previous release.
Input:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;!python yolov5/train.py --img 512 --batch 16 --epochs 100 --yolov5/data/custom_data.yaml \
    --cfg yolov5/models/custom_yolov5s.yaml \
    --weights yolov5/weights/yolov5s.pt --cache --evolve
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Output:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Traceback (most recent call last):
  File "yolov5/train.py", line 516, in &lt;module&gt;
    print_mutation(hyp, results, opt.bucket)
  File "/content/drive/.shortcut-targets-by-id/1hQ281-8ogL2dJzHbXZSWEYDIYei6RRbe/YOLOv5/yolov5/utils/utils.py", line 830, in print_mutation
    b = '%10.3g' * len(hyp) % tuple(hyp.values())  # hyperparam values
TypeError: must be real number, not str
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='gizemtanriver' date='2020-07-30T11:29:58Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gizemtanriver&gt;@gizemtanriver&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='gizemtanriver' date='2020-07-30T19:14:19Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gizemtanriver&gt;@gizemtanriver&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 hi, thank you for the bug report. Yes you are correct, --evolve is currently out of order due to recent PRs. It's on a long list of TODOs. I can not give you an ETA. In the meantime it's inoperable.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='gizemtanriver' date='2020-08-01T22:10:05Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/gizemtanriver&gt;@gizemtanriver&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 this bug should be fixed now. Let me know if you find otherwise.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>