<bug id='698' author='Ramarjohn' open_date='2020-08-10T15:17:05Z' closed_time='2020-09-15T00:38:42Z'>
	<summary>After completing training detect part will show that error</summary>
	<description>
i have to training the own image dataset used training model. but  detect.py file show that error below mentioned
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/47788261/89798989-8b56b600-db4a-11ea-8a58-8020494038d8.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

please give prepare solution and reason for that error,,
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Ramarjohn' date='2020-08-10T15:17:48Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Ramarjohn&gt;@Ramarjohn&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Ramarjohn' date='2020-08-10T15:20:37Z'>
		Hi, you spelled the model wrong. It is not yolov5.pt. You can find the four models on the main page. yolov5s.pt, yolov5m.pt, yolov5l.pt, yolov5x.pt.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Ramarjohn' date='2020-09-10T00:35:51Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>