<bug id='702' author='snovire' open_date='2020-08-11T01:58:01Z' closed_time='2020-08-12T00:59:09Z'>
	<summary>bug in utils of version 2</summary>
	<description>
Hello, I just upgraded from original version into v2, the requirements of environment have been all pip installed successfully. The former version worked well but the v2 got the error when I tried to train:
File "C:\yolov5\utils\datasets.py", line 13, in 
from PIL import Image, ExifTags
File "C:\Users\jliu0134.MONASH\AppData\Local\Continuum\anaconda3\lib\site-packages\PIL\Image.py", line 93, in 
from . import _imaging as core
ImportError: DLL load failed: The specified module could not be found.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/49724561/89848963-102ce880-dbba-11ea-869b-5857a7753235.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='snovire' date='2020-08-11T01:58:41Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/snovire&gt;@snovire&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='snovire' date='2020-08-11T02:33:23Z'>
		Hello, thank you for your interest in our work! This issue seems to lack the minimum requirements for a proper response, or is insufficiently detailed for us to help you. Please note that most technical problems are due to:

Your changes to the default repository. If your issue is not reproducible in a new git clone version of this repository we can not debug it. Before going further run this code and ensure your issue persists:

sudo rm -rf yolov5  # remove existing
git clone https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5 &amp;&amp; cd yolov5 # clone latest
python detect.py  # verify detection
# CODE TO REPRODUCE YOUR ISSUE HERE


Your custom data. If your issue is not reproducible with COCO or COCO128 data we can not debug it. Visit our Custom Training Tutorial for guidelines on training your custom data. Examine train_batch0.jpg and test_batch0.jpg for a sanity check of training and testing data.


Your environment. If your issue is not reproducible in one of the verified environments below we can not debug it. If you are running YOLOv5 locally, ensure your environment meets all of the requirements.txt dependencies specified below.


If none of these apply to you, we suggest you close this issue and raise a new one using the Bug Report template, providing screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue. Thank you!
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Python 3.8 or later with all &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/requirements.txt&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 dependencies installed, including . To install run:
$ pip install -r requirements.txt
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environments&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

YOLOv5 may be run in any of the following up-to-date verified environments (with all dependencies including &lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda&gt;CUDA&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
/&lt;denchmark-link:https://developer.nvidia.com/cudnn&gt;CUDNN&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.python.org/&gt;Python&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://pytorch.org/&gt;PyTorch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 preinstalled):

Google Colab Notebook with free GPU: 
Kaggle Notebook with free GPU: https://www.kaggle.com/ultralytics/yolov5
Google Cloud Deep Learning VM. See GCP Quickstart Guide
Docker Image https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5. See Docker Quickstart Guide 

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Status&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/workflows/CI%20CPU%20testing/badge.svg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If this badge is green, all &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/actions&gt;YOLOv5 GitHub Actions&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Continuous Integration (CI) tests are passing. These tests evaluate proper operation of basic YOLOv5 functionality, including training (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/train.py&gt;train.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), testing (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/test.py&gt;test.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), inference (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/detect.py&gt;detect.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) and export (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/models/export.py&gt;export.py&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
) on MacOS, Windows, and Ubuntu.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>