<bug id='885' author='Wufang1997' open_date='2020-08-31T08:59:09Z' closed_time='2020-09-02T02:14:06Z'>
	<summary>"__getitem__" in LoadImagesAndLabels class</summary>
	<description>
Hi, YOLOv5 team, I found something weird and unreasonable in the definition of getitem in LoadImagesAndLabels class. Though it's a tiny mistake, I suppose you can mix it and make the code better. The question is that once I turned image_weights=True, the model couldn't be trained as expected.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;🐛 Bug&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The following part does not work, since "self.indices" is not defined previously.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    if self.image_weights:
        index = self.indices[index]
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce (REQUIRED)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Input:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;image_weights=True
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Output:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;AttributeError: 'LoadImagesAndLabels' object has no attribute 'indices'
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Can we delete these codes immediately or please assign some values to 'indices'?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Wufang1997' date='2020-08-31T09:00:02Z'>
		Hello &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Wufang1997&gt;@Wufang1997&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thank you for your interest in our work! Please visit our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/Train-Custom-Data&gt;Custom Training Tutorial&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to get started, and see our &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://colab.research.google.com/github/ultralytics/yolov5/blob/master/tutorial.ipynb&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/r/ultralytics/yolov5&gt;Docker Image&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/wiki/GCP-Quickstart&gt;Google Cloud Quickstart Guide&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 for example environments.
If this is a bug report, please provide screenshots and minimum viable code to reproduce your issue, otherwise we can not help you.
If this is a custom model or data training question, please note Ultralytics does not provide free personal support. As a leader in vision ML and AI, we do offer professional consulting, from simple expert advice up to delivery of fully customized, end-to-end production solutions for our clients, such as:

Cloud-based AI systems operating on hundreds of HD video streams in realtime.
Edge AI integrated into custom iOS and Android apps for realtime 30 FPS video inference.
Custom data training, hyperparameter evolution, and model exportation to any destination.

For more information please visit &lt;denchmark-link:https://www.ultralytics.com&gt;https://www.ultralytics.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Wufang1997' date='2020-08-31T12:48:57Z'>
		I am facing the same issue
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Wufang1997' date='2020-08-31T17:34:09Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Wufang1997&gt;@Wufang1997&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yazeedhasan97&gt;@yazeedhasan97&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thanks for the bug report. An argparser argument for enabling weighted image training appears to have been accidentally deleted in a past PR. Commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ultralytics/yolov5/commit/69ff781ca5fa995ce2eeae215a486ab9f7ff566c&gt;69ff781&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 should resolve this (DDP section may need rework). Please git pull and try again. To enable weighted image training:
python train.py --img-weights 
This will select image for training according to their image weights rather than randomly or sequentially selecting them in the dataloader. Image weights are computed as the inverse mAPs of the labelled objects they contain. mAPs obtained from previous epoch's testing. The intended effect is selection more often for images containing problematic classes.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>