<bug id='13' author='zhaishengfu' open_date='2017-05-06T06:53:06Z' closed_time='2017-05-10T13:42:00Z'>
	<summary>QMetaMethod::invoke: Unable to invoke methods with return values in queued connections</summary>
	<description>
thank you for sharing. I compiled successfully but when i run either from video or images, it will stop at such line:
Starting pose estimation demo.
init done
opengl support available
Starting thread(s)
QMetaMethod::invoke: Unable to invoke methods with return values in queued connections
So, what is the problem?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zhaishengfu' date='2017-05-06T16:44:35Z'>
		Hi, I just though of a possible cause! Could you try this and let us know whether it works?

Delete examples/openpose/rtpose.cpp.
Instead, replace it with this slightly modified version from my Dropbox: https://www.dropbox.com/s/kgdtw6d0edn7e8v/rtpose.cpp?dl=0.
On the main folder: make clean &amp;&amp; make all -j8 (assuming a 8-core machine, no need to do it in 3rdparty/caffe).
Try again the same example and command line instruction that you used.

Please, post us whether that solution works and the program output now!
Otherwise, this is the same issue as &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CMU-Perceptual-Computing-Lab/openpose/issues/4&gt;#4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (even if the warning it outputs you is slightly different). You can apply the same solution I posted there. We are trying to find the error meanwhile and your feed-back on the previous possible solution might help us a lot! So please, let us know whether the 1st (and 2nd) solution work!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zhaishengfu' date='2017-05-07T08:18:12Z'>
		Thank you. I used your new rtpose.cpp and now I Can use it correctly. more precisely, the following 3 can run well:
1 ./build/examples/openpose/rtpose.bin --video examples/media/video.avi
2 ./build/examples/openpose/rtpose.bin
3.1_extract_from_image
**But when i compile using debug mode, there are still errors with:
terminate called after throwing an instance of 'std::runtime_error'
what():
Error:
Cuda check failed (7 vs. 0): too many resources requested for launch
Coming from:

src/openpose/pose/poseRenderGpu.cu:renderPoseGpu():439
src/openpose/pose/poseRenderGpu.cu:renderPoseGpu():444
src/openpose/pose/poseRenderer.cpp:renderPose():285**

So Why This happen? and Why the release can work? Could you tell me what is my problem?? what is the core difference with these 2 files?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='zhaishengfu' date='2017-05-07T13:41:56Z'>
		Thank you for your feed-back! I've just added the new fixed rtpose to the repository as default rtpose.
About debug mode, I guess debug mode loads more data to help debug. Before replying you, could you let me know your hardware characteristics? In particular:
Operating system (lsb_release -a on Ubuntu):
CUDA version (cat /usr/local/cuda/version.txt in most cases):
cuDNN version:
GPU model (nvidia-smi):
Compiler (gcc --version on Ubuntu):
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='zhaishengfu' date='2017-05-08T06:32:43Z'>
		Ok, My hardare is :
operating system:
Distributor ID:	Ubuntu
Description:	Ubuntu 14.04.3 LTS
Release:	14.04
Codename:	trusty
CUDA version
CUDA Version 8.0.27
cudnn version
cudnn8.0
GPU
GTX-1070
and my cpu is 4 core
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='zhaishengfu' date='2017-05-10T13:42:00Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/zhaishengfu&gt;@zhaishengfu&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, since your last question is a different topic than the previous one, I am moving it to a new thread so new people can find it easily: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CMU-Perceptual-Computing-Lab/openpose/issues/19&gt;#19&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Let me know in the new issue thread your cuDNN version (you said cudnn8.0, but the newest version is 6).
Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>