<bug id='903' author='diepgfai' open_date='2018-10-29T12:21:33Z' closed_time='2018-11-02T17:28:06Z'>
	<summary>dllexport dllimport template functions not works</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Errors:   "LNK2001	unresolved external symbol "__declspec(dllimport) float __cdecl op::getAverageScore  .... "&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

OpenPose version: Latest GitHub code
I have just updated openpose library and re-compiled it succesfully. Though I cannot compile my application which uses openpose library. AFAIK, template functions in keypoint.hpp cannot be dllexport. Hence the compiler does not find the function in openpose.lib.
I'm using VS2015, Enterprises Update 3. My application did work with the old openpose library which has no template in keypoint.hpp.
I really appreciate any help.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='diepgfai' date='2018-10-29T14:52:04Z'>
		My VS2015 U3 can compile it with no problem (using latest OP code), I am not sure why it doesn't in your case, but if it is compiled successfully, the issue is coming from your custom application, because the examples link the library as external library, so if they work, OpenPose library can be exported successfully. About the templates question you raised, these templates can be dllexported because they are defined in a cpp file.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='diepgfai' date='2018-10-29T15:01:08Z'>
		I tried to add one of the functions in keypoint.hpp in the code of your C++ examples, but it has the same linker error. So I think it is not just the issue of my custom application.
Can you try adding for example the function getKeypointsRectangle in one of your example code and test it?
BTW, thanks for your quick reply.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='diepgfai' date='2018-10-29T15:05:27Z'>
		OK I will try that later (I don't have a Windows machine until I get back home). BTW, that function is only defined for float and double, are you using a different type?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='diepgfai' date='2018-10-29T15:10:46Z'>
		That would be great. Really appreciate your help.
And I just use float for these functions.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='diepgfai' date='2018-11-01T10:11:54Z'>
		Would you please confirm if it works or not? If not I will have to find a workaround for this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='diepgfai' date='2018-11-02T17:28:06Z'>
		Sorry, I was trying to fix the error before posting back. Please, try the latest commit that solves it.
And thanks for the catch! It was an error hard to find given that it requires to be explicitly used on the examples (this error was actually happening in all template functions from keypoints.hpp and string.hpp, not only on this one).
Let me know if there is any further issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>