<bug id='1061' author='zburning' open_date='2019-12-18T16:02:26Z' closed_time='2019-12-19T02:36:06Z'>
	<summary>Problem with gluon.utils.split_data</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The current gluon.utils.split_data() has:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;step = size // num_slice

# If size &lt; num_slice, make fewer slices
if not even_split and size &lt; num_slice:
        step = 1
        num_slice = size

if batch_axis == 0:
        slices = [data[i*step:(i+1)*step] if i &lt; num_slice - 1 else data[i*step:size]
                  for i in range(num_slice)]
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Considering an example:
we have a tensor of shape (31, *), and we want to split it into 8 slices. According to the function, step will be (31 // 8 = 3), so that the tensor will be split into 8 tensors of size [3, 3 ,3 ,3 ,3 ,3, 3, 10], in which the last tensor is extremely large. A better result could be [4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 3]
In many cases, we will have a batch size for model, for example, 32, and we wish each gpu to have a tensor of size 4. But within bucket sampler or in the last batch, it could be smaller, as exampled above, 31, then a tensor of size 10 can be to large in this case.
So I suggest to have step_size = ceil(size / num_slice), then the last slice will always be smaller.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Error Message&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(Paste the complete error message, including stack trace.)
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;To Reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(If you developed your own code, please provide a short script that reproduces the error. For existing examples, please provide link.)
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

(Paste the commands you ran that produced the error.)




&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;What have you tried to solve it?&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;





&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Environment&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

We recommend using our script for collecting the diagnositc information. Run the following command and paste the outputs below:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;curl --retry 10 -s https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dmlc/gluon-nlp/master/tools/diagnose.py | python

# paste outputs here
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='zburning' date='2019-12-19T00:16:30Z'>
		Should this be an issue in the MXNet repo?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='zburning' date='2019-12-19T02:36:05Z'>
		Yes, sorry, I will close this issue and move to the MXNet repo
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>