<bug id='2433' author='happyjin' open_date='2020-09-08T07:38:09Z' closed_time='2020-09-08T23:11:38Z'>
	<summary>Error: in data/train, recording-ids extracted from segments and wav.scp</summary>
	<description>
I got an error during stage 1 of run.sh using hkust dataset. The error message is as below:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/18534928/92446945-2e9df800-f1e9-11ea-8b75-3cc47c627fb8.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Is there anybody who knows how to figure out this error? Thanks in advance!
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T07:57:28Z'>
		Hi,
You already opened the same issue a few days ago (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/espnet/espnet/issues/2415&gt;#2415&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), I'm closing the other one then.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sw005320&gt;@sw005320&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 It seems you created the recipe a few years back, maybe you have some comments on that? Or maybe you know someone who used it recently?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T08:15:10Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/b-flo&gt;@b-flo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  Thanks for your swift comment. I installed the latest espnet and kaldi, then follow the original recipe of hkust asr dataset. I get stuck during stage 1 as the screenshot displayed. I am wondering why it happens? And more importantly, how to fix this error.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T08:26:34Z'>
		Sorry, I'll let others familiar with the dataset comment on the issue. A general fix would be to use utils/fix_data_dir.sh but I don't think such mismatch is expected, something went wrong during data preparation imo.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T08:41:26Z'>
		Did you see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/espnet/espnet/issues/2321&gt;#2321&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T17:49:45Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/happyjin&gt;@happyjin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 - I have faced this error when I accidentally rerun the stage 1; even though the features were extracted during the previous run . I would suggest you clear the train and dev directory and rerun from stage 0 data preparation
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-08T23:11:38Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/kamo-naoyuki&gt;@kamo-naoyuki&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for your advice regarding &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/espnet/espnet/issues/2321&gt;#2321&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 . I follow the problem by following the detailed steps.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/speechLearner&gt;@speechLearner&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for your suggestion and I also remove the previous generated data etc folders and re-run it to get new folders. It works.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='happyjin' date='2020-09-09T01:59:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/speechLearner&gt;@speechLearner&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks, we must fix it since hkust recipe has too much problem...
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>