<bug id='2093' author='lukeyeager' open_date='2015-03-10T17:44:54Z' closed_time='2015-11-26T18:45:19Z'>
	<summary>make pytest fails unless WITH_PYTHON_LAYER is set</summary>
	<description>
I just noticed to day that there is a pytest path in the Makefile. Looks like it was added here:  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BVLC/caffe/pull/1473&gt;#1473&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. When I run , I get this error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;layer_factory.hpp:77] Check failed: registry.count(type) == 1 (0 vs. 1) Unknown layer type: Python

...

*** Check failure stack trace: ***
Aborted (core dumped)
make: *** [pytest] Error 134
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I've got a pretty standard installation here. I assume this is just not something most people check, so it doesn't get updated. Is this really tested and passing in travis?
P.S. If caffe would just exit with an error code instead of coredumping, then the rest of the tests could run and I could get an actual test report. This is an issue across the board with the python interface.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lukeyeager' date='2015-03-10T18:57:34Z'>
		This is a known issue with pytest: if you compile pycaffe without the Python layer option  then this test fails. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/longjon&gt;@longjon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and I haven't had a chance to put in a workaround that determines whether or not this layer is included and skip the test if not.

Is this really tested and passing in travis?

Yeah it is, and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/longjon&gt;@longjon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and I do  in our work. The travis configuration includes Python layer so this passes.
Thanks for reporting since this issue will make the situation with this test clear.
p.s. Travis questions can be answered by looking at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BVLC/caffe/blob/master/.travis.yml&gt;https://github.com/BVLC/caffe/blob/master/.travis.yml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/BVLC/caffe/tree/master/scripts/travis&gt;https://github.com/BVLC/caffe/tree/master/scripts/travis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lukeyeager' date='2015-03-10T19:34:08Z'>
		Oh ok, I didn't know about the WITH_PYTHON_LAYER option. Thanks for the info.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lukeyeager' date='2015-03-10T19:56:01Z'>
		(Re-opening for visibility until the test is adapted to when this condition is off.)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>