<bug id='272' author='valeriano-manassero' open_date='2020-12-30T07:06:18Z' closed_time='2021-01-16T09:20:45Z'>
	<summary>Pipeline controller cloning step procedure</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
during some tests I noticed Pipeline controller cloning steps is taking in consideration archived task also.
This results in cloned tasks that are already in archived state.
Moreover it drives to a lot of confusions with warnings since archived steps may be more than one
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;WARNING - Additionally found task
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I think archived task should not be used at all from a Pipeline controller.
wdyt?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='valeriano-manassero' date='2020-12-31T00:28:50Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/valeriano-manassero&gt;@valeriano-manassero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The pipeline itself is using the  if a task ID is not provided (i.e. looking based on task project/name).
The  will sort all the tasks based on task updated field, but and will leave out the archived tasks, so if we are selecting the first one (i.e. the most updated one), and there are more than one, we get a warning message that there are others that match the query.
It seems that stumbled upon a bug, due to some refactoring the archived were not filtered out when requested with Task.get_tasks, and this is the root cause of the warning (the correct Task was selected nonetheless the archived ones should not appear hence there should not be any warning)
BTW: regardless I would recommend to use the Task id not the Task name (which you can always change). To get the Task ID just press the ID button next to the Task name on the right info panel :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='valeriano-manassero' date='2021-01-13T22:59:33Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/valeriano-manassero&gt;@valeriano-manassero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 the bug has been fixed in v0.17.4
pip install clearml==0.17.4
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='valeriano-manassero' date='2021-01-16T09:20:45Z'>
		I can confirm this is now ok.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>