<bug id='558' author='lferraz-kognia' open_date='2020-05-07T13:58:04Z' closed_time='2020-10-15T09:02:15Z'>
	<summary>incorrect documentation for transform_boxes()</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;📚 Documentation&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

According to the documentation the function transform_boxes() accepts non-batched homographies (3x3) and boxes (Nx4). However, the function crashes in those cases. B must be provided.
Copy of the current documentation:
r""" Function that applies a transformation matrix to a box or batch of boxes. Boxes must
be a tensor of the shape (N, 4) or a batch of boxes (B, N, 4) and trans_mat must be a (3, 3)
transformation matrix or a batch of transformation matrices (B, 3, 3)
Moreover looks like the method is changing one of the input parameters (boxes) when they are in mode == "xywh" I think that is dangerous.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-07T14:05:29Z'>
		to make it simple we should probably just support only batched inputs.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-23T23:01:52Z'>
		Can I work on this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-24T09:22:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/elijose55&gt;@elijose55&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 yes, please go ahead with it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-24T16:16:27Z'>
		Should I change the documentation to this:
r""" Function that applies a transformation matrix to a batch of boxes. Batch of boxes must
be a tensor of the shape (B, N, 4) and batch of transformation matrices must be (B, 3, 3)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-25T08:42:28Z'>
		I would specify shape in the arguments, something like this;
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;r"""Transform a set of bounding boxes given a transformation matrix.

The function applies a transformation matrix to a box or batch of boxes.

Args:
  trans_mat (torch.Tensor): The transformation matrix to be applied to the boxes with a shape of :math:`(B, 3, 3)`.
  boxes (torch.Tensor): The boxes to be transformed with the shape of :math:`(B, N, 4)`.
  mode (str): The format in which the boxes are provided. If set to 'xyxy' the boxes
    are assumed to be in the format (xmin, ymin, xmax, ymax). If set to 'xywh'
    the boxes are assumed to be in the format (xmin, ymin, width, height).
    Default: 'xyxy'

Returns:
  torch.Tensor: The set of transformed points in the specified mode with shape :math:`(B, N, 4)`.
    """
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

In addition, I would add some shape checking in the boxes and matrices.
Besides, this functionality it's meant for 2d boxes (N, 2, 2) but in fact, with proper design it could be easily extended to 3D boxes since it relies on  which basically its agnostic to the points dimensions as soon as the transformation matrix could afford it. &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wyli&gt;@wyli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 would be this or derived functionalities of your interest ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-25T08:43:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lferraz&gt;@lferraz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 you had some more suggestions around bounding boxes functionalities, right ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-25T10:41:24Z'>
		yes &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/edgarriba&gt;@edgarriba&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  it'll be useful, there's a very preliminary poc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Project-MONAI/MONAI/pull/324&gt;Project-MONAI/MONAI#324&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-05-25T11:39:06Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/wyli&gt;@wyli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 great. I believe this can be achieved already with existing kornia functions
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-10-08T08:24:40Z'>
		This issue has been automatically marked as stale because it has not had recent activity. It will be closed if no further activity occurs. Thank you for your contributions, and happy coding day 😎
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='lferraz-kognia' date='2020-10-19T10:58:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lferraz&gt;@lferraz&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 is this still relevant ?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>