<bug id='1007' author='NextSim' open_date='2018-04-24T16:00:17Z' closed_time='2020-09-01T20:59:34Z'>
	<summary>Don't show car info on screen</summary>
	<description>
How  can I turn off the data shown on the screen (accel, brake, control mode, etc)?
I looked through the settings and didn't see anything
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='NextSim' date='2018-04-24T16:08:15Z'>
		You could try adding
"LogMessagesVisible": false
to settings.json, or in the Unreal Engine editor, enter "DISABLEALLSCREENMESSAGES" in the console
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='NextSim' date='2018-04-24T19:25:03Z'>
		I tried adding that and it didn't affect it.  I'll try using the console, but I need to be able to have it launch that way or programatically remove it.
Here is my setting.json
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;{
  "SeeDocsAt": "https://github.com/Microsoft/AirSim/blob/master/docs/settings.md",
  "SettingsVersion": 1.0,
  "SimMode": "Car",
  "RecordUIVisible": false,
  "LogMessagesVisible": false
}

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='NextSim' date='2018-06-20T18:48:00Z'>
		Is this something that is set when the project is packaged?
I have tried on a few scenarios, on City, Africa and Neighborhood the log shows, regardless of what is in the settings file.
I created a project from landscape mountains, and this project, as well as the blocks project, never shows the info, regardless of what is in the settings file.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='NextSim' date='2020-08-17T18:07:51Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jonyMarino&gt;@jonyMarino&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Actually this problem still exists in master, so this issue can be reopened I think
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='NextSim' date='2020-08-17T18:46:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rajat2004&gt;@rajat2004&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you. I thought it was a duplicate of  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/AirSim/issues/1583&gt;#1583&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (closed)
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='NextSim' date='2020-08-17T18:54:29Z'>
		Yeah, that issue seems to have been closed to keep discussion here. Will try to look into this and maybe open a PR
Thanks for all the hard work you and the other maintainers have been putting in to clean up the issues!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>