<bug id='2575' author='731avenger' open_date='2020-04-14T00:05:15Z' closed_time='2020-11-19T15:13:40Z'>
	<summary>PX4 HIL OriginGeopoint Issue (Airsim 1.2.2)</summary>
	<description>
I am attempting to run what seems like a very simple scenario. I need define Airsim and the included PX4 HIL sim with a real origin/home position. After reading through the documentation their is two approaches one can take:
One is to use the params setting which define the home position in the SIL sim. &lt;denchmark-link:https://microsoft.github.io/AirSim/px4_sitl/#setting-gps-origin&gt;https://microsoft.github.io/AirSim/px4_sitl/#setting-gps-origin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;    "Vehicles": {
        "Drone1": {
            "VehicleType": "PX4Multirotor",
            "VehicleSysID": 3,
            "SerialPort": "COM16",
            "UseSerial": true,
            "params": {
               "LPE_LAT": 33.33313889,
               "LPE_LON": -84.2666667
                }
        }
    }
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

However, this approach seems to lead to very mixed results with the PX4 origin being set all over the globe rather inconstantly. In the SIL sim, this method works fine but as soon as you introduced the HIL sim, this method seems to no longer work on PX4 1.10.1 running on the Mini Pixhawk 4 (FMU5).
The second approach is to use the OrginGeopoint option.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;	"OriginGeopoint": {
        "Latitude": 33.33313889,
        "Longitude": -84.2666667,
        "Altitude": 20
    },
    "Vehicles": {
        "Drone1": {
            "VehicleType": "PX4Multirotor",
            "VehicleSysID": 3,
            "SerialPort": "COM16",
            "UseSerial": true,
			"Z": 180
        }
    }
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This method at least got me in the right zip code. However, when I define "33.33313889, -84.2666667" I expect to see that in Qground Control, but QGC is showing a Lat of 33.3487423 and a long -84.240305 which is ~4Km to the northeast of my desired point.
I am running the pre-built plains map on Airsim 1.2.2. I have attempted this with a number of pixhawk 4s and Mini 4s running PX4 1.10, 1.10.1, 1.9 and 1.11. I am running Airsim on Windows 10 64-bit with the latest  updates.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-14T03:19:17Z'>
		The params section in settings.json was added after 1.2.2 release, and therefore doesn't have any effect on the Home position
As to the difference in the positions from OriginGeoPoint, I think the PlayerStart in the env is causing the change. The PlayerStart in UE also has its own offset, which is being added to the Origin set in settings.json. Don't think this can be changed since it's a binary, but an easy fix could be to observe the difference and then compensate for that in settings.json to get the desired coordinates
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-14T15:00:31Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rajat2004&gt;@rajat2004&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I like your idea of just computing the offset, it makes sense that your updating the "0,0" part of the environment rather then player position. I assume the new  section will update the player's position when using the PX4 rather then updating the world position like  ?
As you suggested I calculated my offset, plugged those numbers in to my settings.json
Desired Position:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        "Latitude": 33.33313889,
        "Longitude": -84.2666667,
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

New Calculated Offset:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;         "Latitude": 33.31753548,
        "Longitude": -84.2929529,
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

New PX4 HIL GPS location:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Lat: 33.331389
Lon: -84.2666714
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I am now within about 600m of my desired location, but no matter how much I correct for the offset I still can not get my vehicle in the desired location. What seem like small corrections will send the vehicle kilometers away while large corrections will make small changes or no change. Would it be wise to use a combination of OrginGeopoint settings and local X and Y positions to achieve the correct location?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-14T17:06:33Z'>
		You could, but I think it should be doable with just OriginGeopoint. From my usage, the X,Y,Z values are generally used to work with multiple drones, where we have a common "origin" and each vehicle at a specific offset from there, such as 3m, 6m, etc.
Maybe I'm not understanding this properly due to being a bit sleepy, but shouldn't just setting Lat to 33.31753548 and the corresponding Long value like you calculated work? Why the other values which you've mentioned below that?
My reasoning -  33.3487423 - 33.33313889 = 0.01560341 =&gt; Offset created by the env
therefore, x + 0.01560341 = 33.33313889, and x gives the location to be set in OriginGeopoint
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-14T18:49:27Z'>
		I am having the same issue. I am running the latest AirSim (Beta 1.2.0) and Unreal 4.24 and using Pixhawk 4 running PX4 in a HITL environment on Windows 10 and using my own custom Unreal environment. My settings.json file specifies this OriginGeopoint:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  "OriginGeopoint": {
    "Latitude": 37.776580,
    "Longitude": -122.309579,
    "Altitude": 0
  }
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

and I have my PlayerStart Actor at this offset from the origin of my environment:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/5497625/79261235-63796f00-7e44-11ea-98b4-929294b8c3b8.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

When I press Play to start the simulation, my Pixhawk gets GPS coordinates that are offset from where the OriginGeopoint is set. You can see this on the QGC screenshot:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/5497625/79261388-9b80b200-7e44-11ea-8bf0-e02d0c835543.PNG&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If I move PlayerStart to the origin of my environment (Transform of 0, 0, 0), my Pixhawk gets the correct GPS coordinates when I start the simulation, but the problem is that I want my drone to launch from a specific location in my environment, not from 0,0,0.
My understanding of OriginGeopoint is that it represents the GPS coordinates that are given to the Pixhawk when the simulation starts and which are relative to the launch point of the drone (i.e. where PlayerStart is placed) and not relative to the origin of the environment.
OriginGeopoint
This setting specifies the latitude, longitude and altitude of the Player Start component placed in the Unreal environment. The vehicle's home point is computed using this transformation. Note that all coordinates exposed via APIs are using NED system in SI units which means each vehicle starts at (0, 0, 0) in NED system. Time of Day settings are computed for geographical coordinates specified in OriginGeopoint.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;{
  "SeeDocsAt": "https://github.com/Microsoft/AirSim/blob/master/docs/settings.md",
  "SettingsVersion": 1.2,
  "SimMode": "Multirotor",
  "Vehicles": {
    "mikesim": {
      "VehicleType": "PX4Multirotor",
      "SerialPortBaudRate": "115200",
      "SerialPort": "COM3",
      "UseSerial": true,
      "QgcHostIp": "127.0.0.1",
      "QgcPort": 14550,
      "LocalHostIp": "127.0.0.1"
    }
  },
  "OriginGeopoint": {
    "Latitude": 37.776580,
    "Longitude": -122.309579,
    "Altitude": 0
  }
}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-14T21:29:37Z'>
		In my case, I really don't care where the environment is, I just need to define the exact position of the aircraft. I see great potential in the params setting for my application because it allows me to set a more generic point for the environment while exactly defining the location of the aircraft.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='731avenger' date='2020-04-16T00:31:21Z'>
		Related to: Clarification on the OriginGeopoint &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/AirSim/issues/2588&gt;#2588&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='731avenger' date='2020-07-03T17:07:09Z'>
		
"params" config section was renamed to "Parameters" some time ago, documentation has not been updated. "Parameters" still doesn't seem to work for some other reason.
LPE_* parameters are for LPE estimator, while you are probably using EKF (the default).
The error in position can come from two sources:


OriginGeopoint is not the original position of the vehicle, see discussion linked above;
AirSim applies very crude conversions between NED frame used internally and GPS coordinates exposed to PX4.


Orientation of the vehicle is crappy too since the magnetic field model is very crude as well.

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='731avenger' date='2020-11-19T15:13:39Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/microsoft/AirSim/pull/3147&gt;#3147&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>