<bug id='944' author='M-Kasem' open_date='2018-04-08T08:11:30Z' closed_time='2020-08-14T19:57:41Z'>
	<summary>simGetImages memory error</summary>
	<description>
I have a script that collects images in cvmode. The memory allocated to the python process grows overtime due to calling simGetImages multiple times and eventually the process terminates. I have added a stress test script that just calls simGetImages. I am monitoring the process's memory using System Monitor in Ubuntu 16.04.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import time
from AirSimClient import *
client = MultirotorClient(ip = "", port= 41451)
client.confirmConnection()
for i in range(200000):
    responses = client.simGetImages([ImageRequest(0, AirSimImageType.Scene, False, False)])
    time.sleep(0.01)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The problem becomes much worse with higher resolution images, I am using "Width": 1024 and "Height": 576.
Is there a workaround to avoid this memory problem?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='M-Kasem' date='2018-04-09T20:50:31Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this. We will be looking in to this but if you have time, any hints would be helpful as well :).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='M-Kasem' date='2018-04-12T14:24:18Z'>
		Thanks for your reply :). I solved it temporarily by deleting the client and re-initializing a new one after some iterations.
It would be like that:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;import time
from AirSimClient import *
client = MultirotorClient(ip = "", port= 41451)
client.confirmConnection()
for i in range(200000):
    responses = client.simGetImages([ImageRequest(0, AirSimImageType.Scene, False, False)])
    time.sleep(0.01)
    if i % 1000 == 0:
        del client
        client = MultirotorClient(ip = "", port= 41451)
        client.confirmConnection()
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

In the real code, I make this deletion after calling reset() or teleporting the drone to the home position to make the relative measurements in the API consistent.
I would also like to note that this memory accumulation would affect the reinforcement learning experiments as they generally require more than 100k iterations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='M-Kasem' date='2018-07-06T15:54:13Z'>
		Is there any update on this? We also experienced growing memory usage after calling the getImages function in PawnSimApi.cpp several times / sec.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='M-Kasem' date='2020-08-14T19:57:41Z'>
		I close this due to age. If still happens on the new version Please feel free to open a new issue and include the following (as requested when opening a bug issue)
*Make sure to write all reproduction steps
*Include full error message in text form
*Search issues for error message before filing issue
*Attach screenshot if applicable
*Include code to run if applicable
Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>