<bug id='443' author='e2crawfo' open_date='2020-04-23T21:21:39Z' closed_time='2020-04-25T20:50:56Z'>
	<summary>Trouble installing via pip.</summary>
	<description>
Thanks for your help with the object_id issue.
Now I'm trying to install from the github repo via pip on ubuntu 18.04, but I'm having some issues.
I'm trying to install into a virtual env (though I get the same results if I try to install globally). I installed dependencies by running .
My pip version is 20.0.2. Here is a file showing the output of running  inside the ViZDoom repo: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/files/4525291/install_output.txt&gt;install_output.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It exits without error, but if I later do python -c "import vizdoom then I get a standard ImportError.
One line from the installation output that struck me as potentially relevant was:
warning: install_lib: 'build/lib.linux-x86_64-3.6' does not exist -- no Python modules to install
It seems like maybe it is building the library inside the directories created by pip in /tmp, but then other parts of the code are expecting those files to be in a local directory named build instead?
After installation, if I do
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;cdvirtualenv
cd lib/python3.6/site-packages/
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

then the only files there related to vizdoom are the following:
$ tree vizdoom*
vizdoom-1.1.8.dist-info
├── INSTALLER
├── METADATA
├── RECORD
├── top_level.txt
└── WHEEL
Finally, I  have success using the method listed here (manually compiling in a local build directory and then copying over the pip package):
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/blob/master/doc/Building.md#-linux-1&gt;https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/blob/master/doc/Building.md#-linux-1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='e2crawfo' date='2020-04-23T21:38:38Z'>
		I can confirm this happens with virtual env (miniconda, pip version 19.1.1, python 3.7). However if I install with system python (pip 9.0.1, python 3.6, Ubuntu 18.04), everything works as expected.
Edit: Take that back, I was importing wrong version. Installing current master with pip fails with both python 3.6 and 3.7, pip versions 9.0.1 and 19.1.1 (installing works, but import fails with importerror).
Edit2: Ah, right. This probably has something to do with the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/pull/439#issuecomment-618086114&gt;recent changes&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I was not able to build with the "-C build" flag, but I do have an older CMake (3.10.2).
Edit3: Installing &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/commit/9f3bf5032cacaba86c04c47a5a7026ffa7eb2e49&gt;this version&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 before the setup.py changes works perfectly (system-wide python 3.6, pip 9.0.1).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='e2crawfo' date='2020-04-24T12:55:03Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/e2crawfo&gt;@e2crawfo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, sorry for the inconvenience, recent changes to setup.py messed up the installation for a different version. I reverted most of these changes to make it work again. It should work know for base as well as venv python. For venv for on Ubuntu 16.04 it may be necessary to  first.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Miffyli&gt;@Miffyli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for checking different variants, please let me know if it works for you now, then we will close this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='e2crawfo' date='2020-04-25T16:03:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch&gt;@mwydmuch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the prompt fix! Installing and running  now works on 18.04, system-wide python 3.6.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='e2crawfo' date='2020-04-25T16:57:53Z'>
		Yeah, the changes work for me! Thanks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='e2crawfo' date='2020-04-25T20:50:56Z'>
		Great, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/e2crawfo&gt;@e2crawfo&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Miffyli&gt;@Miffyli&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 thank you for confirming, closing!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>