<bug id='52' author='tomlepaine' open_date='2016-05-03T04:53:57Z' closed_time='2016-06-08T13:04:07Z'>
	<summary>Unexpected jumping behavior when running `cig_host.py`</summary>
	<description>
I just installed ViZDoom on my mac os laptop. I can run bin/vizdoom without any strange behavior, but when I run examples/python/cig_host.py and cig.py the player controlled by the host script jumps and moves uncontrollably. The player controlled by cig.py works just fine.
I cannot recreate this behavior on my linux machine.
Also, I can fix this behavior by fiddling with:
game.add_game_args(), but it seems to be more related to the number of flags, than the flags themselves... This is very puzzling to me.
Any ideas what is going on?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-05-03T05:51:45Z'>
		At the moment, I can only confirm this strange behavior on OSX. The bot
should not jump at all, in the first place. It also behaves similarly in
ASYNC_SPECTATOR mode as if some buttons were constantly pressed.
I also confirm that the problem disappears when only 4 commands (in total,
independent on the number of calls) are added via the add_game_args(). 5th
command (even a repeated one) causes troubles.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Wojciech Jaśkowski, Ph.D.
Laboratory of Intelligent Decision Support Systems
Institute of Computing Science
Poznan University of Technology, Poland
&lt;denchmark-link:http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/wjaskowski&gt;http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/wjaskowski&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

On 3 May 2016 at 06:53, Tom Le Paine &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

I just installed ViZDoom on my mac os laptop. I can run bin/vizdoom
without any strange behavior, but when I run examples/python/cig_host.py
and cig.py the player controlled by the host script jumps and moves
uncontrollably. The player controlled by cig.py works just fine.
I cannot recreate this behavior on my linux machine.
Also, I can fix this behavior by fiddling with:
game.add_game_args(), but it seems to be more related to the number of
flags, than the flags themselves... This is very puzzling to me.
Any ideas what is going on?
—
You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread.
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
#52

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-05-03T10:11:16Z'>
		It'll be hard to check without macs... Anyway maybe something went  wrong with key mappings somehow. Could you try making this  'game.make_action([0])' to check if being idle also results in this crazy jumping?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-05-03T12:13:58Z'>
		On 3 May 2016 at 12:11, Michał Kempka &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

It'll be hard to check without macs... Anyway maybe something went wrong
with key mappings somehow. Could you try making this
'game.make_action([0])' to check if being idle also results in this crazy
jumping?
Yes it does.

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-05-04T02:47:50Z'>
		Great. I'm glad it is not just my machine 😺. If there is anything I can do to help let me know.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-05-04T18:36:31Z'>
		I have the same bug on my mac. not sure the cause.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-06-08T13:04:07Z'>
		This problem has disappeared, quite unexpectedly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-07-26T16:11:25Z'>
		I started having this problem two weeks ago. Any idea what triggers this bug?
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-07-26T16:13:45Z'>
		Not really, w don't generally use macs so it was hard to find it and then ...it disappeared after some commit. I assume that you are using an up-to-date version and the bug is back :(?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-07-26T17:01:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/devendrachaplot&gt;@devendrachaplot&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Which version/commit are you using? Has the bug started occurring after pull/version update?
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-07-27T15:10:45Z'>
		I am using the latest version. Yeah, it has occurred even after I pulled the latest version. Its specifically occurring in cig_bots.py
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='tomlepaine' date='2016-07-31T20:19:34Z'>
		I cannot confirm it at the moment because my mac is broken but I was pretty
sure that this problem has stopped occurring some time ago.
On 27 Jul 2016 5:12 p.m., "Devendra Chaplot" &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

wrote:

I am using the latest version. Yeah, it has occurred even after I pulled
the latest version. Its specifically occurring in cig_bots.py
—
You are receiving this because you modified the open/close state.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
#52 (comment), or mute
the thread
https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AEuSHbZdrzfsaHsSIKmFxq7W-DV6G3eiks5qZ3T2gaJpZM4IV7Xu
.

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>