<bug id='81' author='falcondai' open_date='2016-06-06T14:44:35Z' closed_time='2016-06-09T00:00:43Z'>
	<summary>cannot spawn bots in OSX</summary>
	<description>
I could not get bots to spawn in cig_bots.py on OSX but it works fine on my Ubuntu machine. anything I missed? as a side question, how can i get more detailed logs from vizdoom?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-06T18:05:47Z'>
		Indeed. Something is wrong on OSX.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Wojciech Jaśkowski, Ph.D.
Laboratory of Intelligent Decision Support Systems
Institute of Computing Science
Poznan University of Technology, Poland
&lt;denchmark-link:http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/wjaskowski&gt;http://www.cs.put.poznan.pl/wjaskowski&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

On 6 June 2016 at 16:44, Falcon Dai &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

I could not get bots to spawn in cig_bots.py on OSX but it works fine on
my Ubuntu machine. anything I missed? as a side question, how can i get
more detailed logs from vizdoom?
—
You are receiving this because you are subscribed to this thread.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
#81, or mute the thread
https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe/AEuSHS57XNyTlldvBPSz4E59RZiLv-t2ks5qJDJUgaJpZM4Iu-Ne
.

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-07T03:57:37Z'>
		I am impressed that most of it works. that really helps with the interactive aspects in my development experience.
a separate question: i notice that vizdoom might not exit when i interrupt the python script that called game.init() on both Ubuntu and OSX. I have to kill -9 to terminate them for now. Is there a way to properly close vizdoom in case of an interrupt? I don't mind cleaning up on my local machine but it worries other users on a shared cluster.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-07T09:49:01Z'>
		Could you provide a minimal example which works that way? If I interrupt
the process by ctrl+c, I get RuntimeError: Signal SIGINT received. ViZDoom instance has been closed. and no vizdoom process is left alone
(on OSX at least)
On 7 June 2016 at 05:57, Falcon Dai &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 wrote:

I am impressed that most of it works. that really helps with the
interactive aspects in my development experience.
a separate question: i notice that vizdoom might not exit when i
interrupt the python script that called game.init() on both Ubuntu and
OSX. I have to kill -9 to terminate them for now. Is there a way to
properly close vizdoom in case of an interrupt? I don't mind cleaning up
on my local machine but it worries other users on a shared cluster.
—
You are receiving this because you commented.
Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
#81 (comment), or mute
the thread
https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe/AEuSHTjSfjIs1eJuaewBKI09cAT11Xciks5qJOwygaJpZM4Iu-Ne
.

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-08T13:02:34Z'>
		As a inelegant workaround, to make bots work on OSX copy bots.cfg into ViZDoom/bin/vizdoom.app/Contents/MacOS/zcajun/
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-08T17:52:14Z'>
		the SIGINT issue seems to be related to my use of tensorflow training (testing code seems to exit properly when interrupted). i will report back with a minimal example later. the workaround works for me.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='falcondai' date='2016-06-09T00:00:43Z'>
		I experienced the same inconvenience with Caffe.
Unfortunately deep learning frameworks like to register their own signal handlers that overrides ViZDoom handler or vice versa. To solve this, handlers chaining should be implemented on both sides (this is in my TO DO list for ViZDoom).
The best solution for now is to implement your own signal handler, that will override other handlers, stop training and call game.close().
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Fixed - search path for bots.cfg are now the same as in Linux version (working dir and exe dir).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>