<bug id='88' author='5vision' open_date='2016-06-14T11:57:34Z' closed_time='2016-06-14T17:20:52Z'>
	<summary>Fixed newEpisode with a bug</summary>
	<description>
There is a bug in the commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Marqt/ViZDoom/tree/71abb61e92b4fd6d5e0548760b0195b264eaac3b&gt;71abb61&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that leads to unexpected behavior (memory leak, ViZDoomErrorException, etc.) in game.new_episode().
Adding this-&gt;sendCommand(std::string("map ") + this-&gt;map) seems to be fixes it.
Could you please explain for what it is intended?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T12:00:22Z'>
		Is the memory leak in vizdoom process?
How do you produce it? I have experienced a similar thing but it happens very rarely and it was hard to track it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T12:08:46Z'>
		Yes, the memory leak in vizdoom and it leaks very quickly. We just run the default example/python/learning.py. In the previous commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mwydmuch/ViZDoom/commit/61098a33e5a7854bc48524b03d0f0160eecf1dd9&gt;61098a3&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 there is additional &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Marqt/ViZDoom/commit/71abb61e92b4fd6d5e0548760b0195b264eaac3b?diff=split#diff-dc20e11dab0a4894ed6ee9e6b25f3b05L365&gt;command&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Is it important?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T12:15:10Z'>
		I don't think that it's important. Anyway thanks for reporting this, it happens much faster that in my setup so it'll be easier to track it down. And now I know that it's not my system's issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T12:19:11Z'>
		As for "this-&gt;sendCommand(std::string("map ") + this-&gt;map)" it was meant as a workaround for freezing new episodes but it seams that removing it was a bad decision.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T15:21:21Z'>
		In the early stages of ViZDoom, I encountered strange problem - "never ending" map restarting and this code was added as workaround. I've checked a couple of times recently if this is still happening and I've not noticed it again so I've decided to removed this - sorry, looks like it is still important.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='5vision' date='2016-06-14T17:59:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/5vision&gt;@5vision&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
: Thank You very much for noticing and investigating.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>