<bug_data>
<bug id='384' author='jimmcslim' open_date='2020-07-07T11:51:38Z' closed_time='2020-07-08T19:54:47Z'>
 	<summary>Support triggering the lightbox from the Places view.</summary>
 	<description>
 Doesn't appear to be able to trigger the lightbox from the Places view.
 At the moment, double clicking on a marker on the map, e.g. Europe with 100 photos, zooms into a lower-level, e.g. Germany with 50 photos, and France with 50 photos. This is handy, but would also be good if it were possible to launch the lightbox into a view of all the photos that are 'selected' by the region indicated by the marker, just not sure how to preserve the double-click to zoom functionality - maybe have a pop-out on hover that takes you to the lightbox if clicked?
 	</description>
 	<comments>
 		<comment id='1' author='jimmcslim' date='2020-07-07T13:41:29Z'>
 		Thanks! For performance reasons, we have less data in this view. Need to make it work with fuzzy dates.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='2' author='jimmcslim' date='2020-07-07T14:01:02Z'>
 		You can test this as soon as new Docker images have been pushed, max 2 hours.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='3' author='jimmcslim' date='2020-07-08T00:24:40Z'>
 		I've just pulled the latest image but I don't see any additional UI elements that provide an affordance for launching the lightbox from a map marker? Clicking (or double clicking) a marker just seems to zoom further into the map, which I think is valuable behaviour, but would like to be able to open the lightbox for the one or many photos that the marker represents.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='4' author='jimmcslim' date='2020-07-08T01:48:13Z'>
 		Ah, my apologies. I thought that docker-compose pull would be sufficient to upgrade my stack, but I had to down and up... not just up on a stopped stack. Anyway, I have tested this and I see that it is working... clicking on a marker that encapsulates multiple photos zooms in, and when you are at the level of single photos, clicking on the marker takes you to that photo. Excellent!
 As a post-MVP feature, I think it would be great if there was still some pop-out affordance when a map marker summarises multiple photos if you could go to a lightbox view that would load only those photos in that area.
 		</comment>
 		<comment id='5' author='jimmcslim' date='2020-07-08T03:35:40Z'>
 		You can use the search field to limit results (also in the lightbox) to a country, city, or other keyword.
 		</comment>
 	</comments>
 </bug>
<commit id='0b7d8a68974561e08f837172b47c15feb3c446c2' author='Michael Mayer' date='2020-07-07 15:58:02+02:00'>
 	<dmm_unit complexity='1.0' interfacing='1.0' size='1.0'></dmm_unit>
 	<modification change_type='MODIFY' old_name='frontend\src\model\photo.js' new_name='frontend\src\model\photo.js'>
 		<file_info nloc='509' complexity='172' token_count='3386'></file_info>
 		<method name='localDate' parameters='time'>
 				<method_info nloc='7' complexity='2' token_count='48' nesting_level='0' start_line='186' end_line='194'></method_info>
 			<added_lines>187,188,189,190,193,194</added_lines>
 			<deleted_lines>189,191</deleted_lines>
 		</method>
 		<method name='utcDate' parameters=''>
 				<method_info nloc='3' complexity='1' token_count='18' nesting_level='0' start_line='196' end_line='198'></method_info>
 			<added_lines>196,197</added_lines>
 			<deleted_lines></deleted_lines>
 		</method>
 		<modified_lines>
 			<added_lines></added_lines>
 			<deleted_lines></deleted_lines>
 		</modified_lines>
 	</modification>
 </commit>
</bug_data>
