<bug id='10105' author='rokm' open_date='2017-11-17T12:36:41Z' closed_time='2017-12-14T11:04:59Z'>
	<summary>OpenCVConfig.cmake: issue with imported target configuration remapping</summary>
	<description>
For development and debugging on linux, I tend to build OpenCV in RelWithDebInfo mode for use with my projects, which are also build in RelWithDebInfo mode.
Since commit &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/commit/2d0611bc01b7c51bff8567c332077bc5c3f64c10&gt;2d0611b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, the above setup is broken; the projects that use OpenCV configure without errors, but the build fails with:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;make[2]: *** No rule to make target 'opencv_core-NOTFOUND', needed by 'program-name'.  Stop
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

This is because RelWithDebInfo imported targets are now mapped to Release, which does not exist in this case (as OpenCV was also built in RelWithDebInfo mode).
The comment added to  by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/commit/2d0611bc01b7c51bff8567c332077bc5c3f64c10&gt;2d0611b&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 states that "OpenCV supports Debug and Release only". This is not the always the case, as building OpenCV in  on linux results in build that generates .
Therefore, the remapping should be done only if the requested configuration does not actually exist, or it should be limited to platforms/toolchains where it is known that RelWithDebInfo and MinSizeRel are not supported (presumably Visual Studio?).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bblanchon&gt;@bblanchon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, as the author of the change, can you comment?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='rokm' date='2017-11-17T13:11:21Z'>
		OpenCV doesn't support other build configurations than &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/blob/master/CMakeLists.txt#L107&gt;Debug/Release&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. So OpenCV dev team would not work on this issue, but you can propose PR for this (but it should be simple enough).
Mentioned patch is to support building of user applications (with MSVS at first) with OpenCV binaries which are available in Debug/Release configurations only.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='rokm' date='2017-11-17T13:43:35Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rokm&gt;@rokm&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, I'm afraid I won't be able to help here.
To be honest, I'm not sure how it worked before the patch, as only  only contains  and .
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='rokm' date='2017-11-17T19:11:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alalek&gt;@alalek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, thanks for clarification. So the support is meant as in official developers' support as opposed to a technical limitation.
Still, I would consider this change a regression for linux, because:
a) as before, nothing really prevents one from building OpenCV with cmake -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=RelWithDebInfo ... (except the knowledge that they're on their own w.r.t. support)
The &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/blob/master/CMakeLists.txt#L107&gt;CMAKE_CONFIGURATION_TYPES line&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 does not seem to have any effect; one still gets a RelWithDebInfo build, with  and debug symbols in the libraries, as expected. And without any indication that the configuration may be problematic.
NOTE: on linux, prior to the change, and with default CMake configuration (i.e., without additional remap rules), an application has no problems building against such a build, regardless if application itself is being built in Release, Debug, or RelWithDebInfo mode.
b) when building an application against such a build, again no indication is given by CMake that the configuration may be problematic, until the (rather cryptic) make error
The change seems to be addressing a MSVS-specific issue (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/5564&gt;#5564&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), which arises from the fact that release and debug version of libraries can exist side-by-side in the same OpenCV installation. As such, would you be opposed to making it MSVS-specific as per &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/9161#issuecomment-330234951&gt;original suggestion&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='rokm' date='2017-11-17T19:28:02Z'>
		Actually this problem is not Linux specific, so MSVS is affected too.
Perhaps it is better to grab &lt;denchmark-link:https://cmake.org/cmake/help/v3.0/prop_tgt/IMPORTED_CONFIGURATIONS.html&gt;IMPORTED_CONFIGURATIONS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 from target and to check for missing exotic configurations (case-insensitive check).
If it is missing then register mapping.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;... get property from ${__cvcomponent} target ...
if (NOT ";${CONFIGURATIONS};" MATCHES ";[Rr][Ee][Ll][Ww][iI][Tt][Hh][Dd][Ee][Bb][Ii][Nn][Ff][Oo];")
  set_target_properties(${__cvcomponent} PROPERTIES
      MAP_IMPORTED_CONFIG_RELWITHDEBINFO "Release"
  )
endif()
if (NOT ";${CONFIGURATIONS};" MATCHES ";...other case...;")
  set_target_properties(${__cvcomponent} PROPERTIES
      MAP_IMPORTED_CONFIG_MINSIZEREL "Release"
  )
endif()
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='rokm' date='2017-12-12T20:31:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alalek&gt;@alalek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Although OpenCV does not support building with RelWithDebInfo this is breaking downstream builds which try to link against OpenCV using the OpenCVConfig.cmake generated and they are building their software with RelWithDebInfo
We have several users having trouble here:  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ros-perception/vision_opencv/issues/193&gt;ros-perception/vision_opencv#193&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I'd like to suggest removing the wontfix tag and pushing this up the triage priority.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/bblanchon&gt;@bblanchon&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I have several users confirming reverting the change in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/9656&gt;#9656&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 fixes their builds: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ros-perception/vision_opencv/issues/193&gt;ros-perception/vision_opencv#193&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pjreed&gt;@pjreed&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 @tdenwiler
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>