<bug id='10650' author='maj-tom' open_date='2018-01-20T01:31:13Z' closed_time='2018-02-15T15:48:29Z'>
	<summary>real_time_pose_estimation tutorial is broken (registration step produces output incompatible with detection step)</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; 3.4
Operating System / Platform =&gt; Windows 64 Bit
Compiler =&gt; Visual Studio 2017

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

After building opencv and the tutorial code in opencv\sources\samples\cpp\tutorial_code\calib3d\real_time_pose_estimation, I note that running the detection executable with the pre-generated cookies_ORB.yml included with the source package results in the expected output (it shows the box being tracked in the video). However, running the registration executable results in a cookies_ORB.yml written out that then causes the detection executable to immediately crash with
OpenCV Error: Assertion failed (npoints &gt;= 4 &amp;&amp; npoints == std::max(ipoints.checkVector(2, 5), ipoints.checkVector(2, 6))) in cv::solvePnPRansac, file E:\opencv\sources\modules\calib3d\src\solvepnp.cpp, line 253
In case it matters, when I run the executables, it tells me it's initializing OpenCL. Executables were run with default settings (no command line arguments).
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


Build everything on system as in the header
Run cpp-tutorial-pnp_detection.exe without arguments so it uses the example data and pre-generated cookies_ORB.yml
Observe expected output
Run cpp-tutorial-pnp_registration.exe
Select box corners as appropriate (bottom face first, near, left, right, and far corners in that order; likewise for top face)
Press enter and observe most points being green (few red outliers if previous step was done correctly with points selected just barely outside the corners so edges in the image are included)
Press enter again to complete
Run cpp-tutorial-pnp_detection.exe
Observe assertion failure

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='maj-tom' date='2018-02-05T12:34:15Z'>
		In  &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/9086&gt;#9086&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 minimal number of points accepted by solvePnP have been increased to 4:


But in tutorial application there is a check:


These two checks should be consistent.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>