<bug id='10942' author='dustsigns' open_date='2018-02-26T15:28:15Z' closed_time='2020-08-20T08:49:26Z'>
	<summary>Dependency on Eigen missing in pkg-config file</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; master
Operating System / Platform =&gt; Ubuntu 16.04
Compiler =&gt; g++ 5.4.0

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Enabling OpenCV modules which require the Eigen library result in a pkg-config file for OpenCV which does not include Eigen as a dependency, thus making the compiler fail for programs that use any of these OpenCV modules.
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Consider the following OpenCV build options:
cmake -D OPENCV_EXTRA_MODULES_PATH=../opencv_contrib-3.4.0/modules -D BUILD_LIST=calib3d,features2d,flann,highgui,imgcodecs,imgproc,ml,objdetect,sfm,stereo,video,videoio,viz,xfeatures2 -D BUILD_ITT=OFF -D WITH_1394=OFF -D WITH_GSTREAMER=OFF -D WITH_IPP=OFF -D WITH_JASPER=OFF -D WITH_WEBP=OFF -D WITH_OPENEXR=OFF -D WITH_PVAPI=OFF -D WITH_GIGEAPI=OFF -D WITH_QT=ON -D WITH_TIFF=OFF -D WITH_OPENCL=OFF -D BUILD_opencv_apps=OFF -D BUILD_DOCS=OFF -D BUILD_PACKAGE=OFF -D BUILD_PERF_TESTS=OFF -D BUILD_TESTS=OFF -D BUILD_FAT_JAVA_LIB=OFF -D ENABLE_PRECOMPILED_HEADERS=OFF -D CMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=RELEASE ../opencv-3.4.0/
Note that this requires installing libeigen on my system beforehands like this:
sudo apt-get install libeigen3-dev
Building an OpenCV-based program (that makes use of any OpenCV modules requiring Eigen) with make and pkg-config fails due to libeigen not being listed in the pkg-config file. pkg-config --cflags opencv yields
-I/usr/local/include/opencv -I/usr/local/include
Note that -I/usr/include/eigen3 is missing. It would be helpful if Eigen was added to the pkg-config file so that it does not have to be included manually. My current workaround is to use pkg-config --cflags opencv eigen3 instead of pkg-config --cflags opencv.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dustsigns' date='2018-02-26T15:46:11Z'>
		Eigen is headers only library.
OpenCV doesn't require eigen headers by default. Also eigen objects is not used in OpenCV interfaces.
There is "core/eigen.hpp" header with helper templates. It is not required to use other OpenCV functionality.
It is you (developer) responsibility to configure Eigen include directory for your application. Eigen2 or Eigen3 as you wish: pkg-config --cflags eigen
BTW, pkg-config will not be supported anymore in OpenCV. Consider using CMake instead via find_package(Eigen) statement.

Enabling OpenCV modules which require the Eigen

What modules? Eigen support should be optional in the main OpenCV modules, and should disable modules itself in opencv_contrib if eigen is required (like sfm).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dustsigns' date='2018-02-26T15:58:38Z'>
		Consider the following minimum example:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;#include &lt;opencv2/sfm.hpp&gt;

int main()
{
  return 0;
}
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Trying to compile this with g++ test.cpp $(pkg-config --cflags opencv) -o test.o yields the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;In file included from /usr/local/include/opencv2/sfm.hpp:42:0,
                 from test.cpp:1:
/usr/local/include/opencv2/sfm/numeric.hpp:41:22: fatal error: Eigen/Core: No such file or directory
compilation terminated.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Compilation succeeds with g++ test.cpp $(pkg-config --cflags opencv eigen3) -o test.o.
If a library (like OpenCV with additional modules from contrib) requires these headers, I would expect them to be required as a dependency.
I would greatly appreciate if pkg-config would continue to be supported.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dustsigns' date='2018-02-26T17:26:10Z'>
		This is sfm module (from opencv_contrib) bug and it should be get fixed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dustsigns' date='2020-08-20T08:49:26Z'>
		It seems that this issue has been resolved. It does no longer occur with the OpenCV 4.4.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>