<bug id='11355' author='QuellaZhang' open_date='2018-04-20T07:37:03Z' closed_time='2018-05-31T09:31:05Z'>
	<summary>OpenCV failed with error C3861 when build with permissive- + MSVC on windows.</summary>
	<description>
OpenCV failed with error C3861 when build with permissive- on Windows, I use latest source on master branch. Could you please help take a look at this? Noted that this issue only found when compiles with unreleased vctoolset, that next release of MSVC will have this behavior.

1.git clone &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv&gt;https://github.com/opencv/opencv&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 D:\OpenCV\src
2.git clone &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv_extra&gt;https://github.com/opencv/opencv_extra&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 D:\OpenCV\src\extra
3.open a clean x86 prompt (C:\windows\syswow64\cmd.exe) and browse to D:\OpenCV\src
4.set CL=/permissive-
5.msbuild /p:Configuration=Release;Platform=Win32 build_x86\OpenCV.sln /t:Rebuild /m /p:BuildInParallel=true
Error info:
d:\opencv\src\modules\videoio\src\cap_msmf.hpp(803): error C3861: 'CHECK_HR': identifier not found
d:\opencv\src\modules\videoio\src\cap_msmf.hpp(860): note: see reference to class template instantiation '`anonymous-namespace'::CBaseAttributes' being compiled
d:\opencv\src\modules\videoio\src\cap_msmf.hpp(808): error C3861: 'CHECK_HR': identifier not found
d:\opencv\src\modules\videoio\src\cap_msmf.hpp(811): error C3861: 'CHECK_HR': identifier not found
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='QuellaZhang' date='2018-04-21T04:17:48Z'>
		This is due to CHECK_HR macro being defined in cap_msmf.cpp, but being used in a class template CBaseAttributes&lt;TBase&gt; in cap_msmf.hpp. As usual, the header file's content (.hpp) appears before the source file's content (.cpp) in a compilation unit. The simple fix is to move the CHECK_HR into the hpp file, or to move the CBaseAttributes class template into the source file.
However, I can't find any usage of that class template (CBaseAttributes) throughout the code base. It was merely defined but not used. Am I missing something?
Knowing the places where that class template would be used is necessary before we can determine how to move the code.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='QuellaZhang' date='2018-04-21T08:39:39Z'>
		/cc &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/terfendail&gt;@terfendail&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='QuellaZhang' date='2018-04-23T10:08:26Z'>
		CHECK_HR macro is used in old MediaSession-based code for video processing. I'm going to replace it with SourceReader-based interface that won't use this macro. CBaseAttributes is used by MediaSink class that is part of MediaSession-based code for video processing for WinRT. I'm going to completely remove this code since video support for WinRT is implemented separately.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='QuellaZhang' date='2018-05-31T09:31:05Z'>
		CHECK_HR macro is eliminated from OpenCV.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>