<bug id='13741' author='taarof' open_date='2019-02-01T02:59:23Z' closed_time='2019-02-08T15:30:51Z'>
	<summary>Compilation failure by turing on verbose logging messages</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; 3.4.1
Operating System / Platform =&gt; CentOS 7
Compiler =&gt; GCC 4.8.5

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Faced a compilation error when turned on verbose logging message:
In file included from opencv-3.4.1/modules/core/src/ocl.cpp:57:0:
/opencv-3.4.1/modules/core/src/ocl.cpp: In member function 'bool cv::ocl::Program::Impl::createFromBinary(const cv::ocl::Context&amp;, const unsigned char*, size_t, cv::String&amp;)':
/opencv-3.4.1/modules/core/src/ocl.cpp:3764:59: error: 'src_' was not declared in this scope
CV_LOG_VERBOSE(NULL, 0, "Load from binary... " &lt;&lt; src_.getImpl()-&gt;module_.c_str() &lt;&lt; "/" &lt;&lt; src.getImpl()-&gt;name_.c_str());
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Set log strip level higher than verbose in logger.hpp and build openCV:
#define CV_LOG_STRIP_LEVEL CV_LOG_LEVEL_VERBOSE + 1
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='taarof' date='2019-02-07T06:54:22Z'>
		Although I don't know much about this code, just by scanning for similar code within the same source file, it seems the following replacement should fix the compilation issue - although, I don't know whether this will produce the correct behavior at runtime.
Based on my understanding, the affected function is a member of Program::Impl. Its constructor is given an argument of ProgramSource::Impl, where the fields module_ and name_ could be found, both being strings, having a c_str() method. The problem stems from the fact that Program::Impl no longer keeps around a reference to ProgramSource::Impl after the constructor method finishes. But the constructor appears to have already made a copy of those strings, which are now named sourceModule_ and sourceName_.
Replace
src.getImpl()-&gt;module_.c_str()
With
sourceModule_.c_str()
Also, replace
src.getImpl()-&gt;name_.c_str()
With
sourceName_.c_str()
This needs to be patched in branch 3.4 and then ported to master (4.0)
I have to fight my own issue of slow internet connection, so anyone else is welcome to submit a PR.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>