<bug id='14130' author='LaurentBerger' open_date='2019-03-22T14:43:27Z' closed_time='2019-11-04T13:27:48Z'>
	<summary>Using FileStorage::APPEND</summary>
	<description>
I cannot read data written in file when I use FileStorage:: APPEND
my code :
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;        FileStorage fs;
        fs.open("test.yml", FileStorage::WRITE);
        fs &lt;&lt; "a" &lt;&lt; 48;
        fs.release();
        fs.open("test.yml", FileStorage::APPEND);
        fs &lt;&lt; "b" &lt;&lt; 49;
        fs.release();
        fs.open("test.yml", FileStorage::READ);
        cout &lt;&lt; int(fs["a"]) &lt;&lt; endl;
        cout &lt;&lt; int(fs["b"]) &lt;&lt; endl;

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

result :
a = 48
b = 0
yml file is
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;%YAML:1.0
---
a: 48
...
---
b: 49

&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

It works using xml file
PS I cannot find previous issue about append problem in yml but I can find many post on stackoverflow
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='LaurentBerger' date='2019-03-23T17:10:26Z'>
		ok i write my codes in python few in c++ , you should make sure that you are using C++ API, but i think you are missing " ./ or /: "
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='LaurentBerger' date='2019-07-28T15:47:55Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LaurentBerger&gt;@LaurentBerger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 I had to use something similar in 3.4 and your example worked correctly for me.
Were you using master? Build/config information you can provide us?
Your example is very correct and it is puzzling how it fails.
Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='LaurentBerger' date='2019-07-28T19:09:43Z'>
		Bug is still here using yml file. there is no bug using xml file.
windows 10 win 64
visual studio 2017
opencv-4.1.1-dev
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='LaurentBerger' date='2019-10-31T14:27:55Z'>
		For this reported problem, I find out the following clues. Using the &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/LaurentBerger&gt;@LaurentBerger&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 's code, the produced YAML is:
%YAML:1.0
---
a: 48
...
---
b: 49
The writer use ... followed --- syntax to create a new document once FS::APPEND flag is set. The YAML reader only reads the first document, so it produces 0 for b or any other variables that is not shown above the second --- line.
YAML Syntax Reference:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://yaml.org/spec/1.0/&gt;https://yaml.org/spec/1.0/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

The solution I purposed are:

Change the behavior of YAML writer on FS::APPEND: directly append to the first document. Now each file contains only one document. So in this case, the output turns to:

%YAML:1.0
---
a: 48
b: 49

Change the behavior of YAML reader, support reading multiple documents from one file.

The code to be modified if we take soluiton 1



opencv/modules/core/src/persistence.cpp


        Lines 647 to 650
      in
      469adde






 if( !append) 



 puts( "%YAML:1.0\n---\n" ); 



 else 



 puts( "...\n---\n" ); 





		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='LaurentBerger' date='2019-10-31T17:08:53Z'>
		I did further investigation and found that the current 3.4 branch produces correct results using the same above-mentioned code, which means in 3.4 the reader is able to read multiple documents from one file. Current master branch in 4.x fails to behave the same, so this is a regression issue and I think solution 2 from my last comment would be the correct way to go.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alalek&gt;@alalek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 so this may not be a 3.4.9 issue. It occurs in 4.x
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>