<bug id='15857' author='CiscoTalos' open_date='2019-11-06T16:00:12Z' closed_time='2019-11-07T14:22:04Z'>
	<summary>Talos security advisory for Opencv (TALOS-2019-0852, 0853)</summary>
	<description>
The Cisco Talos team found two security vulnerabilities affecting Opencv OpenCV 4.1.0. As this is a sensitive security issue, this message is to request a point of contact to report the detailed report.
Email requests to admin at opencv.org were also sent.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CiscoTalos' date='2019-11-07T10:27:28Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/CiscoTalos&gt;@CiscoTalos&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you for the detailed report!
We are able to reproduce problem on OpenCV 4.x releases (up to the latest 4.1.2 release).
OpenCV 3.4.8 is not affected by mentioned problems.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CiscoTalos' date='2019-11-07T14:26:20Z'>
		Thanks for the update.  Do you have a timeline for public disclosure?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CiscoTalos' date='2019-11-13T14:51:05Z'>
		Next release is planned in the end of the year (before 25 Dec).
It would be nice to postpone full disclosure till that.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CiscoTalos' date='2019-11-15T15:07:27Z'>
		The issue reached 90 days on Oct 22 and we extended through end of this month (November).  We can issue a final extension to 2019-12-13 which is 30 days from today for public disclosure.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='CiscoTalos' date='2019-12-18T19:36:39Z'>
		Hello,
If you have an exact date for the release at this time, we will make note and provide an additional extension.  You noted before Dec 25, 2019, so it would help to know the exact date.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='CiscoTalos' date='2020-01-02T17:31:26Z'>
		We provided the two week extension to the last communicated date for public disclosure postponement.  Please advise status and/or URL for public release.  Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='CiscoTalos' date='2020-01-02T20:22:41Z'>
		Thank you!
OpenCV 4.2.0 has been released with fix: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/releases/tag/4.2.0&gt;https://github.com/opencv/opencv/releases/tag/4.2.0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>