<bug id='16921' author='WajdiMuh' open_date='2020-03-27T17:42:32Z' closed_time='2020-04-03T04:31:42Z'>
	<summary>Open cv framerate windows issue with double</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; 3.4.9
Operating System / Platform =&gt; Windows
Compiler =&gt; Visual Studio 2019

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

VideoWriter in windows doesn't accept frame rate of type double it will cast it to int
i tried to set the frame rate to 25.6 then i check the output video with mediainfo and it was 25
PS in linux and mac it is working correctly
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;  outputVideo.open("videdit.mp4", codec , 25.6, nframesize, true);
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Issue submission checklist&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


 I report the issue, it's not a question


 I checked the problem with documentation, FAQ, open issues,
answers.opencv.org, Stack Overflow, etc and have not found solution


 I updated to latest OpenCV version and the issue is still there


 There is reproducer code and related data files: videos, images, onnx, etc



	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-27T17:51:01Z'>
		Just curios, is that critical to have 25.6 FPS rather than 26 FPS, in example?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-27T18:08:06Z'>
		this was just an example i know i can round it but sometimes it will cause issues if i want to resync that video with audio using ffmpeg
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-27T22:30:08Z'>
		Please try latest code from 3.4 or master branch - there is fresh unreleased update for MSMF backend.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-27T22:34:46Z'>
		please note that i also tried 4.2.0 and it had the same problem also that on some pcs it works fine and others will get this bug I cant build open cv so ill wait for a new version
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-27T22:42:13Z'>
		
that on some pcs it works fine and others will get this bug

Please add more information.
Do you use the same backend on both cases? Please run with OPENCV_VIDEOIO_DEBUG=1 environment variable and put dump here.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-03-28T21:11:55Z'>
		looks like it is a problem with msmf backend
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-04-01T14:36:02Z'>
		I ran into the same issue writing an AVI file using raw ('DIB ') codec using OpenCV 3.3. I set the frame rate to 15.7 and the output file has Frame rate: 14.99993 fps.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='WajdiMuh' date='2020-04-02T09:54:44Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/WajdiMuh&gt;@WajdiMuh&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yuriy-kozlov&gt;@yuriy-kozlov&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 , I hope fix from &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/16953&gt;#16953&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (based on ) will help.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>