<bug id='4277' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T08:34:27Z' closed_time='2015-08-07T08:42:30Z'>
	<summary>The Cookbook for Python does not explain how to install the 'cv' module</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/1055&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/1055&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Jonathan Watt on 2011-05-10 11:15
|| Priority: Low
|| Affected: None
|| Category: documentation
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: None
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;The Cookbook for Python does not explain how to install the 'cv' module&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;The Cookbook

  http://opencv.willowgarage.com/documentation/python/cookbook.html

dives straight into how you use the 'cv' module without first having a section explaining the ways in which this module can be obtained and installed.

I've been having quite a bit of trouble getting the new 'cv' module installed on my system (Mac OS X 10.6). There seems to be a lot of confusing info out there on blogs and the like related to getting old and now defunct(?) Python bindings, so as far as I can tell the best way to get the bindings for OpenCV 2.2 is to build and install OpenCV from source after installing Numpy.

I had various problems with the OpenCV build system not recognizing Numpy after I'd installed it, but I figured those out and updated the wiki to hopefully help others avoid those problems in future. However, running |make install| still doesn't seem to install the 'cv' module for any version of Python on my system.

Given the difficulties of obtaining and installing the 'cv' module, it seems to me like there should definitely be a section on this in the Cookbook.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-02-12 21:08&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Description changed from The Cookbook
    http://opencv.willowgarage.com/documentation/python/cookbook.... to
    The Cookbook
    http://opencv.willowgarage.com/documentation/python/cookbook....
    More
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-03-21 21:06&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted ()
-   Priority changed from High to Normal
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-03-22 14:26&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Priority changed from Normal to Low
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-04-05 12:44&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted ()
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-07T08:39:35Z'>
		The books are produced indepently from the source code right? There is no use in keeping an issue on this, since there are quite the amount of new python based books that do explain how to install everything correctly. Let us close this down.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>