<bug id='4320' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T08:44:29Z' closed_time='2015-08-12T16:19:11Z'>
	<summary>Bug re-creating window after destroyed.</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/1538&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/1538&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| marioheinzen - on 2012-01-06 01:21
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: None
|| Category: highgui-gui
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: None
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Bug re-creating window after destroyed.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I'm writing a C++ program, with CodeBlocks, wxWidgets and OpenCV 2.3.1. It's running in Windows 7.

When I compile in Debug mode, I can create windows with namedWindow function, destroy it with destroyWindow and re-create again. I think that is the way it should work.
But, when I compile in Release mode the windows don't show after re-creating. The program acts as if the window is there, but nothing appear in the screen.

I don't know if this is a bug, or if I shouldn't destroy windows like that.

Sorry if my english is poor, and best regards.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Luis Díaz Más on 2012-01-09 18:24&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Hi! I was taking a look to the tickets in order to colaborate in the project and I try to reproduce this error in my Linux machine (Debian Lenny). The attached file (recreating_windows.cpp) runs perfectly in both modes (debug and release) in version 2.3.1 and last SVN snapshot with the following flags:

DEBUG: -Wno-long-long -Wall -Wextra -g3 -O0 -D+DEBUG+
RELEASE: -Wno-long-long -Werror -Wall -DNDEBUG -O2.

I'm not sure about the steps to take to collaborate with this tool (trac). If I did something wrong, I'll wait your suggestions to perform correctly the steps the next time ;)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-02-12 20:07&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Description changed from I'm writing a C++ program, with
    [[CodeBlocks]], wxWidgets and [[OpenCV]] 2.3.... to I'm writing a
    C++ program, with CodeBlocks, wxWidgets and OpenCV 2.3.1. It's ...
    More
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-03-20 15:10&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted ()
-   Priority changed from High to Normal
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-03-28 15:45&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Assignee set to Alexander Shishkov
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-04-05 12:46&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted ()
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Andrey Kamaev on 2012-08-16 15:09&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category changed from highgui-images to highgui-gui
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-07T08:50:50Z'>
		The issue is related to OpenCV 2.3.1, however I do not experience this behaviour in either latest 2.4 or master branch. This can be closed down and reopened if some would still experience this error.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>