<bug id='4459' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T09:16:57Z' closed_time='2019-10-24T20:48:57Z'>
	<summary>VideoCapture QuickTime file reader returns frames out of order</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/2579&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/2579&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Mohammad Toossi on 2012-11-28 07:06
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: branch '2.4'
|| Category: highgui-video
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: 
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;VideoCapture QuickTime file reader returns frames out of order&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;The QuickTime implementation of VideoCapture file reader (CvCaptureFile) in "cap_qtkit.mm":https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/highgui/src/cap_qtkit.mm returns the frames in this order: 2, 3, 4, ..., N, N, 1.

Note that the first frame is returned last and that the last frame is returned twice.  This is when VideoCapture is trivially used in a loop to read frames one by one with the &gt;&gt; operator.

Looking at the implementation of CvCaptureFile::grabFrame() in "cap_qtkit.mm:676":https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/highgui/src/cap_qtkit.mm#L676 I suspect that the [mCaptureSession stepForward] call is causing this because it's called even for the first grab call.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Kirill Kornyakov on 2012-11-28 08:09&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Mohammad,

# What is your operating system? Which version of OpenCV are you using?
# Do you have a video, where you can see the frame number? If you have such, please attach, this will simplify the process.
# A short reproducing sample would be also helpful. I understand that it is trivial, but please attach it if you have, this may help a little bit.
# It seems that you have a guess about the root cause... Is it possible you to debug the issue and provide a "pull request":https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/pulls? Otherwise it may too long before somebody has time to look into this issue.
-   Target version set to 2.4.4
-   Assignee changed from Vadim Pisarevsky to Mohammad Toossi
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Mohammad Toossi on 2012-11-28 18:17&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Kirill,

Thanks for your prompt response.

# OS X 10.8.2 with a fresh OpenCV trunk build at commit:7f542e391a
# I have attached a video with 10 frames which show numbers 0-9
# Also attached sample code that displays one frame with each key press. Another issues that I didn't mention in the original bug report is that the video cycles around.  It doesn't return an empty frame at end of video, unlike in other implementations.
# Unfortunately, I'm completely unfamiliar with QTKit.  It would take me much longer to properly fix this than it took me to file this report.  Also, note that the [mCaptureSession stepForward] call only explains one part of the bug (starting with frame 2).  It doesn't explain the strange behavior at the end of video and cycling around, although I suspect that wouldn't be too hard to debug either.

-   File count.avi added
-   File sim.cc added
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Kirill Kornyakov on 2012-11-29 07:13&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;OK, thank you for all the information. We'll now wait for somebody to look into this issue. Any help is appreciated!
-   Assignee changed from Mohammad Toossi to Vadim Pisarevsky
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2013-01-22 22:21&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted (2.4.4)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2013-01-24 17:54&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Assignee deleted (Vadim Pisarevsky)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2013-02-01 10:23&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Assignee set to Vadim Pisarevsky
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Kirill Kornyakov on 2013-02-14 08:07&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Affected version set to branch '2.4'
-   Target version set to 2.4.4
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Andrey Kamaev on 2013-02-20 12:00&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version changed from 2.4.4 to Next Hackathon
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2019-10-24T20:48:56Z'>
		close as outdated
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>