<bug id='4462' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T09:17:46Z' closed_time='2015-08-13T08:49:16Z'>
	<summary>LaTeX build warnings in cvdocs</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/2584&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/2584&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Vsevolod Glumov on 2012-11-29 11:41
|| Priority: Low
|| Affected: None
|| Category: documentation
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: None
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;LaTeX build warnings in cvdocs&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Aside from the regular (produced by Sphinx, I suppose) build warnings, there are many LaTeX-related ones. They are somehow crippled and uninformative (provide neither full name of the file, nor the exact line). It's not quite clear, what can be done about them.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Kirill Kornyakov on 2012-11-29 12:31&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;We'll provide examples when the documentation builder works (http://build.opencv.org/builders/Documentation). We can confirm that documentation is built successfully on our side, so the issue at the OpenCV buildbot looks strange. We need Evgeny to check what can be wrong with it.

Vsevolod will resolve all the warnings except the Latex ones, because he don't has experience with this tool...
-   Priority changed from Normal to Low
-   Description changed from Aside from the regular (produced by Sphinx,
    I suppose) build warnings, there ... to Aside from the regular
    (produced by Sphinx, I suppose) build warnings, there ... More
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-12T16:25:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/5154&gt;#5154&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-13T08:49:16Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sturkmen72&gt;@sturkmen72&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, actually this PR is unrelated to this issue. Original problem was opened for Sphinx documentation for 2.4 branch, and mentioned PR was made for Doxygen documentation for master branch, which does not run LaTeX at all, but uses MathJax for user-side formula rendering.
I think it can be closed since we don't experience mentioned problems: &lt;denchmark-link:http://pullrequest.opencv.org/buildbot/builders/precommit_docs/builds/3850/steps/make%20pdf/logs/stdio&gt;pdf build log for 2.4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>