<bug id='4467' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T09:18:53Z' closed_time='2016-05-10T08:46:21Z'>
	<summary>videostab example throw an exception</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/2620&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/2620&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| susidman susidman on 2012-12-11 02:57
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.0 - 2.4.4
|| Category: samples
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: 
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;videostab example throw an exception&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I build latest opencv(2.4.3) version and run videostab.exe, only giving video filepath as a input argument. eg (videostab myvideo.avi). On the command prompt it outputs the number of frames, then it outputs a text saying estimating motion, but after a while programme gave an exception.

Could someone tel me, where i might have gone wrong, do i need to specify all the input arguments (as help explained i hope that if not specified the arguments, it takes defaults). Or any other prereqists that i need to install on my machine. Pleases note that, i build the whole opencv.sln and it build successfully and there are many output dlls and sample exe's are on the outputDir.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-12-11 08:39&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Subject changed from videostab example does not work (Gives an
    execption) to videostab example throw an exception
-   Description changed from I build latest opencv(2.4.3) version and
    run videostab.exe, only giving video... to I build latest
    opencv(2.4.3) version and run videostab.exe, only giving video...
    More
-   Category set to samples
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Ivan Korolev on 2013-06-14 06:31&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;A similar bug was fixed (http://code.opencv.org/issues/3023), probably it will solve the issue. Could you please attach the program output messages (including the exception)?
-   Affected version set to 2.4.0 - 2.4.4
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-05-08T06:40:01Z'>
		I use the latest master branch version under Win10 with Visual Studio 2012 to have a test, seems that there is NO such kind of issue now, in this case, &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ivan-korolev&gt;@ivan-korolev&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ,could we close this issue now and re-open it if it is appear again?
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>