<bug id='4468' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T09:19:07Z' closed_time='2019-10-24T20:56:32Z'>
	<summary>OpenCV blocks execution indefinitely when cvCapture source physically removed.</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/2622&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/2622&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Paul D'Angio on 2012-12-11 19:11
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: None
|| Category: highgui-video
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: None
|| PR: 
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;OpenCV blocks execution indefinitely when cvCapture source physically removed.&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I am using cvCaptureFromFile() to open a capture from a network stream.  Everything works fine under normal operation.  However, if the network connection to the stream source is lost/physically disconnected, any subsequent call to cvGrabFrame (or cvQueryFrame) blocks indefinitely.  Furthermore, there is no way to check to validity of the cvCapture before calling the blocking cvGrabFrame/cvQueryframe.  This makes it impossible to recover from a network disconnection unless you abort the thread running cvGrabFrame/cvQueryFrame and run the risk of deadlocking any mutexes you might be using.

I would expect that cvGrabFrame/cvQueryFrame would return NULL if the cvCapture source is lost.  It would additionally be nice to be able to query the operational status of a capture without having to call any cvGrabFrame/cvQueryFrame methods.  I have tried to read/write properties to the capture after the network connection is lost and they still execute the same exact behavior and return the same exact values as before 

I have only tested this for network streams and not for USB webcams, although I wonder if the same behavior occurs if the USB camera is unplugged during capture.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Shishkov on 2012-12-11 21:00&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version deleted (2.4.4)
-   Priority changed from High to Normal
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Evgeniy Badaev on 2014-01-22 11:05&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Could be a related issue (OpenCV 2.4.7 x64 | Windows 8.1 x64):
whenever I specify an unreachable RTSP URL as a parameter to 'cv::VideoCapture::open', the execution thread gets blocked indefinitely.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2019-10-24T20:56:32Z'>
		close as outdated
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>