<bug id='4647' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:01:02Z' closed_time='2015-08-07T12:57:10Z'>
	<summary>Sorted circles by accumulator values</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3363&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3363&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| caroline parcq on 2013-11-07 15:07
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.6 (latest release)
|| Category: imgproc, video
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: Medium
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x86 / Windows
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Sorted circles by accumulator values&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;It would be nice to get, as output of the HoughCircles function, the circles sorted in order of importance, using the accumulator value.
Because actually, we do not have any idea in the circles list, which one is the most valuable circle.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Dinar Ahmatnurov on 2013-11-08 07:43&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Hi Caroline! thank you for your ticket!
As you may or may not be aware, OpenCV is opensource library, we don't have as many developers as we need, so if really want something urgent you have to implement it yourself and add to Opencv :)  http://code.opencv.org/projects/opencv/wiki/How_to_contribute
-   Difficulty changed from Easy to Medium
-   Priority changed from High to Normal
-   Assignee deleted (Vadim Pisarevsky)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Dinar Ahmatnurov on 2013-11-08 08:32&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Status changed from New to Open
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Hui Tay on 2013-11-28 08:40&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Hi, I'm new to openCV but was looking at hough.cpp recently. The icvHoughCirclesGradient function (and hence the output of the HoughCircles function) *already* returns circles sorted according to highest accumulated values based on circle centers with the highest vote from surrounding non-neg edge pixels (line 865). I believe the confusion may come about in the 2nd phase of the function when trying to find the best supported radius (around line 945), you can sort the circles according to 'max_count' of supporting radius pixels, but I think that makes less sense and didn't give such good results when I tried it out (since bigger circles then tend to have more support). 

Perhaps best ask someone who understands the houghcircle algorithm better :)
I'm glad to help if anyone finds other issues.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Helen Wong on 2014-10-17 17:51&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I wish to work on this bug and have this bug assigned to me on this platform?
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-07T12:43:47Z'>
		Solution suggested here, unless I got it completely wrong: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/4303&gt;#4303&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 since this is a double, this can be closed.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-07T12:57:10Z'>
		duplicate of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/4303&gt;#4303&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/4403&gt;#4403&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>