<bug id='4684' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:09:52Z' closed_time='2016-07-08T17:04:18Z'>
	<summary>Can we remove the 'Intel License Agreement' comment in the old files</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3498&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3498&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Max Barraclough on 2014-01-22 12:12
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.8 (latest release)
|| Category: documentation
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: 
|| PR: 
|| Platform: Any / Any
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Can we remove the 'Intel License Agreement' comment in the old files&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Following "brief discussion with StevenPuttemans on the forum":http://answers.opencv.org/question/26816/intel-license-agreement-intentional/, the manner in which some (but not all) OpenCV source files make mention of the 'Intel License Agreement' seems confusing, and is either unintentional or is in need of explanation.

If OpenCV is simply released under the BSD license, there is surely no need to make mention of any non-standard license or agreement.

Apologies if a bug-report isn't the appropriate way of raising this issue.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Max Barraclough on 2014-01-22 12:22&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Reading again, it seems clear that the intention is that 'Intel License Agreement' refers to the BSD-style licence specified thereunder. Still, that the license comments are not consistent between BSD-licensed files doesn't seem ideal.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Andrew Senin on 2014-01-22 12:58&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Max, the recent files do not contain the "Intel License Agreement" header. For the old files I'm not sure editing of the licence headers is possible due to legal considerations. 

Anyway I believe this issue shall be discussed on one of team meetings.

Thanks
-   Subject changed from Confusing mention of 'Intel License Agreement'
    in comments to Can we remove the 'Intel License Agreement' comment
    in the old files
-   Target version changed from 2.4.9 to Next Hackathon
-   Operating System changed from Linux to Any
-   HW Platform changed from x64 to Any
-   Assignee set to Vadim Pisarevsky
-   Status changed from New to Open
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Dmitry Retinskiy on 2014-02-03 11:33&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category set to documentation
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
	</comments>
</bug>