<bug id='4702' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:14:19Z' closed_time='2016-07-14T16:11:48Z'>
	<summary>How to integrate doc and tutorial coming from opencv_contrib into docs.opencv.org/trunk and questions regarding samples naming conventions</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3560&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3560&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Alexandre Benoit on 2014-02-18 07:29
|| Priority: Low
|| Affected: branch 'master' (3.0-dev)
|| Category: build/install
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: Easy
|| PR: 
|| Platform: Any / Any
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;How to integrate doc and tutorial coming from opencv_contrib into docs.opencv.org/trunk and questions regarding samples naming conventions&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Hi,
some of the contrib modules of opencv 2.4.x  have been moved to the new opencv_contrib repo for opencv 3.x but their existing doc and tutorial do not appear anymore in the online doc (docs.opencv.org/trunk). Then, how to make it come back ?
I guess it will be activated when the buildfarm will be able to check opencv_contrib. So this would only be a question of project setup that will be solve in some time, but is there a planning about it ?
Then, during this transition (and next) what are the guidelines for contrib developpers ?
=&gt; how to setup tutorials (where to place them ? (in the opencv_contrib/doc/modulename/ folder as it has been done for the bioinspired module tutorial ?) But how to integrate it into the official doc. On individual plateforms, the addition of opencv_contrib with cmake directly targets opencv_contrib/modules folder thus ommiting opencv_contrib/doc ?
=&gt; regarding module samples, how to prepare them ? It would be more convenient if they follow the same name conventions as in the opencv core, for example "cpp-example-mydemo" or "cpp-example-mymodule-mydemo" instead of the current "example_mymodule_mydemo". Currently, samples that are automatically compiled are placed into the opencv_contrib/modules/myModule/sample but sub directories are not considered.

If official guidelines exist, i can describe them in the general readme files to help opencv_contrib developers.
This would help/encourage people propose new methods.
Thanks.

Thanks.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Alexander Karsakov on 2014-02-19 05:55&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Status changed from New to Open
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Maksim Shabunin on 2015-04-27 09:11&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version changed from 3.0-alpha to 3.0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Maksim Shabunin on 2015-04-27 13:54&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;After transition to doxygen documentation, some of problems become obsolete. All documentation from contrib repository is generated from corresponding header files. Tutorials should be put into *&lt;module&gt;/tutorials* folder and additional documentation pages and images to *&lt;module&gt;/doc* folder.

There is also documentation writing guide: http://docs.opencv.org/3.0-rc1/d4/db1/tutorial_documentation.html

For now there are two questions exist:

* How to organize generated tutorials from contrib repository? (they are represented as single pages in corresponding section at this moment http://docs.opencv.org/3.0-rc1/pages.html)
* How to name built samples from contrib repository and do we need to build samples from subfolders (*&lt;module&gt;/samples/***)?
-   Target version changed from 3.0 to 3.1
-   Priority changed from Normal to Low
-   Assignee changed from Ilya Lavrenov to Maksim Shabunin
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-07-14T14:59:59Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mshabunin&gt;@mshabunin&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, are these question solved? can we close this?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-07-14T16:11:48Z'>
		Yes, this is solved: &lt;denchmark-link:http://docs.opencv.org/master/d3/d81/tutorial_contrib_root.html#gsc.tab=0&gt;http://docs.opencv.org/master/d3/d81/tutorial_contrib_root.html#gsc.tab=0&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>