<bug id='4809' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:39:50Z' closed_time='2015-11-25T19:35:15Z'>
	<summary>Error in cap_ximea.cpp</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3851&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3851&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| jean-françois witz on 2014-08-08 13:07
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: branch 'master' (3.0-dev)
|| Category: highgui-video
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: Easy
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x64 / Linux
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Error in cap_ximea.cpp&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;In cap_ximea.cpp there  are several error that I correct in order to have my camera working (tested on ubuntu 14.04 64 bits)

1) in CvCaptureCAM_XIMEA::resetCvImage() method

the Ximea functions : 
    xiGetParamInt( hmv, XI_PRM_WIDTH, &amp;width);
    xiGetParamInt( hmv, XI_PRM_HEIGHT, &amp;height);
    xiGetParamInt( hmv, XI_PRM_IMAGE_DATA_FORMAT, &amp;format); 
where called before the test. As this functions directly modify the ximea image structure the test performed after was always true. It was not possible to change height width and format with this mistake. 

So I put this functions after the switch/case.

The 16 bits images where not handled I add the support for raw pictures and 16 bits pictures in this method and CvCaptureCAM_XIMEA::retrieveFrame()

2) I think the initialisation was not properly handled. So I change it in order to let the default camera parameter set the opencv Image. I keep the automatic gain and exposure to one even if I think that for such camera people know how to change it and want to control it. 

3) In all the  swicth/case I complete the different format and ordinate this with respect to the order given in xiAPI. It allows user from python to change the format using interger values. May be defining specific format properties as a flag could be a good idea but I haven't done it yet.

4) I change sizeof(WORD) with sizeof(n) with n define as a short in order to be less windows specific (I'm not a specialist so you can change back it).   

I try it in the last git opencv-master using python cv2 module and it seems that there are no bug due to this binding.

Please find the corrected file in attachment. I don't know how to push it so I send you by this ticket.

Best regards
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Dmitry Retinskiy on 2014-09-16 11:50&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Jean-François, 

thanks for the suggested fix. Could you put it into the pull request form? Here is the instruction: http://www.code.opencv.org/projects/opencv/wiki/How_to_contribute
Thanks.
-   Assignee set to jean-françois witz
-   Status changed from New to Open
-   Category set to highgui-video
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-11-25T19:22:21Z'>
		This has been fixed by PR: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/pull/5635&gt;#5635&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>