<bug id='4816' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:41:29Z' closed_time='2016-01-23T11:49:42Z'>
	<summary>cv2.warpAffine for large images</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3871&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3871&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Jirka Borovec on 2014-08-18 11:26
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.9 (latest release)
|| Category: python bindings
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: 
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x64 / Linux
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;cv2.warpAffine for large images&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I am using python wrapper cv2 to OpenCV and I found a problem while I want use Affine transform for large images lets say more then 4.000x4.000 pixels. In this case it returns absolutely non sens image, even hard to describe, so please see attachment. If I scale these images before everything is fine but not for full scale images.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Jirka Borovec on 2014-08-18 15:34&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;one small mistake, the refered image size was over 20kx20k pixels
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Ryan Wong on 2014-09-22 20:14&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Please see http://code.opencv.org/issues/1337 , and also http://code.opencv.org/issues/3187 , to verify if they are the same issue.

If they are indeed the same issue, currently cv::remap has an architectural limitation that prevents it from processing input images where the "imageStep" (number of bytes per row of pixels) exceeds 32767, when x86/x86-64 SSE2 code is enabled.

I have a proof-of-concept workaround at https://gist.github.com/kinchungwong/141bfa2d996cb5ae8f42 (which is not publicly shared, and cannot be contributed to OpenCV due to copyright issues). The workaround involves creating crops of the original image (which requires a clone (copy), not just an ROI into the input image) and then rendering (calling remap) on tiles of the output. This approach is amendable to multi-threading.

If necessary, I can provide a written description of the approach, see http://answers.opencv.org/question/22079/volunteer-for-fixing-bug-1337-rotate-remap-crash/, so that a programmer can re-implement the approach without dealing with the copyright issues.

The pull-request mentioned at issue #3187 merely rejects input images where the imageStep exceeds 32767 bytes when x86 SSE2 code is enabled.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-01-23T11:07:35Z'>
		just tested this and rotating the attached file works correctly with all SIMD extensions on at windows10 on master branch
can be closed as well
EDIT: just saw the attached file was much smaller than posted checking again with higher resolution
EDIT2: tested it with 14000x  dimension picture so i would say this bug is resolved so this can be closed!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-01-23T11:37:55Z'>
		bump can be closed
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>