<bug id='4823' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:43:11Z' closed_time='2016-10-13T14:26:24Z'>
	<summary>CascadeClassifier results varies between devices a lot</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/3896&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/3896&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Philip L on 2014-09-05 21:54
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.9 (latest release)
|| Category: ocl
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: 
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x64 / Windows
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;CascadeClassifier results varies between devices a lot&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I am working a lot with the CascadeClassifier detecting faces.
While i tested around with the CPU, OCL and GPU version i have got some huge differences between the results of them.
Initially i wanted to combine all three of them for saving some time scanning folders of pictures.

I used the same parameters for all three of them and got the following results:
While the CPU version found less faces the ocl and gpu version found more, but mostly different faces.
Are the algorithms used for the CascadeClassifier on the different devices just that different? I think this should not be intended is it?

Now it seems like i cannot save time detecting 3 pictures at once on every device, but have to scan the same picture on every device to get the best results (aka highest detection rate).
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Philip L on 2014-09-05 22:09&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Some specs:
Build with Cmake 3.0.1
Intel TBB 4.3
VS 2013
Cuda 6.5

CPU i7-4710MQ (Iris 4600 Graphics)
GPU GTX860M (5.0 cc)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steven Puttemans on 2014-09-09 10:09&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;A first guess why there is a difference between GPU and CPU could be how the algorithm handles the division of the image pyramid. The scaling factor is procentual. So if the image gets devided in piece before GPU processing, then it could be that the image sizes are not identical for each detection. Could you try using a scalefactor of like 1.01 (much smaller steps) and see if the error still persists?
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steven Puttemans on 2014-09-09 10:09&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Assignee set to Philip L
-   Status changed from New to Open
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Philip L on 2014-09-10 11:59&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;It seems like the size which is not reported correctly in some cascade classifier had an impact in my algorithm (since i use the size methods).
I will report back after looking into the size issue.

Edit: the size issue could have been a problem with the oclCascadeClassifier as stated there but in my test case i also used the GPU version so the difference between CPU and GPU is still there.
Will test as asked with a smaller scalefactor soon.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Philip L on 2014-09-10 16:55&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;ok i am back with some results. with the scalefactor of 1.01 i've got similiar results for cpu and gpu although the gpu found around 10% more (negative and positive but that doesnt matter)
the oclcascadeclassifier gave the same results as the cpu classifier except the results were cropped example:
Example 1 (negative) cpu: 122x122 ocl: 98x98 (diff 34px)
Example 2 (positive) cpu: 181x181 ocl: 140x140 (diff 41px)
Example 3 (positive, frontalface) cpu: 177x177 ocl: 96x96 (diff 81px)

Sure this is normal behaviour because of the scalefactor 1.01 (so actually the ocl version would find more it seems) but on the frontalface image the ocl give me a too cropped image.
While on the cpu/gpu i have the whole face the oclCascadeClassifier gives me sometimes just the nose and mouth, the rest was cropped. Also in general the results of the oclCascadeClassifier are way too much cropped.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vladislav Vinogradov on 2014-09-30 11:14&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category set to ocl
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steven Puttemans on 2014-09-30 14:12&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Just a tought, is there rounding of floats to integers on OCL operations?
Maybe that can cause the difference in precision?
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Philip L on 2014-11-29 09:38&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;It currently seems like there was the OclCascadeClassifier class deleted, since i cannot find it in the master branch.

Last thing where i found the class were here:
https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/3d3e9ab6357de2293c064aaa95b9b39785719086/modules/ocl/include/opencv2/ocl.hpp#L859

Someone got an idea what happened or where it should be now?

*Edit: just saw that this was opened for the 2.4.9 branch so nothing happened there ofcourse but just wanted to know where to find the class in 3.0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-10-13T14:14:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alalek&gt;@alalek&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 transfered issue but related to 2.4.9. Since that is basically ancient history I suggest to close until a similar issue would pop up again.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>