<bug id='4885' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T10:57:59Z' closed_time='2015-08-17T10:19:43Z'>
	<summary>HDR Radiance format .. imread / imwrite</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/4069&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/4069&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Andrej XXX on 2014-12-17 10:43
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: None
|| Category: highgui-images
|| Tracker: Feature
|| Difficulty: Easy
|| PR: 
|| Platform: None / None
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;HDR Radiance format .. imread / imwrite&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Hello, I am implementing HDR Radiance format support to my app and even if it is not documented I see that recent OpenCV 3.0 beta supports it. 
This is maybe the known bug, but since I would like to see this working I decided to write a bug report. 

Basically most of the HDR files I have downloaded from various websites cannot be loaded using 'imread'. There is an error message pointing out that there is new line character missing in the header.

OpenCV Error: Unspecified error (RGBE bad file format: missing blank line after FORMAT specifier) in rgbe_error, file ..\..\..\..\opencv\modules\imgcodecs\src\rgbe.cpp, line 97

I looked inside the files and there seems to be new line where it suppose to be. I did not tried to compile OpenCV and debug that. I managed to open all HDR files in XnView with no problems.

What I am using is included java library, so maybe there are some problems with binaries. I run on Windows 7 64bit system. I managed to open few smaller HDR files .. so it feels more like the code is not robust enough. I had to write my own HDR importer, yesterday I tried to write HDR using 'imwrite' which is also not documented but you mention it here on your page :

"http://docs.opencv.org/trunk/doc/tutorials/photo/hdr_imaging/hdr_imaging.html" .. so I was assuming that at least imwrite works correctly, but the files cannot be opened with any other image reader app I have, it can be opened fine with imread but I need it for exporting purposes. 

I hope you can fix that, I switched to OpenCV from another system and I like it more. Keep up good work.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Maksim Shabunin on 2015-04-27 09:12&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Target version changed from 3.0-beta to 3.0
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2015-05-30 07:03&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Tracker changed from Bug to Feature
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2015-05-30 07:05&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category changed from highgui-gui to highgui-images
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-10T11:49:13Z'>
		explanation :
occur when the header of file has GAMMA and EXPOSURE values
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/imgcodecs/src/rgbe.cpp#L222&gt;https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/imgcodecs/src/rgbe.cpp#L222&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

i think &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/imgcodecs/src/rgbe.cpp#L206&gt;https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/blob/master/modules/imgcodecs/src/rgbe.cpp#L206&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 must be reviewed
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/sturkmen72&gt;@sturkmen72&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>