<bug id='4930' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T11:09:10Z' closed_time='2016-09-16T21:18:40Z'>
	<summary>Add avfoundation support for normal OSX build, not just iOS</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/4187&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/4187&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Dustin Spicuzza on 2015-02-10 06:01
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: branch 'master' (3.0-dev)
|| Category: highgui-video
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: Easy
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x64 / Mac OSX
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Add avfoundation support for normal OSX build, not just iOS&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;When using QTKit, things like exposure settings and such aren't supported. AVFoundation supports doing this, however.

I hacked with the makefiles in a very minimal way, and I found the following:

* Can't enable QTKit and AVFoundation at the same time, otherwise link errors occur
* Have to add some frameworks in CMakeLists.txt in videoio -- here's what my line that worked was (not sure if there's too many frameworks there, I just copy/pasted settings from IOS):

&lt;pre&gt;
list(APPEND VIDEOIO_LIBRARIES "-framework Accelerate" "-framework AVFoundation" "-framework CoreGraphics" "-framework CoreMedia" "-framework CoreVideo" )
&lt;/pre&gt;

Once I did this very minimal change, I compiled and was able to set the exposure on the webcam using PROP_IOS_DEVICE_EXPOSURE on my Macbook Pro. I haven't done extensive testing yet, but my understanding is that AVFoundation is mostly identical on iOS and OSX.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2015-05-13 13:28&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category changed from imgproc, video to highgui-video
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-05-04T17:27:18Z'>
		Is somebody already working on this? QTKit is deprecated since OS X 10.9 which is now 2.5 years old. So replacing it with AVFoundation would make sense.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-06-13T04:52:26Z'>
		I created pull request 6672 for this.  The steps to add support are the same as described in the original bug.  On my Mac, reading video is now 10x faster than with QT.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>