<bug id='4952' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T11:14:23Z' closed_time='2020-02-14T08:10:50Z'>
	<summary>imread fail to load empty tiff compression type and unsigned format</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/4238&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/4238&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Essam Zaki on 2015-03-11 16:49
|| Priority: Normal
|| Affected: 2.4.9 (latest release)
|| Category: highgui-images
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: 
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x86 / Windows
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;imread fail to load empty tiff compression type and unsigned format&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I have folder produced by Xerox Scanner
The image is TIFF but the compression type in file header is empty (not signed), imread fail to open these type of image

i suggest to detect the compression as many tools do that 
also i suggest to dected the image format if not signed or wrong signed
 you can find sample of images in the following link
http://answers.opencv.org/question/56995/why-cant-open-attached-tiff-file/

the image is empty A4 paper
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Vadim Pisarevsky on 2015-04-27 12:41&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;-   Category set to highgui-images
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-01-14T08:09:16Z'>
		Attaching repro image:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/files/4057994/14258396366902398.zip&gt;14258396366902398.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-01-29T04:46:52Z'>
		I'm trying to understand what's going on here.
OP says loading Tiff failed because Tiff file had no TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION tag.
But the attached repro image seems to have its TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION tag set to JPEG (integer 7)
Ubuntu libtiff-tools Aptitude package has Tiff command line utilities. Utility tiffinfo can be used to inspect tags. When I run tiffinfo on that attached image I see TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION is set to 7 (new style JPEG).
&lt;denchmark-link:https://www.awaresystems.be/imaging/tiff/tifftags/compression.html&gt;https://www.awaresystems.be/imaging/tiff/tifftags/compression.html&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

For anyone interested in working on this during Hackathon, default compression type in Tiff is assumed to be "no compression." I suppose if image doesn't have TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION specified, it should be treated as having its value set to "no compression."
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-01-29T06:20:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/saskatchewancatch&gt;@saskatchewancatch&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  the repro image was downloaded from image hosting site. It's possible that hosting compress data by itself for optimization. Please attach your repro image as archive, if you have new one.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-01-30T08:35:08Z'>
		Things that can be done to solve this ticket.

 Find the TIFF image without TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION that can reproduce the issue, or form one. It is possible to remove tags from tiff file with tiffset -u [tag_id] file.tiff, but
TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION (an identifier 259) can not be removed with this command, it simply resets to its default value (1).
 Write a simple test to reproduce the problem with obtained file.
 Find a root cause of the problem  (it may be in the libtiff decoder).

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-02-08T15:17:45Z'>
		I have done some testing regarding this issue but I was not able to reproduce the problem. I took three different tiff images for testing:

Original provided by the issuer
No compression tag
Uncompressed tag

I removed compression tag from Uncompressed tag image using exiftool. I was able to read and view all three of the tiff images using cv2.imread() and cv2.imshow(). I used Win64 along with OpenCV 3.4 and 4.1.0. I have also noticed that windows properties show OP's tiff image comression tag as blank so I think they may have mistaken that for a no-tag tiff image. Attached are my images and code, perhaps it may help someone else.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/files/4174497/tiff_test.zip&gt;tiff_test.zip&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-02-09T03:16:46Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/omasaht&gt;@omasaht&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thank you for your investigation.
I'll add some observations off my own:


TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION is a baseline tag. The Tiff documentation is loose on what tags are required, but it does say that programs that read/write Tiffs should be able to handle the baseline tags. It's reasonable to expect a modern Tiff deliverable to have at least TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION.


libtiff itself automatically seems to insert TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION if it is not explicitly set. You can check this by removing the set field calls for TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION and TIFFTAG_PREDICTOR from grfmt_tiff.cpp's encode functionality, and observe that the resulting Tiff will have TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION set to the default value (inspect with tiffinfo tool from libtiff utilities package.


I have two feelings on this:


It's unlikely that a contemporary Tiff deliverable will be missing the baseline TIFFTAG_COMPRESSION field.


The problem may have been fixed indirectly since the issue was opened. The problem does not appear to be reproducible anymore.


As such, it's likely safe to close this issue as fixed indirectly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2020-02-14T08:10:47Z'>
		The issue is closed as not reproducible any more.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>