<bug id='5050' author='opencv-pushbot' open_date='2015-07-27T11:37:23Z' closed_time='2019-05-23T10:47:32Z'>
	<summary>VidoeWriter, FeatureDetection like SURF, SIFT etc.. Moments, BOWTrainer, Documentation for Eclipse in Java and so on, are missing in OpenCV 3.0</summary>
	<description>
Transferred from &lt;denchmark-link:http://code.opencv.org/issues/4450&gt;http://code.opencv.org/issues/4450&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;|| Bahramuidn Adil on 2015-06-30 02:10
|| Priority: High
|| Affected: branch 'master' (3.0-dev)
|| Category: java bindings
|| Tracker: Bug
|| Difficulty: Hard
|| PR: 
|| Platform: x64 / Windows
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;VidoeWriter, FeatureDetection like SURF, SIFT etc.. Moments, BOWTrainer, Documentation for Eclipse in Java and so on, are missing in OpenCV 3.0&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-code&gt;I am using OpenCV 3 which has a wrapper for Java, but I am not able to use SURF and SIFT and some other algorithms in Java. I have tried many ways and googled for a long time, but I cannot find any way for this problem. Also somewhere I even saw that some people says there is now way. Not only this, in Java wrapper I also cannot find VideoWriter class and also BOWTrainer class and so on. Now my question is why OpenCV has a wrapper which is not complete for Java, if there are a lot of problems such as above I mentioned some, then it is no need to publish an incomplete wrapper for another language which is not usable for the users. Before OpenCV 3 I can write video, but now no. I waited for a long time that OpenCV 3 will be good version and will take care of all of the problem of previous versions, but now it has more problem then previous versions (not good documentation for Eclispe ... etc). I think there are alot of problems in OpenCV wrapper for Java, OpenCV must take care of these problems otherwise it is very difficult to use such wrapper in the feature, it call an incomplete wrapper. Thanks
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;History&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-23T11:51:25Z'>
		Related: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/4974&gt;#4974&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 .
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2015-08-26T09:03:29Z'>
		I would like to add the extra modules, like Tracking, to the missing Java interface features on OpenCV 3.0.0. Is there any reason why they are not included?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2016-05-08T23:58:08Z'>
		I am using OpenCV 3.1.0 in java, and BOWTrainer, BOWKmeansTrainer and BOWImgDescriptorExtractor are missing. I am translating these to java manualy. If you consider useful my implementation, I can share when completed. Although the ideal solution would that automatically translates through wrapers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='opencv-pushbot' date='2019-05-23T08:35:44Z'>
		, , ,  ,  and others are there since at least &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.opencv.org/3.4.1/javadoc/index.html&gt;3.4.1&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Regarding the missing javadoc, it is raised in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/issues/4286&gt;#4286&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>