<bug id='6555' author='Frij' open_date='2016-05-18T23:05:05Z' closed_time='2020-12-13T07:33:23Z'>
	<summary>[Python] Reading video, first frame, last frame issue</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying to read a gif file using Video Capture and then playing the same file. I noticed that the first frame is skipped and the last frame is played twice. I've tested that on multiple gif files and I always have the same issue.
I'm using the latest version of OpenCV (3.1) and to read the video, I am using the read() method.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Frij' date='2016-05-19T10:23:51Z'>
		Can you please provide a minimal reproducing example and small image. Also we need more information about your platform: cmake output or cv::getBuildInformation() output.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Frij' date='2016-05-19T12:20:11Z'>
		Save the following simple, 4 frames,  gif animation : &lt;denchmark-link:http://25.media.tumblr.com/26d3b024138cabf2b408ad719dad6ebb/tumblr_mqi8wivNJA1rnvb0co1_500.gif&gt;gif file&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This is the minimal code to display the first frame:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;capture = cv2.VideoCapture("name_of_file.gif")
b,firstFrame= capture.read()
while True:
    cv2.imshow("First Frame",firstFrame)
    if cv2.waitKey(1) &amp; 0xFF == ord('q'):
        break
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

The frame that is diplayed is not the first one but the second one.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Itseez/opencv/files/272526/plateform.txt&gt;platform_info.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Frij' date='2016-05-19T13:38:35Z'>
		Can not reproduce in Ubuntu 14.04 with FFMPEG, seems to be OSX specific issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Frij' date='2016-05-19T13:58:42Z'>
		So the image you're getting is the one with the plain black sphere (no lightning on the black sphere) ?
Because that's not what I'm getting, + when I display all the frames, the last one is repeated twice.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Frij' date='2016-05-19T14:10:44Z'>
		Yes, I get only the first frame (I made several read calls, but only first return b=True). Not sure whether it is a bug or a feature.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Frij' date='2017-05-31T13:50:16Z'>
		Please use the below sample code to play the all 4 frames for above provided gif file with delay of 1 sec. I am able to play all the 4 frames successfully.
&lt;denchmark-h:h1&gt;Sample code:&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

import cv2
print "Opencv Version:" + str(cv2.version)
cap = cv2.VideoCapture("xyz.gif")
while(cap.isOpened()):
b,firstFrame= cap.read()
if b==True:
cv2.imshow("First Frame",firstFrame)
print "frame"
if cv2.waitKey(1000) &amp; 0xFF == ord('q'):
break
else:
break
cap.release()
cv2.destroyAllWindows()
If anyone want to extract and save all the 4 frames as 4 different image file, Please refer the below link
&lt;denchmark-link:https://gist.github.com/revolunet/848913&gt;https://gist.github.com/revolunet/848913&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Frij' date='2017-06-09T13:58:24Z'>
		I'm having this exact same bug in OpenCV 3.1.0 on OS X... Have you found a workaround &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Frij&gt;@Frij&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 ?
Build Info:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opencv/opencv/files/1064255/OpenCV.Build.Info.txt&gt;OpenCV Build Info.txt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Frij' date='2017-06-19T12:55:27Z'>
		Installing OpenCV 3.2.0 with FFMPEG backend solved this problem. Not sure whether it was the version bump or FFMPEG.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>