<bug id='7780' author='doronf-cortica' open_date='2016-12-02T18:45:14Z' closed_time='2016-12-08T15:28:06Z'>
	<summary>imread documentation omission</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;System information (version)&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;


OpenCV =&gt; 3.1
Operating System / Platform =&gt; ❔
Compiler =&gt; ❔

&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Detailed description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

The behavior of imread has changed in version 3.1 and this cannot be found anywhere in the documentation. Before 3.1, imread did not take into account EXIF information about camera orientation. This has been introduced in version 3.1 and imread corrects for camera orientation based on EXIF metadata by rotating or flipping the image. It's great that now EXIF orientation is taken into account, but the way things are now, the same code may or may not rotate an image while reading it, depending on which version of OpenCV is being used. Aside from the question of whether or not changing the behavior of such an important function is appropriate, at the very least this should be documented, to give the programmers a chance of getting what they expect (e.g., by checking the version number and correcting themselves only for OpenCV versions prior to 3.1). But this piece of information doesn't appear in the documentation of imread nor does it appear in the version release. I had to find it in the OpenCV source code. I think the default for this function ought to be not to correct to maintain the established behavior of this function, but even if not, at least please write about it in the documentation...
&lt;denchmark-h:h5&gt;Steps to reproduce&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

cv::Mat aImage=cv::imread("Landscape_6.jpg", CV_LOAD_IMAGE_COLOR);
cout &lt;&lt; aImage.rows &lt;&lt; endl;   // prints 600 prior to 3.1 and 450 in 3.1
&lt;denchmark-link:https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/19801879/20845788/aafbc4dc-b894-11e6-8084-de4e6237d77b.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='doronf-cortica' date='2016-12-02T19:51:27Z'>
		There is &lt;denchmark-link:http://docs.opencv.org/master/d4/da8/group__imgcodecs.html#ga61d9b0126a3e57d9277ac48327799c80&gt;IMREAD_IGNORE_ORIENTATION&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 flag to restore old behaviour (latest master).
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>