<bug id='151' author='deep-jkl' open_date='2019-03-19T10:02:26Z' closed_time='2019-03-22T12:53:42Z'>
	<summary>Zoom on high resolution images freezes</summary>
	<description>
When zooming annotated image that has &gt; 5000x5000 pixels resolution, the canvas stops working.
Browser:
Firefox 65.0.1 (64-bit), Ubuntu 18.04
COCO annotator at &lt;denchmark-link:https://annotator.justinbrooks.ca/&gt;https://annotator.justinbrooks.ca/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

How to replicate
Create a catagory, generate sample dataset ('high resolution' keyword),
pick a brush tool, make some path, zoom in until canvas stops responding
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-19T12:32:41Z'>
		This is a limitation of &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paperjs/paper.js&gt;paperjs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 (&lt;denchmark-link:https://stackoverflow.com/questions/25503708/view-zoom-is-rendering-slow-for-large-canvas-size-in-paper-js&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
). As mentioned in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jsbroks/coco-annotator/issues/150&gt;#150&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 try to limit the amount of keypoints.
Let me know if any of the follow could help with your us case:

All images will be resize to be no larger then 2000 and all annotations will then be scaled to match the original on save
A toggle option for CSS zooming. This would fix the performance issue but when you zoom it the quality would degrade and no component properties will be able to scale with zoom.

I have created an issue on there repo &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/paperjs/paper.js/issues/1644&gt;paperjs/paper.js#1644&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-22T03:04:42Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/deep-jkl&gt;@deep-jkl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Try using the latest build and see if that fixes your problem.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-22T07:55:54Z'>
		Tried on latest docker image, the zoom-&gt;freeze issue is solved, but annotations are not transparent, is this intentional?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-22T12:41:00Z'>
		They should be still transparent, I did increase the transparency to 70% instead of 50%, since I remove the outline around the annotations. I'm going to add in a sliding-bar soon to select the transparency.
Can you confirm that the annotations are somewhat transparent?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-22T12:53:40Z'>
		So it is a bug, when you load annotations they are transparent but once you apply an operation to them they become non-transparent. I'm closing this issue, since its not related.
Please open a new one
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='deep-jkl' date='2019-03-22T15:14:19Z'>
		Thanks for fast response, I confirm your claim that annotations are loaded transparent but modifications causes lost of transparency. New issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/jsbroks/coco-annotator/issues/161&gt;#161&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>