<bug id='1197' author='RapIt' open_date='2019-09-20T17:22:03Z' closed_time='2019-09-26T09:39:08Z'>
	<summary>Change of Visualization Parameters between versions?</summary>
	<description>
I did a version update from 0.7 to 0.8 today. I did absolutely no other changes than adjusting the API calls which changed between the versions, but my visualization broke anyway:
left: 0.7 / right: 0.8
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/844913/65345210-041eed80-dbda-11e9-9fd5-5022a84a9938.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


the color map changed
the zoom-limit in the newer version is lower so that I cannot zoom far enough.
the point cloud is smaller because the z-translation value in the extrinsic matrix changed (except of this single value both intrinsic, extrinsic and other ViewControl parameters are exactly the same. PCL values are also the same. )

The old version is way better, but I would like to use some of the new features. A hint into the right direction in the changelog / code would be great. I have no clue what to change in order to restore the old behavior. I only use default parameters so far and add my geometries (PCLs and MeshSpheres) with add_geometry.
Thanks!
EDIT
I made some further observations: The ViewTrajectory is
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;"boundingbox_max" : [ 0.97073449050827609, 0.76746450924137721, 0.0 ],
"boundingbox_min" : [ -1.1379995291273886, -0.7524822081574073, -2.4096000194549561 ],
"field_of_view" : 59.999999999999993,
"front" : [ 0.0, 0.0, 1.0 ],
"lookat" : [ -0.08363251930955623, 0.0074911505419849589, -1.204800009727478 ],
"up" : [ 0.0, 1.0, 0.0 ],
"zoom" : 0.40847723131794877
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

,but when I manually print the bbox values before adding the pcl to the renderer its max values are [0.97073449  0.76746451 -1.1128], so the z value is falsely set to 0.0. That causes the lookat to be calculated wrong, too and the colormap is applied to a "wrong" range. That does not happen in the 0.7 version, the max bbox values are correct there. How can I fix that?
EDIT 2
I fixed it for me by building from source after setting the z value of max_bound_ in 


Open3D/src/Open3D/Geometry/BoundingVolume.h


         Line 94
      in
      80915c2






 max_bound_(0, 0, 0), 




 to a negative limit. The issue is caused by the combination of bounding boxes when adding 3d geometries, see 


Open3D/src/Open3D/Geometry/BoundingVolume.h


         Line 118
      in
      80915c2






 max_bound_ = max_bound_.array().max(other.max_bound_.array()).matrix(); 




. Since the z axis is negative, the initial value of 0.0 is always greater, so the BoundingVolume is not calculated correctly.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-25T15:58:47Z'>
		Ditto. Updated to 0.8, previously calling draw_geometries() would display a zoomed-in view of point clouds, regardless of there points where (useful for quick viewing results).
Now point clouds are far away from the center and in a zoomed out view which is not optimal.
There is no documentation of the changes either.
Any ideas how to revert back to the older viewing functionality?
Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-25T17:44:01Z'>
		See my EDIT 2 for a fix, which worked for me. It probably solves the issue, but I am not familiar enough with the code and potential side effects to make a PR. Maybe &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/griegler&gt;@griegler&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can comment, he implemented the new bounding volume features.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-25T18:41:17Z'>
		Thanks for pointing this out, I will need to look a bit deeper into this.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-25T18:56:18Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RapIt&gt;@RapIt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 can you share the geometry/code to reproduce the visualization in your first post?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-26T08:58:43Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RapIt&gt;@RapIt&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 maybe you can test &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/intel-isl/Open3D/pull/1205&gt;#1205&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if it fixes your problem?
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-26T09:39:08Z'>
		I just tested the fix, it works perfectly now. No need for example code then? Thank you for the fast response, I will close this issue.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='RapIt' date='2019-09-26T09:40:06Z'>
		Great! No need for the data/code then.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>