<bug id='1249' author='cosama' open_date='2019-10-16T18:53:30Z' closed_time='2019-10-18T19:54:18Z'>
	<summary>Incomplete installation on ARM architectures (Jetson TX2, Ubuntu 18.04)</summary>
	<description>
On a Ubuntu 18.04 installation with ARM architecture (I tried it on a Jetson TX2) neither pip install open3d --user nor pip install open3d-python --user will install a working open3d installation.


package open3d: Downloads and installs open3d-0+unknown, which results in a folder site-packages/open3d-0+unknown.dist-info/ being created, however when typing import open3d in python it won't find the package: ImportError: No module named open3d. No folder site-package/open3d is present.


package open3d-python: When installing this package then it downloads open3d version 0.3.0, which seems to be affected by a bug fixed in a later pull request: #625. I assume this is a legacy package and maybe should be removed.


Building the pip-package from source (I only tested it with pip2) seems to work fine.


Expected behavior

If using pip on such a system it either should install a working version or complain that the architecture is not supported.
Might be related to #841

Environment:

ARMv8 (L4T, Jetson TX2)
Ubuntu 18.04
Tested with both pip2 and pip3

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='cosama' date='2019-10-17T21:58:38Z'>
		This is expected. On ARM we currently don't release pre-compiled pip or conda binary yet. Please build from source for ARM.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='cosama' date='2019-10-18T00:15:30Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yxlao&gt;@yxlao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks for the reply. That's what I assumed. What I was surprised was that the  actually doesn't fail, but installs something non-functional. I have seen other frameworks fail with a message pointing out that the current architecture is not supported. It would be great if that would happen here too.`
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='cosama' date='2019-10-18T16:04:04Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/cosama&gt;@cosama&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Thanks. That's a good point.

For pip install open3d

I've deleted an outdated release. Now it shall fail with a message "architecture not supported".


For pip install open3d-python (which is deprecated)

The reason why ARM platform gets the 0.3.0 is that the package was marked as any: open3d_python-0.3.0.0-py2.py3-none-any.whl
Since 0.4.0 we've added the architecture marker e.g. x86_64: e.g. open3d_python-0.4.0.0-cp27-cp27mu-manylinux1_x86_64.whl.



Our plan is to do re-upload of old releases to the open3d repo with architecture marker and completely deprecate open3d-python.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='cosama' date='2019-10-18T17:01:48Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/yxlao&gt;@yxlao&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Thanks for the quick actions. I can confirm that  now fails with the appropriate message on a TX2. As  is deprecated I think it is okay to leave it as it is for now. Feel free to close this issue.
By the way, I really appreciate having open3d around, I use it for pretty much all my point cloud related tasks and it made my life so much easier recently.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='cosama' date='2019-10-18T19:55:41Z'>
		thanks, glad it's helpful to you, let us know if you run into any other issues on ARM
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>