<bug id='1386' author='sam598' open_date='2019-12-08T20:14:37Z' closed_time='2019-12-13T20:55:25Z'>
	<summary>Manifold detection algorithm does not identify inverted triangles</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
None of the manifold detection tools are able to identify an inverted face as manifold geometry. However the function to create a "half triangle mesh" from a "triangle mesh" fails if the source mesh has an inverted face, and says that the mesh is not manifold.
To Reproduce
This line:
half_triangle_mesh = o3d.geometry.HalfEdgeTriangleMesh.create_from_mesh(triangle_mesh)
Results in:
RuntimeError: Converting mesh to half-edge mesh filed, not manifold
These functions report 0 non-manifold edges and vertices, and that the mesh is vertex and edge manifold:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;triangle_mesh.get_non_manifold_vertices()
triangle_mesh.get_non_manifold_edges(allow_boundary_edges=True)
triangle_mesh.is_vertex_manifold()
triangle_mesh.is_edge_manifold(allow_boundary_edges=True)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Expected behavior


"is_edge_manifold" should return false if a "triangle mesh" cannot be converted into a "half triangle mesh".


"remove_non_manifold_edges" should remove edges that have adjacent triangles with opposite winding directions (as opposed to opposite normal directions).


Maybe there needs to be a function to fix inverted faces? Or an "is_face_manifold" function?


Screenshots
Here is a simplified example mesh showing the offending triangle.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/10446449/70395425-58ed2b80-19b3-11ea-8738-71c23ee0ad66.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This is just an example to illustrate the issue. An actual mesh may have 1 flipped face out of 1000 that is impractical to manually find and fix.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='sam598' date='2019-12-09T08:48:38Z'>
		The problem in the mesh is not really related to its manifold, but with the orientation.
There are already functions like IsOrientable and OrientTriangles, what might be missing is a function that returns a list of inverted faces. Is this what you are looking for?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='sam598' date='2019-12-13T20:55:25Z'>
		Yup "OrientTriangles" fixes that issue. It wasn't initially clear to me what the intent of that function was.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>