<bug id='2280' author='Uio96' open_date='2020-09-03T15:23:41Z' closed_time='2020-11-18T03:13:36Z'>
	<summary>Having trouble with 3D reconstruction on own dataset</summary>
	<description>
IMPORTANT: Please use the following template to report the bug.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Describe the bug
I tried to run the provided RGB-D reconstruction on a dataset. But every time, after I run the code for a while, there will be a termination, which said

joblib.externals.loky.process_executor.TerminatedWorkerError: A worker process managed by the executor was unexpectedly terminated. This could be caused by a segmentation fault while calling the function or by an excessive memory usage causing the Operating System to kill the worker. The exit codes of the workers are {SIGKILL(-9)}

I first assumed that there might be some problems with parallel. So I changed to a single worker. However, it still showed "killed" after some time. I also tried on another one. However, it did not work out. By the way, I once successfully ran the RGB-D reconstruction on other datasets with even more image pairs and the same resolution.  I basically followed the default parameter settings listed on the tutorial page but except the maximum depth value.
To Reproduce
Steps to reproduce the behavior:

Download my dataset and put it into the dataset folder https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dKnUzIBih5WYnxsKDYDg2mZuLm4wtgcS/view?usp=sharing
python run_system.py dataset/Keyframe_Corbs_Desk_1_open3d/config.json --make --register --refine --integrate
See error


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13082153/92134582-b219ac80-edd7-11ea-8a6d-b9004e43ebc4.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment (please complete the following information):

Operating system: Ubuntu 16.04
Python version: (Python 3.5)
Open3D version: 0.9
Is this remote workstation?: no
How did you install Open3D?: conda

Additional context
I am not sure if it is necessary to change other parameter settings.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Uio96' date='2020-09-03T16:48:25Z'>
		I manually check the RGB-D info by visualizing it in a point cloud way. It seems fine to me. I am not sure if the reconstruction system has any other requirements for the depth info.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/13082153/92143637-8d2b3680-ede3-11ea-8451-562f50b5010a.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Uio96' date='2020-09-29T09:40:12Z'>
		Have you been able to figure this out :/? &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Uio96&gt;@Uio96&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Uio96' date='2020-10-27T07:25:22Z'>
		Is this issue solved?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Uio96' date='2020-11-18T03:10:09Z'>
		TLDR: Open3D does not work on CORBS.
Long version:
CORBS is a tricky dataset: its depth images are not contiguous -- it has missing depth every several pixels, like this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6127282/99478159-e48c6d80-2921-11eb-8d02-0423c4c09a42.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This means that our RGBD odometry, which computes dense pixel-wise gradient and uses a direct method that needs dense data association, would not work (properly) on this dataset; and with incorrect poses, TSDF integration will try to allocate as much memory as possible. In the end, a memory overflow will trigger a segfault.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>