<bug id='290' author='ghost(ghost)' open_date='2018-04-11T05:36:56Z' closed_time='2018-04-17T06:07:25Z'>
	<summary>Unable to build shared libraries</summary>
	<description>
The current cyclic dependency between the IO and Core libraries prevent building shared libraries!
This is a bad design issue, and it should be addressed. The user should be able to build static or dynamic libraries.
Although it mostly applies for other platforms, when compiling on Windows with MSVC using set(Open3D_LIB_TYPE SHARED), I got:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;CMake Error: The inter-target dependency graph contains the following strongly connected component (cycle):
  "Core" of type SHARED_LIBRARY
    depends on "IO" (weak)
  "IO" of type SHARED_LIBRARY
    depends on "Core" (weak)
At least one of these targets is not a STATIC_LIBRARY.  Cyclic dependencies are allowed only among static libraries.
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2018-04-11T06:04:19Z'>
		That's interesting because  is  by default and &lt;denchmark-link:https://ci.appveyor.com/project/syncle/open3d&gt;Open3D's CI for Visual Studio&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 never complain about this. Can you tell me which Visual studio and cmake version you are using? We recommend CMake 3.0+ and Visual studio 2015 sp3 (or higher).
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2018-04-11T06:08:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/syncle&gt;@syncle&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Maybe you got confused! The library is STATIC by default.. Double check here:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/IntelVCL/Open3D/blob/3cbee2e1ccc0ec80ed1f031411335421f59927ea/src/CMakeLists.txt#L40&gt;https://github.com/IntelVCL/Open3D/blob/3cbee2e1ccc0ec80ed1f031411335421f59927ea/src/CMakeLists.txt#L40&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

However, me, and perhaps others, want to compile it as SHARED library
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2018-04-11T06:23:30Z'>
		Oh, you are right. Sorry, I got confused. Current cmake toolchain is crafted for building static libraries. As a quick remedy, I tried to remove cross reference in Core and IO module. It relieves cmake error, but visual studio makes linking error. This should be addressed. Can you give a hand to resolve this issue?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ghost(ghost)' date='2018-04-11T08:17:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/syncle&gt;@syncle&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Sure! I will give it a try tonight..
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>