<bug id='422' author='dotchang' open_date='2018-06-29T05:18:44Z' closed_time='2018-07-05T07:37:58Z'>
	<summary>Visualizer::CreateWindow confliction problem</summary>
	<description>
On windows MSVC environment, the name of CreateWindow is defined by windows.h which is basic library by microsoft. (I think it's terrible, but...)
When I tried to use Open3D and other windows software, it makes name confliction problem.
Could you please consider changing the name?
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-02T02:45:53Z'>
		I may misunderstood the point, but Visualizer::CreateWindow() is the function of Visualizer class. Is this naming conflict making some technical issue (such as compilation error)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-02T04:29:02Z'>
		WinUser.h which is a part of WindowsSDK10 of the microsoft gives a global definition as follows,
(line 4283)
#ifdef UNICODE
#define CreateWindow  CreateWindowW
#else
#define CreateWindow  CreateWindowA
#endif // !UNICODE
Then, it makes problems. Do you have good solutions?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-03T17:05:05Z'>
		Did this happen when you are compiling Open3D or when you are compiling an external C++ program that is linked to Open3D?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-04T03:35:10Z'>
		It happened when I tried to use external C++ program.
I want to use Open3D with openFrameworks.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-05T04:57:12Z'>
		Umm, I think I understand this now.
I remember a long time ago  was named , then it conflicts with Windows'  which is a macro mask of  or  (yes, terrible design, but...). I looked for workarounds and eventually decided to change the function name.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/IntelVCL/Open3D/blob/dd511a0d3f973735d15ae9b90e292077886f1e1b/src/Core/Utility/FileSystem.h#L52&gt;https://github.com/IntelVCL/Open3D/blob/dd511a0d3f973735d15ae9b90e292077886f1e1b/src/Core/Utility/FileSystem.h#L52&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I think three::Visualizer::CreateWindow is the same case. Let me hot fix it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-05T04:59:49Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/syncle&gt;@syncle&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to explain it a bit more, the problem is with the macro definition. C++ macro overrides everything. So once a windows header file is included the macro overrides all the valid function names. In a cpp file that uses , it is translated into  or , which breaks the build.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='dotchang' date='2018-07-05T07:37:58Z'>
		Addressed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/intel-isl/Open3D/pull/433&gt;#433&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>