<bug id='936' author='WenyinWei' open_date='2019-04-28T03:00:40Z' closed_time='2019-09-16T15:44:11Z'>
	<summary>Add the lib of realsense</summary>
	<description>
Describe the bug
The github repo does not include the library of realsense, causing the rebuild error in VS 2017, Windows 10.
Expected behavior
To add the realsense.lib directly to this repo and warn new users not to set the cmake option BUILD_LIBREALSENSE on.

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33152225/56857771-0f138000-69a4-11e9-8512-360417d8432e.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Environment (please complete the following information):

Windows 10
Python version: 3.6
Open3D version: latest from github
Is this remote workstation?:  no
How did you install Open3D?: build_from_source gc, visual studio, and so on)

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='WenyinWei' date='2019-04-28T03:30:52Z'>
		And one more detail needs to be mentioned for new users.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33152225/56858195-d2965300-69a8-11e9-87ba-083e50355474.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Rebuilding the INSTALL target needs administrator permission, correspondingly, the command prompt too. Let the new users know so that more time could be saved.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='WenyinWei' date='2019-04-28T04:02:45Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33152225/56858503-6ec25900-69ad-11e9-9478-938684652b20.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

There are many warnings while rebuilding. I guess that the snipping image may help in the future.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='WenyinWei' date='2019-04-28T05:31:25Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33152225/56859138-4d676a00-69b9-11e9-95f0-fc016414ce64.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I have compiled the python-package target and it detected my python exe well when cmake, but the python package still does not automatically includes the open3d. So I manually import the open3d by copying the files created by rebuilding python-package to \my\path\to\python\python36\Lib\site-packages\open3d. Then it works. Maybe someone can add this to the document to tell the new comers to save their time.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='WenyinWei' date='2019-04-28T07:13:15Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33152225/56860314-f0bf7b80-69c7-11e9-8edf-48b1caf4dacf.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Seems that putting open3d.pyd in the folder I said does not help. The directory didn't show where open3d functions are. I have to run the C++ version of open3d.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='WenyinWei' date='2019-04-28T08:20:45Z'>
		It is very strange that I can import the python module well after rebooting Windows. There may be some environmental variables added after rebooting.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>