<bug id='2' author='prasannadate' open_date='2015-06-15T16:12:32Z' closed_time='2015-06-16T23:19:09Z'>
	<summary>Error while installing deepdish</summary>
	<description>
I'm trying to create an LMDB database file to be used with Caffe according to &lt;denchmark-link:http://deepdish.io/&gt;this&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 tutorial on an Ubuntu 14.04 machine using Anaconda Python 2.7.9. However, when I do , I'm getting the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;Collecting deepdish
  Using cached deepdish-0.1.4.tar.gz
    Complete output from command python setup.py egg_info:
    Traceback (most recent call last):
      File "&lt;string&gt;", line 20, in &lt;module&gt;
      File "/tmp/pip-build-qKwOBx/deepdish/setup.py", line 12, in &lt;module&gt;
        with open('requirements.txt') as f:
    IOError: [Errno 2] No such file or directory: 'requirements.txt'

    ----------------------------------------
Command "python setup.py egg_info" failed with error code 1 in /tmp/pip-build-qKwOBx/deepdish
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Any ideas why this error might be occurring and how to go about correcting it? Any help is much appreciated. Thank you.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='prasannadate' date='2015-06-15T19:45:22Z'>
		Can't seem to figure out why the error occurred, but after struggling for a while, I did the following and it seemed to work:

Download the zip file from Github.
Unzip the file after navigating to the directory where you've downloaded the file using the command unzip deepdish-master.zip.
Navigate to the unzipped folder: cd deepdish-master.
Make the setup.py file executable: chmod +x setup.py.
Run the file with the 'install' option: ./setup.py install.
If you want, you may delete the zip folder and the unzipped folder.

Now if you go into the python environment in the terminal and do import deepdish as dd, it works like a charm!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='prasannadate' date='2015-06-16T03:35:59Z'>
		Hey, I did the download compile cycle too. pip install fails for some
strange reason. Il post my pip error logs from work.
SD
On Tue, Jun 16, 2015 at 1:15 AM, Prasanna Date &lt;denchmark-link:mailto:notifications@github.com&gt;notifications@github.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

wrote:

Can't seem to figure out why the error occurred, but after struggling for
a while, I did the following and it seemed to work:

Download the zip file from Github.
Unzip the file after navigating to the directory where you've
downloaded the file using the command unzip deepdish-master.zip.
Navigate to the unzipped folder: cd deepdish-master.
Make the setup.py file executable: chmod +x setup.py.
Run the file with the 'install' option: ./setup.py install.
If you want, you may delete the zip folder and the unzipped folder.

Now if you go into the python environment in the terminal and do import
deepdish as dd, it works like a charm!
—
Reply to this email directly or view it on GitHub
#2 (comment).

&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Shaunak De
&lt;denchmark-link:http://shaunak.de/&gt;http://shaunak.de/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='prasannadate' date='2015-06-16T23:19:09Z'>
		Thanks for noticing this! I just uploaded a new version to PyPI resolving this problem (fixed in &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/uchicago-cs/deepdish/commit/396c20ca6e51cc0a56bbc3a6580969858a4b4f9b&gt;396c20c&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
), so  should now work (make sure you have cython and numpy first though). If it still doesn't work, let me know and I'll re-open this issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>