<bug id='813' author='yangsiyu007' open_date='2020-02-23T08:16:47Z' closed_time='2020-03-18T15:11:56Z'>
	<summary>`conda_dependencies_file_path` and `conda_dependencies_file` have same description</summary>
	<description>
The description for the parameters conda_dependencies_file_path and conda_dependencies_file is exactly the same: "The relative path to the conda dependencies yaml file. If specified, Azure ML will not install any framework related packages." Same for the pip equivalents. This is unhelpful.
Using conda_dependencies_file (instead of conda_dependencies_file_path) for giving the path to the environment.yml file gives the error that the Python interpreter version needs to be specified in the file, even though I have it specified as the first dependency.
&lt;denchmark-h:hr&gt;&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

&lt;denchmark-h:h4&gt;Document Details&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

⚠ Do not edit this section. It is required for docs.microsoft.com ➟ GitHub issue linking.

ID: eb892243-d2f3-79a1-4061-b2d46235aff4
Version Independent ID: a6e4c4ab-3665-c0d3-65ff-abc5cbb0b835
Content: azureml.train.dnn.PyTorch class - Azure Machine Learning Python
Content Source: AzureML-Docset/stable/docs-ref-autogen/azureml-train-core/azureml.train.dnn.PyTorch.yml
Service: machine-learning
Sub-service: core
GitHub Login: @j-martens
Microsoft Alias: jmartens

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='yangsiyu007' date='2020-02-23T08:36:12Z'>
		Actually I retract the second point... The error message about having to specify the Python interpreter version actually meant that Python version needs to be specified exactly (python==3.6.2), and not by a range (python&gt;=3.6).
If these two names are aliases, please make that clear.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='yangsiyu007' date='2020-03-10T21:36:24Z'>
		@mvagelo - is this doc?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='yangsiyu007' date='2020-03-18T14:41:40Z'>
		The docs were updated and (are live) to reflect that conda_dependencies_file_path is deprecated (as well as pip_requirements_file_path) and you should use parameters without the _path.
The change was made a while pack to reflect that relative paths are used instead of full paths. Sorry for the confusion.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='yangsiyu007' date='2020-03-18T15:11:56Z'>
		thanks for your report. this has been fixed through documentation. we shall now proceed to close this thread.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>