<bug id='16' author='tsirif' open_date='2017-11-30T01:46:05Z' closed_time='2019-07-30T20:02:39Z'>
	<summary>Fix OS application directories to work with virtualenvs</summary>
	<description>
Fix metaopt.utils._appdirs to be able to return correct OS specific application directories for the case that Python lives in a virtual environment.
For *nix, it works perfectly.
For OS X: A fix code for  is provided at &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tsirif/orion/commit/095b0d7&gt;tsirif/orion@095b0d7&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, in branch &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tsirif/metaopt/tree/fix/appdirs&gt;fix/appdirs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
Implement and check correctness for:

 OS X
 Windows

This is a bug, if we consider our software to be installable in these OS as well.
As a note: site directory should be contained within the active (which Python runs at a time the _appdirs module) Python's install prefix directory. So that, for the data directory, this would be sys.prefix+share[/appname[/version]] mostly and if sys.prefix is the system site, then choose OS specific data dir.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='tsirif' date='2017-11-30T01:50:13Z'>
		Ok so the thing is &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tsirif&gt;@tsirif&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 that most OS X users like me probably use  to install python in their system, and you would probably always need a  to install a python package unless you would use .
The thing is, the test that we did yesterday was that even within the anaconda environment, we have not been able to install it without sudo. Weird.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='tsirif' date='2017-11-30T02:03:53Z'>
		If our package is to be system-installed via brew for example, then data_site_dir is correctly set and sudo is justifiably asked for. But as there are virtual environments like anaconda, it should be more smart and check where it should install the files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='tsirif' date='2019-02-07T14:47:13Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tsirif&gt;@tsirif&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Do you remember if that was properly fixed by &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Epistimio/orion/pull/22&gt;#22&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 or something was missing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='tsirif' date='2019-07-30T20:02:12Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://camo.githubusercontent.com/208d50cabd9d101500fe5dd548265dcfa00e017e397395692a173e7116c1094a/68747470733a2f2f6769746875622e7472656c6c6f2e73657276696365732f696d616765732f6d696e692d7472656c6c6f2d69636f6e2e706e67&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://trello.com/c/6V9hdnZj/238-fix-os-application-directories-to-work-with-virtualenvs&gt;Fix OS application directories to work with virtualenvs&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>