<bug id='360' author='YuchenWang' open_date='2019-04-02T19:50:18Z' closed_time='2019-04-11T03:47:23Z'>
	<summary>Weird double label in --keep-prev situation</summary>
	<description>
I install it in Mac OS with python3,PyQt5
Let's take in video annotation in video
When I start labelme at first, it all works correct.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15023991/55431229-04f59180-555e-11e9-8ddf-4bffb72dad1c.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

But after I click next image, then it will duplicate the polygon.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/15023991/55431483-aa106a00-555e-11e9-9aac-1d61c76c227d.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If I save the label in this time, it will save 6 polygon which double the original polygon. If I I try to del the duplicate polygon before save, it will cause error and quit the program ValueError: list.remove(x): x not in list.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-03T12:50:56Z'>
		Thanks for the report. I will check it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-13T19:59:23Z'>
		I saw this case was closed. But I just update the new version and it seems that this problem still existed?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-13T21:46:30Z'>
		Are you sure?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-13T21:48:31Z'>
		First of all, I would say the duplicate label is expected behavior when you use --keep-prev.
What I fixed is making it deletable.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-15T21:02:03Z'>
		Yes, I retry it again and also if I try to delete the duplicate label, it still give the same error. (I check my labelme --version, it is labelme 3.11.2, I hope it is the correct version which you fixed)
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-15T21:16:05Z'>
		Could you upgrade to labelme &gt;= 3.12.0 ?
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/4310419/56165889-0a29f600-5fcc-11e9-81df-2a9675b0aeec.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-16T14:20:16Z'>
		Great, now I may remove the duplicate label correctly. Thanks for your quick response.
But I still hope this kind of duplicate label could be solved, so it will not copy the label when the image move backward.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-16T17:54:46Z'>
		Yeah, it seems reasonable to not copying to already labeled image. Could you open an issue for that?
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='YuchenWang' date='2019-04-16T20:36:50Z'>
		Sure, I will open a new issue.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>