<bug id='1276' author='fluffyGator' open_date='2018-02-28T18:22:11Z' closed_time='2018-03-01T17:40:19Z'>
	<summary>Python 2.7 Linux wheel without ucs4 support</summary>
	<description>
Could a Python 2.7, Linux wheel be supported that doesn't have the --enable-unicode=ucs4 (-cp27mu-) requirement. Most Python Linux installs aren't usually compiled with this flag (e.g. Canopy Python package) in my experience. The OSX 2.7 wheel works well with just the  --enable-unicode=ucs2 flag, so I suspect it isn't critical.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='fluffyGator' date='2018-02-28T18:40:07Z'>
		@dursch00 We are using  for building this package, I don't know how we should change the unicode configure flag. I'll investigate closely, but this is likely to be the root cause of &lt;denchmark-link:https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/unable-to-install-deepspeech-on-centos-6-9/26023&gt;https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/unable-to-install-deepspeech-on-centos-6-9/26023&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='fluffyGator' date='2018-02-28T18:43:11Z'>
		Ok, that was faster than I expected, I found that on some github issue:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;PYTHON_CONFIGURE_OPTS="--enable-unicode=ucs4" pyenv install
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

I'm wondering if there's value in more than cp27-m and cp27-mu variants ?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='fluffyGator' date='2018-02-28T18:46:41Z'>
		@dursch00 This should be an easy task, mostly duplicating the current 2.7 builds and just tweaking do_deepspeech_python_build to add the configure flags. If you like, you can try a PR :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='fluffyGator' date='2018-02-28T20:18:41Z'>
		Thanks for quick response.. One thing I just noticed that may adversely affect this that tensorflow also doesn't have a cp27m option for Linux ....
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='fluffyGator' date='2018-02-28T21:25:10Z'>
		I don't think it's such a big deal, there is still value for us in providing the deepspeech python bindings for those systems.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='fluffyGator' date='2019-01-03T02:52:58Z'>
		This thread has been automatically locked since there has not been any recent activity after it was closed. Please open a new issue for related bugs.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>