<bug id='1674' author='MahdiEsf' open_date='2020-06-22T19:30:20Z' closed_time='2020-10-16T10:51:19Z'>
	<summary>error: 'Expected size[1] in [0, 21], but got 25\n\t [[{{node FPN_slice_lvl4/narrow_to/Slice}}]]'</summary>
	<description>
I have built docker serving MLK images with the latest updates released recently &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/serving/tree/master/tensorflow_serving/tools/docker&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/serving/tree/master/tensorflow_serving/tools/docker&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. Now that I want to make predictions with CPU serving images using fine tuned Mask-RCNN model, I get the following error:
error: 'Expected size[1] in [0, 21], but got 25\n\t [[{{node FPN_slice_lvl4/narrow_to/Slice}}]]'
This error is more frequent with images of relatively bigger size (&gt;1000-pixel width/height), whereas I get right predictions on smaller-size images. BTW, the model was trained on images of different sizes.
Also, I saw a previously reported issue in 2018 during training time which is similar to my issue: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/models/issues/4981&gt;tensorflow/models#4981&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='MahdiEsf' date='2020-06-23T09:54:20Z'>
		In order to expedite the trouble-shooting process, please provide a code snippet to reproduce the issue reported here. Thanks!
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='MahdiEsf' date='2020-06-24T23:50:08Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/rmothukuru&gt;@rmothukuru&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 What code snippet are you specifically asking for? I basically trained a mask-RCNN model and exported its tar file in S3 using a training docker image (had to set MODE_MASK=False in the training bash command since I do not need object segmentation as:
python train.py --config DATA.BASEDIR=/opt/ml/input/data/training MODE_FPN=True MODE_MASK=False 
"DATA.VAL=('any_val',)"  "DATA.TRAIN=('any_train',)".......
Also, set cfg.MODE_MASK = False at the end of training phase where model artifact is exported for serving as:
.....
cfg.DATA.BASEDIR = '/opt/ml/input/data/training'
cfg.DATA.VAL=('any_val',)
cfg.DATA.TRAIN=('any_train',)
cfg.MODE_FPN = True
cfg.MODE_MASK = False......)
I used serving codes here &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/tensorflow/serving/tree/master/tensorflow_serving/tools/docker&gt;https://github.com/tensorflow/serving/tree/master/tensorflow_serving/tools/docker&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to build cpu  serving docker image and predictions are successful on low-size images but throws the above error on higher-size images!
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='MahdiEsf' date='2020-07-10T15:21:59Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/MahdiEsf&gt;@MahdiEsf&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
Would it be possible to share the request that triggers the error?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='MahdiEsf' date='2020-10-16T10:51:19Z'>
		Automatically closing due to lack of recent activity. Please update the issue when new information becomes available, and we will reopen the issue. Thanks!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>