<bug id='106' author='RichiH' open_date='2019-04-24T06:29:55Z' closed_time='2019-05-04T09:54:24Z'>
	<summary>[Bug] Long file_name not supported</summary>
	<description>
I maintain an extensive photo collection via git-annex; think of it as a distributed git-LFS without lock-in to a single file source. It checks symlinks into Git and maintains the content outside of main Git; by default it refers to said files via a content hash.
Trying your latest docker image, I get the following error:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;[2019-04-24 03:23:20]  
Added main jpg file ".git/annex/objects/00/v8/SHA512E-s129561--70c0b10e5f36e64acfdfeda1ec35e6ddedb903a1240cbfe2bc145ef971129e709e460b7026d5fe2332b5ec0f8bb58a7a47347ccbac19e5ef70634355d956329e.JPG/SHA512E-s129561--70c0b10e5f36e64acfdfeda1ec35e6ddedb903a1240cbfe2bc145ef971129e709e460b7026d5fe2332b5ec0f8bb58a7a47347ccbac19e5ef70634355d956329e.JPG"
No location: lat and long are missing in metadata

(Error 1406: Data too long for column 'file_name' at row 1) 
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='RichiH' date='2019-04-25T00:53:22Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this. How many chars should we allow for file names? 65,535 is the max for MySQL.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='RichiH' date='2019-04-25T01:53:19Z'>
		4096 chars should work, that's the max for most Linux file systems. OS X seems limited to 1024 chars.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='RichiH' date='2019-04-26T00:43:19Z'>
		Error on CI:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;(Error 1071: Specified key was too long; max key length is 3072 bytes)
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='RichiH' date='2019-04-26T02:35:27Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/RichiH&gt;@RichiH&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Please test. Seems like MySQL doesn't work with (much) more than 512 chars if you use 4 byte UTF-8 (required for emojis). TiDB is more powerful. PhotoPrism should work with both.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='RichiH' date='2019-05-04T09:54:24Z'>
		Ok, no feedback. Seems to work 👍
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='RichiH' date='2019-05-04T10:31:07Z'>
		Sorry, very much under the water...

Will the current docker work to test this?

Sent by mobile; please excuse my brevity.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='RichiH' date='2019-05-04T11:48:08Z'>
		I just merged to master. Our Docker images get updated automatically, if all tests are green. They are tagged with the build date, so you can see how old they are.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>