<bug id='199' author='lastzero' open_date='2020-01-15T12:17:04Z' closed_time='2020-01-20T17:11:38Z'>
	<summary>Mapbox GL: Geometry exceeds allowed extent</summary>
	<description>
When zooming in (or easing) to certain locations on the map,  you can see the error "Geometry exceeds allowed extent, reduce your vector tile buffer size" on the JS console, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mapbox/mapbox-gl-js/issues/8639&gt;mapbox/mapbox-gl-js#8639&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 and &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/mapbox/mapbox-gl-js/issues/8992&gt;mapbox/mapbox-gl-js#8992&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
They closed the original issue and limited comments, maybe because they think it's an issue with the tiles and not Mapbox GL itself. Needs further investigation.
San Francisco typically works pretty well to test this:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://demo.photoprism.org/places/s2:80858741f414&gt;https://demo.photoprism.org/places/s2:80858741f414&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='lastzero' date='2020-01-15T12:32:05Z'>
		Looks like Maptiler has a ticket for this, added ~5 months ago, but they need an example to fix this...
I'd love to send them a link, the login to their forum doesn't work though... at least not without turning off security settings and ad blocker: &lt;denchmark-link:https://support.maptiler.com/i490-geometry-exceeds-allowed-extent-reduce-your-vector-tile-buffer-size&gt;https://support.maptiler.com/i490-geometry-exceeds-allowed-extent-reduce-your-vector-tile-buffer-size&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='lastzero' date='2020-01-15T18:52:36Z'>
		Location after zooming in is hopefully fixed with this change: lat/lng are set again on render to increase the precision for higher zoom levels. Still see those Mapbox GL warnings on the JS console, but we might be able to ignore them for now. Some icons seem also missing:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/72461987-5f4f9e00-37d0-11ea-8a28-86d7c67954e1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='lastzero' date='2020-01-20T17:11:15Z'>
		MapTiler support: "Hi, thanks for the report. This is an issue during the generating of the vector tiles in the openmaptiles project.
This will hopefully be fixed in the upcoming (or the next) release.
It affects only certain layers and the message is just a warning -- it should not in any way prevent the map from being rendered correctly."
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>