<bug id='242' author='linosgian' open_date='2020-02-04T20:26:53Z' closed_time='2020-04-01T08:04:34Z'>
	<summary>[Mobile]: Infinite scroll not working</summary>
	<description>
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Description&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Even after the latest commit (&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/commit/491751f4fc7d7779f793b3773c6e6673c306b5ef&gt;491751f&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
),  infinite scrolling does not work on mobile devices.
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Testing devices&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

A. Honor 10 - Chrome 79.0.3945.136
B. Samsung Tab A (2018) - Chrome 79.0.3945.136
&lt;denchmark-h:h3&gt;Potential root cause&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

I'm gonna take a leap here and guess what might affect the scrolling just for mobile devices:



photoprism/frontend/src/pages/photos.vue


         Line 90
      in
      491751f






                 pageSize: 60, 





pageSize initial value shown above is used to determine whether the next batch of photos (50?) should be loaded:



photoprism/frontend/src/pages/photos.vue


        Lines 150 to 151
      in
      491751f






  const count = this.dirty ? (this.page + 2) * this.pageSize : this.pageSize; 



  const offset = this.dirty ? 0 : this.offset; 








photoprism/frontend/src/pages/photos.vue


        Lines 167 to 174
      in
      491751f






  this.scrollDisabled = (response.models.length &lt; count); 



  



  if (this.scrollDisabled) { 



  this.offset = offset; 



  



  if(this.results.length &gt; 1) { 



  this.$notify.info(this.$gettext('All ') + this.results.length + this.$gettext(' photos loaded')); 



                         } 





	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-04T20:39:24Z'>
		Strange, works for me on Android 10 with Chrome...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-05T16:24:42Z'>
		Wondering if anyone else has these issues and can confirm?
Our recent changes are there to keep all clients in sync. When you add or remove photos, the result is marked as dirty. In that case, we load the full list again and not just the next entries when scrolling down.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-05T21:58:22Z'>
		It seems that the infinite scroll library we're using (vue-infinite-scroll) might be outdated.
I found this related issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/ElemeFE/vue-infinite-scroll/issues/124&gt;ElemeFE/vue-infinite-scroll#124&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-16T06:20:03Z'>
		They recommend adding -webkit-user-drag: none;, we can try that. Works when you install our Web app on the home screen (removes browser toolbar at the top). Maybe broke after updating dependencies. It used to work.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-16T06:26:34Z'>
		Tested it a second time and it worked. Maybe only happens when the browser toolbar is in a certain position.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-16T13:33:23Z'>
		I can reproduce it on Galaxy Tab A with Android 9: if I open the demo in the browser directly, infinite scrolling does not work. If I open the progressive web app it scrolling works fine.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='linosgian' date='2020-02-16T21:57:42Z'>
		It's definitely only occurring on Chrome (Android) devices. I've tested the same device (Honor 10) on Firefox Preview browser and the scrolling works just fine. Also tested this on Chrome on iOS and it also works fine. I could test what you're suggesting &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lastzero&gt;@lastzero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='linosgian' date='2020-03-23T21:02:34Z'>
		Maybe this fixes it. Build is running!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='linosgian' date='2020-03-24T15:18:13Z'>
		Should be working now. Added touch event listeners to trigger refresh (top) and loadMore (bottom). Hope this doesn't break things in other / older browsers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='linosgian' date='2020-04-01T07:35:50Z'>
		I just updated to the latest build, and it works fine on all devices/browsers (those I've tested at least)
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='linosgian' date='2020-04-01T08:04:34Z'>
		Thank you for testing!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>