<bug id='296' author='Aidan-OS' open_date='2020-05-06T16:51:09Z' closed_time='2020-05-07T14:59:21Z'>
	<summary>Photos missing after upload</summary>
	<description>
Found and installed Photoprism today in hopes of moving all images off my google drive to a personal server. I used the docker compose method of creating the container.
My first uploads went fine, testing with single images. I noticed that the quality filter was blocking everything, so I turned it off. I also noticed that there is an NSFW Filter that I needed to turn off, so I did so in the Docker Compose and restarted the server.
Now, when I import a photo, either using the web interface or right on the server, the image does not appear. The amount of photos in the menu on the left does not reflect the amount of photos the software sees when browsing.
For example, when I tested importing 3 files by putting them in the "Import" folder on the server, connecting to the container and running photoprism import and photoprism index, the file count for files in the "private" section increased to 3, however when I go to browse there are no files.
Accurate image counts for what I have uploaded
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1919827/81204923-f5821c80-8f97-11ea-8782-35f11b4561cb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Private tab
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1919827/81204948-003cb180-8f98-11ea-85e0-8a3ae54022b8.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Photos found in main tab (Cropped due to privacy reasons)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1919827/81205070-2cf0c900-8f98-11ea-83ab-21d198c4f62f.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T16:53:34Z'>
		Maybe the problem is that they are still marked as private? You can open the private page, mark all images and click on the lock in the context menu (bottom right). This should remove the private flag.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T16:54:24Z'>
		Also make sure to properly restart the container, docker restart does NOT work for configuration changes. You need down and up.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T16:54:28Z'>
		There are no Images available for selection on the private page, as seen in the second photo
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T16:55:13Z'>
		I have been using  as stated here: &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.photoprism.org/en/latest/getting-started/docker-compose/#step-2-run&gt;https://docs.photoprism.org/en/latest/getting-started/docker-compose/#step-2-run&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T16:57:16Z'>
		Thanks for the hint, this is wrong :/ Will change it! Down and up works.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:02:59Z'>
		Used Down and Up, that has made my password change go through thankfully. Sadly I am still unable to upload any new files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:04:16Z'>
		What do the logs say? See Library &gt; Logs tab.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:05:40Z'>
		PHOTOPRISM_DETECT_NSFW is false and PHOTOPRISM_UPLOAD_NSFW is true now, right?
See &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/286&gt;#286&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:06:43Z'>
		Oddly enough, the logs are empty. I checked them earlier and there was some, but they seem to have vanished. PHOTOPRISM_DETECT_NSFW is false and PHOTOPRISM_UPLOAD_NSFW is true.
I have already browsed that issue, and that is why I changed them to their current values :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:08:32Z'>
		docker-compose logs --tail="100" -f
Logs in the browser disappear when you reload so that we don't get memory issues.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:11:36Z'>
		If your photos are not strictly private, you're welcome to test with our demo too. Just in case it's a problem with a specific file.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:12:07Z'>
		I uploaded 2 Images. The first has appeared in the photo browser, however the second has not.
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="1 files uploaded in 8.347812ms"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="moving files from 1588785005218"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="import: no .ppignore file found"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="mediafile: taken at 2020-05-06 17:10:05.863905449 +0000 UTC"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="import: moving main png file Image-37.png to 2020/05/20200506_171005_75306D05.png"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:05Z" level=info msg="convert: 2020/05/20200506_171005_75306D05.png -&gt; 2020/05/20200506_171005_75306D05.jpg"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:06Z" level=info msg="mediafile: 11 thumbnails created for 20200506_171005_75306D05 [261.019556ms]"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:06Z" level=info msg="import: added main png file 2020/05/20200506_171005_75306D05.png"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:07Z" level=info msg="index: no latitude and longitude in metadata"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:07Z" level=info msg="photo: changed photo title to “Unknown / 2020”"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:07Z" level=info msg="import: added related jpg file 2020/05/20200506_171005_75306D05.jpg"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:07Z" level=info msg="import: deleted empty directory /photoprism/import/upload/1588785005218"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:07Z" level=info msg="import completed in 1 s"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="1 files uploaded in 562.062µs"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="moving files from 1588785019465"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="import: no .ppignore file found"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="mediafile: taken at 2020-05-06 17:10:20.111666555 +0000 UTC"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="import: moving main png file Image-38.png to 2020/05/20200506_171020_C70D9FEC.png"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:20Z" level=info msg="mediafile: 11 thumbnails created for 20200506_171020_C70D9FEC [92.919637ms]"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="mediafile: taken at 2020-05-06 17:10:20.123666351 +0000 UTC"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="index: no latitude and longitude in metadata"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="photo: changed photo title to “Unknown / 2020”"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="import: added main png file 2020/05/20200506_171020_C70D9FEC.png"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="import: deleted empty directory /photoprism/import/upload/1588785019465"
photoprism_1  | time="2020-05-06T17:10:21Z" level=info msg="import completed in 1 s"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:19:30Z'>
		Files upload to the demo without issue, however I am unable to test with the files I am currently trying on my personal server due to their NSFW nature. Could this have been a problem with the NSFW Filter, and if so, what is the best method for fully removing all data on my server and then starting from scratch again?
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:21:55Z'>
		Same problem with JPEG files? The quality filter would certainly "block" PNGs without additional metadata, as those are typically used for screenshots and not for photography. We only support PNG because many users were asking for it. (Note: You can, and already did, turn off the quality filter. It's an optional feature.)
You can simply delete the database and re-index. If you use the built-in server, delete the database directory (or Docker volume).
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:24:39Z'>
		All files I have been uploading have been PNGs without metadata. If it is the case that you do not fully support them, I sadly will have to find another software.
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:30:32Z'>
		We fully support them, but if there is no metadata, we can not provide additional value by searching it or showing the position on a map. Professional digital asset management systems might be better suited, like companies use them for product photos.
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:32:26Z'>
		We even support Exif headers in PNGs, which is not very common.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:36:50Z'>
		After deleting the database (/root/Pictures), I started the container again. Now, after indexing, it claims there are 34 photos, however none appear:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1919827/81209501-a12e6b00-8f9e-11ea-9503-1b91ba86cbf0.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I understand there should be no photos, as I just deleted them, but I don't see why Photoprism still thinks they are there.
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:39:33Z'>
		Did you fully reload the app in the browser? Otherwise the number will not update. Pictures is probably not the database, directory is named database. In our docker-compose.yml example it's a docker volume, you need to use docker volume ls to see all volumes and then docker volume rm to delete it, should be named something like  photoprism_photoprism-database.
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:47:48Z'>
		I seem to understand now. I am looking to upload photos and then give them tags manually.
I just uploaded 2 photos, one of which was recognized as a portrait. In the "Labels" section, I see the image as the thumbnail for "Portrait", however when I click on it, it tells me that there are no photos with that label.
This seems to me that the software is aware that my pictures are on the server, however is not showing them to me in any way so that I may add labels to them.
		</comment>
		<comment id='21' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:52:35Z'>
		Sounds like the nsfw / private flag is still set somehow. You could run photoprism config (for example in a terminal with docker-compose exec photoprism bash) and see if it is turned on for any reason.
		</comment>
		<comment id='22' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:54:49Z'>
		Do you need the upload for anything specific? Otherwise you could just copy the files to the originals / import directory or use WebDAV for remote file management.
		</comment>
		<comment id='23' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T17:58:33Z'>
		Yes. After further testing I have deemed that it is some sort of problem with the NSFW tag, as uploading metadataless SFW png files works perfectly fine.
When running photoprism config I that detect-nsfw is false and upload-nsfw is true
The reason I am setting this up is for an artist who creates both NSFW and SFW works. They wish to be able to easily browse files they have uploaded and share them with select people over the internet. They do not like their files being hosted on hardware they do not control, thus I am assisting the movement to a small, locally hosted image server.
		</comment>
		<comment id='24' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T18:01:07Z'>
		I see, makes sense. They could connect via WebDAV (supported by all major operating systems), it's also more convenient than web upload. You need to set a password in the config, the URL to connect is example.com/originals/ and example.com/import/, whatever way of adding images you like.
		</comment>
		<comment id='25' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T18:03:04Z'>
		It's already late here, I'll test NSFW tomorrow. Maybe there is an issue with our configuration.
		</comment>
		<comment id='26' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T18:05:49Z'>
		Is this the only way of bypassing the problems that seem to exist with the NSFW filter? I would prefer to leave them with an all in one and simple package, as they are not very technologically literate.
The matter is not pressing and I have not found another software that appears to meet all our requirements, so I would be glad to wait for a possible fix.
		</comment>
		<comment id='27' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-06T18:07:35Z'>
		If the NSFW filter is broken, we will fix it - just not tonight ;)
		</comment>
		<comment id='28' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-07T07:03:23Z'>
		I had the same issue, I just had to disable the "filter low quality pictures" option, and they all appeared. Resolution of my photos was full HD, so I guess there is something wrong?
		</comment>
		<comment id='29' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-07T07:18:31Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pluja&gt;@pluja&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Resolution is just one information that is used for the filter, exif information as created by a typical, modern camera is also important. High-res pictures can as well be screenshots or wallpapers. We want to make it easy to browse personal photography. Some people might use PNG without Metadata for this, but not the majority. I agree, we should not name it "quality filter" as this makes everyone think the resolution is not good enough or it's an ugly picture... "require a review for non-photographic or low-resolution images" was a bit long for a checkbox label... suggestions welcome.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Aidan-OS&gt;@Aidan-OS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Tested upload this morning with heaps of NSFW PNG images, and had no issues after setting the NSFW flags as described () and disabling private and quality filter in Settings. However, updating to Chrome 81 broke the upload file selector. That needs to be fixed now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='30' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-07T08:28:29Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Aidan-OS&gt;@Aidan-OS&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/pluja&gt;@pluja&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Added an additional check before running NSFW detection in the backend and improved the quality filter description. New Docker images for testing should be available in about one hour.
		</comment>
		<comment id='31' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-07T13:34:29Z'>
		Updated getting started for docker-compose: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism-docs/commit/3a8cce4191ed7b5218d96d8a58c75c7b23621298&gt;photoprism/photoprism-docs@3a8cce4&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It was in fact a bit old and not accurate anymore.
		</comment>
		<comment id='32' author='Aidan-OS' date='2020-05-07T14:59:20Z'>
		Also updated our pure Docker docs and added more details to the docker-compose guide: &lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.photoprism.org/en/latest/getting-started/docker-compose/&gt;https://docs.photoprism.org/en/latest/getting-started/docker-compose/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Hope this is good for now, let us know when you have questions or spotted a typo! I'll close this ticket as the comments are getting way to long for anyone to read.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>