<bug id='299' author='ravetam' open_date='2020-05-10T15:27:12Z' closed_time='2020-05-11T12:29:33Z'>
	<summary>Lost thumbnail after reindexed</summary>
	<description>
First of all, this is an awesome tool, I have been using it for the past week to organize and geotag all my photos from a recent trip. One issue I encountered twice is that photoprism were not able to reverse lookup certain GPS location which causes the image to be tagged with "Unknown" location. So what i did is slightly modify those images GPS data with exiftool.
Once re-indexed and since the image hash has now changed and thumbnail are named using the image's hash, Photoprism no longer finds the thumbnail.
ERROR photo: thumbnail not cached
However, a few smaller thumbnails are generated which i assumed are being used for labeling.

├── 69f05da9b6a8113125dce0e5ffb9c5f6a5132f47_224x224_center.jpg
├── 69f05da9b6a8113125dce0e5ffb9c5f6a5132f47_224x224_left.jpg
├── 69f05da9b6a8113125dce0e5ffb9c5f6a5132f47_224x224_right.jpg
└── 69f05da9b6a8113125dce0e5ffb9c5f6a5132f47_3x3_resize.png

Maybe this can be fixed my renaming and moving the existing thumbnails to its new location. This will reduce a lot of orphaned thumbnails.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-10T17:56:50Z'>
		Well observed, this is because we disabled on-demand thumbnail rendering as users with no thumbs at all were running out of memory, see &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/294&gt;#294&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
.
In your case, on demand rendering probably wouldn't hurt as it's just a couple of photos. Your existing thumbs can not be found as the sha1 hash changed and that's the cache key.
Either set PHOTOPRISM_THUMB_UNCACHED: "true" in docker-compose.yml or render missing thumbs:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;docker-compose exec photoprism photoprism thumbs
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

We should automatically re-render those thumbs in the future and maybe delete the old ones to save storage.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-10T18:14:33Z'>
		My change should automatically trigger resampling when files were updated in the index. It does not clean-up the cache directory to remove old thumbs, that's an optimization we'll take care of later.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-10T18:15:09Z'>
		New Docker build is available within the next hour. You're welcome to test!
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-11T03:14:10Z'>
		thanks for the quick response! i will test it tonight and post my result
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-11T12:29:33Z'>
		Tested and confirm issue is fixed, new thumbnails are being generated now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='ravetam' date='2020-05-11T12:33:35Z'>
		Excellent, thank you! :)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>