<bug id='300' author='uLUViL3gCs' open_date='2020-05-10T20:34:41Z' closed_time='2020-05-11T09:10:29Z'>
	<summary>A deleted photo does not find its way back to the system</summary>
	<description>
Description:
If a known photo once got deleted from the system (physical removal from disk, followed by an Index), a new import of the EXACT SAME photo does not bring back the photo. The system seems not to trigger a “re-import” of a file that has been known from the past - irrespective of whether it  got deleted in between or not.
You can debate on the severity and also on the likelihood of this scenario; nonetheless I suppose this should be taken care of. As a user I’d like to have the chance to be able to remove a file and later change my opinion and add it again. Same is true in case user accidentally removed a file, observes her/his failure and is trying to correct it some time later again.
Steps to reproduce:
 OK:
•	remove database 
•	remove files within Originals folder 
•	restart photoprism 
•	import some random files and check that import works OK (Library -&gt; Import -&gt; Import)  
•	delete ALL or a SET of files  
•	Re-index system and check that “removal” for the selected file(s) worked correctly (Library -&gt; Originals -&gt; Index (Complete Rescan: True))
NOK:
•	Import the EXACT SAME file(s) as deleted earlier and check that files are added (back) to the system
=&gt; None of the re-added files appear in the system; neither any counter nor any list reflects the re-added files
•	Re-index system to check it solves the problem
=&gt; Same result; re-added files are still not visible
Tested with:
PhotoPrism version 200510-561323d-Linux-x86_64
Firefox 76.0
Chrome Version 81.0.4044.138
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-10T20:47:15Z'>
		Should be visible in archive at least? It's true that photos that have been moved to archive don't get restored when you upload / import them a second time. Since the purge command may now also (soft) delete (=archive) a photo, it's possible that it doesn't get restored too.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T07:26:19Z'>
		
Should be visible in archive at least?

Unfortunately not. Even the archive appears to be/remain empty.

It's true that photos that have been moved to archive don't get restored when you upload / import them a second time.

I understand. One main difference I see here is that in case A) user actively archived a photo, the file on disk remained in originals folder while in case of B) deleting/purging the photo, it is no longer available.
In case of A) by the way, a restoration is successful.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T07:46:30Z'>
		Already found the issue, pushing a fix soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T07:49:36Z'>
		With this fix, re-imported files will even get the file name they previously had.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T07:50:35Z'>
		Thank you! Again, well observed :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T08:11:32Z'>
		Docker build is running: &lt;denchmark-link:https://travis-ci.org/github/photoprism/photoprism/builds/685548527&gt;https://travis-ci.org/github/photoprism/photoprism/builds/685548527&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T09:03:18Z'>
		
With this fix, re-imported files will even get the file name they previously had.

Excellent! Re-tested with

PhotoPrism version 200511-984ffb5-Linux-x86_64

Now the pictures indeed are finding way back to the system; also, the earlier file names are applied.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-11T09:09:44Z'>
		Next build will update photo count in places and labels after webdav sync (download). Hope we're finally done with fixes now!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>