<bug id='330' author='Jinvis' open_date='2020-05-23T15:02:11Z' closed_time='2020-07-03T17:42:32Z'>
	<summary>Frontend: Show helpful message if websocket connection fails</summary>
	<description>
Hi,
I use my mariadb for photoprism,  as the pics show, but when I access photoprism through my domain name, the numbers at left gone, and catalogs' options also gone, but it works well when i access with local domain name, such as 192.168.0.242:2342 , it is confused.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26951454/82733753-acc4b480-9d48-11ea-9e2c-73477f01b354.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26951454/82733573-3ecbbd80-9d47-11ea-8847-ca45ede31ce1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26951454/82733500-d54baf00-9d46-11ea-9097-1ad750a69891.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

internet domain name(such as &lt;denchmark-link:http://www.baidu.com&gt;www.baidu.com&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26951454/82733549-1a6fe100-9d47-11ea-96cc-4993bf4b6c3b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

local domain name(such as 192.168.0.242:2342)
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-23T16:59:40Z'>
		I have seen this earlier and it looked like the numbers were only available right after login-in. Later they disappeared. Logging out and in always brought the numbers back.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-23T23:27:16Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opichals&gt;@opichals&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
,
You are right, it work well after relogin, but after I refreshed photoprism page, the issue come again.
And this issue is gone with using local domain name (192.168.0.242:2342), no mater how many times I access the page.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T03:20:58Z'>
		Might be a websocket issue, we frequently send updated numbers and lists to the client. You might see an error when you open the browser JavaScript console (developer tools).
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T04:00:12Z'>
		See also Official configuration for Caddy &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/285&gt;#285&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T05:09:02Z'>
		I found a connection error in console:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/26951454/82746196-ae7d8f00-9dbf-11ea-9963-defceebc626a.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T10:24:50Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/Jinvis&gt;@Jinvis&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 if u are using nginx, you can try to add:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;proxy_set_header Upgrade $http_upgrade;
proxy_set_header Connection "upgrade";
proxy_buffering off;
proxy_http_version 1.1;
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T17:01:48Z'>
		Seems it has been indeed caused by the websocket connection failing.
From another angle it should not stop showing the numbers altogether when numbers update channel connection is not working IMO. I'd expect it to show stale numbers/filters till the next reload (or re-login) action.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-24T17:17:37Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opichals&gt;@opichals&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Yes, indeed we should at least show a clear error message. Since our app makes heavy use of websockets to keep everything in sync, not just the counters, we should disable all actions in the UI to avoid data loss and/or confusion until we have time to implement a fallback mode.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='Jinvis' date='2020-05-25T00:10:44Z'>
		Hi &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lastzero&gt;@lastzero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

It works after add the config in nginx
Thanks
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='Jinvis' date='2020-06-23T09:32:56Z'>
		Let's see if we can fix this with additional code before our release. It's mainly a documentation issue so that our users know what the requirements are and how to configure their servers.
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='Jinvis' date='2020-06-23T09:34:45Z'>
		If someone from our community has a good idea, we'd be happy to accept a pull request. A warning message that explains the issue and potential solutions would already help.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='Jinvis' date='2020-07-01T16:35:22Z'>
		Message links to this issue until we have finished our docs...
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/86269086-886eba00-bbc9-11ea-83e2-af56f9b21ede.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='Jinvis' date='2020-07-03T15:05:53Z'>
		Moved the info to the sidebar navigation and added a help page which contains examples for common proxies:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/86481002-6ef77a80-bd4f-11ea-9eb2-b0c1207ce2a8.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='Jinvis' date='2020-07-03T17:42:32Z'>
		Seems to work, received no complaints. Please create a new issue if you find a bug!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>