<bug id='331' author='opichals' open_date='2020-05-23T16:06:49Z' closed_time='2020-05-31T21:30:24Z'>
	<summary>Album view shows only first 59 photos</summary>
	<description>
Steps to reproduce

go to https://demo.photoprism.org
select all photos in the photos section (show 83 photos)
add to album (create a new one e.g. 'Test')
go to 'Test' album view and see only the first 59 images being rendered (mosaic view)
shows 59 photos found notification even though the album has more photos

Tested in latest stable Google Chrome.
Similarly it also appears on 3 weeks old local docker-based &lt;denchmark-link:https://hub.docker.com/layers/photoprism/photoprism/20200429/images/sha256-ecf1703af071f569169b5969889430cd8d3a9ed02b2d227813a4038012536478?context=explore&gt;photoprism/photoprism:20200429&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
  install where it says 38 photos while there is more than a hundred items in the  table in the DB associated with the particular album .
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='opichals' date='2020-05-23T18:06:14Z'>
		Good catch! Fixed it locally, but can't push right now as I'm in the middle of a huge change for albums.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='opichals' date='2020-05-23T18:06:50Z'>
		Seems like master doesn't have this already (just updated my git working copy). Perhaps got fixed here because I had to wipe the DB?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='opichals' date='2020-05-23T18:08:21Z'>
		No, it's just fixed on my computer. Will be pushed to develop when I'm done, then master.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='opichals' date='2020-05-23T18:09:12Z'>
		Was a JS issue as we've changed how results are counted, forgot to change it in albums.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='opichals' date='2020-05-26T11:54:16Z'>
		It's fixed, you can test it on our demo when we release a new Docker build, hopefully tomorrow or later this week. Currently working on moments with some breaking changes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='opichals' date='2020-05-27T18:16:57Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lastzero&gt;@lastzero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Just tried to create a new  album &lt;denchmark-link:https://demo.photoprism.org/albums/aqb05e7jcvk8qlxs?view=mosaic&amp;order=oldest&gt;https://demo.photoprism.org/albums/aqb05e7jcvk8qlxs?view=mosaic&amp;order=oldest&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 album and it still only shows 59 photos added.
Ah, nevermind there is no new dockerhub published image since 5 days ago.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='opichals' date='2020-05-27T18:34:20Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/opichals&gt;@opichals&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Still no new Docker builds, will let you know when it's merged to master.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='opichals' date='2020-05-31T19:02:36Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/lastzero&gt;@lastzero&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 Looks good at demo.photoprism.org now.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>