<bug id='334' author='uLUViL3gCs' open_date='2020-05-25T10:11:05Z' closed_time='2020-06-01T18:39:25Z'>
	<summary>Favorite counter erroneously increasing for archived files</summary>
	<description>
Description:
 Whenever a user is “liking” a file that is located in Archive, the Favorite Counter is increased.
Liking a file located in archive, does not seem to be an use case as such anyways, so that the file itself is not going to be marked as “liked” anyway.
Same, however, should be true for the counter, the counter should not increase either.
Note: the counter is updated to “correct value” again as soon as any file in the system is either added or removed from archive.
Problem is rather of cosmetic character.
Steps to reproduce:
OK:

Archive a file
select Archive in navgation pane

NOK:

click “like” button on any file in Archive =&gt; the favorite counter in navigation bar is increasing by each click

Tested with:
 PhotoPrism™ 200522-c88cd69-Linux-x86_64 
Chrome 81.0.4044.138 / macOS 10.15.4
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-26T11:21:28Z'>
		Great observation. I was already wondering how to handle changes in archive in general. Technically, it's possible and the biggest challenge is not to update counters etc like in this case. Adds some complexity.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-05-26T11:54:43Z'>
		It's fixed, you can test it on our demo when we release a new Docker build, hopefully tomorrow or later this week. Currently working on moments with some breaking changes.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-06-01T18:39:24Z'>
		
Technically, it's possible and the biggest challenge is not to update counters etc like in this case. Adds some complexity.

Successfully retested on PhotoPrism™ 200601-716012a-Linux-x86_64.
Pretty nice solution from usability/user expecation point of view: the files in archive and the favorite counter seem to be "decoupled" and the counter gets updated correctly, when liked files are either archived or un-archived.
=&gt; Issue closed.
 from the original issue &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/334&gt;#334&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 to be resolved, I'd like to raise the question whether or not similar "decoupling" should apply for "private" marked files, too:
Currently, a "private" marked file that gets a "like" increases the favorites counter. When Favorites  section is inspected, however, these "private" and "liked" files do not show up. The result is a "mismatch" of Favorites counter in navigation bar and actual files in Favorites container.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/64777347/83441955-a8cf1b80-a447-11ea-9278-c214596a00fd.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Underlying question: how should "private" marked files reflect/show up/influence (in) the system otherwise than in the "private" section itself? Should you find references to private files somewhere at all - or just within the private section?
In my humble opinion, private marked files should "vanish" from the system where ever possible and only be seen in "private" section.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='uLUViL3gCs' date='2020-06-05T05:22:16Z'>
		Great work!
That's how I expected private marked files should behave, thanks!

User is still able to change like/dislike flag of an archived file and it is correctly getting visible only when file is un-archived. No counter mismatch.
Counters correctly update when files are archived.

Checked with:
PhotoPrism™ 200604-5b1c0f2-Linux-x86_64
(Chrome 81.0.4044.138 / macOS 10.15.4)
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>