<bug id='370' author='wiwie' open_date='2020-06-30T17:48:17Z' closed_time='2020-07-01T18:03:27Z'>
	<summary>Album and Album Share: Clicking on any picture with pid &amp;gt; 100 shows fullscreen overlay for picture with pid=1</summary>
	<description>
I am using the newest docker as of 5 minutes ago.
I created an album with more than 100 pictures. I created a share for this album as well.
With either album and share, when I click on any picture with pid&gt;100, the picture fullscreen overlay is shown for picture with pid=1 instead of the clicked picture.
I did not reset the database when updating to the newest docker. If that could be the cause of this issue, please let me know and I'll try again after resetting the database.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T17:54:21Z'>
		Did you clear the browser cache? Might be related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/309&gt;#309&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, since we now load the full list of photos for large result sets.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:18:08Z'>
		Tried clearing browser cache, tried it in a private tab, tried in Firefox and Chromium. Same result.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:19:47Z'>
		Same happens to me, but not always... clearly a bug. That's why we didn't want to implement &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/309&gt;#309&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
, but now we'll fix it... once the problem is clear... files are being update in the background, so the index of images changes all the time.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:21:34Z'>
		Might only happen while the indexer is running and adding new files...
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:24:57Z'>
		All images had been indexed (at least initially) before I observed the behavior. Last indexing I initiated was yesterday.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:25:53Z'>
		If the indexer re-encounters indexed files their index is probably not modified?
Edit: Correction. If you are talking about the index UI-wise (i.e. concerning the sort order in the UI) as opposed to the index of the photo in the DB, there are of course cases where the index of a previously indexed photo can change when encountering other new photos and the chosen sorting method requires it. But since all my photos had been indexed, this can be excluded as cause in my case.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T18:27:37Z'>
		Not sure, but thanks for reporting this. It was a long day, I'll take a look at this tomorrow. Probably a frontend (JS) issue. Everyone is most welcome to debug this in the meantime :)
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T19:15:10Z'>
		The issue occurs, as long as not all photos of the album have been loaded.
When opening an album with sufficiently many pictures such that not all pictures are loaded initially, all pictures with pid&gt;100 behave faulty.
When scrolling down a bit such that some more pictures are loaded but not all, still all pictures with pid&gt;100 behave faulty.
As soon as one has scrolled down all the way down and all pictures have been loaded, all pictures including those with pid&gt;100 behave correctly.
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T19:33:56Z'>
		That's by design. If all photos are loaded, we use the actual results for the photo viewer. If not, we request the full list (up to 3333 files).
		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='wiwie' date='2020-06-30T19:46:59Z'>
		I was probably not clear enough in my explanation.
This issue that clicking on an image with pid&gt;100 brings up the wrong fullscreen version of the first image of the album (pid=1) occurs only as long as not all images of the album have been loaded. Once all images have been loaded (by scrolling all the way down), the issue disappears and clicking on any image (also pid&gt;100) brings up the correct fullscreen version.
Edit: Oh I think I know now what you are getting at. Yes, it may of course be by design. I only tried to narrow down the search space for the bug for you a bit. But I guess I didn't tell you anything that you didn't already know then :-D
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='wiwie' date='2020-07-01T15:52:23Z'>
		can confirm that it works now. However, opening a picture seems to take longer than yesterday (spinner on top shows longer)? this happens at least in the share from yesterday. It seems snappier in the "all pictures" overview. possibly nothing related to your changes, just thought I should mention it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='wiwie' date='2020-07-01T16:04:46Z'>
		It does since we load the full list, however this was optimized during the day. Should be 30% faster now.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='wiwie' date='2020-07-01T18:03:07Z'>
		Ok. I'm using the latest docker as of 5 minutes ago and it's still perceivable slower than yesterday.
		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='wiwie' date='2020-07-01T18:11:22Z'>
		I have an idea how to optimize it further... We'll be the kings of complexity 🤴
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>