<bug id='399' author='PiotrEsse' open_date='2020-07-13T15:29:20Z' closed_time='2020-09-03T06:59:50Z'>
	<summary>Wrong Auto Geotagging with Polish city names.</summary>
	<description>
Hi, I found a bug where PP cant show location but images in fact contain valid Geolocation data.
Way to replicate bug:


photos have geolocation data


photoprism cannot determine the country


PP sometimes adds valid tags


Such photos fall into the "unknown" location category


To solve the issue You just specify the country when editing the photo and all data appear correctly - street, city, etc.


It may have something to do with Polish signs for the city. Noticed with the city of Polska / GDAŃSK
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-13T16:23:35Z'>
		Can you provide us with example files for testing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-14T11:32:11Z'>
		Might be related to &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/issues/380&gt;#380&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
. I'll try with random coordinates in Poland. Still would be helpful to get more details for testing.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-14T11:39:32Z'>
		Works for me, but I assume there are specific coordinates that are broken because of incoherent OpenStreetMap data. So in order to really debug and fix this, we need coordinates and/or a test image from you.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/87421353-19389300-c5d7-11ea-8b16-24b23d382f71.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-14T11:40:54Z'>
		To be correct - it works for me most of the time ;-)
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T05:27:25Z'>
		More wrongly tagged pictures
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506741-56029980-c66c-11ea-9a14-182462d109cc.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506746-59962080-c66c-11ea-9c39-0dab2c9a2bfc.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506757-6155c500-c66c-11ea-9f15-556c83043eb7.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506761-63b81f00-c66c-11ea-8a71-8fce06b7a4d2.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506779-70d50e00-c66c-11ea-993b-4ba0cd2ccbfc.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87506788-75012b80-c66c-11ea-92aa-11578cc9d7ec.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T05:28:03Z'>
		ups, closed by accident...
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T05:37:25Z'>
		Amazing, thank you!
Migrated your backend translation to gettext by the way, so that we have a common toolset: &lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/tree/develop/assets/locales/pl&gt;https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/tree/develop/assets/locales/pl&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T06:28:05Z'>
		
Amazing, thank you!
Migrated your backend translation to gettext by the way, so that we have a common toolset: https://github.com/photoprism/photoprism/tree/develop/assets/locales/pl

Thank You!
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T07:28:30Z'>
		Looks good to me, wouldn't know what to improve? Added Huawei models P20 / P20 Pro and removed automatically generated image descriptions for you though :)
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/87516177-42136380-c67d-11ea-9886-2d7edb3840c1.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T07:31:46Z'>
		Can you try again using a fresh PhotoPrism instance with empty storage directory and database?
		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T09:18:33Z'>
		I should remove /originals folder or just do complete rescan?
		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T09:21:52Z'>
		Don't delete your originals, please :) Just automatically created JSON or YAML sidecar files. They can hold a backup of the database, so just deleting the database won't remove all previously indexed data. They should be in a separate directory, depending on your configuration (see docker-compose.yml). When using Docker, you might have to remove the volume with docker volume rm, unless it was mounted to a regular host directory where you can simply delete the files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T09:24:54Z'>
		Note that we're continuously updating our example  files, to reflect recent changes in configuration like new or renamed parameters: &lt;denchmark-link:https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&gt;https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T11:50:27Z'>
		I have default docker-compose.yml version 3.3 from Your link.
I found  sidecar files in:
_/var/lib/docker/volumes/root_photoprism-storage/data/sidecar
Should I delete all subfolders there? (I have subfolders with years - ie 2014..2015..2016...etc) I found there *.jpg files
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-15T12:02:32Z'>
		Yes, it's safe to delete them, alternatively you can change the volume name in docker-compose.yml
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-16T07:17:56Z'>
		An update.
Yesterday Ive deleted all sidecar files and reindex files again. Theres still the same issue - some files are not properly updated with country tag. But I doscover another bug - Ill fill new issue right away.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87638497-2aeb7900-c744-11ea-91e7-c491d8fb86c8.jpg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-07-16T07:23:08Z'>
		Additionally I found bug in logs:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/42764623/87639716-f4166280-c745-11ea-8b95-34356961b678.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-09-03T06:37:24Z'>
		Can we close this? I'm sure there is some "bad" geo data every once in a while but that needs to be fixed over time for specific coordinates.
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-09-03T06:58:52Z'>
		Yes, close this. Will take care later ;-)
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='PiotrEsse' date='2020-09-03T06:59:50Z'>
		Dear Michael,
sure Ive closed this. We ll take care about this later if any issue arrise.
-- 
-- 
Pozdrawiam serdecznie,
*Piotr Esse
*
------------------------------------------------------------------------

|Mobile: +48 506392139 | E-mail: piotr.esse@spero.click
&lt;mailto:piotr.esse@spero.click&gt; |

  * /Zgłoszenia prosimy przesyłać na adres naszego systemu:
    *zgloszenia@spero.click*/
  * /**Jeśli jesteś już naszym klientem - *zaloguj się
    &lt;&lt;denchmark-link:https://spero.click/pm/clients/login&gt;*&gt;https://spero.click/pm/clients/login&gt;*&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 na Twój panel klienta aby
    dodawać i sprawdzać Twoje zgłoszenia oraz mieć dostęp do innych
    informacji odnośnie naszej wspólnej współpracy./
  * /Jeśli nie masz dostępu do panelu klienta - zgłoś brak dostępu. /
  * /**Baza wiedzy: zanim zadasz pytanie - zajrzyj do naszej *bazy
    wiedzy &lt;&lt;denchmark-link:https://spero.click/pm/knowledge-base&gt;**&gt;https://spero.click/pm/knowledge-base&gt;**&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

    */

/Ta wiadomość może zawierać informacje, które są uprzywilejowane, poufne
i nie podlegają ujawnieniu na mocy obowiązującego prawa. Jeśli czytelnik
tej wiadomości nie jest zamierzonym odbiorcą lub agentem odpowiedzialnym
za dostarczenie jej do zamierzonego odbiorcy, zostajesz powiadomiony, że
otrzymałeś tę wiadomość elektroniczną omyłkowo oraz, że wszelkie
przeglądy, rozpowszechnianie, rozpowszechnianie lub kopiowanie tej
wiadomości jest surowo zabronione. Jeśli otrzymałeś tę wiadomość
elektroniczną przez pomyłkę, powiadom nas natychmiast e-mailem i usuń
oryginalną wiadomość ze swojego systemu. Dziękujemy za zrozumienie.
This message may contain information that is privileged, confidential
and exempt from disclosure under applicable law. If the reader of this
message is not the intended recipient, or an agent responsible for
delivering it to the intended recipient, you are hereby notified that
you have received this electronic message in error and that any review,
dissemination, distribution or copying of this message is strictly
prohibited. If you have received this electronic message in error,
please notify us immediately by email, and delete the original message
from your system. Thank you. /


Michael Mayer wrote on 03.09.2020 08:38:
&lt;denchmark-link:#&gt;…&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;



 Can we close this? I'm sure there is some "bad" geo data every once in
 a while but that needs to be fixed over time for specific coordinates.

 —
 You are receiving this because you modified the open/close state.
 Reply to this email directly, view it on GitHub
 &lt;#399 (comment)&gt;,
 or unsubscribe
 &lt;https://github.com/notifications/unsubscribe-auth/AKGIST5L2JRDOXOTHH6IQOTSD42TDANCNFSM4OYTFFOQ&gt;.



		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>