<bug id='414' author='flesser' open_date='2020-07-19T07:59:45Z' closed_time='2020-07-21T13:25:24Z'>
	<summary>Indexing aborts when encountering broken symlink that looks like an image file</summary>
	<description>
I am trying to index my existing collection in read-only mode.
Somewhere in there I have some broken symlinks (pointing to destinations that don't exist anymore) that are named *.JPG.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Actual Behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Once Photoprism encounters the first one of them, the indexing process stops and no further images are indexed:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;time="2020-07-18T17:52:00Z" level=error msg="stat /photoprism/originals/2010/2010 Norwegen/zzPräsentation/01/0101.JPG: no such file or directory"
time="2020-07-18T17:52:08Z" level=info msg="purge: searching index for hidden media files"
time="2020-07-18T17:52:08Z" level=info msg="indexed 25207 files in 1m25.465540257s"
time="2020-07-18T17:52:08Z" level=info msg="closed database connection"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

# docker exec photoprism ls -l "/photoprism/originals/2010/2010 Norwegen/zzPräsentation/01/"
total 15976
lrwxrwxrwx 1 www-data www-data      69 Jun 21  2011 0101.JPG -&gt; /home/Bilder/Fotos/Norwegen 2010/2010-08-18/P1040281.JPG
Restarting the index process stops at the same place again and no photos after the '2010/' folder are indexed.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;Expected Behavior&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

PhotoPrism logs, but ignores those broken "files" and continues indexing.
&lt;denchmark-h:h2&gt;PhotoPrism version&lt;/denchmark-h&gt;

Whatever was in docker latest yesterday at that time, but also tried again this morning with the current 200718-24cfa1a-Linux-x86_64.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='flesser' date='2020-07-19T12:35:56Z'>
		Excellent catch! Turns out, godirwalk needs an error handler to skip such broken links...
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='flesser' date='2020-07-19T12:49:23Z'>
		I'll merge this to master after testing some other potential issues that may have been introduced with recent optimizations.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='flesser' date='2020-07-19T14:53:06Z'>
		Fixed additional issues with wrong file type extensions, like PNGs that end with ".jpg". Lots of files imported from Google Photos seem to suffer from this. Also removed a potential deadlock in our log events.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='flesser' date='2020-07-20T22:13:34Z'>
		This (and much more) should be fixed now.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>