<bug id='587' author='totti4ever' open_date='2020-11-09T05:16:05Z' closed_time='2020-11-26T23:53:07Z'>
	<summary>Bug? I have two folders (in album's folder view) with no content</summary>
	<description>
The folder appears black and there is no content although I can see the pics of that folder in library's folder mode and they are also shown in calendar and places view.
Did I miss something or is this a bug? If so, how can I report for details?
cheers
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-09T08:59:22Z'>
		Might be a bug. Can you add a screenshot? What are the folder names (any special characters in it)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-09T09:13:22Z'>
		This is how it looks like:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/49901208/98521637-fd3aba80-2273-11eb-827e-3f0d073abce3.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

Folder names are both having a comma in them - this might be the reason? I'd say that is the difference to the ones without a problem
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-09T09:53:05Z'>
		Yes. Guess it's because our API can search for multiple values by separating them with a comma like folder:a,b. Might need to quote the name like folder:"a,b".
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-09T11:24:47Z'>
		I'm not talking about search (although there should be the same effect). I clicked on Almbums --&gt; Folders and the folders with commas in their path are empty.
I cannot quote anything there, I guess this has to be done somewhere in the code (when pictures are assigned to folders or so)?
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-09T15:45:31Z'>
		I know you're not talking about search, the server API is the same for all views though. Needs to be fixed in code somewhere.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-21T17:47:22Z'>
		Just started a new Docker build for testing. Available soon.
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='totti4ever' date='2020-11-26T23:53:07Z'>
		Closing this since no negative test reports came in.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>