<bug id='621' author='Engr-AllanG' open_date='2020-11-17T16:13:11Z' closed_time='2020-11-22T22:10:43Z'>
	<summary>Unable to share with public link with expiration date</summary>
	<description>

Installed via docker compose in proxmox container running ubuntu 18.04
Separate container running nginx reverse proxy
Everything seems to be working normally using my subdomain.domain.com
When I create a share link and paste it into a private browser for testing, it takes me to my login screen instead of a public view, which is what I expected. After I log in, it then goes to mydomain.com/photos

I am guessing this is related to my reverse proxy. Any tips on where to start looking? For what its worth, I am successfully using my reverse proxy with Nextcloud, Seafile, W10 blue iris, Cryptpad and 3 or 4 other applications, so i'm not a complete novice. But I can't seem to figure this one out. I'm not certain if its a bug or a configuration issue.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-17T17:04:06Z'>
		If you reopen the link after being logged in, do you see the expected page?
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-18T08:23:34Z'>
		&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/alexislefebvre&gt;@alexislefebvre&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 no after logging in, the album share link gets redirected to my main photos folder. I noticed that the share link does not have "public" in it:
e.g. 
But if I right click a photo in preview and copy link address - that one  have "public" in the link and it does work as intended:
e.g. 
this leads me to believe it is a photoprism issue. Thoughts?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-18T16:48:27Z'>
		I discovered the issue is related to having an expiration date on the link. Above the selection it says "Invalid DateTime". I'll have to check the date/time of the OS this evening. I suspect it is set incorrect. If it is correct, then maybe a bug.
With no expiration date, the share link works
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-18T17:17:16Z'>
		You're right, we can see this error on &lt;denchmark-link:https://demo.photoprism.org/albums/aqjyfk72jstm22m5/berge-2020&gt;https://demo.photoprism.org/albums/aqjyfk72jstm22m5/berge-2020&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 too:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/2071331/99564059-3ee10900-29ca-11eb-8fe9-ab6b3a1817bb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

And the share link &lt;denchmark-link:https://demo.photoprism.org/s/1gxdaj4bas/berge-2020&gt;https://demo.photoprism.org/s/1gxdaj4bas/berge-2020&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
 doesn't work, like you described it.
		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-19T09:57:46Z'>
		Thanks for reporting, we will have a look at it on the weekend!
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='Engr-AllanG' date='2020-11-22T22:10:40Z'>
		Just tested on new ubuntu 20.04 container - public album share link with expiration worked as expected! I didn't test the actual expiration of the link yet (will have to wait 24 hours), but the link itself functions.
Excellent app - I'm loving it
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>