<bug id='701' author='DillFrescott' open_date='2020-12-12T21:18:41Z' closed_time='2020-12-13T01:10:26Z'>
	<summary>Bug: Videos save as jpg?</summary>
	<description>
Both direct download and webdav saves the video as an image. That's not what I want.
	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-12T23:07:06Z'>
		If you download a video file via WebDAV you get an image? A file selector for web downloads should be on our roadmap otherwise. Same for raw and other non JPEG formats.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-12T23:20:00Z'>
		Yep. It gives me an image of the thumbnail and it confused me haha.
Ok that's fine.
Is there anything I might have done in the config that's causing the video to turn into a jpg? It's fine when it's still on PhotoPrism, it shows up as a video, just not when I download it or do WebDAV.
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-12T23:21:07Z'>
		Or is there a way to exec into the container and change something till it can be properly fixed?
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:25:16Z'>
		No problem with downloading and playing videos via WebDAV whatsoever:

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/101999911-d859bd00-3ce1-11eb-940f-967e59f1d063.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;


&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/101999909-d263dc00-3ce1-11eb-84d2-200c5d00cd71.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:27:23Z'>
		Note that we originally didn't plan to support videos. JPEG as default download format was meant for RAWs that most users can't properly use for most of what you're typically doing with a downloaded picture e.g. sharing, or watching on TV.
		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:47:28Z'>
		Maybe you don't use WebDAV but our REST API? That's not the same. Or you downloaded a mp4.jpg thumb instead of the actual video?
		</comment>
		<comment id='7' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:53:28Z'>
		Hmmm.
What I did was select the video by tapping in the lower right corner of the thumbnail.
Then the little circle with the 1 pops up at the bottom right of the page. I click that and then the green download button that extends from that menu.
It asks if I want to save a jpeg file.
I'll look again to notice if it's a mp4.jpeg file and report back.
My WebDAV server is just
&lt;denchmark-link:https://github.com/hacdias/webdav&gt;https://github.com/hacdias/webdav&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

This WebDAV server. It does the same thing as clicking the download button except I click the cloud and select the WebDAV server. Then when I check the WebDAV data folder it's a jpg.
		</comment>
		<comment id='8' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:54:50Z'>
		This was tested on my Windows 10 desktop as well as my iPhone using multiple browsers
		</comment>
		<comment id='9' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:55:22Z'>
		You don't need an extra WebDAV server, PhotoPrism is a WebDAV server:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://docs.photoprism.org/user-guide/backup/webdav/&gt;https://docs.photoprism.org/user-guide/backup/webdav/&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='10' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:57:02Z'>
		You mentioned the api thing. This is the url of the jpeg from trying to download a video...
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/56714680/102000292-1dff9100-3cb4-11eb-9346-e35f8b25b8a5.jpeg&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='11' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:57:35Z'>
		In addition, you can download all files in the files tab:
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/301686/102000310-8d8e7400-3ce6-11eb-850b-f695e05b7681.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='12' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T00:59:45Z'>
		
You mentioned the api thing. This is the url of the jpeg from trying to download a video...

Looks like the REST API... you can hack it, but you can as well use the download button in the dialog or connect via WebDAV...
		</comment>
		<comment id='13' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:06:28Z'>
		Ok. So I tried the download button and this is what I got
&lt;denchmark-link:https://i.ibb.co/b60d9Ht/capture.jpg&gt;https://i.ibb.co/b60d9Ht/capture.jpg&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='14' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:07:39Z'>
		I must be doing something incorrectly
		</comment>
		<comment id='15' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:08:26Z'>
		Nevermind I just noticed theres a jpg and an mp4
		</comment>
		<comment id='16' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:08:47Z'>
		Both the same file but i guess its the sidecar thing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='17' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:09:40Z'>
		You are right in that there is a download format and size selector missing when you click download in the context menu or full screen photo viewer. But there are other ways, as described, to download all files.
		</comment>
		<comment id='18' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:10:23Z'>
		Ok. Thank you for the help!
		</comment>
		<comment id='19' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:11:07Z'>
		By the way, I accidently clicked unstack. How do I undo that? Because now the mp4 is not listed under files anymore :(
		</comment>
		<comment id='20' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:13:34Z'>
		There is no way to manually merge arbitrary files in our UI yet. You can make sure the files have the same base name (without extension), remove the Unstacked flag in the edit dialog settings tab (on the right), and then wait a little or re-index.
		</comment>
		<comment id='21' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:14:19Z'>
		Ok. Thank you
		</comment>
		<comment id='22' author='DillFrescott' date='2020-12-13T01:15:07Z'>
		You're welcome.
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>