<bug id='721' author='CyanBC' open_date='2020-12-18T17:46:21Z' closed_time='2020-12-19T11:18:50Z'>
	<summary>Albums are lost on re-install</summary>
	<description>
If I remove and reinstall the docker instance of photoprism I lose all album information. I do not modify anything between removal and reinstall.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/16420413/102642779-86ada880-41a1-11eb-8884-f3fc722a3e4b.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

If I check mariadb I can see the photos_albums, and album tables are properly filled out before remove/reinstall.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/16420413/102642478-169f2280-41a1-11eb-99d5-598fadb0a684.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/16420413/102642541-333b5a80-41a1-11eb-97ec-bc22e326cf60.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

After removal and reinstall I log into photoprism from my browser and re-scan (Complete Rescan NOT selected) then I can see some previous albums (not all), the the photos_albums is empty.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/16420413/102643372-8530b000-41a2-11eb-9f21-31e2c1336650.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

but also no albums show up in the albums page.
&lt;denchmark-link:https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/16420413/102643465-abeee680-41a2-11eb-8e30-da78a2d585bb.png&gt;&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

I'm concerned that upgrading to newer versions would also cause a loss of album information.
I use the ARM64 (odroid N2+) image with mariadb.
My docker-compose.yaml:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;version: '3.5'

services:
  photoprism:
    image: photoprism/photoprism-arm64
    container_name: photoprism
    restart: unless-stopped

    security_opt:
      - seccomp:unconfined
      - apparmor:unconfined
    ports:
      - 8097:8097 # [local port]:[container port]

    # Run "photoprism help" and "photoprism config" too see all config options and current values:
    environment:
      PHOTOPRISM_ADMIN_PASSWORD: "photoprism"     # Initial admin password: PLEASE CHANGE!
      PHOTOPRISM_DEBUG: "false"                      # Run in debug mode (shows additional log messages)
      PHOTOPRISM_PUBLIC: "true"                     # No authentication required (disables password protection)
      PHOTOPRISM_READONLY: "false"                   # Don't modify originals directory (reduced functionality)
      PHOTOPRISM_UPLOAD_NSFW: "true"                 # Allow uploads that MAY be offensive
      PHOTOPRISM_DETECT_NSFW: "true"                 # Flag photos as private that MAY be offensive
      PHOTOPRISM_EXPERIMENTAL: "false"               # Enable experimental features
      PHOTOPRISM_SITE_URL: "http://localhost:8097/"  # Canonical / public site URL
      PHOTOPRISM_SITE_TITLE: "PhotoPrism"
      PHOTOPRISM_SITE_CAPTION: ""
      PHOTOPRISM_SITE_DESCRIPTION: ""
      PHOTOPRISM_SITE_AUTHOR: ""
      PHOTOPRISM_HTTP_HOST: "0.0.0.0"
      PHOTOPRISM_HTTP_PORT: 8097
      PHOTOPRISM_SETTINGS_HIDDEN: "false"            # Users can not view or change settings
      PHOTOPRISM_DATABASE_DRIVER: "mysql"          # Use MariaDB instead of SQLite for improved performance
      PHOTOPRISM_DATABASE_SERVER: "mariadb-photo:3306"
      PHOTOPRISM_DATABASE_NAME: "photoprism"
      PHOTOPRISM_DATABASE_USER: "photoprism"
      PHOTOPRISM_DATABASE_PASSWORD: "photoprism"
      PHOTOPRISM_SIDECAR_JSON: "true"                # Automatically create JSON sidecar files using Exiftool
      PHOTOPRISM_SIDECAR_YAML: "true"                # Automatically backup metadata to YAML sidecar files
      PHOTOPRISM_THUMB_FILTER: "lanczos"             # Resample filter, best to worst: blackman, lanczos, cubic, linear
      PHOTOPRISM_THUMB_UNCACHED: "false"             # Enable on-demand thumbnail rendering (high memory and cpu usage)
      PHOTOPRISM_THUMB_SIZE: 2048                    # Pre-rendered thumbnail size limit (default 2048, min 720, max 7680)
      PHOTOPRISM_THUMB_SIZE_UNCACHED: 7680           # On-demand rendering size limit (default 7680, min 720, max 7680)
      PHOTOPRISM_JPEG_SIZE: 7680                     # Size limit for converted image files in pixels (720-30000)
      PHOTOPRISM_JPEG_QUALITY: 92                    # Set to 95 for high-quality thumbnails (25-100)
      PHOTOPRISM_DARKTABLE_PRESETS: "false"          # Use darktable presets (disables concurrent raw to jpeg conversion)

    volumes:
      # Storage folder for settings, index &amp; sidecar files (DON'T REMOVE):
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/config:/photoprism/storage"
      # Your personal photo and video collection ([local path]:[container path]):
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/originals:/photoprism/originals"
      # Mounting the import folder is optional (see docs):
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/Import:/photoprism/import"
      
# Uncomment the following lines to use MariaDB instead of SQLite for improved performance &amp; scalability:
  mariadb:
    image: mariadb
    container_name: mariadb-photo
    restart: unless-stopped
    command: mysqld --transaction-isolation=READ-COMMITTED --character-set-server=utf8mb4 --collation-server=utf8mb4_unicode_ci --max-connections=512 --innodb-rollback-on-timeout=OFF --innodb-lock-wait-timeout=50
    volumes:
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/mysql"
    environment:
      MYSQL_ROOT_PASSWORD: photoprism
      MYSQL_USER: photoprism
      MYSQL_PASSWORD: photoprism
      MYSQL_DATABASE: photoprism
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

	</description>
	<comments>
		<comment id='1' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T01:07:33Z'>
		Thanks for reporting this! We're currently working on YAML backup files for albums - maybe this is related... what specific versions were you using, and upgrading to?
Obviously I tested this (just did it again) and it works for me. Does it also happen using our latest development build?
If you've upgraded from a much older version, it's possible that the database schema changed too much in the meantime. We've been continuously adding new features and don't have the resources to provide a guaranteed upgrade path between every single development version. That's why we're about to release a stable version that also comes with YAML backups in case the database gets lost.
		</comment>
		<comment id='2' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T03:29:05Z'>
		Did you re-index? Photo and video metadata is was still there after upgrading, only the albums were missing?
		</comment>
		<comment id='3' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T04:12:23Z'>
		I'm sorry, the versions were the ones available yesterday (photoprims/mariadb), though I can see the docker has been updated 2 hours ago. I'm not sure how to find the specific version (PhotoPrism® 201217-3c973730-Linux-aarch64)?
The photos are still there after re-index, the library (web view) is empty until re-index on reinstall.
I'm not sure if the metadata was preserved since I made no changes to them.
This is not an upgrade, I only started testing this out yesterday.
		</comment>
		<comment id='4' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T04:27:54Z'>
		If there were no search results after re-installation and you had to re-index, it seems the complete database was lost rather than just the albums specifically? Please make sure to use a permanent volume for storing the database in this case.
That's exactly what our new YAML backup files for albums will solve. The are a few config changes when upgrading (you may now also set the most important config options directly in Settings without editing your Docker config):
&lt;denchmark-link:https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&gt;https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;

What changed? Instead of asking our users to enable JSON and YAML files for best results, we enable them by default and offer disable flags in case they don't want this:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_BACKUPS: "false"            # Don't backup photo and album metadata to YAML files
PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_WEBDAV: "false"             # Disable built-in WebDAV server
PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_SETTINGS: "false"           # Users can not view or change settings
PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_PLACES: "false"             # Disables reverse geocoding and maps
PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_EXIFTOOL: "false"           # Don't create ExifTool JSON files for improved metadata extraction
PHOTOPRISM_DISABLE_TENSORFLOW: "false"         # Don't use TensorFlow for image classification
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='5' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T04:35:50Z'>
		Yep, this is wrong (no permanent volume at the MySQL/MariaDB storage location, which is /var/lib/mysql):
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;volumes:
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/mysql"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

 Anonymous volume as shown in our example config at &lt;denchmark-link:https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&gt;https://dl.photoprism.org/docker/docker-compose.yml&lt;/denchmark-link&gt;
:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;volumes:
      - "/var/lib/mysql"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

Option B) External folder mounted as permanent storage:
&lt;denchmark-code&gt;volumes:
      - "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/mysql:/var/lib/mysql"
&lt;/denchmark-code&gt;

		</comment>
		<comment id='6' author='CyanBC' date='2020-12-19T11:18:50Z'>
		I tried the newer image from today, and repeated my steps (remove, reinstall) and this seems to solve the issue:
volumes:
- "/usbdrives/OldSSD/photoprism/mysql:/var/lib/mysql"
Thank you!
		</comment>
	</comments>
</bug>